<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001229726AAIGIE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 35</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>Excitation for the PL imaging measurements was performed with a 445 nm CW laser (Insaneware) through an optical fibre into an integrating sphere. The intensity of the laser was adjusted to a 1 sun equivalent intensity by illuminating a 1 cm 2 -size perovskite solar cell under short-circuit and matching the current density to the ğ½ SC under the sun simulator (22.0 mA/cm 2 at 100 mWcm -2 , or 1.375x10 21 photons m -2 s -1 ). A second optical fiber was used from the output of the integrating sphere to an Andor SR393i-B spectrometer equipped with a silicon CCD camera (DU420A-BR-DD, iDus). The system was calibrated by using a calibrated halogen lamp with specified spectral irradiance, which was shone into to integrating sphere. A spectral correction factor was established to match the spectral output of the detector to the calibrated spectral irradiance of the lamp. The spectral photon density was obtained from the corrected detector signal (spectral irradiance) by division through the photon energy (â„ğ‘“), and the photon numbers of the excitation and emission obtained from numerical integration using Matlab. In a last step, three fluorescent test samples with high specified PLQY (~70%) supplied from Hamamatsu Photonics where measured where the specified value could be accurately reproduced within a small relative error of less than 5%. Measurement conditions: All films and cells were prepared fresh and immediately encapsulated in a glovebox after preparation with the exception of films and cells with spiro-OMeTAD which require oxygen doping for enabling sufficient transport capability in the device (non-oxgygen treated spiro-OMeTAD cells exhibited FFs below 20 % with negligible photovoltaic performance). Thus, films and cells with spiro-OMeTAD were treated in atmosphere overnight at 25% relative humidity, and subsequently encapsulated before the PL measurements. The PL of the samples was readily recorded after mounting the sample after an exposure between 10-20 s to the laser light. Thus, the PLQY is obtained on timescales relevant to the ğ‘‰ OC measurements on the cells. We note that all absolute PL measurements were performed on films with the same HTL, ETL and perovskite thicknesses as used in the operational solar cells. The absorption of the samples was considered in the PLQY calculation and was approximately 85% for cells illuminated through the top encapsulation glass, and ~93% through the bottom glass.</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2467</offset>
      <text>Bottom selective contacts: (HTLs or ETLs): PEDOT:PSS (Heraeus Celivious 4083) was spincoated at 2000 r.p.m for 40s (acceleration 2000 r.p.m/s) and subsequently annealed at 150 Â°C for 15 minutes; P3HT (Sigma Aldrich, Mn~27 000) was spincoated from a 3 mg/mL DCB solution at 3000 r.p.m for 30s (acceleration 3000 r.p.m/s) and subsequently annealed 100 Â°C for 10 minutes. P3HT films were also oxygen plasma treated for 5 s to ensure sufficient wetting of the perovskite as discussed in a previous work.  1  PolyTPD (Ossila) was spincoated from a 1.5 mg/mL DCB solution at 6000 r.p.m for 30 s (acceleration 2000 r.p.m/s) and subsequently annealed 100 Â°C for 10 minutes. PTAA (Sigma Aldrich) was spincoated was spincoated from a 1.5 mg/mL Toluene solution at 6000 r.p.m for 30 s (acceleration 2000 r.p.m/s) and subsequently annealed 100 Â°C for 10 minutes. For PTAA and PolyTPD coated samples, a 60 ÂµL solution of PFN-P2 (0.5 mg/mL in methanol) was added onto the spinning substrate at 5000 rpm for 20 s resulting in a film with a thickness below the detection limit of our AFM (&lt; 5 nm). For compact/mesoporous TiO2 samples, first a nippon Sheet Glass 10 Î©/sq was cleaned by sonication in 2% Hellmanex water solution for 30 minutes. After rinsing with deionised water and ethanol, the substrates were further cleaned with UV ozone treatment for 15 min. Then, 30 nm TiO2 compact layer was deposited on FTO via spray pyrolysis at 450Â°C from a precursor solution of titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) in anhydrous ethanol. After the spraying, the substrates were left at 450Â°C for 45 min and left to cool down to room temperature. Then, a mesoporous TiO2 layer was deposited by spin coating for 20 s at 4000 rpm with a ramp of 2000 rpm s-1, using 30 nm particle paste (Dyesol 30 NR-D) diluted in ethanol to achieve 150-200 nm thick layer. After the spin coating, the substrates were immediately dried at 100Â°C for 10 min and then sintered again at 450Â°C for 30 min under dry air flow. Before processing the perovskite layer TiO2 coated films were microwave plasma treatment (4 min., 200W). Compact SnO2 films were fabricated by using a Tin(IV) oxide nanoparticle dispersion diluted 1:7 vol. with DI-H2O and filtered through 0.45 Î¼m PVDF filter prior to spin coating on the substrate at 2000 rpm (acceleration 2000 r.p.m/s) for 30 s. After 20 minutes of annealing at 150 Â°C, the spin coating procedure was repeated and the samples were annealed again for 30 more minutes. Before processing the perovskite layer TiO2 coated films were microwave plasma treatment (4 min., 200W). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5056</offset>
      <text> Perovskite Layer: The triple cation perovskite solution was prepared by mixing two 1.3 M FAPbI3 and MAPbBr3 perovskite solutions in DMF:DMSO (4:1) in a ratio of 83:17 which we call "MAFA" solution. The 1.3 M FAPbI3 solution was thereby prepared by dissolving FAI (722 mg) and PbI2 (2130 mg) in 2.8 mL DMF and 0.7 mL DMSO (note there is a 10% excess of PbI2). The 1.3 M MAPbBr3 solution was made by dissolving MABr (470 mg) and PbBr2 (1696 mg) in 2.8 mL DMF and 0.7 mL DMSO (note there is a 10% excess of PbBr2). Lastly, 40 ğœ‡ğ¿ of a 1.2M CsI solution in DMSO (389 mg CsI in 1 mL DMSO) was mixed with 960 ğœ‡ğ¿ of the MAFA solution resulting in a final perovskite stoichiometry of (CsPbI3)0.05[(FAPbI3)0.83(MAPbBr3)0.17]0.95 in solution. The perovskite film was deposited by spin-coating at 4000 r.p.m (acceleration 1300 rpm/s) for 35 seconds; 10 Seconds after the start of the spinning process, the spinning substrate was washed with 300 ÂµL EA for approximately 1 second (the antisolvent was placed in the centre of the film). The perovskite film was then annealed at 100 Â°C for 1 hr on a preheated hotplate. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6175</offset>
      <text> Top selective contacts: (HTLs or ETLs): SpiroOMeDAT was spincoated from a spiro-OMeTAD (Merck) solution in chlorobenzene (70 mM) at 4000 rpm for 20 s (acceleration 4000 rpm/s). Spiro-OMeTAD was doped with bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide lithium salt (Li-TFSI, Sigma-Aldrich), tris(2-(1H-pyrazol-1-yl)-4-tertbutylpyridine)-cobalt(III) tris(bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide) (FK209, Dynamo) and 4-tert-Butylpyridine (tBP, Sigma-Aldrich). The molar ratio of additives for spiro-OMeTAD was: 0.5, 0.03 and 3.3 for Li-TFSI, FK209 and tBP respectively. PC61BM (Solenne BV) was spincoated from a 30 mg/mL DCB solution at 6000 rpm (acceleration 2000 r.p.m/s) for 30 s and the resulting Perovksite/PCBM film further annealed at 100 Â°C for 30 minutes. For C60 (Creaphys) and LiF ETLs, the perovskite films were transferred to an evaporation chamber where 30 nm of C60 (1 nm of LiF) were deposited at 0.1 Ã…/s (0.03 Ã…/s) under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). Metal contacts: pin-type devices were completed by transferring the samples to an evaporation chamber where 8 nm BCP (Sigma-Aldrich) at 0.2 A/s and 100 nm copper (Sigma-Aldrich) at 0.6 Ã…/s were deposited under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). nip-type devices were completed by transferring the samples to an evaporation chamber where 100 nm gold (0.7 Ã…/s) were deposited under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). nip-cells were oxgygen doped overnight at 20% relative humidity prior to device and PL measurements. Current density-voltage characteristics: ğ½ğ‘‰-curves were obtained in a 2-wire source-sense configuration with a Keithley 2400. An Oriel class AAA Xenon lamp-based sun simulator was used for illumination providing approximately 100 mW cm -2 of AM1.5G irradiation and the intensity was monitored simultaneously with a Si photodiode. The exact illumination intensity was used for efficiency calculations, and the simulator was calibrated with a KG5 filtered silicon solar cell (certified by Fraunhofer ISE). The temperature of the cell was fixed to 25 Â°C and a voltage ramp of 67 mV/s was used. A spectral mismatch calculation was performed based on the spectral irradiance of the solar simulator, the EQE of the reference silicon solar cell and 3 typical EQEs of our cells. This resulted in 3 mismatch factors of ğ‘€ = 0.9949, 0.9996 and 0.9976. Given the very small deviation from unity the measured ğ½ SC was not corrected by the factor 1/ğ‘€. All EQEs presented in this work were measured by ISE-Fraunhofer. Scanning Electron Spectroscopy: SEM images were acquired with a Zeiss Ultra Plus SEM. Photoemission Spectroscopy Measurements: Photoemission experiments were performed at an ultrahigh vacuum (UHV) system consisting of sample preparation and analysis chambers (both at base pressure: 1 Ã— 10 -10 mbar) as well as a load lock (base pressure: 1 Ã— 10 -6 mbar). All of the samples were transferred to the UHV chamber using a transfer rod under rough vacuum (1 Ã— 10 -3 mbar). Ultraviolet photoemission spectroscopy (UPS) was performed using a helium discharge lamp (21.22 eV) with a filter to reduce the photoflux and to block visible light from the source hitting the sample. All spectra were recorded at room temperature and normal emission using a hemispherical Specs Phoibos 100 analyzer, and the overall energy resolution was 140 meV. Transient Photocurrent (TPC)/Photovoltage (TPV) and differential charging: Photovoltage transients were recorded with an oscilloscope (Agilent 81150A) at different external load resistance (RLoad) of 1 MÎ© (TPV) and 50 Î© (transient photocurrent). A constant background illumination was provided by a white LED which was continuously increased ranging from 10 -3 equivalent suns to approximately 3 suns. Each measured data point corresponds to a different illumination intensity. A Q-switched neodymium-doped yttrium aluminium garnet (Nd:YAG) laser (NT242, EKSPLA)) with a pulse length of 5 ns, a repetition rate of 10 Hz and excitation wavelength of 532 nm was used to generate the charge carriers, while neutral optical density (OD) filters were used to attenuate the power output. The laser fluence was kept low to ensure a small perturbation on top of the constant background current (generating a maximum voltage deflection of 20 mV at 1 MÎ© without background illumination). In order to obtain the carrier lifetime (ğœ) from TPV, the photovoltage was fitted with a monoexponential decay at each laser fluence. ğœ plotted versus the obtained VOC at the given intensity. At low intensities, the effects of external circuit are visible with an ğ‘…ğ¶-time of ~1ms. The differential capacitance was obtained by integrating the TPV signals to obtain Î”ğ‘„, while the Î”ğ‘‰ was obtained from the maximum photovoltage of the TPV transients at each intensity. The differential capacitance is obtained from CDC = Î”ğ‘„/Î”ğ‘‰ and plotted versus the VOC. The geometrical capacitance (ğ¶ geo ) is visible at low intensities or VOCs and accumulated charge in the active layer at higher VOCs. The accumulated charge carrier density in the bulk is obtained by integrating ğ‘› bulk = 1 ğ‘’ğ´ğ‘‘ âˆ« (ğ¶ DC -ğ¶ geo ) ğ‘‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‰ 0 and also plotted versus the VOC at each intensity.  S2 . Quasi-Fermi level splitting of various perovskite films illuminated through the perovskite (blue circles) or the charge transport layer (red symbols) using a 445 nm CW laser. In case of the neat perovskite film, the red symbol corresponds to a measurement through the bottom glass substrate. We note that the 445 nm laser is absorbed within a narrow window in the perovskite layer (&lt;150 nm penetration depth) according to optical transfer matrix simulations which are also shown in Supplementary Figure  S12 . The graph shows that illuminating through the electron transport layers (ETLs) C60, PCBM causes a significantly lower QFLS (up to 30 meV) compared to illumination through the perovskite, which is attributed to substantial parasitic absorption in the ETL at this wavelength. A smaller difference in the QFLS depending on the illumination side was observed for the other transport layers. Remarks: We note that we do not claim that every individual parameter is perfectly consistent with existing literature, however, we consider them as plausible. Importantly, all parameters marked with a star were varied as part of a much larger set of device simulations in order to understand the interplay between these parameters as good as possible. In particular, the impact of the majority (âˆ†E maj ) and minority carrier (âˆ†E min ) band offsets are discussed in the main text. The impact of strongly doped (1x10 18 /cm 3 ) and essentially undoped (1x10 5 /cm 3 ) charge transport layers was tested with an insignificant influence on the here presented results. The role of the carrier mobilities of the charge transport layers was tested with an insignificant influence on the here presented results. The interface recombination velocities and bulk lifetimes were varied as discussed here and in a previous work.  4  The impact of the transport layer thickness was tested. The built-in voltage is given by the workfunction difference of the electrodes, and its influence was tested. The interface recombination velocities in the metal contacts were set to 1x10 7 cm/s for both majority and minority carriers, while PEDOT was treated similar to a contact metal, however, with asymmetric minority and majority recombination velocities. The QFLS was calculated as an average of the emission from the perovskite, that is QFLS avg = ln (âˆ« exp(QFLS(x)) dx d pero 0 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13740</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Figure </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13762</offset>
      <text> Parameter ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13776</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Figure S13. Simulated ğ½ğ‘‰-curves for different built-in voltages (ğ‘‰ BI ) across the device. The ğ‘‰ BI is given by the workfunction difference of the electrodes and is limited by the perovskite bandgap of 1.6 eV. The ğ‘‰ BI was varied by equally reducing the energetic offsets between and the perovskite valence/conduction bands and the workfunctions of the metals at the bottom and top contact, respectively. The results suggest that a considerable ğ‘‰ BI of â‰ˆ1V is required in order to efficiently extract the charges and reproduce experimental JVcurves.</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
