<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001307454HCDBFD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 51</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>Best Research-Cell Efficiencies 2000</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47</offset>
      <text>Increasing concentration is represented by darker shades. Samples were excited at 435 nm via the film surface. Contributions from (PEA)2(MA)n-1PbnI3n+1 are highlighted for the case where n = 1 (purple); 2 (green); and 3 (red). Inset shows a zoom of the PL spectra indicated in the box. We note that there is evidence of detector saturation at 525 nm for the 40 mM sample, leading to an underestimate of the n = 1 contribution in this case.  ). The contribution between 600-650 nm is associated with the pump pulse. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>562</offset>
      <text> Materials &amp; Methods </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>583</offset>
      <text> Sample Preparation Glass slides were cut to 1 x 1 cm and washed in detergent, acetone, water and isopropanol sequentially. Mesoporous titanium dioxide (mp-TiO2) substrates were prepared by spin-coating commercial mp-TiO2 paste (Dyesol), diluted in ethanol 2:7 (paste: ethanol), at 6000 rpm for 30 s onto the clean glass slides. They were then annealed at 500 o C for 45 minutes. The MAPbI3 deposition method was adapted from that of Jeon et al.  38  The MAPbI3 precursor solution contained a 1:1 molar ratio of PbI2 (Alpha Aesar) and MAI (Dyesol) at a concentration of 1.2 M in a mixture of γ-Butyrolactone and dimethyl sulfoxide (ratio 3:7). Once properly mixed, the resulting solution was spin-coated onto the relevant substrate in a 3-step program at 1000, 5000 and 6000 rpm for 10, 30 and 20 s respectively. 800 µL of toluene was drop casted onto the spinning film between the second and third step to aid crystallisation. After the spin-coating program, the film was annealed on a 100 o C hotplate for 10 minutes. The formation of the perovskite was indicated by a colour change from pale yellow to dark brown. Once cooled, iodide salt coatings were added via the method first reported by Aristidou et al.  8  Briefly, solutions were prepared by dissolving the desired concentration of iodide salt (ammonium iodide, methylammonium iodide, n-butylammonium iodide, phenylammonium iodide, phenylmethylammonium iodide, phenylethylammonium iodide) in a 1:4 solvent mixture of IPA and chlorobenzene (CB). All salts were acquired from Sigma Aldrich except methylammonium iodide, which was from Dyesol. One hundred microlitres of salt solution was dripped onto pre-deposited perovskite films with a 20 s loading time before spinning at 4,000 rpm and annealing at 100 o C for 5 min. This was followed by a washing step, in which the film was treated with one hundred microlitres of the 1:4 IPA:CB mixture and spin-coated at 4,000 rpm. HTLs, if relevant, were subsequently deposited via spin-coating such that a 30 ± 5 nm thick layer was formed. PTAA (Mw = 28.422 kDa) and PTPD (MW = 80,000 kDa) were deposited from 10 mg/mL and 8mg/mL solutions respectively, in CB and spin-coated at 5000 and 2500 rpm respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2799</offset>
      <text> Transient Absorption Spectroscopy: TAS is a pump-probe technique that operates on the idea that photogenerated charges change the optical density (OD) property of semiconductors. An initial 'pump' laser pulse, with energy larger than the band-gap, is used to excite electrons from the ground (𝜓 0 ) to an excited state (𝜓 1 ). Subsequently, a second beam probes the absorbance of 𝜓 1 by exciting it to 𝜓 1 (Figure  S9 ). In the case of our measurements on 3D/RDP|HTL films, 𝜓 1 is the HTL after hole injection i.e. the HTL + polaron. Importantly, the initial change in optical density, 𝛥𝑂𝐷 𝑚𝑎𝑥 at the wavelength characteristic of the oxidised HTL is proportional to the concentration, 𝑛 1 of 𝜓 1 by the Beer-Lambert law -𝛥𝑂𝐷 = ε 1 𝑛 1 𝑙, where ε 1 and 𝑛 1 are the extinction coefficient of the excited state and path length respectively. Therefore, 𝛥𝑂𝐷 𝑚𝑎𝑥 is a direct indicator of the hole injection yield to the HTL. Ultrafast transient absorption spectroscopy measurements were conducted by using a transient absorption spectrometer (HELIOS) with a 635 nm pulsed excitation laser pump and a pulsed white light probe. The pump was generated via an optical parametric amplifier (TOPAS Prime, Spectra-Physics) while the probe was generated through a sapphire crystal. Both pump and probe have a frequency of 500Hz and are original from Solstice Ti:Sapphire regenerative amplifier (Newport, Spectra-Physics) with an instrument response time of 200 fs. The intensity of pump was measured of 24 μJ/cm 2 per pulse by using VEGA power meter from OPHIR Photonics. Photoluminescence and Absorbance Spectroscopy: Steady-state photoluminescence was carried out with a commercial Horiba Fluorolog 1039 spectrometer (excitation wavelength: 510 nm; probe: 760 nm). Time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) was carried out with the same probe wavelength at an excitation of 635 nm (0.11 nJ cm -2 ), with a commercial Horiba Deltaflex system. The excitation source for the TCSPC was a Horiba NanoLED-635L with a fluence of 0.11 nJ cm -2 , repetition rate of 1 MHz and pulse half-life of 120 ps. UV-Vis spectra were captured with a Shimadzu UV-2600 integrating sphere spectrophotometer. The excitation source for the TCSPC was a Horiba nanoLED-370 with an excitation wavelength of 369 nm, a pulse duration of 1.3 ns, and a repetition rate of 1 MHz X-Ray Diffraction: XRD patterns were recorded using a Bruker D8 Discover X-ray diffractometer using monochromatic Cu Kα1 and Cu Kα2 radiation of wavelengths 1.54056 and 1.54439 Å, respectively. The Grazing Incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD) crystallographic data for the samples was collected using a PANalytical XPert PRO diffractometer using a GI thin film bracket stage and monochromatic Cu Kα1 and Cu Kα2 radiation of wavelengths 1.54056 and 1.54439 Å (40 mA, 45 kV). 2D Phase Purity Determines Charge-Transfer Yield at 3D/2D Lead Halide Perovskite Heterojunctions A n intense research effort over the past decade has driven the meteoric rise in power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs) to values over 25%. 1 Today, many of their remaining short-comings can be traced back to structural defects. Remarkably, harmful bulk defects that form electronic states within the band gap, i.e., traps, are found at relatively low concentrations in hybrid perovskites compared to other solution-processed technologies.  2  However, the interruption of crystal symmetry at the surface and grain boundaries inevitably leads to a significant population of traps at the interfaces with the charge transport layers (CTLs).  [3] [4] [5]  Such trap states ultimately limit the quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) of electrons and holes under illumination, and thus the open-circuit voltage (V OC ), in MAPbI 3 to below the theoretical maximum of 1.32 V 6 and lead to current voltage hysteresis and chemical instability.  [7] [8] [9]  Braly et al. showed that Lewis base passivation of positively charged traps in MAPbI 3 , such as iodide vacancies (V I ), with electron donating tri-n-octylphosphide (TOPO) leads to an internal QFLS of 1.28 eV.  10  The implication of this is that the bulk material does not intrinsically limit the V OC and that effective trap passivation at the surface and grain boundaries should lead to values approaching the radiative limit. Therefore, an intense research effort has set about developing strategies that emulate such passivation with other small molecules, inert polymers, and CTLs.  [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] [16] [17] [18]  Treatment of perovskite with iodide salts is another wellestablished passivation strategy. It has been shown that adding overstoichiometric (&lt;5 wt %) amounts of small iodide salts, where "small" is here defined as those salts containing an R-NH 3 + cation that would satisfy Goldschmidt's tolerance factor if incorporated into a traditional 3D perovskite lattice,  19  to the perovskite precursor mixture can yield devices with a slightly larger PCE, but when applied in excess, the buildup of unreacted R-NH 3 I can degrade device performance.  [20] [21] [22]  On the other hand, introducing 2D character to perovskite by adding bulky ammonium iodide salts (R-NH 3 I), i.e., those that cannot be incorporated into the 3D perovskite lattice, has come to the fore as an effective passivation strategy. The R-NH 3 I is either added to the precursor solution to induce bulk passivation  23, 24  or as a post-treatment to provide targeted functionalization of the perovskite|CTL interface [where CTL = hole transport layer (HTL) in nip, electron transport layer (ETL) in pin].  [25] [26] [27]  In the latter strategy, a layer of reduceddimensional perovskite (RDP) with formula (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 is formed between the 3D perovskite layer and the CTL. Such 3D/RDP PSCs have superior stability in comparison to their purely 3D counterparts,  24, [28] [29] [30]  which is often attributed to the hydrophobicity of the R-NH 3 + ions in the RDP layer.  [31] [32] [33]  Less clear is the role of the RDP layer in enhancing charge extraction and ultimately device PCE.  26, [28] [29] [30] [33] [34] [35]  Here, the progression of research has largely relied on empirical observations rather than rigid design rules based on a comprehensive understanding of the 3D/RDP system. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>9179</offset>
      <text> Pioneering work has elucidated the importance of energy Published: March 26, 2021 Letter pubs.acs.org/JPCL cascades, energy transfer, and charge mobility in the 3D/RDP system,  [36] [37] [38] [39]  but a consistent model for hole injection at the 3D/RDP|HTL interface is still lacking. The Grancini group has made significant steps forward in this regard, showing that effective RDP-on-3D passivation is predicated by a flat conformation of the RDP layer.  40  In another study, they showed that the 3D/RDP interface is dynamic, in that the RDP layerinitially consisting largely of (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 (n = 1)can scavenge intrinsic MA cations from the 3D perovskite t o f o r m d e v i c e -l i m i t i n g , h i g h e r -o r d e r ( R -NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 1, 2, ...) heterostructures, which can be proscribed by careful design of the RDP-inducing passivant.  41  Elsewhere, Teale et al. developed a technique for dimensional mixing of the passivating RDP layer. They used grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS) to suggest that device PCE was enhanced for mixed-n RDPs but suggested that further study should be carried out with more precise optical techniques.  42  Interestingly, the common denominator in the latter two studies is the significance of the n value in the passivating (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 layer. However, the link between the value of n and charge extraction remains unseen. Additionally, it is unclear whether the RDP layer actively mediates hole injection in 3D/RDP|HTL systems  26, 43, 44  or forms an electronically benign passivating layer.  23, 40  Herein, we use a combination of surface-sensitive structural and time-resolved optical spectroscopy to elucidate the full scale of passivation in n-i-p MAPbI 3 perovskite films treated with R-NH 3 I salts. We show that cation bulkiness is a prerequisite to enhancements in the injection efficiency, with smaller cations actually working to reduce charge extraction by forming trapping centers. We reveal that the improvements with bulky cations are due to the treatment of excess PbI 2 with R-NH 3 I to form (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 at the MAPbI 3 | HTL interface. Moreover, we gain new insights into the charge s e p a r a t i o n m e c h a n i s m a t t h e M A P b I 3 | ( R -NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 |HTL (3D/RDP|HTL) interface: (i) the RDP layer does not mediate hole injection between the 3D perovskite and the HTL; (ii) efficient hole injection is possible only for n = 1 and is significantly inhibited in systems where n &gt; 1. These results yield an important design rule for the development of high-performance 3D/2D perovskite optoelectronics. In order to investigate the role of chemical structure in determining the efficacy of passivation, we screened methylammonium and phenethylammonium (MAI and PEAI) and The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters pubs.acs.org/JPCL Letter several other R-NH 3 I (R-NH 3 + = ammonium, phenylammonium, phenylmethylammonium, and butylammonium) salts. We note that samples were prepared via a one-step deposition of MAPbI 3 with a 1:1 PbI 2 :MAI ratio as reported elsewhere,  45  followed by iodide salt treatment and annealing as outlined in the Supporting Information. Device efficiency is ultimately based on the yield of sustained charge injection at the interfaces between MAPbI 3 and its CTLs. Therefore, we first investigated the role of R-NH 3 I in determining the hole-transfer yield at the MAPbI 3 :R-NH 3 I|HTL interface with microsecond transient absorption spectroscopy (μs-TAS). Details of the μs-TAS technique and setup can be found in the Supporting Information. Figure  S1  shows that MAPbI 3 exhibits no transient absorption features on the microsecond time scale, which is in line with the typical 10-100 ns recombination time scale for this material in the fluence range used. On the other hand, when interfaced with the HTL poly(triarylamine) (PTAA), a broad TA feature is observed with a maximum signal strength, ΔOD max at 1500 nm, which can be attributed to hole polarons in PTAA formed after injection from the MAPbI 3 valence band.  46, 47  Given the proportionality between ΔOD max and the concentration of injected holes in PTAA, we could then track the impact of each R-NH 3 I treatment on hole transfer to the HTL. Figure  1  shows the relative hole injection yield (i.e., ΔOD max ) in MAPbI 3 |HTL films in the case of passivation with 20 mM of the different iodide salts. Strikingly, only the iodide salts with bulky cations, i.e., those to the right of the control (black) film in Figure  1 , can improve the hole injection yield to the HTL. In contrast, application of MAI and AI to MAPbI 3 results in a reduction in hole injection yield at the MAPbI 3 |HTL interface. This supports work elsewhere in the literature, where MAI applied in great excess, or as a post-treatment, works to lower the PCE of PSCs.  [20] [21] [22]  In order to understand this surprising result, we turned to steady-state and time-resolved photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy using MAI as an example salt treatment with a small cation. In Figure  1b, c  we see that the lifetime and intensity of the MAPbI 3 film after MAI treatment are much reduced. This suggests that the addition of MAI adds additional trap-states through which the photoexcited charges in the MAPbI 3 layer can recombine. Consideration of the reaction between MAI and the perovskite film leads to a potential explanation for the increase in trap density after MAI passivation and annealing. Ascrystallized MAPbI 3 contains an excess of PbI 2 at the grain boundaries because of the ready escape of MAI during annealing.  48  This excess PbI 2 is known to improve the performance of perovskite solar cells through a passivation effect  [48] [49] [50]  and may also lower the hole injection barrier at the MAPbI 3 |HTL interface, improving hole extraction.  49, 50  We display evidence for the formation of excess PbI 2 with grazingincidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD) measurements in Figure  S2 , where our control MAPbI 3 film shows a peak at 2θ = 12.6°a ssociated with the (001) orientation of unreacted PbI 2 .  51  We also observe a contribution at 2θ = 14.2°, associated with the (110) orientation of the 3D perovskite. The removal of the 2θ = 12.6°peak in the MAI-treated sample (Figure  S2 , second panel) suggests that the MAI reacts with PbI 2 , removing its beneficial passivation effects. We note that the peak position of the (110) contribution associated with 3D perovskite remains unchanged and the intensity is not reduced, allowing us to discard the idea that MAI treatment deteriorates performance by exerting strain on, or damaging, the pre-existing 3D perovskite structure.  52  On the other hand, MAPbI 3 films treated with R-NH 3 I salts containing bulky R-NH 3 + cations consistently exhibit hole injection yields greater than that of the unpassivated control. We used PEAI as an example bulky R-NH3I salt. The enhanced PL lifetime and intensity in MAPbI 3 :PEAI films exhibited in Figure  1b ,c provide strong evidence that recombination of photoexcited charge carriers in MAPbI 3 is much suppressed after PEAI treatment. Furthermore, the entirely opposite effect of PEAI compared to MAI treatment on charge separation in the MAPbI 3 film suggests that the cation plays a decidedly different role in the former case. Further insight into the mechanism of passivation in the case of MAPbI 3 :PEAI films is given in Figure  1c , where an additional PL contribution can be observed at 525 nm. As has been established elsewhere,  26, 35  passivation with bulky organic cations leads to the formation of a reduced dimensional perovskite (RDP) layer with formula (PEA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 at the top surface of the 3D perovskite film due to the inability of the cation to intercalate into a traditional 3D perovskite lattice. We therefore attribute the 525 nm feature to (PEA) 2 PbI 4 atop the 3D perovskite film. We provide further evidence for this in Figure  S3 , where we excited 3D/RDP at 450 nm (penetration depth, ∼100 nm) from the film and substrate faces, respectively, and measured the PL. The much enhanced intensity of the 525 nm contribution after excitation from the film face confirms that the RDP layer is concentrated at the top surface of the MAPbI 3 film. Moreover, in Figure  S4  we present the PL spectra of 3D perovskite treated with the other bulky R-NH 3 I salts (i.e., PAI, PMAI, and BAI). The features observed in the 500-550 nm region of the spectrum indicate the formation of (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 heterostructures in all cases. This is in good agreement with the literature, where bulky R-NH 3 I salts such as these are routinely used to induce RDP layers.  25, 28, 53  We can therefore conclude that bulky R-NH 3 + cations are prerequisite to the enhancements in interfacial charge injection observed after iodide salt passivation. We also carried out GIXRD to obtain interface-specific insight into the formation of the RDP (Figure  S2 ). Notably, in the case of passivation with the R-NH 3 I salts, the (001) peak associated with PbI 2 is entirely removed after all but PAI treatment, which still shows a substantial reduction in intensity. This suggests that the RDP layers are seeded by reaction between R-NH 3 I and excess PbI 2 at the 3D perovskite surface. We next looked to quantify exactly how interfacial hole injection correlates with the growth of the RDP passivating layer on the 3D perovskite by increasing the concentration of PEAI from 4 to 40 mM. Given the potential for PEA + to combine with intrinsic MA + from the 3D perovskite film to form (PEA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 , we paid particular attention to the formation of n &gt; 1 RDP layers. We first investigated the growth of the RDP on 3D perovskite as a function of [PEAI] with XRD. Raw XRD patterns (Figure  S5 ) exhibit strong diffraction peaks for 3D perovskite films at 14.2°, 28.5°, and 32.5°, which are associated with the (110), (220), and (310) lattice orientations of 3D tetragonal halide perovskite.  48  Furthermore, the (002) orientation of (PEA) 2 PbI 4 , present within the RDP, becomes increasingly prevalent as a function of [PEAI].  26  In Figure  2a  we track the evolution of the (  110 ) and (002) characteristic peaks of the 3D perovskite and RDP, respectively, as a function of [PEAI]. This data suggests that the RDP is present even at a relatively low concentration of 10 mM. Moreover, for [PEAI] &gt; 10 mM, the 3D perovskite contribution reduces in intensity, suggesting significant damage to the underlying 3D perovskite layer at high PEAI concentrations. We next turned to PL spectroscopy hoping that the orders of magnitude greater sensitivity of this technique could reveal more about the 2D character of the passivated films. In Figure  2b  we summarize the evolution of the RDP with [PEAI] by tracking the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 (n = 1), (PEA) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 (n = 2), and (PEA) 2 (MA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 (n = 3) contributions in the PL spectra at 525, 560, and 610 nm, respectively (raw spectra in Figure  S6 ).  41, 54, 55  Interestingly, we find that the n &gt; 1 features for the [PEAI] ≤ 10 mM samples are minimal when compared to the n = 1 contribution. Notably, the contribution from the n = 2 structure increases with [PEAI] thereafter to 4% and 25% for 20 and 40 mM, respectively. Additionally, a third contribution associated with the n = 3 structure is present at 5% in the PL spectrum of the 40 mM film. It can therefore be concluded that an almost phase-pure (PEA) 2 PbI 4 layer is formed after PEAI treatment at concentrations equal to or below 10 mM because of the consumption of the excess PbI 2 in the film. At higher concentrations, we suggest that the additional PEAI begins to attack the perovskite itself presumably at unsaturated PbI 6 octahedra via V MA sitesand combines with intrinsic MA + to form higher-order RDP (n &gt; 1) heterostructures. We next assessed the impact of RDP growth on the relative hole injection yield, i.e., ΔOD max from μs-TAS. The results in Figure  2c  show that the relationship between hole injection and [PEAI] is nontrivial, reaching a maximum at 10 mM. Importantly, this is the concentration at which the largest amount of phase-pure (PEA) 2 PbI 4 (i.e., n = 1) RDP is formed, with minimal formation of higher-order n &gt; 1 structures. Indeed, the formation of these higher-order structures in the passivating layer is concomitant with a decrease in the hole injection yield. To probe the origin of this maximum in hole injection yield at 10 mM, we captured PL decay dynamics for 3D|HTL and 3D/RDP|HTL with the results displayed in Figure  2d . The PL decay of 3D perovskite can be fitted to a biexponential with a fast (τ 1 ) and slow (τ 2 ) component indicative of charge trapping at grain boundaries and in the bulk, respectively.  56  Upon addition of an HTL, the fast decay (τ 1 = τ inj ) becomes indicative of hole injection, and the slow component (τ 2 ) is due to either unquenched charges that remain in the bulk  57  or surface recombination.  5  The rapid (τ inj = 503 ps) hole injection kinetics observed after interfacing 3D perovskite with PTAA are in line with previous literature reports,  46  attributed to the significant energetic offset (ΔE ≈ 0.2 eV) at the 3D|PTAA interface. We note that τ inj here is much larger than the instrumental response of our TCSPC setup (τ IRF ≈ 100 ps) allowing for accurate assignation of the kinetics. Importantly, τ inj (=513 ps) for 3D/RDP|PTAA is similar to that for 3D|PTAA (Table  1 , bold), suggesting that the RDP layer has little impact on the kinetics of hole injection at the 3D/RDP|HTL interface. In light of this, we rationalize the increased hole injection yield (n + in Figure  2d , inset) at [PEAI] = 10 mM as a decrease of the recombination rate constant in the 3D layer (k rec,M ), rather than an increase in the hole injection rate constant (k inj ). The findings presented so far prove that upon passivation of 3D perovskite with 10 mM PEAI (i) an almost phase-pure Table  1 . Biexponential Fitting (y(t) = A 1 e -t/τ 1 + A 2 e -t/τ 2 ) Parameters for the Time-Resolved Single-Photon Counting Decays Given in Figure  2a  sample a We note that τ 1 = τ inj for PTAA-coated samples. A 1 τ 1 (=τ inj ) (ps) A 2 τ 2 ( The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters pubs.acs.org/JPCL Letter (PEA) 2 PbI 4 layer is formed; (ii) this layer is positioned at the 3D|HTL interface; and (iii) hole injection is not impeded by the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 passivating layer. We therefore next looked to build a picture of the interfacial energetics to explain these observations. While it is established that the conduction band minimum (CBM) of RDP lies well ab ov e the CBM of MAPbI 3 ,  23, 40, 43, [58] [59] [60]  reporting on the position of the valence band maximum (VBM) has not been consistent. This is most likely due to variations in band gap (n value) and ligand coverage, both of which have a significant impact on the VBM.  42  Cho et al. reported that the valence band (VB) energy of (PEA) 2 PbI 4 is similar to that in MAPbI 3 .  26  In contrast, several other literature reports place the VBM of RDPs as shallower than the 3D VBM.  43, 44  Elsewhere, another group of reports place the VBM of RDPs as deeper than the 3D VBM.  23, 40, 58  As such, depending on the literature report, the 3D/RDP interface alternates between type I (3D band gap lies within the RDP band gap) and type II (only the 3D conduction band lies within the RDP band gap), which has important implications for the mechanism of hole injection at the 3D/RDP|HTL interface. In the type I case, the RDP VB lies below that of MAPbI 3 and hole injection to the HTL occurs via tunnelling (Figure  3a ). Otherwise, in the type II case, the RDP VB lies between that of MAPbI 3 and the HTL HOMO and thus mediates hole injection (Figure  3b ). In order to establish which of the two proposed mechanisms is at work, we conducted femtosecond-TAS (fs-TAS) studies on 3D and 3D/RDP films formed after treatment of 3D perovskite with the optimized concentration of 10 mM PEAI. We probed the absorption in the visible/near-infrared (400-800 nm) region after exciting the samples at 635 nm and found two distinct bleaching peaks at ∼476 nm (PB1) and ∼760 nm (PB2). PB2 is assigned to the band edge transition of 3D perovskite, which is in line with the absorption onset of the 3D perovskite film in Figure  S7  at 760 nm. The origin of PB1 is debated but may be due either to excitation from a deeper valence band  61, 62  or a charge-transfer state involving PbI x complexes.  63  The broad positive band between 500 and 700 nm is assigned to photoinduced absorption (PIA), potentially from I 2 -like reversable photodissociation products of PbI x -.  63  As indicated in Figure  S7 , 2D (PEA) 2 PbI 4 has a strong ground-state absorption beginning at 525 nm. In TA spectra, this absorption can lead to a photobleaching feature (PB3) between 500 and 525 nm.  36, 40  We hypothesized that if the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 layer plays an active role in mediating hole injection, PB3 would be present in the TA spectrum at time τ inj after initial excitation of the 3D perovskite. However, the shape of the 3D (Figure  3c ) and 3D/RDP (Figure  3d ) spectra are The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters pubs.acs.org/JPCL Letter strikingly similar across the 6 ns time window for the measurement. This result suggests that no hole injection occurs between the 3D perovskite and RDP layer. We note that the RDP layer in the optimized system, after treatment with 10 mM PEAI, is very thin, and so PB3 (maximum ∼500 nm) could be obscured by PB1 (maximum ∼476 nm), which is assigned to the much thicker 3D perovskite film. However, we show in Figure  S8  that even for a much thicker RDP layer, after 40 mM PEAI treatment, still no features are observed that can be attributed to PB3. This adds weight to our argument that no injection occurs between the 3D and RDP layers. In agreement with our time-resolved PL studies we find an increased lifetime of photoexcited charges in the 3D/RDP samples (Figure  3e ,f, magenta lines) compared to pure 3D (Figure  3e ,f, black lines). Additionally, we checked the decay of PB1 and PB2 for signs of 3D-to-RDP injection. This would be evidenced by a rising component in PB1, due to proximity to the RDP GSB, and a "quenching" component in PB2, due to depopulation of the 3D perovskite after injection to the RDP. However, no such abnormalities in the recombination kinetics were observed. Combining this with the lack of new features associated with PB3 in the 3D/RDP TA spectra, we suggest that the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 layer formed after PEAI passivation does not accept holes from the 3D perovskite on the time scales studied (&lt;6 ns). Given that hole injection to the HTL in the bestperforming PSC devices occurs on faster time scales, often subnanosecond as observed in Figure  2d  and elsewhere,  46, 64  we can say with some certainty that the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 layer in our 3D/RDP system does not actively mediate hole injection. This suggests that the 3D/RDP interface is type I, as put forward elsewhere.  23, 40, 58  Given RDP coverage on the 3D perovskite surface is likely incomplete in the optimized system, hole injection can occur via two potential mechanisms: (i) tunnelling at the 3D/RDP|HTL interface and (ii) direct injection in regions of immediate contact between the 3D perovskite and HTL. In Figure  4 , we summarize the mechanism of R-NH 3 I passivation in our system. First, the bulky R-NH 3 I reacts with PbI 2 at the 3D perovskite surface (Figure  4a  and b ). If [R-NH 3 I] &lt; 10 mM, the formation of pure (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 at the 3D perovskite surface is favored, with minimal disruption of the MA + content in the MAPbI 3 bulk (Figure  4c ). Here, the hole injection barrier is sufficiently thin, and/or there is enough direct contact between the 3D perovskite and HTL, that charge injection can proceed efficiently. However, if [R-NH 3 I] &gt; 10 mM, a thicker (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 1, 2, 3...) layer is formed (Figure  4d ) because of the combination of R-NH 3 + with intrinsic MA + . There is some evidence that such layers stack with a tendency to lower n at the interface with the 3D perovskite,  36  but it is likely that the phase distribution of the RDP is highly disordered.  65  This situation then harms interfacial hole injection in three potential ways: (i) removal of intrinsic MA + from the 3D perovskite layer could generate trap states at the 3D/RDP interface; (ii) the disordered RDP layer containing (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 1, 2, 3...) could form trap states via hole funnelling; and (iii) the tunnelling yield through the RDP layer decreases exponentially with layer thickness. The 10 mM optimum concentration for PEAI found herein is in excellent agreement with the optimum PCE found elsewhere,  29, 66  on MAPbI 3 -based PSCs with a 1:1 stoichiometry. We note that the optimum concentration of PEAI would likely increase in the case of PbI 2 -rich stoichiometry.  25  Ultimately, during R-NH 3 I passivation with bulky ammonium iodide salts, the passivation layer at the 3D perovskite surface undergoes a transformation from PbI 2 to (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 . While the presence of PbI 2 at the grain boundaries has been known to exert a limited improvement on PSC efficiency,  [48] [49] [50]  PbI 2 is a known proponent of degradation in devices.  67  Exchanging PbI 2 for (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 therefore offers a superior passivation method given that (i) the (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 layer is relatively stable and water resistant and (ii) the charge extraction efficiency, and by extension the PCE, is much enhanced. In conclusion, we presented a comprehensive investigation of the passivation and charge-transfer mechanism at 3D/RDP| HTL heterojunctions. We showed that passivation ensues via a mechanism by which R-NH 3 I reacts with excess PbI 2 in the 3D perovskite film to form a layered (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 heterostructure. We revealed that the RDP layer does not actively mediate hole transfer between the 3D perovskite and HTL layers, implying that interfacial hole injection occurs via tunnelling, regions of direct 3D|HTL contact, or a combination of both. As such, precise growth of the RDP layer is critical, with n = 1 yielding a significant improvement in interfacial hole injection across the 3D/2D|HTL interface, but n &gt; 1 being detrimental to charge injection. We expect that proper consideration of the resulting 3D/RDP interface in these systems will aid the design of future passivation strategies capable of further enhancing the efficiency and stability of perovskite optoelectronics. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31989</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32013</offset>
      <text> * sı Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c00362 .  Figure S1 :Figure S2 : S1S2 Figure S1: Transient absorption spectrum of MAPbI3 and MAPbI3|PTAA captured 10 -6 s after excitation at 510 nm (fluence: 10 μJ cm -2 ) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32322</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 : S3 Figure S3: Steady-state photoluminescence spectra of 3D/RDP, formed after treatment of MAPbI3 with 20 mM PEAI, measured with excitation (450 nm) at the film (solid line) and substrate (dashed line) faces. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32543</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 : S4 Figure S4: Photoluminescence spectra of MAPbI3 films treated with 10 mM PMAI (grey), BAI (red), PAI (green) and with no treatment (black). Samples were excited at 435 nm via the film surface. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32751</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 : S5 Figure S5: X-ray diffraction patterns for MAPbI3 films treated with 0, 4, 10, 20 and 40 mM PEAI. The (110) and (002) peaks associated with MAPbI3 and (PEA)2PbI4 are highlighted with (☆) and (•) respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32979</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 : S6 Figure S6: Raw photoluminescence spectra of MAPbI3 treated with 4, 10, 20 and 40 mM of PEAI. Increasing concentration is represented by darker shades. Samples were excited at 435 nm via the film surface. Contributions from (PEA)2(MA)n-1PbnI3n+1 are highlighted for the case where n = 1 (purple); 2 (green); and 3 (red). Inset shows a zoom of the PL spectra indicated in the box. We note that there is evidence of detector saturation at 525 nm for the 40 mM sample, leading to an underestimate of the n = 1 contribution in this case. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33528</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 : S7 Figure S7: Absorption spectra of 3D, 2D and 3D/RDP formed after treatment of MAPbI3 with 10 mM PEAI. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33645</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 : S8 Figure S8: (a) Femtosecond transient absorption spectra as a function of time for a 3D/RDP film formed after treatment of MAPbI3 with 40 mM PEAI. The decay dynamics at 476 nm and 760 nm are shown in (b) and (c) respectively. The films were pumped at 635 nm (fluence: 25 μJ cm -2). The contribution between 600-650 nm is associated with the pump pulse. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34014</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 : S9 Figure S9: Three state diagram for transient absorption spectroscopy. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34100</offset>
      <text> Robert J. E. Westbrook,* Weidong Xu, Xinxing Liang, Thomas Webb, Tracey M. Clarke, and Saif A. Haque* Cite This: J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12, 3312-3320 Read Online ACCESS Metrics &amp; More Article Recommendations * sı Supporting Information ABSTRACT: Targeted functionalization of 3D perovskite with a 2D passivation layer via R-NH 3 I treatment has emerged as an effective strategy for enhancing both the efficiency and chemical stability of ABX 3 perovskite solar cells, but the underlying mechanisms behind these improvements remain unclear. Here, we assign a passivation mechanism where R-NH 3 I reacts with excess PbI 2 in the MAPbI 3 film and unsaturated PbI 6 octahedra to form (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 . Crucially, we show that precise control of the 2D (R-NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 layer underpins performance improvements: n = 1 yields over a 2-fold improvement in hole injection to the HTL; n &gt; 1 deteriorates hole injection. Ultrafast transient absorption spectroscopy suggests this n-dependence is rooted in the fact that fast (&lt;6 ns) hole injection does not occur between the 3D and 2D layers. These results help explain contemporary empirical findings in the field and set out an important design rule for the further optimization of multidimensional perovskite optoelectronics. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35407</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. (a) ΔOD max , i.e., ΔOD from transient absorption spectroscopy (TAS) measured 1 μs after excitation, for TiO 2 |MAPbI 3 :R-NH 3 I (20 mM)|PTAA samples, where R-NH 3 + is ammonium (A), methylammonium (MA), butylammonium (BA), phenylammonium (PA), phenylmethylammonium (PMA), and phenethylammonium (PEA). The same parameter for a MAPbI 3 |HTL sample with no passivation treatment is given in black. The samples were excited at a wavelength of 510 nm and pulse fluence of 10 μJ cm -2 . A probe wavelength of 1500 nm was used to identify injected holes in the HTL layer. The structures of the passivating agents surround (a); anticlockwise: AI, MAI, BAI, PAI, PMAI, and PEAI. (b) Time-resolved single-photon counting (TCSPC) decays of MAPbI 3 films treated with 20 mM PEAI (magenta) and MAI (brown). The control MAPbI 3 decay with no coating is given in black. Samples were excited with a pump wavelength of 635 nm at 0.11 nJ cm -2 and probed at 760 nm. (c) Steady-state photoluminescence of the samples after excitation via the film surface with a wavelength of 450 nm at 260 mW cm -2 . </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36519</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Hole injection in 3D/RDP|HTL films. (a) Change in the (110) peak from 3D perovskite (☆) and the (002) peak from the RDP passivating layer (•) with [PEAI]. (b) Evolution of the RDP photoluminescence spectrum in 3D/RDP films at 525 (n = 1; purple), 560 (n = 2; green), and 610 nm (n = 3, red) as a function of [PEAI]. (c) ΔOD max , i.e., ΔOD from transient absorption spectroscopy (TAS) measured 1 μs after excitation, of 3D/RDP|PTAA films with increasing [PEAI]. The films were excited at 510 nm (fluence: 1.5 μJ cm -2) and probed at 1500 nm, the maximum of the PTAA polaron. (d) Time-resolved single-photon counting (TCSPC) decays for 3D (solid points) and 3D/RDP films (empty points) with and without PTAA (orange) (excitation, 635 nm; fluence of 0.11 nJ cm -2 ; probe, 760 nm). Inset depicts the competing kinetic processes at the MAPbI 3 |HTL interface. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37408</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Charge injection mechanism in 3D/RDP|HTL formed after treating MAPbI 3 with 10 mM PEAI. Illustration of the two possible mechanisms for hole injection at the 3D/RDP|HTL interface: (a) tunnelling injection (type I interface) and (b) mediated hole injection (type II interface). Femtosecond transient absorption spectra of (c) 3D and (d) 3D/RDP films as a function of time. The two key photoinduced absorption features at 476 nm (blue) and 760 nm (red) are highlighted. The decay dynamics in the case of 3D (black) and 3D/RDP (pink) at 476 and 760 nm are shown in panels e and f, respectively. Films were pumped at 635 nm (fluence: 25 μJ cm -2 ), resulting in the 550-650 nm gap in the spectra. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38126</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Proposed mechanism for R-NH 3 I passivation. (a) R-NH 3 I is spin-coated atop the 3D perovskite surface. (b) R-NH 3 I targets PbI 2 sites. (c) R-NH 3 I reacts with PbI 2 to form (R-NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 after annealing. (d) At high concentrations, excess R-NH 3+ combines with MA + from the MAPbI 3 bulk to form higher-order (R-NH 3 ) 2 MA n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n &gt; 1) layered structures after annealing. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38543</offset>
      <text> Transient absorption spectra of MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 | PTAA; grazing incidence X-ray diffraction patterns of MAPbI 3 passivated with different R-NH 3 I coatings; steady-state photoluminescence spectra of a 3D/RDP film with excitation at the air and substrate interfaces; steady-state photoluminescence spectra of MAPbI 3 treated with R-NH 3 I salts; X-ray diffraction patterns for MAPbI 3 treated with different concentrations of PEAI; steady-state photoluminescence spectra of MAPbI 3 treated with different concentrations of PEAI; absorption spectra of 3D, 2D, and 3D/RDP films; femtosecond transient absorption characterization of 3D/RDP films; materials and methods (PDF) ■ AUTHOR INFORMATION Corresponding Authors </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39264</offset>
      <text>			 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c00362 J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12, 3312-3320 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:41:30 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39539</offset>
      <text>			 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c00362 J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12, 3312-3320 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39628</offset>
      <text>			 J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12, 3312-3320</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
