<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001313682BGDEHD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 74</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>As shown in Fig.  1c , the pristine PbBr2 film showed a characteristic diffraction peak at 18.48°, corresponding to the lattice plane of (020). After dipping the film in the FAI solution, this peak completely disappeared, and a new peak at 13.84° corresponding to the (001) plane of the 3D perovskite emerged. When PEG, PS and PMMA were coated onto the PbBr2 film, the transition from PbBr2 to 3D perovskite still proceeded, as evidenced by the emergence of (001) peaks with comparable intensities to those of the pristine PbBr2 film. Notably, when the CLP was deposited on the PbBr2, the film maintained the (020) peak of PbBr2 after dipping in the FAI solution, and the (001) peak corresponding to 3D perovskite was significantly weaker. The peak intensity and integral area are presented in Supplementary Table  2 . When PbBr2 films were dipped in the 4F-PEAI solution, similar results were observed. Pristine PbBr2 reacted with 4F-PEAI, and formed 4F-PEA2Pb(IxBr1-x)4, showing a characteristic diffraction peak at 5.48°. When PEG, PS, and PMMA were used to cover the PbBr2 film, the transition from PbBr2 to 2D perovskite was not prevented. However, for PbBr2 films covered with the CLP, the intensity of the (100) peak of 2D perovskite 4F-PEA2Pb(IxBr1-x)4 was significantly reduced. The peak intensity and integral area are presented in Supplementary Table  3 . These results revealed that the CLP layer can effectively inhibit the intercalation of FA + and 4F-PEA + into the inorganic template of PbBr2. Supplementary Note 2: pEDMA and the CLP were employed to prevent the reaction between PbBr2 films and FAI at an elevated temperature of 100 °C (Supplementary Fig.  6 ). The FAI solution was spin-coated on PbBr2/pEDMA and PbBr2/CLP films, and annealed at 100 °C for 10 to 300 min. After only 30 min, XRD patterns of PbBr2/pEDMA/FAI films showed a distinct peak corresponding to 3D perovskite. On the contrary, the diffraction peak of 3D perovskite in PbBr2/CLP/FAI films remained at a much weaker intensity even after 300 min of thermal annealing. This indicates that the CLP is more effective at inhibiting ion diffusion than pEDMA under thermal stress. To investigate the stabilization effects of EDMA monomers and pEDMA in the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures, we aged 3D/EDMA/2D and 3D/pEDMA/2D films at 100 °C for 120 min, and compared the evolution of PL spectra. As shown in Fig.  2d , EDMA and pEDMA only offer partial stabilization the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures under thermal stress. After thermal ageing, the PL emission intensity of 2D perovskite 4F-PEA2PbI4 in both the 3D/EDMA/2D and 3D/pEDMA/2D films reduced, and PL emission of the quais-2D perovskite 4F-PEA2FAPb2I7 emerged. Thus, we conclude that the high degree of crosslinking and the network structure of the POSS-EDMA-based CLP play crucial roles in stabilizing the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures. Supplementary Note 3: It is challenging to directly measure the thickness of the CLP layer that was prepared using a concentration of 3 mg mL -1 . Instead, we prepared CLP layers with concentrations of 10, 15 and 20 mg mL -1 , and directly measured the thickness of the CLP layers using a profilometer (Bruker, Dektak). As shown in Supplementary Figure  8a , as the concentration increases from 10 to 20 mg mL -1 , the thickness of the as-prepared CLP layer increases from ~14 nm to ~40 nm. Using polynomial fitting to simulate the layer thicknesses, we estimate the thickness of the CLP layer for the concentration of 3 mg mL -1 to be 2~3 nm. Additionally, we conducted XPS depth profiling, as shown in Supplementary Figure  8b . We used the signals of oxygen (O 1s) to track the existence of the CLP. After etching for only 30 seconds, the signals of oxygen disappeared. The etching rate of the argon gun towards the reference material (NPB, the molecular structure is shown in Supplementary Figure  8c ) was calibrated to be 0.5~0.6 Å s -1 , and thus the thickness of the CLP layer should be below 1.8 nm. Supplementary Note 4: Previously, we have incorporated 3F-PEAI for surface treatment of 3D perovskite in p-i-n inverted PSCs [5]  . Herein, for n-i-p PSCs, the principle for selecting the organic ligand and tuning band alignment is entirely different. In p-i-n PSCs, the 2D layer on the surface of the 3D perovskite should be suitable for electron transfer and can block holes. However, this requirement is not easily met by regular 2D perovskite modification strategies. The 2D perovskite layer usually has a conduction band minimum (CBM) that is much higher than that of the 3D perovskite, which results in an electron-blocking effect. Thus, using a 2D perovskite layer on 3D perovskite in a p-i-n device is likely to reduce the efficiency of PSCs. Using ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) and absorption spectroscopy, the band alignment of low dimensional perovskite films of differing quantum well widths (n = 1 -4) was estimated. It was found that quantum confinement upshifted the CBM, which induced electron blocking in p-i-n PSCs. In order to achieve efficient electron transfer, it is necessary to increase the n values of the low dimensional perovskites in order to minimize CBM offset. Using transient absorption (TA) spectra to evaluate the n values of the low-dimensional perovskites, it was revealed that the ligand of 3F-PEA produced low-dimensional perovskite containing majority n = Supplementary Figure  9  | XPS spectra of 3D perovskite (FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05 (a) and 2D perovskite 4F-PEA2PbI4 (b). The peaks are fitted with Gaussian function.</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5592</offset>
      <text>3, while 2F-PEA and 4F-PEA produced low dimensional perovskite containing majority n = 2. Therefore, we selected 3F-PEA as the target ligand to conduct further optimization in p-i-n inverted PSCs. Herein, for n-i-p PSCs in this work, the band alignment requirements for the 2D perovskite layer are the opposite. In n-i-p devices, the 2D perovskite should have a CBM that is as high as possible to block electrons. Thus, we selected the ligand of 4F-PEA which produces the smallest n values when preparing low dimensional perovskites. Supplementary Figure  2  | Photo of a CLP film on a glass substrate. a, The CLP thin film was deposited on the glass substrate by spin coating the CLP precursor solution (30 mg mL -1 in tetrahydrofuran) at 200 rpm for 30 seconds. b, The CLP thin film was separated from the glass substrate by a tweezer. Supplementary Figure  6  | TGA of polymerized EDMA (pEDMA) with x mol% POSS. Comparison of the device performance obtained by 3D, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures. The standard error is represented in boxplots, for which the box extends from the 25 th to the 75 th percentiles, the empty squared dot depicts the average value, the short dash lines depict the minima and maxima. For each structure, sixteen cells were fabricated at the same condition.      Two-dimensional (2D) and quasi-2D modifications of three-dimensional (3D) perovskite active layers have contributed to advances in the performance of perovskite solar cells (PSCs). However, the ionic diffusion between the surface 2D and bulk 3D perovskites leads to the degradation of the 3D/2D p er ov sk ite h et er os tr uc tures and limits the long-term stability of PSCs. Here we incorporate a cross-linked polymer (CLP) on the top of a 3D perovskite layer and then deposit a 2D perovskite layer via a vapour-assisted two-step process to form a 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. P ho to lu mi nescence spectra and thickness-profiled elemental analysis indicate that the CLP stabilizes the heterostructure by inhibiting the diffusion of cations (formamidinium, FA + and 4 -f u or op henyl et hy la mm onium, 4F-PEA + ) between the 2D and 3D perovskites. For devices based on carbon electrodes, we report small-area devices with an efficiency of 21.2% and mini-modules with an efficiency of 19.6%. Devices retain 90% of initial performance after 4,390 hours operation under maximum power point tracking and one-sun illumination at elevated temperatures. Organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have recently undergone a rapid rise in certified power-conversion efficiencies (PCEs) to exceed 25% for sub-1 cm 2 PSCs 1-4 and 20% for perovskite solar modules (PSMs)  [5] [6] [7]  . Many of the best PSCs employ two-dimensional (2D) or quasi-2D modified (three-dimensional) 3D perovskite (3D/2D perovskite) heterostructures, which provide defect passivation  [8] [9] [10]  and favourable band alignment  [11] [12] [13]  and thus can improve open-circuit voltage (V OC ) and fill factor (FF)  [14] [15] [16]  . These 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures are Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y  inspiration from rechargeable batteries or fuel cells, where ion diffusion is inhibited by inserting separation materials (such as POSS-and EDMA-based polymers) as proton exchange membranes  [40] [41] [42] [43]  . POSS consists of a rigid, cubic Si-O-Si cage-type core with eight ethylene groups that can bridge the linear EDMA chains in various directions via olefin polymerization. Approximately 3 mol% POSS dispersed in EDMA provides abundant cross-linking points and leads to the formation of a polymer film with highly cross-linked networks  [44] [45] [46]  . When the self-polymerization was carried out on a glass substrate, a uniform and free-standing transparent CLP film was obtained (Supplementary Fig.  2 ). The self-polymerization reaction was confirmed by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) (Supplementary Fig.  3 ). Moreover, the CLP film was found to be insoluble in polar solvents such as H 2 O, isopropanol (IPA) and dimethylformamide (DMF) (Supplementary Fig.  4  and Supplementary Video 1). Pristine PbBr 2 films are transparent and colourless. However, PbBr 2 films dipped in FAI or 4F-PEAI solutions rapidly turn brown or yellow. X-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements verified the formation of 3D FAPb(I x Br 1-x ) 3 (brown) and 2D 4F-PEA 2 Pb(I x Br 1-x ) 4 (yellow)  [47] [48] [49]  , as shown in Fig.  1c, d . For PbBr 2 films covered by PEG, PS, PMMA and EDMA monomers, similar phenomena were observed. This indicates that these small molecules and linear polymers are not ideal candidates for inhibiting the diffusion of FA + and 4F-PEA + cations. On the contrary, the PbBr 2 / pEDMA and PbBr 2 /CLP films maintained their original colour after dipping in FAI or 4F-PEAI solution. The XRD patterns show the PbBr 2 films were not fully transformed into 3D FAPb(I x Br 1-x ) 3 or 2D 4F-PEA 2 Pb(I x B r 1-x ) 4 , which indicates that the cross-linked pEDMA and CLP layer can effectively inhibit the diffusion of FA + and 4F-PEA + cations. Meanwhile, the formation of a small 2D diffraction peak in the PbBr 2 /pEDMA and PbBr 2 /CLP films indicates a small amount of FA + and 4F-PEA + can still pass through the CLP layer to form 3D or 2D perovskites (Fig.  1c, d  and Supplementary Note 1). Our further studies show that the CLP layer is more effective at inhibiting ion diffusion and has better stability under thermal stress due to the incorporation of POSS (Supplementary Figs.  5  and 6  and Supplementary Note 2). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11189</offset>
      <text> Stabilization effect of CLP on perovskite heterostructures To fabricate the conventional 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure, we deposit a (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 (formamidinium, FA; methylammonium, MA) 3D perovskite layer on a SnO 2 -coated ITO glass substrate and then post-treat the surface with a solution of 4-fluorophenylethylammonium iodide (4F-PEAI) in IPA solvent (Fig.  2a )  8, 17, 50  . XRD patterns in Fig.  2b  show a characteristic diffraction peak at 5.2°, which indicates the formation of 2D 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 ((4F-PEA)  17, 49  . After thermal ageing at 100 °C for 120 min, the 2D 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 diffraction peak in the 3D/2D heterostructure disappears. Additionally, the photoluminescence (PL) spectra show that the emission peaks of 3D (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 and 2D 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 are located at 800 nm and 511 nm respectively for the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure (Fig.  2c ). After thermal ageing, the emission peak of 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 for the 3D/2D heterostructure also completely disappears. These results are indicative of the instability of the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure, which is attributed to ion diffusion between the surface 2D and bulk 3D perovskites  21, 22  . 2 FA n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 , n = 1) To fabricate the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure, we first deposited a 3D perovskite layer. The CLP layer is formed by spin coating a POSS and EDMA mixed solution in chlorobenzene and ethyl acetate mixed solvent on the above 3D perovskite and annealing at 100 °C for 10 min (Supplementary Fig.  7 ). These low-polarity solvents are compatible with 3D perovskites and thus do not induce degradation of the 3D perovskite. The thickness of the CLP layer is estimated to be &lt;3 nm (Supplementary Fig.  8  and Supplementary Note 3). The 2D perovskite layer was deposited by a vapour-assisted two-step process  [51] [52] [53]  . Lead iodide (PbI 2 ) was first evaporated on the CLP layer and commonly prepared by spin coating an organic cation salt solution on top of 3D perovskites and in situ formation of thin low-dimensional perovskites (such as 2D and quasi-2D) on the surface  [17] [18] [19] [20]  . The ion diffusion between the surface 2D and bulk 3D perovskites (for example, cations in the 3D perovskite layer move towards the 2D layer) is known to contribute to the degradation of 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures under bias, illumination and heat  13, 21, 22  . Currently, the long-term operational stability of these highly efficient PSCs is limited to &lt;2,000 hours at room temperature, and ~500 hours at elevated temperatures (≥60 °C) under maximum power point (MPP) tracking and continuous illumination (Supplementary Table  1 ). For ion diffusion within the perovskite absorbing layer, mitigation strategies have been sought after via halide compositional tuning  [23] [24] [25]  , the incorporation of large organic cations  [26] [27] [28] [29]  and the introduction of ionic additives  [30] [31] [32] [33] [34]  . For ion diffusion across interfaces and the stacked layers within PSCs, the construction of interlayers has been proven effective  [35] [36] [37] [38] [39]  . In particular, Bi et al. chose tri-s-triazine-based graphitic carbon nitride nanosheets to form an iodide diffusion barrier layer in p-i-n PSCs  35  . Wang et al. deposited a chlorinated graphene oxide layer between the perovskite and hole transporting layer (HTL) in n-i-p PSCs to prevent the iodide ions in the perovskite layer from diffusing into the HTL  36  . However, inhibiting ion diffusion between the 3D and 2D perovskites and stabilizing the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures remains an ongoing challenge  13, 21, 22  . To construct a stable 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure, we propose to introduce an interlayer between the 3D and 2D perovskite layers. The interlayer needs to effectively inhibit ion diffusion and, meanwhile, not hinder charge transport between the 3D and 2D perovskite layers. For the deposition of the interlayer and 2D perovskite layer, the technique and process need to be operated without degrading or damaging the underlying layers. Comparing small molecules versus regular polymers as the interlayer, we found that a highly cross-linked polymer (CLP) was more effective at inhibiting ion diffusion and stabilizing the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure. We selected a polymer prepared by self-polymerization of ethylene dimethacrylate (EDMA) and polyhedral oligomeric silsesquioxane (POSS) under moderate conditions (≤100 °C) and processed the polymer layer from a solution that does not degrade the 3D perovskite. For simplicity, CLP represents the POSS-EDMA-based polymer below. At the same time, we developed a vapour-assisted two-step deposition process to form the 2D perovskite layer on the 3D perovskite/CLP bilayer, which prevented the destruction of the underlying 3D perovskite during the deposition of the 2D perovskite. We fabricated carbon-electrode-based PSCs using the 3D/ CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure with an efficiency of 21.2% (aperture area of 0.16 cm 2 ), and demonstrate a carbon-electrode-based PSM with a certified efficiency of 18.2% (aperture area of 17.1 cm 2 ). The cell achieved a T 90 (the time taken for device efficiency to reduce to 90% of its initial value) of 4,390 hours under one-sun illumination and MPP tracking at 60 °C, showing superior stability compared with the PSCs based on conventional 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures at elevated temperatures. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16667</offset>
      <text> Selection of CLP The molecular structures of EDMA, POSS, CLP and preparation process of the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure are presented in Fig.  1a . For the design and selection of CLP, it should inhibit the diffusion of FA + and 4F-PEA + cations between the 3D and 2D perovskite layers and stabilize the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure. Some organic materials including small molecules and polymers were screened based on an experiment studying the reactions of lead bromide (PbBr 2 )/organic films with formamidinium iodide (FAI) or 4-fluorophenylethylammonium iodide (4F-PEAI) (Fig.  1b ). These organic materials include a small molecular EDMA monomer; three linear polymers of polyethylene glycol (PEG), polystyrene (PS) and polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA) (Supplementary Fig.  1 ) and two cross-linked polymers of EDMA (pEDMA) and the CLP. We decided to investigate pEDMA and the CLP by taking Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y  then a 4-fluorophenylethylammonium iodide (4F-PEAI)  17, 50  solution (15 mmol in IPA) was spun on the above 3D/CLP/PbI 2 stacked film and annealed at 100 °C for 10 min (Supplementary Note 4 details the selection of 4F-PEAI). XRD spectra in Fig.  2b  show a stronger characteristic diffraction peak at 5.2° for the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure than the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure, which indicates the formation of a thicker 2D perovskite layer  49, 50  . The cross-sectional SEM images show a ~500 nm 3D perovskite layer and a ~10 nm low-dimensional perovskite layer for the 3D/2D heterostructure and a ~500 nm 3D perovskite layer, a several nanometre CLP layer and a thicker ~30 nm 2D perovskite layer for the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure (Fig.  2a ). The XRD spectrum of the aged 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure shows that the characteristic diffraction peak at 5.2° remains relatively unchanged. A similar effect is observed for the PL spectra, where the PL emission peaks for the aged 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure retain their initial positions and intensities (Fig.  2c ). A thick 2D perovskite layer was directly prepared on a 3D perovskite without the CLP layer by the same vapour-assisted two-step process as in the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. Notably, the red-shift PL peak position of the 2D perovskite in the 3D/thick 2D (vapour-deposited) heterostructure compared with the normal solution-processed 3D/2D heterostructure is attributed to the difference in thickness and quantum confinement effect  50, 54  . The intensity of the PL emission peak of 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 largely decreases, and a new peak corresponding to 4F-PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 (n = 2) appears after thermal ageing of the 3D/thick 2D heterostructure  21, 22  . This indicates that the 3D/thick 2D heterostructure shows better stabi lity than normal solution-processed 3D/2D heterostructure; however, its stability remains inferior to that of the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite hetero structure. The PL spectra of the heterostructure using EDMA as the interlayer showed similar behaviour with that of the 3D/thick 2D heterostructure (Fig.  2d ). pEDMA as the interlayer resulted in suppression of the formation of the peak for 4F-PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 ; however, the intensity of the PL emission peak of 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 still decreased. These results indicate that the CLP layer plays the dominant role of stabilizing the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure under thermal stress. To correlate the degradation of the 2D perovskite to ion diffusion, we employed atomic force microscopy-based infrared spectroscopy (AFM-IR) measurements to investigate the surface properties of the perovskite heterostructures. Imaging results were recorded at 1,712 cm -1 , which corresponds to the symmetric C = NH 2 + bending of FA + . As shown in Fig.  2e , initially, the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure showed distinct signals of FA + cations, while there were low signals of FA + cations in the initial 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. This indicated that the 2D perovskite layer in the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure achieved more complete and uniform coverage on the Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y  3D perovskite layer than that in the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure. After the perovskite heterostructures are aged at 100 °C for 120 min, the FA + signals largely increase on the surface of the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure, which indicates the upward diffusion of FA + ions and the phase transformation from the 2D perovskite of 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 into 3D perovskite during thermal stress. On the contrary, the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure shows an almost unchanged FA + signal, which verifies the limited ion diffusion between the 3D and 2D perovskites and the enhanced stability of the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) spectra show that the characteristic peaks of N in FA + for the 3D perovskite layer and 4F-PEA + for the 2D perovskite layer are at 400.8 eV and at 402.0 eV, respectively (Supplementary Fig.  9 ). XPS depth profiling in Fig.  2f  shows that the characteristic peak of F in 4F-PEA + can be detected only on the top surface for ~45 s. For the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure, 4F-PEA + can be detected on the film surface for ~120 s, which is also indicative of the thicker 2D layer in the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. Meanwhile, the downward diffusion of 4F-PEA + ions in the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure is observed after thermal ageing, which is inhibited by the CLP layer in the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure. Furthermore, we conducted ultrafast transient absorption (TA) spectroscopy measurements of 3D/2D and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures as shown in Fig.  2g    55, 56  . Both initial perovskite heterostructures show the characteristic peaks at 773 nm from 3D perovskite, and at 515 nm from 2D perovskite 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 (n = 1)  56  . Additionally, small n = 2 2D perovskite peaks are also observed for the two heterostructures. This indicates that a small amount of FA + diffuses into the 2D perovskite through the CLP layer to form n = 2 perovskites. After ageing at 100 °C for 120 min, the characteristic peak from 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 (n = 1) for the 3D/2D heterostructure almost completely vanished, while the peak for the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure remained unchanged. Thus, we conclude that the CLP layer not only largely inhibits the ion (including both FA + and 4F-PEA + ) diffusion between the stacked perovskite layers but also effectively stabilize the phase states of the 3D and 2D perovskites under thermal stress. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23252</offset>
      <text> Charge carrier dynamics and device performance To investigate the carrier dynamics within the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure and with perovskite/HTL stacks, we conducted time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) measurements. On glass  substrates, the 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure and the 3D/CLP film show longer average carrier lifetimes (τ avg ) (315 ns and 341 ns) than the pristine 3D perovskite (248 ns) (Fig.  3a  and Supplementary Table  4 ). The τ avg of the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure further increases to 423 ns. This is indicative of synergistic passivation from the CLP and 2D perovskite. When a 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis (N,N-di-p-methoxyphenyl-amine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) layer was deposited on top of the samples, the 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures show similar τ avg and τ 1 (Fig.  3b ). This indicates efficient charge extraction from the perovskites to the HTL can still be achieved after incorporating the CLP layer in the perovskite heterostructure. Consistent results were also obtained for the steady-state PL spectra (Supplementary Fig.  10 ). Space charge-limited current spectra  [57] [58] [59]  of the perovskite heterostructures show that the 3D/2D and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures generate current densityvoltage (J-V) curves with similar shapes and comparable current values (Supplementary Figs.  11  and 12 ) for both electron-only and hole-only devices. By fitting the linear regions, the electron and hole mobilities of the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure are similar compared with that of the 3D perovskite or 3D/2D heterostructure. Thus, the CLP layer has not hindered the transport of either the electrons or the holes within the heterostructures. We conducted ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) and ultraviolet-visible absorption spectroscopy (UV-vis) measurements to estimate the energy levels of the perovskite heterostructures (Supplementary Fig.  13 ). Compared with the 3D perovskite (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MA    V OC (V) J SC (mA cm -2 ) FF PCE (%) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25326</offset>
      <text> Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y   PbBr 3 ) 0.05 , the incorporation of the CLP on the 3D perovskite leads to negligible change of the bandgap (1.55 eV), conduction band minimum and valence band maximum (Fig.  3c ). The 2D perovskite 4F-PEA 2 PbI 4 possesses a much larger bandgap of 2.36 eV and forms type-I band alignment with the 3D perovskite  60  . The close valence band maximum position of the 3D and 2D perovskites do not hinder the transport of holes from the 3D perovskite layer to the HTL  10, 11  , while the higher conduction band minimum of the 2D perovskite than the 3D perovskite acts as an electron-blocking layer, effectively preventing the recombination of electrons in the perovskite and holes in the HTL for the 3D/2D and 3D/CLP/2D heterostructures  10, 13  . This favourable band alignment contributes to the enhanced V OC of as-fabricated cells, and the selection of 4F-PEAI is discussed in Supplementary Note 4. To avoid the instability issues associated with metal electrodes  36, 61, 62  , we prepared carbon electrodes based on the screen-printing technique (Supplementary Fig.  14 ) to fabricate PSCs with a device architecture of ITO/SnO 2 /3D/CLP/2D/spiro-OMeTAD/ carbon. We optimized the concentration of the CLP solution and found that the CLP layer prepared with a concentration of 3 mg ml -1 delivered the optimal cell efficiency (Fig.  3d ). We fabricated cells using 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D heterostructures as the light-absorbing layers, and the distribution of efficiencies is presented in Fig.  3e , Supplementary Table  5  and Supplementary Fig.  15 . The cells based on 3D perovskite achieve an average efficiency of 18.83%. The average efficiencies of devices based on 3D/2D and 3D/CLP heterostructures are improved to 19.81% and 19.91%, respectively. The cells based on the 3D/CLP/2D heterostructure deliver an average efficiency of 20.29%. The efficiency improvement mainly results from the enhanced V OC , which is attributed to the synergistic passivation effect of the CLP and 2D perovskite. Figure  3f  shows the representative J-V curves of the cells. For the champion 3D/CLP/2D cell, we achieve a high efficiency of 21.2% with a V OC of 1.13 V, a current density (J SC ) of 24.00 mA cm -2 and a FF of 0.78 for carbon-electrode-based PSCs (Supplementary Table  6 ). The steady-state power output (SPO) efficiency of the cell reaches ~20.87% (Supplementary Fig.  16 ). The external quantum efficiency spectrum of the 3D/CLP/2D PSC shows an integrated short-circuit current density of 23.34 mA cm -2 (Fig.  3g ), which is in agreement with the J-V scanning result. We further fabricated a PSM with six sub-cells in series, as shown in Fig.  3h  and Supplementary Fig.  17 . The champion PSM based on the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure with a carbon electrode and an aperture area of 17.1 cm 2 achieves a PCE of 19.6% with V OC of 6.73 V, short-circuit current of 66.2 mA and FF of 0.751. Furthermore, it exhibits SPO efficiency of 19.1% under a bias voltage of 5.5 V for 100 s (Fig.  3i ). Meanwhile, the PSM achieves a certified efficiency of 19.3% and SPO of 18.2% (Supplementary Fig.  18 ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28511</offset>
      <text> Device stability To study operational stability, we monitored the cell performance under MPP tracking conditions and continuous one-sun illumination at 60 °C (Supplementary Fig.  19 ). The estimated T 90 lifetime of the 3D/2D PSC is 560 h. The PSC based on the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure maintains ~92% of the initial efficiency after 1,000 hours under continuous illumination. According to time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) of these 1,000 h-aged cells, the diffusion of iodide ions from the perovskite layer to the spiro-OMeTAD layer is effectively suppressed in the 3D/CLP/2D PSC (Supplementary Fig.  20 ). Combined with the XPS depth profiling (Supplementary Fig.  21 ), we find that the CLP layer and 2D perovskite synergistically contribute to the suppressed diffusion of iodide. To eliminate the negative effect of spiro-OMeTAD on the cell stability and verify the stability of the perovskite heterostructures, we carry out four repairing cycles of the cell by re-depositing the spiro-OMeTAD layer. The cell maintains ~90% of the initial efficiency after 5,000 h continuous operation (Fig.  4a ). The cell performance recovery indicates that the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure is highly stable against light and heat stress. Furthermore, a more stable poly(3-hexylthiophene)-spiro-OMeTAD (P3HT-spiro-OMeTAD) (3:1 w/w) mixed HTL is adopted to replace the unstable spiro-OMeTAD  12  . The initial efficiencies of as-fabricated PSCs slightly reduce to 18.6% based on 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure and 18.0% based on 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure (Supplementary Fig.  22 ). For the long-term operational stability, the efficiency of the 3D/2D PSC decays a 0 500 1,000  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30234</offset>
      <text> Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y  to ~90% of the initial value after 672 h of continuous operation, while the 3D/CLP/2D PSC maintains 90% of its initial efficiency after continuous operation for 4,390 h at 60 °C (Fig.  4b ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30479</offset>
      <text> Conclusion In summary, we successfully suppress the ion diffusion between surface 2D and bulk 3D perovskites by introducing a highly cross-linked network polymer. A highly stable 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure is constructed and combined with a carbon electrode to fabricate PSCs with an efficiency of 21.2% and mini-PSMs with an efficiency of 19.6% (certified stabilized efficiency of 18.2%). After 4,390 hours of continuous operation under MPP tracking and one-sun illumination, the device retains 90% of its initial performance. Other materials were purchased from Aladdin and all the materials were used as received unless otherwise specified. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31134</offset>
      <text> Methods </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31143</offset>
      <text> Materials </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31154</offset>
      <text> Synthesis of the additive in carbon paste 1.0 g of DMSA (5.5 mmol), 0.99 g of ethylene dimethacrylate (EDMA) (5 mmol), 79.1 mg of octavinyloctasilasesquioxane (POSS) (0.125 mmol) and 38 mg of 2,2-dimethoxy-2-phenylacetophenone (2 wt% of reactants) were well dispersed in the tetrahydrofuran (THF) (20 ml) in a quartz flask. The mixture was irradiated using a 365 nm UV lamp (25 W) for 2 h at room temperature. After the reaction was complete, n-hexane was added to obtain a solid crude product. The obtained product was dissolved in THF and precipitated in excess hexane again. Then, the solid was washed with deionized water and further dried under vacuum. Finally, 1.57 g of white additive powder was obtained. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31868</offset>
      <text> Preparation of the carbon electrode Six g graphite, 2 g carbon black powder, 1.76 g of above additive powder and 0.8 g polyacrylate were mixed in the 2-butoxyethanol/pentyl acetate/ethyl acetate (volume ratio of 5:3:2) mixed solvents and kept ball milling for 12 h to obtain the carbon paste. The pre-prepared carbon paste was coated onto a carbon cloth via a screen-printing process to obtain the carbon film. The carbon paste/carbon cloth-based electrode was peeled off and then soaked in ethanol while sonicating for 10 min to remove the residual solvent. Finally, the carbon electrode was taken out and dried at room temperature. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32503</offset>
      <text> Fabrication of perovskite solar cells and mini-modules ITO glass was patterned by laser etching (Universal Laser Systems, VLS2.30) with a femtosecond laser. Then the glass substrates were cleaned by sequential ultrasonication in a detergent solution, deionized water and anhydrous ethanol. The SnO 2 dispersion was spin coated on the substrates at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and then annealed at 150 °C for 30 min. After that, a 1.4 M (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 perovskite precursor solution containing of 0.5 M MACl was prepared in DMF/DMSO/ GBL (v/v = 2:1:2). The perovskite precursor solution was spin coated on SnO 2 at 1,000 r.p.m. for 10 s and 5,000 r.p.m. for 20 s. The wet film was then immediately put into a sealed sample chamber connected to a home-built vacuum-pumping system and immediately exposed to low pressure (20 Pa) for 10 s. Subsequently, the perovskite film was put on a hotplate and annealed at 120 °C for 40 min to obtain the pristine 3D perovskite film. Next, 15 mM 4F-PEAI/IPA solution was spun on the above 3D perovskite at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s to prepare 3D/2D perovskite heterostructure. For the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite film, 3 mg EDMA, POSS (3 mol% of EDMA) and 2,2′-Azobis(2-methylpropionitrile) initiator (2 wt% of EDMA) were first dissolved in 1 ml of chlorobenzene and ethyl acetate mixed solution (v:v = 1:1) to prepare the CLP solution, and then spun on the above 3D perovskite at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. Then a 30 nm-thick layer of PbI 2 was evaporated at a rate of 0.3 Å s -1 onto the 3D/CLP bilayer film in a vacuum chamber. Subsequently, the same concentration of 4F-PEAI/ IPA solution was spun on the above 3D/CLP/PbI 2 film at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and annealed at 100 °C for 10 min to prepare the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. After cooling down to room temperature, a HTL (73 mg ml -1 spiro-OMeTAD in chlorobenzene with 9.36 mg Li-TFSI salt in acetonitrile and 30 μl 4-tert-butylpyridine) was deposited on the perovskite film by spin coating at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s. For the stability test, the P3HT-spiro-OMeTAD mixed HTL (54.75 mg P3HT and 18.25 mg spiro-OMeTAD with 4.68 mg Li-TFSI in acetonitrile and 15 μl 4-tert-butylpyridine) was deposited with the same spin-coating process. Finally, the pre-prepared carbon electrode was pressed onto the HTL under a pressure of 0.3 MPa at 60 °C for 15 s via a pneumatic hot press to complete the whole devices fabrication. For fabricating carbon-based modules, laser scribing was performed twice, before and after perovskite film deposition, to form P1 and P2 with 1,064 nm wavelength to complete the series interconnection between sub-cells in the module. Meanwhile, mechanical scribing was performed on the carbon electrode to obtain sub-electrode units insulated from each other before assembly. Finally, the electrode was pressed onto the HTL with the same process of small-area devices. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35434</offset>
      <text> Repairing of PSCs by re-depositing the HTL The degraded PSCs were first disassembled to obtain the free-standing carbon electrode and perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD semi-cell. The spiro-OMeTAD on the semi-cell was washed out with chlorobenzene, followed by the deposition of the new spiro-OMeTAD HTL. Finally, the above disassembled carbon electrode was reassembled on the semi-cell to complete the repair of degraded PSCs. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35852</offset>
      <text> Characterization The cross-sectional morphology of perovskite film was investigated by a field-emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM, Hitachi SU8010). The TRPL spectra were measured by a HORIBA Jobin-Yvon Fluorolog-III fluorimeter. The steady-state PL spectra were measured with a 405 nm wavelength excitation source and the PL emission was collected using an optical fibre coupled with an Ocean Optics spectrometer ('Flame') calibrated by the manufacturer. UV-vis absorption of perovskite films was measured by UV-vis spectrometer (lambda 750 S, PerkinElmer). Thermogravimetric analysis was carried out using a TA Instruments TGA 2050 thermogravimetric analyser. The XRD patterns were collected from X-ray diffractometer (D8 Advance). AFM-IR experiments were carried out using a commercial AFM-IR set-up (NanoIR3s, Bruker) that consists of an AFM microscope operating in contact mode and a Quantum Cascade Laser or QCL laser (MIRcat, Daylight Solutions Inc.) that was tunable from 2,350 cm -1 to ≈870 cm -1 (from 4.25 μm to 11.49 μm). The J-V curves were measured using a solar simulator (Oriel 94023 A, 300 W) with a source meter (Keithley 2400) under 100 mW cm -2 illumination (AM 1.5 G) with a scan rate of Supplementary Figure 8 |Supplementary Figure 10 |Supplementary Figure 13 |Supplementary Figure 15 | 8101315 Estimation of the thickness of the CLP layer. a, The dependence of CLP layer thickness on solution concentration. The thicknesses of CLP layers prepared with the concentrations of 10, 15 and 20 mg mL -1 are directly measured using a profilometer. Each average (symbol) and standard deviation (error bar) was calculated from the thickness values measured at 3 positions. The thickness of the CLP layer prepared with a concentration of 3 mg mL -1 was estimated by fitting the results with a polynomial function. b, XPS in-depth profiling of 3D/CLP films. The signal for oxygen (O 1s) was used to track the CLP layer. c, Molecular structure of NPB, which was used as the reference for the Argon gun etching process. (a) The steady-state PL spectra of 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D heterostructures on glass substrates. (b) The steady-state PL spectra of 3D/Spiro-OMeTAD, 3D/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD, 3D/CLP/Spiro-OMeTAD and 3D/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD. Energy level analysis of 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures. (a, b) UPS spectra corresponding to the secondary electron onset region and the valence band maximums (VBMs) of 3D ((FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05), 3D/CLP, and 2D (4F-PEA2PbI4) perovskite films. (c, d) Tauc plot of (FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05 and 4F-PEA2PbI4 showing determination of optical band gap from the intercept. The statistics of photovoltaic performance parameters. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38567</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Figure 16 | 16 Device performance of 3D/CLP/2D PSCs. J-V curves measured at reverse and forward scan (a) and the stabilized output and calculated PCE of the device at a fixed bias (b). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38767</offset>
      <text> FS 2 Supplementary Figure 21 | 221 Steady-state power output efficiency 20.87%Stabilized current density 22.20 mA cm -Analysis of the iodide diffusion in 3D/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD and 3D/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD stacked layer. XPS depth profiling of oxygen (O 1s) of 3D/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD (a) and 3D/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD (c). The detection of oxygen corresponds to the Spiro-OMeTAD layer. XPS depth profiling of iodide (I 3d) of 3D/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD (b) and 3D/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD (d). The detection of iodide corresponds to the perovskite layer, and iodide that diffuses from the perovskite layer to the Spiro-OMeTAD layer. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39375</offset>
      <text> Note: Mesoscopic TiO2: m-TiO2; Mesoscopic ZrO2: m-ZrO2; Mesoscopic Carbon: m-C; Copper phthalocyanine: CuPc; Trifluoromethanesulfonic acid vapor doping of carbon nanotube: TFMS-CNT; single titanium (Ti) adatoms anchored on reduced graphene oxide: Ti-rGO; defective multi-walled carbon nanotube: D-MWCNT; poly[(4,4'bis(2butyloctoxycarbonyl-[2,2'-bithiophene]-5,5-diyl)-alt-(2,2'bithiophene-5,5'-diyl)]: PDCBT; Tantalum doped tungsten oxide: Ta-WOX. nature energy Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01205-y Stabilization of 3D/2D perovskite heterostructures via inhibition of ion diffusion by cross-linked polymers for solar cells with improved performance Long Luo 1,8 , Haipeng Zeng 1,8 , Zaiwei Wang 2,8 , Min Li 1 , Shuai You 1 , Bin Chen 2 , Aidan Maxwell 2 , Qinyou An 3 , Lianmeng Cui 3 , Deying Luo 4 , Juntao Hu 5 , Shangzhi Li 1 , Xueqing Cai 1 , Weixi Li 1 , Lin Li 1 , Rui Guo 1 , Rong Huang 6 , Wenxi Liang 1 , Zheng-Hong Lu 4,5 , Liqiang Mai 3,7 , Yaoguang Rong 1,3 , Edward H. Sargent 2 &amp; Xiong Li 1 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40397</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Preparation of the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure and selection of CLP. a, Schematic of the device structure, the deposition of the 2D perovskite layer and the molecular structures and synthesis process of POSS, EDMA and the CLP. b, Schematic for investigating the effectiveness of different polymers at inhibiting ion diffusion. The polymer layer is deposited by spin coating PEG, PS, PMMA and CLP solutions (10 mg ml -1 ) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 20 s. Then the films are dipped either in a FAI solution (20 mg ml -1 in IPA) or a </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40951</offset>
      <text> /Spiro-OMeTAD 3D/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD Time (ns) Normalized PL intensity (a.u.) Normalized PL intensity (a.u.) τ avg = 23 ns τ avg = 27 ns τ avg = 30 ns τ avg = 25 ns </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41121</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Charge carrier dynamics and device performance. a, TRPL spectra of 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures on glass substrates. b, TRPL spectra of 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures on spiro-OMeTAD. The measured spectra are fitted by bi-exponential decay function. c, Energy diagram of 3D perovskite, 3D/ CLP, 2D perovskite and spiro-OMeTAD. d, Dependence of cell efficiency on the concentration of the CLP solution.Each average (symbol) and standard deviation (error bar) was calculated from 16 cells prepared at the same conditions. e, Distribution of efficiencies obtained by cells using 3D, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/ CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures. The standard error is represented in box plots, for which the box extends from the 25th to the 75th percentiles; the empty squared dot depicts the average value; and the short dashed lines depict the minima and maxima. For each structure, 16 cells were fabricated at the same condition. f, Representative J-V curves of PSCs fabricated using 3D perovskite, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures as the lightabsorbing layer. g, External quantum efficiency spectrum and corresponding integrated current density of the champion cell based on the 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. h, J-V curves of the champion PSM based on the 3D/ CLP/2D perovskite heterostructure. The inset shows a photograph of the PSM. i, The steady-state output and calculated PCE of the PSM at a fixed bias. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42661</offset>
      <text> Table 1 | Summary of reported operating stability of PSCs. 1 The perovskite layer is treated with bulky organics, and the back contact is either metal (Au, Ag and Cu) or carbon. (Ref[1][2][3][4][5][6][7][8][9][10][11][12][13][14][15][16][17][18][19]  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42913</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Table 2 | Peak intensity and integral area obtained from the (001) peak of 3D perovskite and the (020) peak of PbBr2 for different samples. ). Perovskite passivation Samples Electrode Peak intensity/ PCE/% (Aperture area/cm 2 ) (001)3D Peak area/ (001)3D Lifetime (MPP) Peak intensity/ T (°C) (020)PbBr2 Journal/Year Peak area/ (020)PbBr2 CLP/4F-PEAI Carbon 21.17 (0.16) T90 = 4392 hrs 60 °C This work CLP/4F-PEAI PbBr2/CLP + FAI Carbon 2980 18.2 (17.1) 860.9 - -4720 This work 1284.1 MeO-PEAI (ST) Au 25.8 (0.096) T90 = ~ 500 hrs - Nature (2021, Ref. 1) FAHCOO (BT) /OAI (ST) PbBr2/pEDMA + FAI Au 3160 25.6 (0.08) 1957.2 T85 = 450 hrs 35 5750 Nature (2021, Ref. 2) 2027.8 DMePDAI2 (ST) Au 24.7 (0.12) T90 = 1000 hrs ~ 40 Science (2021, Ref. 3) OLAI (ST) PbBr2/PMMA + FAI Ag 12780 24.3 (0.07) 3340.5 T95 = 500 hrs - ~ 40 Science (2022, Ref. 4) - 3F-PEAI/MAI (ST) 3F-PEAI/MAI (ST) PbBr2/PS + FAI Ag Ag 12540 23.3 (0.05) 23.3 (0.05) 3396.1 1000 hrs -no degradation T92 = 500 hrs - RT 65 Nat. Photon. (2022, Ref. 5) (2022, Ref. 5) Nat. Photon. - choline chloride (ST) i-BABr (ST) PbBr2/PEG + FAI Au Au 13140 23.1 (0.16) 20.42 (17.1) T90 = 500 hrs T82 = 500 hrs 2900.3 - RT RT Science (2020, Ref. 6) (2021, Ref. 7) Science - BA2PbI4 (ST) PbBr2/EDMA + FAI Au 16761 24.35 (0.094) T98 = 1620 hrs 4631.1 - - Nat. Energy (2021, Ref. 8) - EAI/MAI (ST) Au 16.6 (22.4) T90 = 1570 hrs 40 Nat. Energy (2020, Ref. 9) OATsO (ST) Pristine PbBr2 + FAI Au 17360 24 (0.13) 3683.9 800 hrs -no degradation - 40 Nature (2022, Ref. 10) - iPAmHCl (BT) Au 23.9 (0.16) 2000 hrs -no degradation RT Nat. Energy (2021, Ref. 11) -PbBr2 Au - 24.04 (0.08) - T95 = ~ 2000 hrs RT 7940 (2021, Ref. 12) Science 1858 - rGO/ Au 20.4 (0.16) T95 = 1000 hrs 60 Science (2019, Ref. 13) - Ag 22.02 (0.13) T92 = 1000 hrs 85 Nat. Nanotechnol. (2020, Ref. 14) PbPyA2/TMS (ST) Cu 24.3 (0.09) T90 = 1000 hrs 55 Science (2022, Ref. 15) lead sulfate (ST) Cu 21.1 (-) T97 = 1200 hrs 65 Science (2019, Ref. 16) - Cu 20.1 (17.9) 550 hrs -no degradation 60 Science (2021, Ref. 17) - Ti1-rGO/FTO 20.6 (0.09) T95 = 1300 hrs 60 Nat. energy (2021, Ref. 18) - Au/MgF2 20.9 (0.113) 1400 hrs -no degradation 60~65 Nat. Energy (2021, Ref. 19) Note: 4-methoxy-phenethylammonium iodide: MeO-PEAI; octylammonium iodide: OAI; Octylammonium tosylate: OATsO; N, N- dimethyl-1,3-propane diammonium diiodide: DMePDAI2; Oleylammonium iodide: OLAI; isobutylamine bromide: i-BABr. 3- iodopropyl trimethoxysilane [Si (OCH3)3(CH2)3I]: I-SAM; Polyethylenimine: PEIE; poly[2,2ʹʹʹʹ-bis[[(2-butyloctyl)oxy]carbonyl] [2,2ʹ:5ʹ,2ʹʹ:5ʹʹ,2ʹʹʹ-quaterthiophene]-5,5ʹʹʹ-diyl]): PDCBT; BCF-doped poly(triarylamine): PTAA-BCF; 4-fluoro- 29 phenethylammonium iodide: 4F-PEAI; 3-fluoro-phenethylammonium: 3F-PEAI; pyrene-based ethylammonium iodide: PREAI; isopropylammonium chloride: iPAmHCl; n-hexyl trimethyl ammonium bromide: HTABr; ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid dipotassium salt: EDTAK; ethylammonium iodide: EAI; aminovaleric acid iodide: AVAI; 5-ammoniumvaleric acid iodide: 5-AVAI; 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium tetrafluoroborate: BMIMBF4; Pyridine-2-carboxylic lead: PbPyA2; Hexamethyldisilathiane: TMS; Maximum power point tracking: MPPT; Surface treatment: ST; Bulk treatment: BT; Room temperature: RT. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46167</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Table 3 | Peak intensity and integral area obtained from the (100) peak of 2D perovskite and (020) peak of PbBr2 for different samples. Samples Peak intensity/ (100)2D Peak area/ (100)2D Peak intensity/ (020)PbBr2 Peak area/ (020)PbBr2 PbBr2/CLP + 4F-PEAI 12130 1701.2 5190 1246.5 PbBr2/pEDMA + 4F-PEAI 13132 2995.94 5334 1414.3 PbBr2/PMMA + 4F-PEAI 69936 10773.73 - - PbBr2/PS + 4F-PEAI 45850 8193.18 - - PbBr2/PEG + 4F-PEAI 37900 6635.57 - - PbBr2/EDMA + 4F-PEAI 111407 22590.81 - - Pristine PbBr2 + 4F-PEAI 156555 26662.17 - - PbBr2 - - 10600 2635.4 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46735</offset>
      <text> 30 Supplementary Table 4 | The fitted parameters from TRPL of various perovskite samples. Samples A1 τ1 A2 τ2 τavg (ns) Pristine 3D 0.569 91 0.431 455 248 3D/2D 0.527 84 0.473 574 315 3D/CLP 0.562 134 0.438 607 341 3D/CLP/2D 0.491 89 0.509 825 424 Pristine 3D/ Spiro-OMeTAD 0.645 5.6 0.355 55 23 3D/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD 0.639 7.7 0.361 68 30 3D/CLP/ Spiro-OMeTAD 0.643 6.1 0.357 59 25 3D/CLP/2D /Spiro-OMeTAD 0.641 6.7 0.359 62 27 Note: The measured PL decay kinetics are fitted by bi-exponential decay function as follow 𝐹(𝑡) = 𝐴 1 exp(-𝑡 𝜏 1 ⁄ ) + 𝐴 2 exp(-𝑡 𝜏 2 ) ⁄ The average lifetime: τ 𝑎𝑣𝑔 = (𝐴 1  *  𝜏 1 + 𝐴 2  *  τ 2 ) (𝐴 1 + 𝐴 2 ) ⁄ </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47433</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Table 5 | The photovoltaic parameters of PSCs fabricated with 3D, 3D/2D, 3D/CLP, and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures. Active layer VOC (V) JSC (mA cm -2 ) FF PCE (%) 3D 1.05 ± 0.02 23.82 ± 0.35 0.75 ± 0.02 18.83 ± 0.69 3D/2D 1.08 ± 0.03 23.93 ± 0.19 0.76 ± 0.02 19.81 ± 0.54 3D/CLP 1.09 ± 0.02 23.83 ± 0.23 0.76 ± 0.02 19.91 ± 0.63 3D/CLP/2D 1.10 ± 0.02 23.78 ± 0.30 0.77 ± 0.01 20.29 ± 0.63 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47862</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Table 6 | Summary of reported performance for state-of-the-art PSCs using carbon electrodes. (Ref 18,20-35 ) Device structure Area/ cm 2 VOC (V) JSC (mA cm -2 ) FF PCE (%) Journal/ Year ITO/SnO2/Perovskite/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD/Carbon 0.16 1.13 24 0.78 21.2 This work ITO/SnO2/Perovskite/CLP/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD/Carbon 17.1 6.73 3.87 0.75 19.6 This work FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 0.07 0.858 22.8 0.66 12.8 Science (2014, Ref. 20) FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 0.8 0.94 23.8 0.66 14.89 Joule (2020, Ref. 21) FTO/m-TiO2/Perovskite/CuPc/Carbon 0.09 1.05 20.8 0.74 16.1 Nano Energy (2016, Ref. 22) Adv. Energy FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 0.108 1.023 22.25 0.767 17.47 Mater. (2021, Ref. 23) ITO/SnO2/perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/TFMS-CNT 0.1 1.01 24.21 0.72 17.5 Nano Lett. (2019, Ref. 24) Adv. Energy FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 0.1018 0.956 24.26 0.762 17.68 Mater. (2022. Ref. 25) ITO/PTAA/Perovskite/C60/SnO2/Carbon 0.06 1.04 22.6 0.769 18.1 Nat. Energy (2020, Ref. 26) Adv. Energy FTO/c-TiO2/m-TiO2/Perovskite/2D/Carbon 0.1 1.03 24.3 0.739 18.5 Mater. (2022, Ref. 27) Angew. Chem. Int. ITO/APTES/C60/Perovskite/Carbon 0.08 1.12 22.72 0.73 18.64 Ed. (2021, Ref. 28) Energy Environ. FTO/SnO2/Perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Graphene/FTO 0.09 1.05 22.78 0.78 18.65 Sci. (2019, Ref. 29) FTO/c-TiO2/m-TiO2/Perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Carbon 0.1 1.08 23.33 0.762 19.2 Adv. Funct. Mater. (2018, Ref. 30) FTO/c-TiO2/m-TiO2/Perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Ti-rGO/FTO 0.09 1.059 26.0 0.785 21.6 Nat. Energy (2021, Ref. 18) FTO/SnO2/perovskite/D-MWCNT:Spiro-OMeTAD/Graphene/FTO 0.049 1.08 25.9 0.78 22.07 Adv. Funct. Mater. (2022, Ref. 31) FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 70 9.63 2.95 0.629 10.75 Energy Environ. Sci. (2016, Ref. 32) FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 50 7.05 2.247 0.704 11.2 Nat. Commun. (2017, Ref. 33) FTO/c-TiO2/(m-TiO2/m-ZrO2/m-C)/Perovskite 60.87 8.50 2.50 0.61 12.87 Nano Energy (2020, Ref. 34) ITO/SnO2/Perovskite/PDCBT/Ta-WOX/Carbon 4 4.2 5.3 0.69 15.3 Adv. Energy Mater. (2021, Ref. 35) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49924</offset>
      <text> The operational stability of PSCs using spiro-OMeTAD as the HTL under continuous illumination in N 2 at 60 °C. The cells are repaired by re-depositing the spiro-OMeTAD after every 1,000 hours of continuous illumination. b, The operational stability of PSCs using a mixed P3HT-spiro-OMeTAD HTL under continuous illumination in N 2 at 60 °C. The initial PCEs of the cells based on 3D/2D and 3D/CLP/2D perovskite heterostructures are 18.1% and 18.6%, respectively. The bias at the MPP was calculated and applied automatically. 20 16 Repaired PCE (%) 8 12 4 (3D/CLP/2D)/spiro-OMeTAD MPP tracking under one-sun illumination at 60 °C 0 1,500 2,000 2,500 3,000 3,500 4,000 4,500 5,000 Time (h) b 1.0 Normalized PCE 0.4 0.6 0.8 T 90 0.2 (3D/2D)/P3HT-spiro-OMeTAD (3D/CLP/2D)/P3HT-spiro-OMeTAD MPP tracking under one-sun illumination at 60 °C 0 0 1,000 2,000 3,000 4,000 5,000 Time (h) Fig. 4 | Long-term stability test. a,</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
