<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001330274GDHGEA</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 107</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Stabilizing Formamidinium Lead Iodide Perovskite by Sulfonyl-Functionalized Phenethylammonium Salt via Crystallization Control and Surface Passivation</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>162</offset>
      <text>Metal halide perovskites have exhibited great potential in developing next-generation solar cells as well as light-emitting diodes, mainly due to their unique optoelectronic properties and easy solution process.  [1] [2] [3] [4]  Typical perovskite materials use 3D ABX 3 structures, where A is a small and monovalent cation occupying the cuboctahedral site of the BX 6 octahedra framework.  [5]  Until now, only three kinds of cations, i.e., Cs þ , CH 3 NH 3 þ (MA), and CH(NH 2 ) 2 þ (FA), are found to be adequate to form 3D perovskite with lead halides according to the restriction of Goldschmidt tolerance factor (t).  [6] [7] [8]  Large-size organic ammonium cations, such as butylammonium and phenethylammonium (PEA), will lead to layered 2D structures with typical formula of A 2 BX 4 , which typically show enlarged bandgap and decreased electronic conductivity, rendering them unsuitable for application as an efficient light absorber for solar cells.  [9] [10] [11]  However, such bulky cations have been utilized to improve the performance and stability of small cation-based 3D perovskites via defect passivation and dimensionality modulation at the crystal or film surface.  [12, 13]  Among reported bulky cations, PEA is the most common candidate, probably due to its straightforward chemical structure and convenient commercial availability.  [14]  The PEA cations have been demonstrated to form a simple assembly or a thin 2D/3D heterostructure at the 3D perovskite surface.  [15]  The ammonium cation and the aromatic phenyl group in PEA are found to be capable of passivating charged and neutral electronic traps, respectively, at the surface of 3D perovskite, thus decreasing nonradiative recombination and improving open-circuit voltage (V OC ) performance.  [16, 17]  In contrast, the bulky cation-based surface functionalization also improves the phase stability of metastable CsPbI 3 and formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) perovskites at room temperature, probably due to a modification of surface energy or crystal strain.  [18]  Moreover, the hydrophobic phenyl group will further improve the environmental stability through blocking moisture away from the vulnerable 3D perovskite. Generally, the PEA bulky cation modifications are introduced by post spin-coating deposition on perovskite films or as an additive in perovskite precursor solutions. The post deposition can only modify the top surface of the perovskite films, leaving most of the buried part untreated.  [19, 20]  In contrast, the additive strategy is beneficial for achieving homogeneous modification.</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2761</offset>
      <text>The ORCID identification number(s) for the author(s) of this article can be found under  https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202000069 . DOI: 10.1002/solr.202000069 Bulky organic ammonium cations have been widely used to stabilize lead halide perovskites via surface passivation or dimensionality modulation. Herein, a sulfonyl fluoride-functionalized phenethylammonium salt (SF-PEA) is reported as a bifunctional additive to stabilize the formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) perovskite. The sulfonyl group is found to interact with PbI 2 in the precursor and slow down the crystallization of FAPbI 3 during thermal annealing, leading to improved crystalline quality and decreased structural defects. After annealing, the spontaneous assembly of SF-PEA on the crystal surface of FAPbI 3 not only passivates the surface defects, but also protects the perovskite from phase transition that is caused by strain or moisture invasion. The resulting FAPbI 3 films are extremely stable, which can maintain their black phase for more than 3 months in air with 40-50% relative humidity, much better than pristine and unsubstituted phenethylammonium (PEA)-based samples. Because of the greatly improved phase stability and crystallization quality, a champion power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 21.25% (certified PCE of 20.70%) is achieved in planar n-i-p structured solar cells, which is the highest one among "methylammoniumfree" FAPbI 3 perovskite photovoltaics. Previous literatures mainly focused on the surface effect caused by the bulky cations, whereas their impacts on the crystallization dynamics are largely omitted, especially for the additive route in which the whole crystallization process is associated with the additives.  [21]  As well known, the intermolecular interactions in the perovskite precursor solution play a crucial role on the crystallization dynamics.  [22, 23]  Considering that the active sites on PEA cation are limited, we proposed to introduce additional functional groups onto its phenyl unit for enhancing the intermolecular interactions as well as the perovskite crystallization. Herein, we report a successful example of sulfonyl fluoride-functionalized phenethylammonium salt (SF-PEA) that features with a sulfonyl fluoride group on the para-position of the PEA (chemical structures shown in Figure  1a ) for fabricating and stabilizing high-quality FAPbI 3 perovskite thin films. The sulfonyl group is found to interact with PbI 2 in precursor and slow down the crystallization of FAPbI 3 during thermal annealing, leading to an improved crystalline quality and decreased structural defects. Combining with the surface passivation and protection effects, we achieved extremely stable FAPbI 3 films that can maintain their back phase for more than 3 months in air with relative humidity (RH) of 40 AE 5% without encapsulation, much better than pristine and PEA-based samples. In planar n-i-p structured solar cells, we achieved a champion power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 21.25% (certified PCE of 20.70%), which is the highest one among "MA-free" FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells (PSCs). The unencapsulated device retains 91% of its initial PCE after 1000 h with a humidity of 50-60%. Compared with Cs þ -and MA-based lead halide perovskites, the FAPbI 3 shows more optimal bandgap and broader absorption spectra, thus possessing a higher efficiency maxima under standard solar spectrum.  [24] [25] [26]  However, it suffers from a poor ambient stability because its nonperovskite δ-phase is thermodynamically more favorable than the black α-phase at room temperature.  [27]  Mixed cations and anions strategy that incorporates MA, Cs þ , and Br À is often used to stabilize the black α-phase of FAPbI 3 , but these additives can widen its bandgap and decrease the thermal stability. Herein, we use bulky cation strategies to fabricate and stabilize FAPbI 3 perovskite for retaining its inherent low bandgap merits. The FAPbI 3 perovskite films are first prepared on glass substrate using a solvent-engineered one-step spin-coating procedure, with detailed fabricating parameters described in the Experimental Section. The bulky cation halide salts of SF-PEA or PEA are added into the precursor solution with a molar ratio of 1.0% to that of FAPbI 3 . The FAPbI 3 film fabricated without using any additive is denoted as "pristine," and the ones with addition of PEA or SF-PEA are denoted as "w/PEA" and "w/SF-PEA," respectively. After spin coating, the three types of precursor films are all transparent without significant difference in color (Figure  1b ). However, their crystallization velocities are quite different when they were annealed at 150 C on a hotplate. The pristine and w/PEA samples were found to turn into a black phase quickly after heating for about 40 s, with complete color conversion within 60 s, indicating a fast crystallization of the α-phase FAPbI 3 . In contrast, the color conversion of w/SF-PEA sample is much slower. The transparent appearance was retained during the first 60 s, and another 60 s is required to finish the color conversion from yellow to black, as shown in Figure  1b . These results suggest that the incorporation of SF-PEA as an additive into the precursor of FAPbI 3 can distinctly decrease the crystallization velocity. Considering the structural difference between PEA and SF-PEA, we attribute the retarded crystallization in w/SF-PEA sample in the presence of additional sulfonyl fluoride group. The oxygen atoms in the sulfonyl group contains totally four groups of lone pair electrons (Figure  1a ), representing a strong Lewis base that may form adduct with the Lewis acid of PbI 2 in the precursor solution and modulate the crystallization dynamics. To verify such intermolecular interactions, we prepared a PbI 2 /SF-PEA complexes (for method, see Supporting Information) and used Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy to compare the complexes with pure SF-PEA. The complete FTIR spectra are shown in Figure  S1 , Supporting Information, and Figure  1c  shows an enlarged segment that are closely related to the vibration of the sulfonyl group. The strong peaks appeared at 1209 and 1400 cm À1 for the pure SF-PEA corresponds to the stretching vibrations of S═O bonds.  [28]  Upon complexing with PbI 2 , these two characteristic peaks were shifted to 1216 and 1404 cm À1 , respectively. This indicates that the SF-PEA likely formed an adduct with PbI 2 via the interaction between Pb 2þ and the S═O bonds, which increases the activation energy of nucleation, and then retards the perovskite crystal growth.  [29, 30]  According to classic crystallization theory, a low crystallization velocity will be beneficial to the growth of large-size crystals with high crystalline quality.  [30, 31]  As the incorporation of bulky cation of SF-PEA significantly decreases the annealing-induced crystallization velocity of FAPbI 3 , we therefore investigate the surface morphology of the three types of perovskite thin films by comparing their top-view scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images. As shown in Figure  2a , all of the three samples show typical polycrystalline character of lead halide perovskite, with grain size in the range of tens to hundreds of nanometers. The average grain size for the pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA samples are calculated to be 315.3, 443.6, and 704.1 nm, respectively, suggesting that the introduction of bulky cations is indeed capable of increasing the grain size. The increase in average grain size means reduced grain boundaries, which is beneficial to the optoelectronic qualities of the polycrystalline semiconductor materials. We note that the perovskite film with SF-PEA exhibited smooth surface morphology, as demonstrated by atomic force microscopy (AFM) images (Figure  S2 , Supporting Information), although it consists of larger-sized grains. The smooth and uniform thin-film morphology is advantageous to the subsequent deposition of a thinner hole-transporting layer with full coverage for achieving low transporting resistance as well as low current leakage. To further evaluate the crystalline quality, X-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements were carried out on the three types of perovskite samples, with results shown in Figure  2b . It can be found that their XRD patterns are very similar, all showing the characteristic diffraction peaks of 3D perovskite without any signal of 2D species.  [32]  The pristine sample showed a weak peak at 11.8 that corresponds to the nonperovskite δ-phase, which was almost disappeared in the w/PEA and w/SF-PEA samples, suggesting that such small amount of bulky cations (1.0 mol%) can effectively suppress the formation of the unfavorable δ-phase FAPbI 3 . The intensity of diffraction peaks corresponding to the α-phase FAPbI 3 (typical 2θ of 14.0 , 28.0 , 31.5 , 40.2 , and 42.7 ) was gradually enhanced in the order of pristine &lt; w/PEA &lt; w/SF-PEA. The full-width-half-maximum (FWHM) values of the peak at 2θ of 14.0 for the three samples were calculated to be 0.64 , 0.60 , and 0.49 . The decrease in the FWHM value clearly indicates improved crystallinity, which is consistent with SEM observations. Figure  2c  shows the ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectra of the samples. The three samples showed typical absorption of α-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite with an optical bandgap (E g ) of around 1.49 eV. Their absorption onset as well as normalized photoluminescence (PL) spectra are almost overlapped (Figure  S3 , Supporting Information), indicating that the E g was maintained upon the addition of bulky cations. Previous work showed that the incorporation of over 5 mol% bulky cations can lead to the formation of 2D/3D heterostructures and an increase in E g .  [33]  Here, the unchanged E g can attribute to the trace amounts of bulky cations, only 1.0 mol%, which is more likely to play the role of surface functionalization, rather than to form 2D/3D heterostructures. This is particularly important as the inherent E g feature of FAPbI 3 can be utilized, unlike traditional mixed cations strategy of incorporating MA, Cs þ , and Br À , which significantly enlarge the E g to values around 1.6 eV. It can be found that the bulky cations involved samples showed steeper and higher absorbance than the pristine near their band edge, suggesting a decrease in sub-bandgap states for the w/PEA and w/SF-PEA perovskites. The enhanced absorption is probably due to an improved perovskite phase purity, with additional contribution from light scattering due to the improved grain size. We further use time-resolved PL (TRPL) spectroscopy to estimate the optoelectronic quality of the perovskite films.  [34]  As shown in Figure  2d  and Table  S1 , Supporting Information, the TRPL profiles of the three samples can be fitted to a twocomponent exponential decay model. Compared with the pristine sample, the average lifetime was significantly prolonged from 250.9 to 657.9 ns and 1208.0 ns for the PEA-and SF-PEAassisted FAPbI 3 films, respectively. Generally, an extension of TRPL lifetime suggests the removal of nonradiative decay pathways to some extents, and thus an improvement of the optoelectronic quality of perovskite semiconductors. Apparently, the high optoelectronic quality of SF-PEA-based perovskite films could be attributed to the enhanced phase purity and crystallinity, which decreased the charge traps in the perovskite films as will be discussed later. Under ambient conditions, the α-phase of FAPbI 3 is subject to undergo undesirable transition to form photoinactive δ-phase, which is a critical challenge for the application of FAPbI 3 in optoelectronic devices. During our preliminary stability evaluations, we found that the incorporation of bulky organic cations can effectively improve the ambient stability of the FAPbI 3 perovskite. As shown in Figure  3a , the black pristine FAPbI 3 film decomposes quickly, and it was completely bleached within 1 week when maintained in ambient with RH of 40 AE 5% and temperature at 20 AE 5 C. The formed colorless product was proven to be δ-phase FAPbI 3 (Figure  S5 , Supporting Information). Under the same conditions, such phase transition from black to colorless was greatly retarded in the w/PEA and w/SF-PEA samples. Notably, the new bulky cation of SF-PEAbased FAPbI 3 films can maintain its black appearance for at least 2 months. The UV-vis absorption spectra were used to quantitatively record the variation of α-phase FAPbI 3 during the ambient storage (Figure  S4 , Supporting Information). Figure  3b  shows the evolution of absorbance at 600 nm (normalized to the initial value of the w/SF-PEA sample) for the three samples. The w/SF-PEA sample shows constant absorbance near their band edge, suggesting negligible phase transition during such long ambient storage duration. As far as we know, this is the best shelf lifetime for MA-, Cs-, or Br-free FAPbI 3 perovskites to date. Previous studies have proven that the PEA-based bulky cations can spontaneously assemble to the grain surface of 3D perovskites during the crystallization process.  [12]  As shown in Figure  3c , such surface functionalization can not only passivate the surface defects, but also decrease the surface energy and improve hydrophobicity (Figure  S6 , Supporting Information), thus protecting the perovskite from phase transition caused by strain or moisture invasion. Although such bulky organic cations are capable of forming low-dimensional perovskite, we have not observed any related information in the XRD measurement, which might be attributed to the very small amount (only 1% molar ratio) of bulky cation additives in the perovskite precursor solution. Therefore, we mainly attribute the enhanced phase stability of black FAPbI 3 to the passivation and surface energy engineering. Compared with the perovskite films with PEA, the SF-PEA seems to be more efficient in enhancing the phase stability of FAPbI 3 . Therefore, there might be additional contributions arising from the SF-PEA bulky cations, most probably related to the sulfonyl group decorated on the phenyl of SF-PEA. Previous studies have revealed that the ammonium and aromatic groups in PEA can heal negative charged and neutral iodine related defects, respectively.  [17]  The Lewis basefeatured sulfonyl group provides extra passivation effect to positive-charged defects, such as undercoordinated Pb 2þ at the surface of 3D FAPbI 3 perovskites. This can be partially reflected by the extended PL lifetime for the SF-PEA base FAPbI 3 perovskite film. The more comprehensive passivation achieved by the SF-PEA salt will not only eliminate more charge defects, but also lead to a larger extent of decrease in surface energy, thus greatly stabilizes the pervoskite phase of FAPbI 3 . The high crystalline quality of the SF-PEA involved FAPbI 3 films may further improve the phase stability as internal structure defects that can induce phase transition are decreased. High-quality film means a low trap density. We evaluate the trap density of different perovskite films using the space charge limited current (SCLC) measurement on electron-only devices, which have the architecture of fluorine-doped tin dioxide (FTO)/TiO 2 /perovskite/PCBM/Ag. As shown in Figure  3d , the devices show ohmic response (linear relation) at low bias and a marked increase in the current injection at the intermediate region as the traps are continuously fielded with increasing bias until reaching the trap-filling limit voltage (V TFL ). The trap density is calculated based on the following equation  [35]   n trap ¼ 2ε 0 ε r V TFL eL 2 (1) where ε r is the relative dielectric constant of perovskite, ε 0 is the vacuum permittivity, e is the electron charge, and L is the thickness of perovskite film. The calculated trap density of the pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 films are 5.36 Â 10 15 , 3.65 Â 10 15 , and 3.08 Â 10 15 cm À3 , respectively. These results directly prove that the bulky cation-based additives can decrease the trap density, thus improving the electronic quality as well as structural stability of the FAPbI 3 perovskite films. To further study the photovoltaic performance of different FAPbI 3 samples, PSCs with a planar n-i-p configuration of FTO glass/SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/Au were fabricated (Figure  4a ). Detailed fabrication process was described in the Experimental Section. The typical current density-voltage ( J-V ) characteristics for the champion PSCs based on pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 perovskite films are shown in Figure  4b , and the corresponding device parameters are shown in Table  1 . The pristine FAPbI 3 -based devices show a best PEC of 15.32%, with short-circuit current density ( J SC ) of 22.49 mA cm À2 , opencircuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.051 V, and fill factor (FF) of 64.77%. These results are in line with previous literatures.  [12]  The incorporation of bulky cation additives of PEA and SF-PEA remarkably improves all of the photovoltaic parameters, achieving champion PCE of 18.39% and 21.25%, respectively. Moreover, the J-V scanning hysteresis is also decreased for the additive-based devices (Figure  S7 , Supporting Information). The improved performance of the SF/PEA sample-based devices was mainly attributed to the higher V OC and FF values. As the electron-and hole-transporting materials are same, the enhanced V OC should be attributed to decreased carrier recombination in perovskites with high crystallization quality. The w/PEA-and w/SF-PEAbased devices showed gradually decreased series resistance (R s ) and enhanced shunt resistance (R sh , Table  1 ), thus resulting in gradually improved FF performance. The bulky cation-based FAPbI 3 perovskite additives show larger crystal size, less grain boundary, and lower charge trap density, which facilitate charge transporting and suppress carrier recombination. Moreover, the uniform thin-film morphology with smooth surface helps to deposit thin and full-coverage hole-transporting layer, further benefiting the FF performance. The external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the devices are shown in Figure  4c . It can be found that the threshold of the spectral response reaches 850 nm, which matched well with the absorption character of FAPbI 3 perovskite. The integrated current density values from EQE spectra are also in good agreement with the J sc obtained from J-V measurement. The improved photocurrent of the w/SF-PEA sample-based device was primarily due to the elevated light-harvesting efficiency and enhanced charge transportation, which was closely related to the larger crystal size and higher phase purity of the perovskite film. Figure  4d  shows the stable photocurrent density measured near the maximum power point, and the calculated stable power output are in good agreement with the J-V scanning curves. The histograms of efficiency statistics for three batches of devices fabricated with optimized conditions are shown in Figure  4e . The performance of these devices were highly reproducible, showing average PCE of 13.11%, 16.8%, and 20.32% for devices based on pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 samples, respectively. One of the optimized devices based on w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 was measured in an independent laboratory, which showed a certified stabilized PCE of 20.70% (Figure  S8 , Supporting Information). As far as we know, this is the highest PCEs for "methylammonium-free" FAPbI 3 PSCs to date. Finally, we estimated the stability of PSCs devices based on pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 perovskite films. The unencapsulated devices were stored under ambient exposure with a RH of 50-60% at room temperature, and their J-V curves were measured at different intervals. As shown in Figure  4f , the PCEs of devices based on pristine and w/PEA FAPbI 3 samples sharply decreased to below 50% at 70 and 400 h. In contrast, the PCEs of device based on w/SF-PEA sample exhibited remarkable stability, retaining 91% of their original PCEs after 1000 h. Such a good environmental stability should be attributed to the enhanced stability of the active perovskite layer. The more than 21% efficiency as well as excellent environmental stability achieved by our strategy made great progress for future commercialization of efficient and stable PSCs. In summary, we have demonstrated an efficient strategy for fabricating FAPbI 3 perovskite films with high optoelectronic quality and phase stability via incorporating functionalized bulky organic cations as crystallization modulator. The sulfonyl group in SF-PEA interacts with the PbI 2 in precursor to decrease the crystallization velocity and improves the crystalline quality. Moreover, the assembly of SF-PEA on the surface of FAPbI 3 significantly improves its stability in the black perovskite phase via surface passivation and moisture blocking. With the multifunctional additive of SF-PEA, the FAPbI 3 perovskite films show extremely high air stability and optoelectronic properties. Consequently, we achieved a champion PCE of 21.25% (certified stabilized PCE of 20.70%), which is to date the best performance among "methylammonium-free" FAPbI 3 -based PSCs. When stored in air with a humidity of 50-60%, the unencapsulated device can retain 91% of its initial PCE after 1000 h. This work suggests that chemical tailoring of bulky organic cations is a promising way to further improve the stability and performance of hybrid perovskite materials. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24294</offset>
      <text> Experimental Section Materials and Reagents: The SnO 2 colloid precursor was obtained from Alfa Aesar (tin(IV) oxide, 15% in H 2 O colloidal dispersion), and the nanoparticles were diluted by deionized water to 2.67% before use. The SF-PEA was purchased from Adamas-beta and used without further purification. Other materials used for PSC fabrication were purchased from TCI and p-OLED. The super dehydrated solvent of N-methyl pyrrolidone (NMP), dimethylformamide (DMF), and tetrahydrofuran (THF) were all purchased from Sigma Aldrich. The PbI 2 /SF-PEA complexes were obtained by pouring the SF-PEA and PbI 2 -mixed DMF solution to a large amount of chlorobenzene. The precipitates was collected by filtration and dried in a vacuum drying chamber. FAPbI 3 Perovskite Samples Fabrication: The FTO glass substrates were sequentially washed with deionized water, ethanol, and acetone for 15 min with sonication. The substrates were further cleaned with UV ozone treatment for 15 min before used. The perovskite precursor solution contained FAPbI 3 (1.3 M) without/with 1.0 mol% PEA or SF-PEA were dissolved in anhydrous DMF:NMP solution (4:1 volume). The perovskite solution was spin coated in a two-step program at 1000 and 4000 rpm for 10 and 30 s, respectively. During the second step, 100 μL of diethyl ether was poured on the spinning substrate 15 s prior to the end of the program. The substrates were then annealed at 150 C for 15 min in a nitrogen-filled glove box. PSCs Fabrication: The substrates were sequentially washed with deionized water, ethanol, and acetone for 30 min with sonication. The substrates were further cleaned with UV ozone treatment for 15 min before used. For planar structured PSC, the diluted SnO 2 nanoparticles solution (2.67%) was spin coated on FTO substrates in ambient air and then annealed at 160 C for 30 min. The preparation of perovskite films is the same as fabrication of FAPbI 3 perovskite samples. Subsequently, the substrates were cooled down to room temperature. The spiro-OMeTAD solution was prepared by dissolving 72.8 mg of spiro-OMeTAD in 1 mL of chlorobenzene which was doped by 30.5 μL of 4-tertbutylpyridine and 20 μL of bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide lithium salt (520 mg mL À1 in acetonitrile) solution. Then, the spiro-OMeTAD solution was deposited onto the perovskite layers by spin coating at 3000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, 50 nm-thick film of Au was thermally evaporated under high vacuum on top of the hole-transporting layer. Materials and Devices Characterization: The UV-vis absorption spectra of perovskite films were measured using a model CARY 100 spectrophotometer. Fluorescence spectra were measured with F90pro fluorescence spectrometer. Emission lifetimes were determined with the single-photon counting technique by means of Edinburgh FLS980 spectrometer. The FTIR spectra were recorded using the Nicolet 6700 spectrophotometer. XRD measurement was conducted on a Rigaku D/max 2550 VB/PC apparatus. AFM images were obtained using Veeco IIIa MultiMode AFM scanning probe microscope. SEM images were obtained using a TESCAN VEGA 3 SBH scanning electron microscope. Photocurrent density-voltage ( J-V ) curves of devices were measured by Keithley 2400 Source Meter Instruments under standard AM 1.5 simulated solar irradiation (WXS-155S-10). The active area of the device was defined by the cross area of top and bottom electrodes and a homemade black metal mask of 0.09 cm À2 . Monochromatic EQE spectra were measured by Newport-74125 system (Newport Instruments). Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Bulky cations modulating FAPbI 3 crystallization. a) Chemical structures of PEA and SF-PEA. b) The comparison of crystallization velocity for pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 perovskite films. c) FTIR spectroscopy spectra of pure SF-PEA and PbI 2 /SF-PEA complexes. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28129</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Bulky additives enhanced crystalline quality and photophysical properties. a) Top-view SEM images, b) XRD patterns, c) absorption spectra, and d) TRPL spectra of pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 perovskite samples deposited on glass substrates. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28403</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Improved moisture stability and electronic quality of SF-PEA-based FAPbI 3 perovskite films. a) Photos and b) evolution of absorption at 600 nm of the pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 samples exposed to RH of 40 AE 5% at 20 AE 5 C for different time. c) Schematic model of the perovskite film incorporating SF-PEA at grain boundaries. d) Dark I-V measurement data of the electron-only devices with the architecture FTO/TiO 2 /perovskite/ [6,6]-phenyl-C 61 -butyric acid methyl ester (PCBM)/Ag for different perovskite films. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28957</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Photovoltaic performances. a) Cross-sectional SEM image of the planar n-i-p structured PSCs device. b) Current density-voltage curves and c) EQE spectra of best performance PSCs based on the pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 samples. d) Stabilized photocurrent of the best device under a voltage bias near the maxima power point. e) Histogram of efficiencies from 25 individual devices. f) Evolution of PCEs for PSCs with/without additives measured in ambient air with a humidity of 50-60% at room temperature. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29496</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 Device parameters of planar n-i-p structured PSCs based on pristine, w/PEA, and w/SF-PEA FAPbI 3 perovskite film samples. PSCs V OC J SC FF PCE R s R sh [V] [mA cm À2 ] [%] [%] [Ω cm 2 ] [Ω cm 2 ] Pristine 1.051 22.49 64.77 15.32 9.89 2858 w/PEA 1.087 23.18 73.01 18.39 5.16 3903 w/SF-PEA 1.127 23.67 79.65 21.25 3.64 6265 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29835</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (2 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30288</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (3 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30741</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (4 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31194</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (5 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31647</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (6 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32100</offset>
      <text>			 Sol. RRL 2020, 4, 2000069 2000069 (7 of 7) © 2020 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim 2367198x, 2020, 5, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/solr.202000069 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
