<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001337437FCHEBC</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 115</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Liquid medium annealing for fabricating durable perovskite solar cells with improved reproducibility</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>112</offset>
      <text>Solution processing of semiconductors is highly promising for the high-throughput production of costeffective electronics and optoelectronics. Although hybrid perovskites have potential in various device applications, challenges remain in the development of high-quality materials with simultaneously improved processing reproducibility and scalability. Here, we report a liquid medium annealing (LMA) technology that creates a robust chemical environment and constant heating field to modulate crystal growth over the entire film. Our method produces films with high crystallinity, fewer defects, desired stoichiometry, and overall film homogeneity. The resulting perovskite solar cells (PSCs) yield a stabilized power output of 24.04% (certified 23.7%, 0.08 cm 2 ) and maintain 95% of their initial power conversion efficiency (PCE) after 2000 hours of operation. In addition, the 1-cm 2 PSCs exhibit a stabilized power output of 23.15% (certified PCE 22.3%) and keep 90% of their initial PCE after 1120 hours of operation, which illustrates their feasibility for scalable fabrication. LMA is less climate dependent and produces devices in-house with negligible performance variance year round. This method thus opens a new and effective avenue to improving the quality of perovskite films and photovoltaic devices in a scalable and reproducible manner. </text>
      <annotation id="32">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:54:11Z</infon>
        <location offset="953" length="4"/>
        <text>2000</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1468</offset>
      <text> S olution processing of semiconductors is a promising approach for the fabrication of cost-effective electronics and optoelectronics  (1, 2) . Recently, metal halide perovskites based on a solution process have been shown to have electronic and optoelectronic properties applicable in various device applications, particularly photovoltaics (PV)  (3) (4) (5) (6) . These perovskites have reached a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 25.5% within just one decade of research  (7)  and are therefore regarded as promising candidates for next-generation PV. Reviewing the development of this family of materials, early investigations of device physics revealed that the perovskite crystal quality (e.g., crystallinity, morphology, stoichiometry, etc.) profoundly influenced cell and module efficiencies  (8, 9) . The operational lifetime of high-efficiency cells has been prolonged to several thousand hours during accelerated aging tests, gradually approaching the requirements for practical use  (10) . In the context of device aging courses, the crystal quality again has become a research focus with an emphasis on its time evolution  (11) , which is governed by thermodynamic and kinetic factors, including components, chemical potential, structure, phase transition and segregation, ion migration, and defect concentrations  (10) . To promote the commercialization of perovskite PV, it is important to develop a scalable solution process with sufficient reproducibility. Research should expand the investigation of crystal quality in the spatial perspective  (12) , aiming at precise control of perovskite crystallization kinetics over the entire film at any atmosphere. However, there will be substantial difficulties in achieving this. First, perovskite formation includes a reaction between Lewis acids and bases that occurs quickly and spontaneously even at low temperature  (13) . Second, halide perovskites for practical use are often mixtures  (14)  in which the different components exhibit different reactivity and diffusivity during film growth. In addition, the precursor reactants are sensitive to moisture and common solvents  (15, 16) , which leads to considerable variance with each slight change in processing conditions. High-quality crystalline perovskite films generally have a large grain size, which is achieved by retarding nucleation and promoting crystal growth according to the LaMer model  (17) . Several strategies have been successfully applied to decrease the nucleation rate  (18, 19) , which effectively influences crystallization kinetics. In addition, higher annealing temperature and/or prolonged annealing time are reported to increase the crystallinity of perovskites by increasing crystal growth rate or inducing a recrystallization process  (20, 21) . However, coincident defects caused by unfavorable volatile component loss are often found, accompanied by substantial inhomogeneity in the film over a larger area  (22, 23) . Moreover, local fluctuations in processing atmosphere leads to films with varied quality  (15, 16)  and thus poor reproducibility. Therefore, it is challenging to develop a simple, controllable, and effective annealing technology that meets the requirements for scalable and reproducible fabrication. Here, we demonstrate liquid medium annealing (LMA) as a method of effectively modulating the crystal growth of halide perovskite materials. Rather than merely raising the annealing temperature, LMA adopts omnidirectional heating, particularly an extra "top-down" heat transfer on the film to accelerate crystal growth with a higher heating rate. In addition, the liquid medium extracts residual solvents from precursor films to mitigate their disturbance for crystal growth. Moreover, the liquid medium creates a microenvironment for crystal growth to prevent volatile component loss from the desired stoichiometry over the entire film. Consequently, LMA leads to excellent film homogeneity, which is also less dependent on the processing atmosphere and applicable for all-weather in-house fabrication. Small-area devices (0.08 cm 2 ) using LMA exhibited a stabilized power output of 24.04% (certified 23.7%) and maintained 95% of their initial PCE after 2000 hours of stabilized power output (SPO) tracking. The corresponding large-area solar cells (1 cm 2 ) achieved a stabilized power output of 23.15% (certified PCE of 22.3%) and kept 90% of their original PCE after 1120 hours of SPO tracking. To our knowledge, this is the smallest efficiency gap between smalland large-area devices ever reported. Our findings provide a reproducible technology with which to fabricate high-quality and homogeneous perovskite films for the production of efficient and stable large-area solar cells or other perovskite-based optoelectronics. Fine control on the annealing process, especially in the early stage, is crucial to modulating the crystallization dynamics and quality of perovskite films. In contrast to most annealing technologies, which are generally performed under certain atmosphere, we used LMA to fabricate perovskite films in which the asdeposited film is annealed in the preheated liquid (Fig.  1A ). The liquid medium in use (anisole in this work) needs to exhibit a high thermal conductivity and low viscosity with the appropriate organic solvent extraction ability but negligible reactivity with perovskites. Different from the traditional annealing (Ref) method, LMA (Fig.  1B ) uses the liquid to transfer heat and create a reaction microenvironment that produces substantially different crystallization dynamics of perovskite films mainly by affecting the heating mode and solvated intermediates. In traditional annealing, heating is "bottomup," meaning that heat transfers from hotplate to glass substrate to perovskite films (Fig.  1D ). This results in delayed heating at the film surface, where the directional crystallization has already begun  (24) . This heating transfer is in the opposite direction from crystallization, which may impede the crystal growth because of the limited diffusion of the reactants. LMA provides omnidirectional heating, in particular an extra "top-down" heat transfer, which allows fast heating of the film surface once it is in contact with the hot liquid (Fig.  1C ). This top-down heating mode is in line with the crystal growth direction of perovskite polycrystalline films. To illustrate the heating mode, we performed finite element analysis to simulate the thermal field and the annealing time in two processes (Fig.  2, A  and B ). Keeping the heat source at 150°C, the Ref film required ~13 s to reach 140°C at equilibrium upon bottom-up annealing (Fig.  2A ). The retarded heating rate was attributed to the heat transfer delay of glass and the considerable thermal convection between perovskite and air. By contrast, the perovskite film by LMA took only ~4 s to reach 141°C (Fig.  2B ) because the top-down heating mode allowed immediate heating of the entire perovskite film in a hot liquid. In addition, the liquid medium could form a relatively stable thermal field on perovskite films by avoiding unfavorable thermal convection with air. We investigated the temperature evolution in perovskite films and found that LMA exhibited a much faster heating rate of 32.7°C/s compared with that of Ref at 8.7°C/s (Fig.  2C ). Also, the temperature variation along the vertical direction of perovskite film was negligible for annealing (Fig.  2C , inset) because of the extremely thin thickness of the film compared with the substrate. Overall, the higher heating rate in the initial stage could potentially accelerate the diffusion of reactants (such as organic cations, Pb-I octahedra, etc.) and thus promote the grain growth rate, which will be discussed later. Anisole is an ideal liquid medium for perovskite fabrication because of its high thermal conductivity (0.137 W/m K) and relatively low viscosity (0.99 mPa/s at 20°C). In addition, it has a poor solubility in water but is miscible with most organic solvents (fig.  S2  and sup plementary text S1). Thus, the residual solvent [e.g., dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO)] in precursor films can be easily extracted, which potentially provides sufficient reactants to participate in crystal growth. To confirm this, we prepared PbI 2 (DMSO) and MA 2 Pb 3 I 8 •2DMSO intermediate powders (where MA is methylammonium), the major components in precursor films  (24) , to assess the solvent extraction ability of anisole. The relative intensity ratio of PbI 2 /PbI 2 (DMSO) signals from x-ray diffraction (XRD) measurement is summarized in fig.  S3 . After immersing PbI 2 (DMSO) powder in anisole for 20 min at 20°C, the PbI 2 /PbI 2 (DMSO) intensity ratio doubled compared with that in air (Fig.  2D ). When conducting LMA at 150°C for 10 s, no appreciable PbI 2 (DMSO) residue was observed. By contrast, the sample annealed in air retained a considerable amount of PbI 2 (DMSO) after heating at 150°C for 10 s. Similar results were observed when annealing MA 2 Pb 3 I 8 •2DMSO at either 20°C or 150°C (Fig.  2E  and fig.  S4 ): LMA resulted in a quicker conversion to MAPbI 3 . LMA thus improves solvent extraction from solvated intermediate, especially at high temperatures. To quantify the perovskite film growth rate by LMA, we monitored triple-cation perovskite film growth of FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z (where FA is formamidinium) in two-step deposition by ex situ ultraviolet-visible spectroscopy. The absorbance at 780 nm was used as an indicator for perovskite formation. The LMA sample exhibited an overall higher absorbance than Ref at the same time in the range of 40 to 100°C (fig.  S5 ). The change of absorbance was plotted as a function of time to obtain the growth rate (k) at each temperature (fig.  S5  and supple mentary text S2). LMA led to a significantly larger k than that of Ref (Fig.  2F ), and the rate difference (Dk) increased with temperature (from 5.49 × 10 -4 s -1 at 40°C to 1.28 × 10 -2 s -1 at 100°C; Fig.  2F, inset ). LMA resulted in a substantially different film morphology and quality. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images revealed that LMAprepared perovskite film had a larger grain size of 2.25 ± 0.66 mm (Fig.  2H   (Fig.  2G  and fig.  S6A ). This could be attributed to the accelerated crystal growth rate, which is positively correlated with grain size  (25)  High-quality perovskite films produced by LMA are likely related to the modulated crystal growth dynamics in the following aspects. First, increased grain size is often achieved at high temperature annealing  (20) , when the grain growth is overwhelmed by promoting the diffusion of reactant. Because of its high heating rate in LMA, precursor films experienced much shorter periods of low temperature (Fig.  2C ), which results in en-larged crystal size. Second, during traditional annealing, the wet precursor film preferentially crystallizes from the surface because of solvent evaporation driven by surface tension near the air-liquid interface  (24, 26) . As a result, residual solvents entrapped underneath the solidified surface are likely to interrupt the construction of perovskite structure  (26) . Moreover, reactive components are prone to react at the air-liquid interface, which changes the stoichiometry of the crystal. During LMA, however, the air-liquid interface is replaced by liquid-liquid contacts, and thus residual solvents are quickly extracted by liquid medium across the entire film thickness. This not only mitigates the disturbance of crystal growth from residual solvents but also prevents undesired side reactions during ambient processing, which leads to polycrystalline films with fewer defects and desired stoichiometry (discussed below). Last, LMA creates a spatially uniform chemical environment by efficient extraction of residual solvents and isolation from ambient conditions and a temporally uniform heat field by fast "top-down" annealing. It further ensures superior uniformity of the resultant films. Grain boundaries (GBs) in a polycrystalline film usually exhibit different optoelectronic properties from the grain bulk  (27) . LMA results in larger grains in the as-prepared film, which reduces the GBs and improves the absorber uniformity with respect to their optoelectronic characteristics. As evidenced by scanning Kelvin probe microscopy measurement, LMA-treated perovskite films exhibited smaller distribution, with a surface potential difference of ~25 mV (10 × 10 mm 2 area), whereas that of Ref was &gt;40 mV (Fig.  3,  A  and B   and supplementary text S3), and the fluorescence lifetime mapping was collected in the 10 × 10 mm 2 region of the perovskite films. In traditional annealing, the volatile and chemically reactive components such as MA + /FA + and I -can easily evaporate or react with ambient molecules (e.g., H 2 O, O 2 , etc.)  (28) , which causes local element loss and non-stoichiometry at the film surface  (22) . The liquid medium creates a robust microenvironment in which to inhibit volatile component evaporation from desired stoichiometry during annealing (Fig.  1E  and fig.  S9 ). To demonstrate this, methylammonium distribution [the infrared frequency of 1480 cm -1 represents the C-N stretching (n C-N ) absorption of the MA + ion] was probed by peak force infrared (PFIR) mi-croscopy (Fig.  3, E  and F ). The results showed that LMA-prepared perovskites exhibited an overall slightly increased IR response compared with the Ref sample, along with the more concentrative signal distribution without local low-signal regions (blue regions in Fig.  3E ). Stronger IR signal represents better preservation of organic components in the film  (29) , which indicates that LMA could protect this volatile component from escaping to produce more uniform component distribution. We also performed x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements to examine I - 3d and Pb 2+ 4f signals from corresponding perovskite films. The LMA sample exhibited the same binding energy with respect to I - 3d and Pb 2+ 4f peaks as that of Ref (fig.  S10A ). However, the I/Pb ratio in the LMA perovskite was 2.92, whereas that in Ref was only 2.74 (fig.  S10B ). This means that the I -ions are largely preserved during LMA, resulting in a more stoichiometric structure to alleviate the formation of vacancy defects. We also probed XPS mapping in an area of 50 × 50 mm 2 and found that the binding energy variation of perovskite I -and Pb 2+ ions was reduced by LMA (fig.  S11  and supplementary text S3). Therefore, LMA has great potential to produce spatially uniform perovskite films, which is beneficial for the scalable fabrication of larger-aperture area PSCs with improved efficiency and stability. We have revealed that LMA leads to the improved crystallinity and spatial uniformity of component and/or chemical distribution in the resultant films, which corresponds to the defect behavior that determines the corresponding device performance. We first performed PL quantum efficiency (PLQE) measurements on the perovskites at different light intensities (Fig.  3G ). The LMA-treated sample exhibited a higher PLQE of 19.6% compared with Ref (4.0%) under 100 mW/cm 2 irradiation. In addition, its PLQE increased more rapidly with enhancing laser intensity, indicating that the nonradiative recombination centers were more quickly filled  (30, 31) . PLQE also allows the perovskite solar cells to operate as lightemitting diode (LED) devices. The electroluminescence (EL) signal appeared at a low applied voltage of ~1.1 V, with the emission peak located at ~800 nm, which is consistent with other reports (32) (fig.  S12 ). The maximum external quantum efficiency (EQE) reached 8.15% for an LMA-based device at 1.6 V bias voltage, whereas Ref only obtained 0.90% (Fig.  3H ). This result shows that the defects related to nonradiative losses in the perovskite absorber were significantly suppressed by the LMA process. Moreover, temperaturedependent PL emission, transient photovoltage and photocurrent decays, and space-chargelimited current measurements (figs. S13 to S16 and supplementary text S4) further confirmed the lower charge carrier recombination rate and improved carrier transport and extraction in the LMA-fabricated device. We extensively applied the LMA process to other perovskite systems (e.g., MAPbI 3 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 ) and observed improved crystallinity and grain size (fig.  S17  and supplemen tary text S5), as well as marked enhancement of carrier lifetime in LMA samples (Fig.  3I ). The spatial uniformity of different perovskite systems was also characterized by PL mapping measurements (fig.  S18  and supplementary text S5). Variations in PL emission peak positions were all reduced with the LMA process (Fig.  3I ), indicating the uniform composition distribution of LMA samples regardless of perovskite system. We also found that LMA is feasible for one-step deposition to achieve improved carrier lifetime and reduced variation in PL peak positions (Fig.  3J ), which leads to improvements in other optoelectronic properties (fig.  S20  and supplementary text S6). Finally, to illustrate the applicability of LMA technology on larger-scale perovskite films, we fabricated perovskite films (FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z , 6×6 cm 2 ) and found that their quality and uniformity could also be improved by LMA (figs. S22 to S25 and supplementary text S7). From these results, we conclude that LMA technology can be universally applied to the fabrication of uniform perovskite films with high quality. We then fabricated perovskite solar devices (ITO/SnO 2 / FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z /Spiro-OMeTAD/Au) using LMA to investigate their photovoltaic performance. Statistical analyses on 100 individual devices for each condition were summarized. Both the open-circuit voltage (V OC ) and the short-circuit current density (J SC ) of PSCs were slightly improved by LMA (average V OC of 1.151 V and J SC of 24.66 mA/ cm 2 compared with Ref at 1.145 V, 24.52 mA/ cm 2 , respectively), which was consistent with the corresponding EQE measurements (fig.  S29 ), whereas the fill factor (FF) was substantially enhanced from 77.58 to 81.18% on average (fig.  S30 ). The improved photovoltaic parameters could be attributed to higher crystallinity and fewer defects in LMA-prepared perovskite films. The corresponding PCE achieved 23.24% on average compared with Ref at 21.80% (Fig.  4A ). The best device (with an aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 ) gave a stabilized power output of 24.04% (with a reverse scan PCE of 24.27% and a forward scan PCE of 23.17%; Fig.  4B ) and obtained a certified power output of 23.7% under steady-state tests at maximum power point (fig.  S31 ). LMA leads to uniform perovskite films, which is expected to be beneficial for largearea devices. We fabricated devices with a 1 cm 2 active area based on the same perovskite composition and device architecture. The V OC and J SC of the LMA device (1.155 V and 24.38 mA/cm 2 on average, respectively) and Ref (1.152 V and 24.47 mA/cm 2 on average, respectively) showed similar trends with corresponding small-area devices (fig.  S32 ). When the FF for Ref was reduced to 72.42%, that for LMA achieved 78.54% on average, closer to that of the corresponding small-area devices. It has been reported that FF is reduced with increases in the device area  (6, 33, 34) , likely because of the increase of parasitic resistive losses. LMA leads to excellent film uniformity in large areas, which provides large shunting resistance and small series resistance over the entire thin film device (fig.  S33 ). As a result, the LMA-fabricated large-area PSCs exhibited an average PCE of 22.17% (obtained from 80 individual devices), whereas that of Ref was 20.38% (Fig.  4A ). The best LMA device (with an aperture area of 1 cm 2 ) gave a stabilized power output of 23.15% (with a reverse scan PCE of 23.35% and a forward scan PCE of 22.54%; Fig.  4C ) and yielded a certified PCE of 22.3% (average value from a reverse scan PCE of 22.6% and a forward scan PCE of 22.0%) (fig.  S34 ). To our knowledge, this PCE is the highest ever reported for a 1-cm 2 device. The efficiency difference of the best-performing cell between the small (~0.1 cm 2 ) and large (1 cm 2 ) area was reduced from 1.37% (Ref sample; tables S8 and S9) to 0.92% (LMA sample; Fig.  4D ), and is the smallest reported thus far (fig.  S35 ), which implies promising potential for the scalable fabrication of perovskite solar cells by LMA. To investigate the stability of the resultant devices with the desired composition, the performance evolution under different kinds of stressors was monitored. The thermal stability test (stored at 85°C under nitrogen atmosphere following the ISOS-D-2I protocol) was performed first. LMA devices retained 95.2% of their initial PCE after 2184 hours of aging, whereas Ref retained 75.8% (fig.  S36 ). In addition, we investigated the operational stability of unencapsulated devices at one-sun LED irradiation with SPO tracking in a nitrogen atmosphere. This revealed that the LMA device only experienced a 5% PCE loss after 2000 hours of aging, whereas a PCE loss of up to 20% was found in Ref (Fig.  4E ). According to the degradation mechanisms of PSCs during operation  (10) , high-crystallinity perovskites with ideal stoichiometry and fewer GBs in the film are beneficial for suppressing ion and defect migration, which prolongs the operational lifetime of the device. We also monitored the operational lifetime of 1-cm 2 PSC devices. Although the Ref devices suffered aggravated PCE reduction of up to 39% after 1120 hours of aging, LMA devices only exhibited 10% PCE loss (Fig.  4F ). Perovskite films with fewer defects and high uniformity largely reduce the degradation sites at the initial state, which extends the operational lifetime of the corresponding devices profoundly. Therefore, perovskites produced by LMA have a great potential to be adopted in larger-area solar devices with enhanced efficiency and lifetime. In general, reproducible processing under variable ambient conditions is one of the primary criteria for the commercialization of perovskite PV to ensure low manufacturing costs. However, perovskite has been demonstrated to be moisture sensitive, which causes variations in performance when fabricated at different humidity levels  (15, 35, 36) . Even when annealing perovskites in moisture-free surroundings (e.g., in the glove box), the crystal quality can be significantly influenced by various volatile organic compounds.  (16)  Instead of laboriously and expensively controlling the annealing atmosphere, the LMA method is less dependent on the fabrication climate (in-house) because of the robust microenvironment created by the liquid medium. We also investigated its reproducibility under all-weather in-house conditions. The perovskite solar cells (FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z as absorber) were fabricated in four quarters with varied humidity in the laboratory (the average temperature/humidity for spring, summer, autumn, and winter were ~20°C/ ~30% RH, ~35°C/~65% RH, ~25°C/~40% RH, and ~15°C/~15% RH, respectively). The traditional annealing method was strongly dependent on weather, resulting in an average PCE of &gt;22% in winter and 19% in summer with poor reproducibility. There was no obvious performance difference in LMA devices (fig.  S37 ), with most having a PCE of &gt;23% (Fig.  4G ) because of the liquid medium, which effectively blocks interference from the ambient conditions (Fig.  1E ). This result shows the all-weather adaptability of LMA technology for the widespread fabrication of perovskite photovoltaics. We also fabricated solar cells with different perovskite compositions (e.g., MAPbI 3 , FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 , and FASn 0.5 Pb 0.5 I 3 ) and multiple processing (e.g., one-step spin-coating) to determine the generality of LMA technology. The LMA process was associated with a noticeable performance improvement (fig.  S19, S21 , and S27 and supplementary text S5, S6, and S8). Furthermore, the liquid medium can be expanded from anisole to trichlorobenzene and Dowtherm A (fig.  S38 ), for example, highlighting the extensive opportunities to further improve LMA technology for perovskite thin film fabrication. </text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:46:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="20071" length="5"/>
        <text>24.27</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:54:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="22225" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25839</offset>
      <text> Materials Materials used in this work include: ITO substrate, purchased from Advanced Election Technology Co., Ltd. SnO2 colloid precursor (tin(IV) oxide, 15% in H2O colloidal dispersion), dowtherm A, purchased from Alfa Aesar. PbI2 (99.999%), CsI (99.9%), N,Ndimethylformamide (99.99%), dimethyl sulfoxide (99.5%), isopropanol (99.99%), chlorobenzene (99.9%), acetonitrile (99.9%), and 4-tert-Butylpyridine (96%), purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Phenethylammonium iodide (99.5%), spiro-OMeTAD (99.8%) and PTAA (MOS), purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology in China. Anisole (99%), purchased from Macklin. Trichlorobenzene (99%), purchased from Aladdin. MAI, MACl, MABr, FAI and FACl were synthesized using the methods reported previously.  (37)  The details for MAX (X=Cl, Br, I) synthesis are as follows: 12 mL methylamine water solution (~0.1 mol) was added to a 100 mL three-neck flask which immersed in a water/ice bath. A certain amount (0.12~0.14 mol) of HX acid was slowly dropped into the bottle with continuous stirring. The mixture was refluxed for 2 h under a N2 atmosphere. Subsequently, the solution was concentrated to a dry solid by using rotary evaporation at 80 °C. This crude product was re-dissolved into 20 mL ethanol, then 100 μL diethyl ether was slowly dropped along the bottle wall and a white product deposited. This recrystallization was repeated three times, and the obtained precipitate was dried in a vacuum oven for 10 h at 40 ℃. The final products were sealed in a N2-filled glovebox for future use. The synthesis procedure for FAX (X=Cl, I) was similar to MAX, except that HX acid was added into a 0.1 mol formamidine acetate ethanol solution for further reaction. The PbI2(DMSO) powder was synthesized by adding PbI2 (448 mg) into mixed solvents DMSO/γ-butyrolactone (GBL) (1.0 mL, 3:7 vol/vol ratio) and stirring for 2 h at 100 °C. The solution was then cooled to room temperature and dried in a vacuum oven for 12 h at 40 ℃. The MA2Pb3I8•2DMSO powder was synthesized by adding PbI2 (833 mg) and MAI (287 mg) into mixed solvents DMSO/γ-butyrolactone (GBL) (1.0 mL, 3:7 vol/vol ratio) and stirring for 2 h at 100 °C. The solution was then cooled to room temperature and dried in a vacuum oven for 4 h at room temperature.  (38)  Methods Devices fabrication. The ITO substrate was cleaned by ultrapure water, acetone, ethanol and isopropanol successively. After 30 minutes of UV-O3 treatments, SnO2 nanocrystal solution (2.5%, diluted by water) was spin-coated on the substrate at 4000 rpm for 30 s, then annealed at 150 °C for 30 min in air. Perovskite films (with different components) were fabricated by either one-step spin-coating or two-step spin-coating. After that, the phenethylammonium iodide solution (0.024 M, dissolved in isopropanol) was spin-coated with 5000 rpm for 30 s to form a passivation layer for both Ref and LMA samples. Then the HTM solution, in which a Spiro-OMeTAD / chlorobenzene (60 mg mL -1 ) solution was employed with the addition of 28 μL Li-TFSI / acetonitrile (260 mg mL -1 ), and 24 μL 4-tertbutylpyridine, was deposited by spincoating at 3500 rpm for 30 s. The device was finished by thermal evaporation of Au (100 nm) under vacuum. (1) The perovskite films which were fabricated by the two-step solution process: MAPbI3 perovskite. the PbI2 (1.3 M, dissolved in DMF:DMSO (9:1, v:v) ) solution was spincoated on ITO/SnO2 at 2300 rpm for 30 s and annealed at 70 °C for 1 min in a nitrogen glovebox. After cooling the PbI2-coated substrate to room temperature in a nitrogen glovebox, a mixed organic cation solution (MACl 0.07 M; MAI 0.38 M, dissolved in isopropanol) was spin-coated with 2000 rpm for 30 s to form a wet precursor film. FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 perovskite. The PbI2 (1.35 M, dissolved in DMF:DMSO (9:1, v:v) ) solution mixed with 10% CsI was spin-coated on ITO/SnO2 at 2300 rpm for 30 s and annealed at 70 °C for 1 min in a nitrogen glovebox. After cooling the PbI2-coated substrate to room temperature in a nitrogen glovebox, a mixed organic cation solution (FACl 0.07 M; FAI 0.35 M, dissolved in isopropanol) was spin-coated with 2000 rpm for 30 s to form a wet precursor film. FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz perovskite. The PbI2 (1.35 M, dissolved in DMF:DMSO (9:1, v:v) ) solution mixed with 5% CsI was spin-coated on ITO/SnO2 at 2300 rpm for 30 s and annealed at 70 °C for 1 min in a nitrogen glovebox. After cooling the PbI2-coated substrate to room temperature in a nitrogen glovebox, a mixed organic cation solution (MABr 0.02 M; MACl 0.07 M; FAI 0.38 M, dissolved in isopropanol) was spin-coated with 2000 rpm for 30 s to form a wet precursor film. For traditional annealing (Ref) process, the as-coated precursor film was directly put onto the 150 °C hot-plate to anneal for 15 min in air (Fig.  S1A ); For liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, the liquid (e.g. anisole) in crystallizing dishes with spout was put onto the 150 °C hotplate in advance to form the hot liquid (liquid medium pre-heating about 15 min), then the ascoated precursor film was immersed in liquid to anneal for 3 min (Fig.  S1B ). After the annealing, the perovskite film was taken out of the liquid medium and the residual liquid on the perovskite surface was slightly blown away by N2 gun. (2) The perovskite films which were fabricated by the one-step solution process: Cs0.05(FA0.95MA0.05) 0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 perovskite. The precursor solution was prepared by dissolving 0.07 M CsI, 1.33 M PbI2, 0.07 M PbBr2, 1.26 M FAI, 0.07 M MABr, 0.14 M MACl in 1 mL anhydrous DMF:DMSO (4:1, v/v). Then the solution was deposited on the prefabricated ITO/SnO2 substrates by a two-step spin coating program: first at 1000 rpm with a ramp of 1000 rpm s -1 for 10 s, and then at 5000 rpm with a ramp of 3000 rpm s -1 for 30 s. At the 30th second of spinning, 200 μL of anti-solvent (chlorobenzene) was dripped at the centre to form a wet precursor film. For traditional annealing (Ref) process, the as-coated precursor film was directly put onto the 120 °C hot-plate to anneal for 60 min in N2 glovebox. For liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, the liquid (e.g. anisole) in crystallizing dishes with spout was put onto the 150 °C hot-plate in advance to form the hot liquid (about 15 min), then the ascoated precursor film was immersed in liquid to anneal for 3 min. After the annealing, the perovskite film was taken out of the liquid medium and the residual liquid on the perovskite surface was slightly blown away by N2 gun. (3) The FASn0.5Pb0.5I3 device fabrication. The p-i-n structure (ITO/PEDOT:PSS/Perovskite/C60/BCP/Cu) was adopted in fabricating FASn0.5Pb0.5I3 solar cells. PEDOT:PSS (Al 4083) was firstly spin-coated on ITO substrates at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and annealed on a hotplate at 120 °C for 20 min in ambient air. The perovskite precursor solution was prepared by dissolving 2 M FAI, 1 M PbI2, 1 M SnI2, 0.1 M SnF2 in 1 mL anhydrous DMF:DMSO (3:1, v/v). Then the solution was deposited on the prefabricated ITO/PEDOT:PSS substrates by a one-step spin-coating program: 5500 rpm with a ramp of 3000 rpm s -1 for 40 s, at the 30th second of spinning, 200 μL of anti-solvent (ethyl acetate) was dripped at the centre. For traditional annealing (Ref) process, the as-coated precursor film was directly put onto the 100 °C hot-plate to anneal for 10 min in N2 glovebox. For liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, the liquid (e.g. anisole) in crystallizing dishes with spout was put onto the 100 °C hot-plate in advance to form the hot liquid (about 15 min), then the as-coated precursor film was immersed in liquid to anneal for 3 min. After the annealing, the perovskite film was taken out of the liquid medium and the residual liquid on the perovskite surface was slightly blown away by N2 gun. The device was finished by thermal evaporation of C60 (25 nm), BCP (7 nm), Cu (150 nm) under vacuum. (4) The PEA2(FAPbBr3)2PbBr4 film fabrication. The perovskite precursor solution was prepared by dissolving 0.6 M PbBr2, 0.4 M FABr, 0.4 M PEABr, 0.06 M MACl in 1 mL DMSO under continuous stirring for 2h at 70 °C. Then the solution was spin-coated onto the quartz substrates via a two-step spin coating program at 1000 and 5000 rpm for 10 and 60 s, respectively. After spin coating for 20 s during the second step, 400 μL of chlorobenzene was poured onto the perovskite films. For traditional annealing (Ref) process, the as-coated precursor film was annealed at 90 °C for 60 min. For liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, the liquid (e.g. anisole) in crystallizing dishes with spout was put onto the 90 °C hot-plate in advance to form the hot liquid (about 15 min), then the as-coated precursor film was immersed in liquid to anneal for 5 min. After the annealing, the perovskite film was taken out of the liquid medium and the residual liquid on the perovskite surface was slightly blown away by N2 gun. (5) The stability analysis devices. Aiming at avoiding the additional influences of other functional layers/species to clearly compare only the stability difference between perovskite films fabricated by different processing, we changed some device configuration on the Ref and LMA fabricated devices. For thermal stability tests, the FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 perovskite was used as the absorber due to thermal instability of MA-containing perovskite  (39) . For SPO stability tests the FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz perovskite was still as the absorber. For both thermal stability and SPO stability tests, the PEAI passivation layer was removed, because the PEAI could be gradually converted into the PEA2PbI4 phase under heating (the SPO stability tests could also lead to the heating effect with the temperature about 40-60 ℃), which brought into significantly efficiency drop and shorter lifetime  (40) . Moreover, considering that the Spiro-OMeTAD was not a stable HTL, we used the Spiro-OMeTAD/PTAA hybrid HTL in our stability test  (41)  to achieve better stability, in which a Spiro-OMeTAD/PTAA (36/5 mg mL -1 , dissolved in chlorobenzene) mixed solution was employed with the addition of 35 μL Li-TFSI (260 mg mL -1 , dissolved in acetonitrile), and 30 μL 4-tertbutylpyridine, and deposited by spin-coating at 1500 rpm for 30 s. It should be noted that all the changes on the PSCs used in stability analysis were simultaneously conducted on both Ref and LMA samples. Basic Materials Characterization. The morphology of perovskite thin films were measured using a cold field-emission scanning electron microscope equipment (SEM, Hitachi S-4800). The XRD patterns were collected by using a PANalytical X'Pert Pro X-ray powder diffractometer with Cu Kα radiation (λ = 1.54050 Å). The UV-vis absorption spectra were obtained by an UV-visible diffuse reflectance spectrophotometer (UV-vis DRS, Japan Hitachi UH4150). PL and TRPL spectra were measured by FLS980 (Edinburgh Instruments Ltd) with an excitation at 470 nm. The PLQE data were obtained from a three-step technique through the combination of a 445 nm continuous wave laser, a spectrometer, an optical fiber, and an integrating sphere. XPS measurements were carried out on the XPS AXIS Ultra DLD (Kratos Analytical). FTIR spectroscopy were measured using Fourier transform infrared spectrometer (Tensor 27, Germany Bruker). </text>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:45:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="32407" length="3"/>
        <text>C60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:45:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="33652" length="3"/>
        <text>C60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="35186" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:47:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="35679" length="17"/>
        <text>Spiro-OMeTAD/PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:48:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="35777" length="17"/>
        <text>Spiro-OMeTAD/PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37117</offset>
      <text> Photoluminescence Mapping. PL mapping measurements were conducted by a Laser Scanning Confocal Microscope (Enlitech, SPCM-1000) equipped with 470 nm pulse laser and galvo-based scanner in air. The excitation wavelength was 470 nm, and we collected the emission signal in the wavelength range from 375 nm to 1025 nm. The signal collection area for each sample was 2500 (50 × 50) μm 2 . Scanning Kelvin Probe Force Microscopy. SKPM was performed on perovskite samples in air using a MFP 3D-Classic Scanning Probe Microscope (Asylum Research, Inc.). This technique relies on an AC bias applied to the tip to produce an electric force on the cantilever that is proportional to the potential difference between the tip and the sample. The scanning was done in a dual pass scan mode, during the first scanning the spatial variations in the surface potential were directly measured, and second scanning gave the work function by nulling local electrostatic force gradient arising from contact potential differences between the AFM tip and the sample surface. The conductive AFM probe is ASYELEC-01-R2 with Ti/Ir coating and resonant frequency 75 kHz. X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy Mapping. XPS Mapping measurements were conducted on the PHI QUANTERA-II SXM (ULVAC-PHI, Japan) with the Al Kα radiation (1486.6eV, linewidth 0.68 eV), the signal collection area for each sample was 2500 (50 × 50) μm 2 . The binding energy at different positions were obtained by extracting the corresponding XPS spectra from the mapping results through Multipak software, then utilized the peak fitting function to obtain the detailed peak positions. Peak Force Infrared Microscopy. In short, for peak force infrared (PFIR) imaging, the AFM (Multimode 8) was operated in peak force tapping mode, allowing for the tip-sample distance to be known at all times. Infrared light from a quantum cascade laser (MIRcat-QT, Daylight Solutions) was focused to the apex of the AFM probe (HQ:NSC15/Pt, Mikromasch). A phaselocked loop synchronized the laser pulses with every peak force tapping cycle. The laser pulse (500 ns, 600-900 mW) timing was set to occur when the tip was in dynamic contact with the sample. Vertical deflections from laser-induced contact resonance were read-out by a quadrant photodiode and digitized. PFIR signal was acquired from the amplitude of a fast-Fourier transform of the contact resonance. For the PFIR images, the scan size was 16 (4 × 4) μm 2the scan rate is 0.25 -0.3 Hz (depending on image). There are 384 pixels/line. Resonant frequency of the AFM tip is 264 kHz. Laser output power depends on chosen frequency. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39742</offset>
      <text> Time-Resolved Photoluminescence Mapping. For the TRPL mapping measurements, a laser scanning confocal microscope system (SouthPort, JadeMat) equipped 473 nm laser and galvobased scanner was used in air. The objective was 40x with numerical aperture of 0.8. The carriers lifetime were collected based on Time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC), the resolution was set to 80 ps with 32768 channel. The signal collection area for each sample was 100 (10 × 10) μm 2 . Device Characterization. The TPV and TPC measurements were performed on Molex 180081-4320 simulating one sun working conditions, the carriers were excited by a 532 nm pulse laser. External quantum efficiencies were measured by an Enli Technology (Taiwan) EQE measurement system. For the solar cell device operating as a LED, the devices were mounted in an integrating sphere and the power output measured for calculation of the EQE (Enlitech, LQ-100X). The current density-voltage characteristics of perovskite devices were obtained using a Keithley 2400 source-measure unit under AM 1.5G illumination at 1000 W/m 2 with a Newport Thermal Oriel 91192 1000 W solar simulator. The scan speed was set as 33 mV/s (with 0.01 V step, 0.3 s delay time) and 100 mV/s (with 0.02 V step, 0.2 s delay time) under either reverse scan (1.2 V ~ -0.2 V) or forward scan (-0.2 V ~ 1.2 V). The shading masks (including small area and large area) were sent to National Institute of Metrology, China (NIM, China) for certification. And the active area was defined as 8.313 mm 2 (small area) and 100.142 mm 2 (large area). The thermal stability tests were carried out in a nitrogen glove box, and the devices were put on a hot-plate with a temperature of 85 °C. The SPO stability tests were conducted in a nitrogen glove box by ageing devices under 1-sun illumination (white LED source, 100 mW/cm 2 ) with constant 0.9 V bias voltage at averaged temperature about 40 ℃ (temperature is kept in the range of 30-50 ℃). Notably, all devices are unencapsulated. And the residual water in ageing box is below 0.1 ppm during 85 ℃ heating or SPO tracking. Finite Element Analysis. The heat transfer analysis was carried out using a finite element code (ABAQUS). The Glass, Perovskite with the dimensions of 0.18×0.18×0.7 mm 3 , 0.18×0.18×0.0006 mm 3 were modeled, respectively (Fig.  S39A ). When performing the heat transfer analysis, the linear hexahedral diffusive heat transfer elements, DC3D8, were used. The Glass has 225,000 hexahedron elements, while the Perovskite has 7,500 hexahedron elements (Fig.  S39B ). The heat transfer analysis required specification of thermal conductivity, specific heat, density in this study which are listed in Table  S12 . The solid, homogenous section was used to assign material properties to the elements. The initial temperature was set to 25 °C in the entire model. No temperature boundary conditions were applied. The thermal response of the model was driven entirely by thermal loading through film coefficients. Conductive heat transfer was defined between Glass and Perovskite contacting surfaces, and a thermal conductance was specified, which was 1500 W/m 2 /°C. Heat flux on the surfaces was applied by film conditions. For simplicity, the hot plate and liquid medium were regarded as isothermal body, and the surfaces of Glass and Perovskite which were in contact with hot plate and liquid medium had a same film coefficient of 0.5 W/m 2 /°C, and the surfaces were initially associated with a sink temperature of 150 °C. The surface of Perovskite which was exposed to air had a film coefficient of 0.28 W/m 2 /°C, and the surface was initially associated with a sink temperature of 25 °C.  (42, 43)  The heat transfer procedure was performed using a transient step and the total time period is 60 s. The initial time increment size was 0.0001 s, and the automatic type of incrementation was used for the sequence increment which were determinate by the ABAQUS algorithm. The maximum time increment size and maximum allowable temperature change per increment were 5 s and 10 °C, respectively. </text>
      <annotation id="29">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:54:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="41449" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="30">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:54:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="41812" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43852</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Text S1 The Miscibility of Anisole with Solvents Anisole exhibits a strong miscibility with commonly used organic solvents in perovskites fabrication, such as dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), isopropanol (IPA), etc.  (44, 45)  This is also proved by mixing these solvents with anisole, and it forms a uniform mixture without liquid separation, respectively (Fig.  S2A-C ). From Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy analysis the stretching vibration peak of C-O bond in anisole (1248.6 cm -1 ) is slightly shifted to lower wavenumbers when mixing with DMSO (1246.9 cm -1 ) or IPA (1245.5 cm -1 ) (Fig.  S2F-G ), which indicates the weak interaction between anisole and them.(45) Meanwhile, there is no obvious C-O peak shift in DMF/Anisole mixture (Fig.  S2E ), means the interaction between anisole and DMF is weaker than DMSO or IPA, and this is also confirmed by other reports.  (45)  In comparison, the water is not miscible with anisole (Fig.  S2D , a drop of red ink is added into water for clear illustration), which can be attributed to their large polarity difference according to the "like dissolves like" rule. Therefore, the anisole is a good candidate to serve as the liquid annealing medium, which can effectively extract residual solvent from wet perovskite film while avoiding moisture attacking.                          S8 .    S9 .   S9 .  to clearly compare the PCE difference between small aperture area and large aperture area. Note that our LMA fabricated PSC devices exhibit the highest 1 cm 2 aperture area PCE of 23.15% and the smallest δ(PCE) of 3.7%.    S10 .   S11 ), which is mainly due to the lackness of systematic exploration on fabrication details. However, based on these results the liquid medium annealing technology still exhibits the extensive room to fabricate PSCs with enhanced optoelectronic performance.  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45745</offset>
      <text> Table S1 The fitted carriers lifetime of FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films and perovskite with carrier transport layers which obtained from the TRPL measurements (Fig.  S16B ).  </text>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="45787" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45919</offset>
      <text> Ref-PVSK </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45929</offset>
      <text> Table S5 The fitted carriers lifetime of large area (6×6 cm 2 ) FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film (divided into 5 select pieces (regions 1-5)) which obtained from the TRPL measurements (Fig.  S23E-F ).  of 7 Fig. 1 . 71 Fig. 1. Diagram of the LMA process. (A) The LMA process includes liquid medium preheating, perovskite annealing, and removal of residual liquid. (B) LMA illustration with anisole as the liquid medium. (C and D) Heating direction on perovskite films with the LMA process (omnidirectional heating) (C) and the traditional annealing process (Ref, upward heating) (D). (E) Detailed growth dynamics including residual solvent (DMSO) removal and reactant diffusion, as well as preventing volatile component loss and inhibiting moisture invasion using the LMA process. </text>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="45994" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46707</offset>
      <text> ). The uniform distribution of surface potential found in LMA samples is beneficial for effective photocarriers extraction in a layerstacked PSCs to avoid potential recombination. The PL-mapping measurements were performed in the 50 × 50 mm 2 region (fig. S8 Li et al., Science 373, 561-567 (2021 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47006</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Crystallization dynamics of perovskites under the Ref and LMA processes. (A and B) Finite element analysis on the thermal field distribution with annealing time with the Ref process (A) and the LMA process (B). (C) Temperature evolution of perovskite film surface with annealing time. Inset: Temperature evolution of perovskite film at different depths. (D) Relative content of PbI 2 /PbI 2 (DMSO) under the Ref and LMA processes at 20°C (for 20 min) or 150°C (for 10 s), expressed as the ratio of the XRD peak areas for the PbI 2 and the PbI 2 (DMSO) signals. (E) Relative content of MAPbI 3 /MA 2 Pb 3 I 8 •2DMSO under Ref and LMA processes at 20°C (for 20 min) or 150°C (for 10 s), expressed as the ratio of the XRD peak areas for the MAPbI 3 and the MA 2 Pb 3 I 8 •2DMSO signals. (F) Crystallization rate (k) of spin-coated FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z film under different temperatures (40 to 100°C) calculated from in situ ultraviolet-visible results. Inset: Crystallization rate difference (Dk) between the Ref and LMA processes (Dk = k LMAk Ref ). (G and H) Top-view field emission SEM images of FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z films under the Ref (G) and LMA (H) processes. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48221</offset>
      <text> 4 of 7 Fig. 3 . 473 Fig. 3. Uniformity and defect behavior of FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z films under the Ref and LMA processes and the universality of LMA technology. (A and B) Surface potential images measured by scanning Kelvin probe microscopy of the Ref-and LMA-fabricated perovskite films. (C and D) Time-resolved photoluminescence mapping measurements on the Ref-and LMA-fabricated perovskite films with the carrier lifetime as the target signal. (E and F) PFIR microscopy at an IR frequency of 1480 cm -1 (which is resonant with the C-N stretching absorption of MA + ion) of Ref-and LMA-fabricated perovskite films. (G) PLQE measurements on the Ref-and LMA-fabricated perovskite films as a function of excitation power. (H) EQE curves of EL on the Ref-and LMA-fabricated devices while operating as LEDs. Inset: EL image of the LMA-fabricated devices under 1.6 V bias voltage. (I and J) Carrier lifetimes (obtained from time-resolved photoluminescence results as a perovskite quality indicator) and PL peak position variation (obtained from PL-mapping statistical results as a perovskite uniformity indicator) of perovskites with different compositions: MAPbI 3 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 (I) and perovskites prepared under the one-step spin-coating (Cs 0.05 (FA 0.95 MA 0.05 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 system) and two-step spin-coating (FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z system) processes (J). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49625</offset>
      <text> Li 7 Fig. 4 . 74 Fig. 4. Optoelectronic performance and stability of FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z -based PSCs prepared under the Ref and LMA processes. (A) PCE distribution of 100 individual PSC devices (aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 ) and 80 individual PSC devices (aperture area of 1 cm 2 ) fabricated under the Ref and LMA processes, respectively. (B and C) J-V curves with reverse (1.2 V to -0.2 V) and forward (-0.2 V to 1.2 V) scan of LMA devices with aperture areas of 0.08 cm 2 (B) and 1 cm 2 (C). Inset: Stabilized PCE at the maximum power point tracking under 1.02 V (B) or 0.98 V (C) bias. (D) PCE comparison of the best-performing 0.08-cm 2 PSC and 1-cm 2 PSC under the Ref and FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y PbI 3-z Br z LMA processes, respectively. (E and F) Evolution of normalized PCEs of Ref and LMA devices with aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 (E) and 1 cm 2 (F) under continuous light irradiation and SPO tracking with a white LED lamp at 100 mW cm -2 in a nitrogen atmosphere. (G) PCE distribution of Ref-and LMA-fabricated PSCs under different seasons (the average temperature/humidity in the laboratory for spring, summer, autumn, and winter were ~20°C/~30% RH, ~35°C/~65% RH, ~25°C/~40% RH, and ~15°C/~15% RH, respectively). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50861</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. The SEM images of FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films under traditional (Ref) and liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. (A) The SEM image and corresponding grain size statistics of Ref sample, the average grain size is about 0.85 μm. (B) The SEM image and corresponding grain size statistics of LMA sample, the average grain size is about 2.25 μm. </text>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="50902" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51228</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. The comparison of the FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film quality under traditional (Ref) and liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. (A) The XRD patterns under Ref and LMA process, respectively. (B) The PL spectroscopy under Ref and LMA process, respectively. (C) The TRPL spectroscopy under Ref and LMA process, respectively. </text>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="51273" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51570</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. Photoluminescence mapping of the (A) Ref and (B) LMA fabricated FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films with the emission peak position as the indicator. </text>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="51657" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51736</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. The detailed growth dynamics including residual solvent (DMSO) evaporation and reactants diffusion, as well as the scheme of thermal decomposition and hydration under traditional annealing process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51957</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. The XPS measurements of FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films under traditional (Ref) and liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. (A)XPS spectra of I 3d and Pb 4f signals. (B) The I/Pb ratio of perovskite film, calculated from the integral area of XPS results. </text>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="52007" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52234</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. XPS mapping measurements of FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films. (A and B) The binding energy distribution of I -under (A) traditional (Ref) and (B) liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. The I 3d5/2 peak positions are served as the target signal. (C and D) The binding energy distribution of Pb 2+ under (C) traditional (Ref) and (D) liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. The Pb 4f7/2 peak positions are served as the target signal. </text>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="52288" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52688</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. EL spectra of the FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz based devices which operate as LEDs under different bias voltage. (A) Traditional annealing (Ref) fabricated devices. (B) Liquid medium annealing (LMA) process fabricated devices. </text>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="52732" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52935</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. Colour plots of the normalized steady-state PL spectra for (A) Ref and (B) LMA treated FA1-x- </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53055</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. Carrier mobility measurements. (A) Vertical dark J-V curve of ITO/FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz/Au. (B and C) SCLC characteristics of the ITO/FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz/Au device under (B) Ref and (C) LMA process, respectively. </text>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="53147" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="53216" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53298</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. The comparison of carrier injection rate. (A) The PL spectra; (B) The TRPL spectra of FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films and perovskite films with transport layer which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. </text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="53410" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53539</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. The comparison of the perovskite films quality with different compositions. (A and B) The UV-Vis spectra of the (A) MAPbI3 and (B) FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films. Inset: The Urbach energies (Eu) of perovskites which are calculated from the equation: α = α0 exp(E/Eu), where α is absorption coefficient. (C and D) The PL spectra of the (C) MAPbI3 and (D) FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films. (E and F) The TRPL spectra of the (E) MAPbI3 and (F) FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films. (G and H) The XRD pattern of the (G) MAPbI3 and (H) FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films. (I and J) The SEM images of MAPbI3 perovskite films under (I) Ref and (J) LMA process. (K and L) The SEM images of FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 perovskite films under (K) Ref and (L) LMA process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54265</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. The spatial uniformity characterization of the perovskite films with different components. (A and B) The PL mapping images of the (A) Ref and (B) LMA treated MAPbI3 films with the emission peak position as the indicator. (C and D) The PL mapping images of the (C) Ref and (D) LMA treated FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films with the emission peak position as the indicator. (E and F) The TOF-SIMS mapping of the (E) Ref and (F) LMA treated FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films with the Pb 2+ as the indicator. (G and H) The TOF-SIMS mapping of the (G) Ref and (H) LMA treated FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 films with the Cs + as the indicator. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54889</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. The optoelectronic performance of Ref and LMA fabricated PSCs with MAPbI3 and FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 as the absorbers, respectively. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55143</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. The comparison of the Cs0.05(FA0.95MA0.05)0.95Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 film quality under one-step spincoating processing. (A) The UV-Vis spectra; (B) The PL spectra; (C) The TRPL spectra; (D) The XRD patterns of perovskite films under Ref and LMA process. (E and F) The SEM images of perovskite films under (E) Ref and (F) LMA process. (G and H) The PL mapping images of perovskite films under (G) Ref and (H) LMA process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55585</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. The optoelectronic performance of Ref and LMA fabricated PSCs (Cs0.05(FA0.95MA0.05)0.95Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 as absorber) under one-step spin-coating processing. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. (E and F) J-V curves with the reverse (1.2 V to -0.2 V) scan of (E) Ref and (F) LMA devices. Inset: the corresponding photovoltaic parameters. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56014</offset>
      <text> Fig. S22 . S22 Fig. S22. Large area FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz films. (A) Optical image of 6×6 cm 2 area perovskite films under Ref process. (B) Optical image of 6×6 cm 2 area perovskite films under LMA process. (C) Schematic illustration of the fabricated large-area perovskite film which cut into 5 select pieces (regions 1-5). </text>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="56051" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56343</offset>
      <text> Fig. S23 . S23 Fig. S23. The comparison of the large area (6×6 cm 2 ) FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film quality, which divided into 5 selected pieces (regions 1-5). (A and B) The UV-Vis spectra of the perovskite films under (A) Ref and (B) LMA process. (C and D) The PL spectra of the perovskite films under (C) Ref and (D) LMA process. (E and F) The TRPL spectra of the perovskite films under (E) Ref and (F) LMA process. (G and H) The XRD patterns of the perovskite films under (G) Ref and (H) LMA process. </text>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="56414" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56848</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. The SEM images of large area (6×6 cm 2 ) FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film, which divided into 5 selected pieces (regions 1-5). (A-E) Regions 1-5 under Ref process. (F-J) Regions 1-5 under LMA process. </text>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="56915" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57071</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. The PL mapping images of large area (6×6 cm 2 ) FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film, which divided into 5 select pieces (regions 1-5). (A-E) Regions 1-5 under Ref process. (F-J) Regions 1-5 under LMA process. </text>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="57145" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57299</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 . S26 Fig. S26. The optoelectronic performance of based on Ref (blue) and LMA (yellow) fabricated PSCs (6×6 cm 2 FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film with selected regions 1-5), respectively. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57596</offset>
      <text> Fig. S27 . S27 Fig. S27. The optoelectronic performance of Ref and LMA fabricated PSCs based on FASn0.5Pb0.5I3 as the absorber. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57828</offset>
      <text> Fig. S28 . S28 Fig. S28. The PLQY of PEA2(FAPbBr3)2PbBr4 film under Ref and LMA process, respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57932</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 . S29 Fig. S29. External quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra together with the integrated JSC for the PSC devices (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber). (A) Traditional annealing (Ref) fabricated devices, with the integrated JSC of 24.99 mA/cm 2 . (B) Liquid medium annealing (LMA) process fabricated devices, with the integrated JSC of 25.02 mA/cm 2 .These results also agree well with the values of short-circuit current density obtained from J-V results (Fig.S30B). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58407</offset>
      <text> Fig. S30 . S30 Fig. S30. The optoelectronic performance of 100 devices (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber, with an aperture area of 8.313 mm 2 ) which fabricated under traditional (Ref) or liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, respectively. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. The detailed photovoltaic parameters can be found in TableS8. </text>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="58480" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58816</offset>
      <text> Fig. S31 . S31 Fig. S31. Certificated results by the National Institute of Metrology, China (NIM, China). The reverse scan is performed from 1.2 V to -0.1 V at 33 mV/s, with a PCE of 23.5% (Voc=1.155 V, Isc=2.096 mA, FF=80.7%). The forward scan is performed from -0.1 V to 1.2 V at 33 mV/s, with a PCE of 21.6% (Voc=1.147 V, Isc=2.094 mA, FF=74.6%). The device is also performed under maximum power point (MPP) tracking at bias voltage of 1.0 V, gives a stabilized PCE of 23.7%. The aperture area of device is 8.313 mm 2 . </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59340</offset>
      <text> Fig. S32 . S32 Fig. S32. The optoelectronic performance of 80 devices (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber, with an aperture area of 100.142 mm 2 ) which fabricated under traditional (Ref) or liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, respectively. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. The detailed photovoltaic parameters can be found in TableS9. </text>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="59412" length="22"/>
        <text>FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59750</offset>
      <text> Fig. S33 . S33 Fig. S33. The J-V curves and corresponding series resistance (Rs) and shunt resistance (Rsh) of the best performance large area PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber, with an aperture area of 100.142 mm 2 ) which fabricated under traditional (Ref) or liquid medium annealing (LMA) process, respectively. (A) Ref PSC, with the Rs of 6.91 Ω, Rsh of 3704.12 Ω. (B) LMA PSC, with the Rs of 4.18 Ω, Rsh of 6800.41 Ω. The corresponding photovoltaic parameters can be found in TableS9. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60252</offset>
      <text> Fig. S34 . S34 Fig. S34. Certificated results by the National Institute of Metrology, China (NIM, China). The reverse scan is performed from 1.2 V to -0.1 V at 33 mV/s, with a PCE of 22.6% (Voc=1.160 V, Isc=25.69 mA, FF=75.8%). The forward scan is performed from -0.1 V to 1.2 V at 33 mV/s, with a PCE of 22.0% (Voc=1.145 V, Isc=25.67 mA, FF=75.1%). The aperture area of device is 100.142 mm 2 . </text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:43:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="60447" length="4"/>
        <text>1.16</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60649</offset>
      <text> Fig. S35 . S35 Fig. S35. The PCE of PSC devices with simultaneously small aperture area (~0.1 cm 2 ) and large aperture area (~1 cm 2 ). The PCE of Ref 1,(53) Ref 2,(54) Ref 3,(55) Ref 4,(56) Ref 5,(57) Ref 6,(33) Ref 7,(58) Ref 8,(59) Ref 9,(34) Ref 10,(6) Ref 11,(60) are originated from the existing reports. Inset: the comparsion of large aperture area (~1 cm 2 ) PCE and δ(PCE) between the existing reports (Ref 1-11) and our work. δ(PCE) is defined as: δ(PCE) = PCE(small area)-PCE(large area) PCE(small area) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61169</offset>
      <text> Fig. S36 . S36 Fig. S36. Thermal stability tests of PSC devices (FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 as absorber) which fabricated under traditional (Ref) or liquid medium annealing (LMA) process. Evolution of normalized PCEs of Ref and LMA devices kept at 85 °C in a nitrogen atmosphere, following ISOS-D-2I standard. The error bars represent the standard deviation for eight devices. </text>
      <annotation id="31">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:54:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="61406" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61536</offset>
      <text> Fig. S37 . S37 Fig. S37. The optoelectronic performance of traditional annealing (Ref) and liquid medium annealing (LMA) fabricated PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber) under different seasons (the average temperature/humidity for spring, summer, autumn and winter are ~20 ℃/~30% RH, ~35 ℃/~65% RH, ~25 ℃/~40% RH, ~15 ℃/~15% RH, respectively). (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. The detailed photovoltaic parameters can be found in TableS10. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62060</offset>
      <text> Fig. S38 . S38 Fig. S38. The optoelectronic performance of traditional annealing (Ref) and liquid medium annealing (LMA) fabricated PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber) with the anisole, trichlorobenzene, dowtherm A as liquid medium, respectively. (A) Open circuit voltage. (B) Short-circuit current. (C) Fill factor. (D) Power conversion efficiency. The results show that trichlorobenzene or dowtherm A can also be a usable heat transfer medium to fabricate efficient PSCs, although the corresponding performane is lower than anisole treated one (TableS11), which is mainly due to the lackness of systematic exploration on fabrication details. However, based on these results the liquid medium annealing technology still exhibits the extensive room to fabricate PSCs with enhanced optoelectronic performance. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62876</offset>
      <text> Fig. S39 . S39 Fig. S39. FEA model for heat transfer analysis. (A) assembly model. (B) mesh model. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62976</offset>
      <text> Table S3 Photovoltaic parameters for the PSCs with different compositions (MAPbI3 and FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3). S3 The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 15 individual PSC devices which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. Table S2 The fitted carriers lifetime of perovskites with different components which obtained from the TRPL measurements (Fig. S17E-F). τ1 (ns) MAPbI3 69.03 Ref-ETL/PVSK/HTL 58.07 Voc Ref Jsc LMA (V) (mA/cm 2 ) τ1 (ns) LMA-PVSK 116.3 5.3 FF 56.7 (%) LMA-τ2 (ns) ETL/PVSK/HTL 2.08 63.8 PCE 171.5 (%) τ2 (ns) FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 MAPbI3 570.1 LMA Ref Ref LMA 1.120±0.013 1.130±0.009 269.6 28.0 73.4 22.73±0.44 23.00±0.53 840.9 75.36±2.81 78.46±1.32 87.15 376.9 758.8 19.20±0.96 20.38±0.46 FA0.9Cs0.1PbI3 Ref LMA 1.120±0.013 1.123±0.008 23.39±0.28 23.83±0.41 77.88±1.18 80.29±0.56 20.40±0.62 21.48±0.44 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63890</offset>
      <text> Table S4 S4 The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan rate is 100 mV/s) of 20 individual one-step spin-coated PSC devices (Cs0.05(FA0.95MA0.05)0.95Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 as the absorber) which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. Voc (V) Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Ref 1.133±0.009 23.96±0.21 75.70±0.95 20.56±0.34 LMA 1.138±0.006 23.95±0.28 77.46±1.07 21.10±0.41 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64319</offset>
      <text> Table S6 S6 The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 10 individual PSCs (regions 1-5) which were cut from 6×6 cm 2 spin-coated FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz film. Region 1 Region 2 Region 3 Region 4 Region 5 Ref Voc (V) LMA Jsc τ1 (ns) τ2 (ns) τ1 (ns) Ref LMA 1.147±0.011 1.138±0.012 1.135±0.014 1.143±0.015 1.144±0.012 0.86 1.85 21.26 3.35 1.54 Region 1 Region 2 Region 3 Region 4 Region 5 17.83 17.45 95.58 17.41 15.62 33.27 23.95 37.97 21.43 23.93 1.140±0.009 1.137±0.020 1.128±0.016 1.119±0.026 1.137±0.016 τ2 (ns) 134.38 112.04 125.18 106.41 116.49 Ref 24.51±0.35 24.64±0.37 24.30±0.38 24.34±0.53 24.28±0.48 (mA/cm 2 ) LMA 24.57±0.24 24.65±0.14 24.66±0.15 24.42±0.27 24.41±0.33 FF (%) Ref LMA 76.49±1.31 79.24±1.79 79.55±2.043 77.42±2.71 76.53±2.84 74.805±2.20 77.34±1.34 79.05±1.83 79.83±1.83 79.26±1.62 PCE (%) Ref LMA 21.38±0.55 22.33±0.65 21.69±0.92 22.31±0.68 20.99±1.25 22.12±0.58 20.32±1.11 22.28±0.75 21.36±0.83 22.14±0.56 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65362</offset>
      <text> Table S7 S7 The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 10 individual FASn0.5Pb0.5I3 PSC devices which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. Voc (V) Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Ref 0.623±0.022 26.70±1.72 55.30±1.70 9.20±0.69 LMA 0.630±0.010 29.63±0.66 65.09±1.23 12.15±0.44 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65726</offset>
      <text> Table S8 Photovoltaic parameters for the small area (0.08 cm 2 ) PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as the absorber). S8 The best Ref cell and LMA cell under the forward (-0.2 to 1.2 V) and reverse (1.2 to -0.2 V) scan directions. The scan rate is 33 mV/s (with 0.01 V step, 0.3 s delay time). The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan rate is 100 mV/s) of 100 individual PSC devices which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. Voc Jsc FF PCE (V) (mA/cm 2 ) (%) (%) Best Ref cell Reverse scan Forward scan 1.160 1.155 25.01 24.89 79.38 77.43 23.03 22.26 Best LMA cell Reverse scan Forward scan 1.163 1.159 25.01 24.86 83.44 80.42 24.27 23.17 Ref cells (average) 1.145±0.012 24.52±0.44 77.58±2.53 21.80±0.62 LMA cells (average) 1.151±0.011 24.66±0.40 81.18±1.08 23.24±0.48 </text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:45:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="66374" length="5"/>
        <text>1.163</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66560</offset>
      <text> Table S9 Photovoltaic parameters for the large area (1 cm 2 ) PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber). S9 The best Ref cell and LMA cell under the forward (-0.2 to 1.2 V) and reverse (1.2 to -0.2 V) scan directions. The scan speed is 33 mV/s (with 0.01 V step, 0.3 s delay time). The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 80 individual PSC devices fabricated by Ref and LMA process, respectively. Voc Jsc FF PCE (V) (mA/cm 2 ) (%) (%) Best Ref cell Reverse scan Forward scan 1.163 1.160 25.12 25.07 74.14 71.49 21.66 20.79 Best LMA cell Reverse scan Forward scan 1.165 1.159 25.37 25.16 79.00 77.30 23.35 22.54 Ref cells (average) 1.152±0.011 24.47±0.38 72.42±3.80 20.38±1.09 LMA cells (average) 1.155±0.013 24.38±0.40 78.54±1.94 22.17±0.61 </text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu,kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:43:20Z</infon>
        <location offset="67141" length="5"/>
        <text>21.66</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>67379</offset>
      <text> Table S10 Photovoltaic parameters for the PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber) fabricated under different seasons S10 . The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 50 individual PSC devices which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, respectively. Voc Jsc FF PCE (V) (mA/cm 2 ) (%) (%) Spring Ref LMA 1.130±0.028 1.164±0.013 24.01±0.50 24.44±0.50 79.61±2.90 80.47±1.28 21.58±0.79 22.97±0.58 Summer Ref LMA 1.123±0.019 1.148±0.014 24.05±0.25 24.42±0.49 71.66±4.45 79.67±1.58 19.36±1.29 22.35±0.78 Autumn Ref LMA 1.139±0.025 1.162±0.016 24.19±0.33 24.28±0.59 76.76±2.12 80.41±1.49 21.14±0.75 22.73±0.71 Winter Ref LMA 1.163±0.018 1.163±0.012 24.42±0.42 24.50±0.50 78.25±1.59 80.92±1.36 22.22±0.69 23.05±0.52 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>68188</offset>
      <text> Table S11 Photovoltaic parameters for the PSCs (FA1-x-yMAxCsyPbI3-zBrz as absorber) with different annealing medium. S11 The average value and standard deviation (obtained from reverse scan results, the scan speed is 100 mV/s) of 15 individual PSC devices which fabricated under Ref and LMA process, the LMA process includes anisole, trichlorobenzene, dowtherm A as the liquid medium, respectively. Voc Jsc FF PCE (V) (mA/cm 2 ) (%) (%) Ref 1.159±0.011 24.22±0.37 79.74±1.81 22.33±0.56 Anisole 1.152±0.012 24.47±0.35 83.17±1.08 23.44±0.46 LMA Trichlorobenzene 1.151±0.022 24.25±0.52 78.31±3.09 21.86±0.97 Dowtherm A 1.155±0.009 24.37±0.35 80.41±1.24 22.63±0.46 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>68866</offset>
      <text> Table S12 Material properties used in FEA for heat transfer analysis.(61, 62) S12 Thermal conductivity Specific heat Density (W/m/K) (J/kg/K) (kg/m 3 ) Glass 1.4 750 2.5 Perovskite 0.3 306 4.2 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>69060</offset>
      <text>			 of </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>69067</offset>
      <text>			 RESEARCH | REPORTDownloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>69187</offset>
      <text>			 of 7 RESEARCH | REPORT Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">ISOSD2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">kham@ucsd.edu</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2024-11-16T10:55:27Z</infon>
      <node refid="31" role=""/>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="2" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="1" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
