<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001329339HBGFAD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 102</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>FhG-ISE/AMOLF</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25</offset>
      <text>Materials. Colloidal tin oxide solution (SnO2, 15% in H2O) was purchased from Alfa Aesar. Methylamine (40% in methanol, ca. 9.8 mol/L) was purchased from TCI. Potassium iodide (anhydrous, 99%), lead(II) nitrate (ACS reagent, ≥99%), acetic acid (&gt;99%), formamidine acetate (99%), hydriodic acid (contains no stabilizer, distilled, 57 wt.% in H2O, 99.99% trace metals basis), hydrochloric acid (ACS reagent, 37%), N,N-dimethylformamide (anhydrous, 99.8%), dimethyl sulfoxide (anhydrous, ≥99.9%), chlorobenzene (anhydrous, 99.8%), diethyl ether (contains 1 ppm BHT as inhibitor, anhydrous, ≥99.7%) and 4-tert-butylpyridine (98%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Spiro-MeOTAD was purchased from Merck. PbI2 (95%) for powder synthesis was purchased from Kanto Chemical Co., Inc. Acetonitrile (HPLC) for the powder synthesis was purchased from DeaJung Chemicals. All the purchased chemicals were used as received without further purification. Synthesis of PbI2. Lead iodide (PbI2) was synthesized by reacting KI with Pb(NO3)2, where the aqueous</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1071</offset>
      <text>III-V Multijunction Cells (2-terminal, monolithic) LM = lattice matched MM = metamorphic IMM = inverted, metamorphic Two-, three-, and four-junction (concentrator) Three-junction or more (non-concentrator) Two-junction (non-concentrator) KI solution (23.2 g KI in deionized water (DI water)) and the aqueous Pb(NO 3)2 solution (33.1 g Pb(NO3)2 in DI water) were mixed with vigorous stirring at room temperature for 4 h, which was followed by adding acetic acid (20 mL) and additional DI water (2 L) and then heated at 90 °C for more than 24 h. The supernatant liquid was removed, and the precipitate was recrystallized by cooling down. The recrystallized golden crystals were filtered and rinsed with DI water several times. Finally, the product was dried at 85 °C in a vacuum oven for 24 h and then stored in Ar filled glove box. Synthesis of FAI and MACl. Formamidinium iodide (FAI, HC(NH2)2I) was synthesized by reacting 15 g of formamidinium acetate with 30 mL of hydroiodic acid in a round-bottomed flask in an ice bath for 2 h. Dark yellow precipitate was recovered by evaporating at 60 ºC for 1 h. Resulting product was dissolved in ethanol and recrystallized in diethyl ether, which was repeated for three times. methylammonium chloride (MACl, CH3NH3Cl) was synthesized using methylamine and hydrochloric acid in a similar way with FAI. The final white precipitates were dried at 50 °C in a vacuum oven for 24 h and then stored in Ar filled glove box. Synthesis of FAPbI3 powder. For FAPbI3 powder synthesis, 7.66 g of FAI was added into Erlenmeyer flask containing 150 mL acetonitrile (ACN) under vigorous stirring and then the synthesized PbI2 or low-grade (95% purity) commercial PbI2 (15.67 g) (PbI2:FAI = 1:1.3) was slowly added together with extra 50 mL ACN. The brown precipitate appeared after addition of PbI2. After vigorous stirring for 24 h, the powder turned gradually bright yellow. Then the powder was washed with ACN and diethyl ether for six times. The final product was dried in a vacuum oven for 24 h and then stored in Ar filled glove box. The yield was 93%. (Caution: in case of scale-up, rotary evaporator is recommended to dry the powder instead of using a vacuum oven.). The FAPbI3 powder is also commercially available from ShareChem Co., Ltd. Solar cell fabrication. F-doped tin oxide (FTO) coated conductive glasses (T18VU70, 12-13 Ω/sq, AGC Fabritech Co., Ltd.) were cleaned by detergent, followed by ultrasonic treatment in ethanol for 20 min. UV/ozone (UVO) treatment was conducted for 60 min prior to use. SnO 2 film was deposited on the FTO substrate by spin-coating the commercial SnO2 colloidal solution (diluted with DI water to adjust to 4 wt%) at 4000 rpm for 20 s, which was annealed at 185 °C on a hotplate for 30 min. The FAPbI3 perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing 663 mg of the synthesized FAPbI3 powder and 71 μL of DMSO (molar ratio 1:1) in 568 μL of DMF with different molar ratio (0 mol%, 10 mol%, 20 mol%, 30 mol% and 40 mol%) of MACl (optimal was 20 mol%). For the conventional precursor mixture solution, except for using the synthesized powder, PbI2 (Alfa Aesar, 99.9985%) and the synthesized FAI were dissolved. The solution was spin-coated at two consecutive steps of 1000 rpm for 5 and 5000 rpm 20 s. During the second spin-coating step, 1 mL of diethyl ether was quickly dripped on the rotating substrate (5000 rpm) at 17 s to obtain an adduct intermediate film. The adduct films were annealed at 150 °C on a hotplate for 10 min. The spiro-MeOTAD layer was formed on the perovskite layer by spin-coating of 20 μL of the stock solution comprising 50 mg spiro-MeOTAD in 0.55 mL chlorobenzene including 19.5 μL t-BP (tert-butylpyridine) and 11.5 μL Li-TFSI solution (540 mg Li-TFSI in 1 mL acetonitrile (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.8%)) at 3000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, Ag electrode with a thickness of ca. 150 nm was deposited on top of the spiro-MeOTAD layer under 4×10 -7 torr using a thermal evaporator. The as-fabricated PSCs were stored in the desiccator overnight before the current density-voltage (J-V) measurement. Characterizations. J-V curves were recorded using a Keithley 2400 source meter under the simulated one sun illumination (AM 1.5G, 100 mW/cm 2 ) using a solar simulator (Oriel Sol 3A class AAA) equipped with 450 W Xenon lamp (Newport 6280NS), in which light intensity was adjusted by NRELcalibrated Si solar cell with KG-2 filter. Solar cells were covered with a metal mask with an aperture area of 0.125 cm 2 during the measurement. External quantum efficiency (EQE) was measured by either an EQE system (PV measurement Inc.) equipped with a 75 W Xenon source lamp (USHIO, Japan) or a QuantX-300 Quantum Efficiency System (Newport) equipped with 100 W Xenon lamp. EQE data were collected at DC mode without bias light. The absorbance of the perovskite film was measured by UV-vis spectrometer (Lambda 45, Perkin-Elmer). Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) was measured using a fluorescence spectrometer (Quantaurus-Tau C11367-12, Hamamatsu). Perovskite films were photo-excited with a 464 nm laser pulsed at the frequency of 10 MHz. The PL was detected by high sensitivity photon counting near-IR detector. Timeresolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra were measured using a time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) system by FluoTim 200 (PicoQuant) with 500 kHz repetition rate. The perovskite films were excited by 375 nm laser source, and then the emitted PL from the samples was collected by a photon multiplier tube (PMT) detector (PMA 182, PicoQuant-GmbH) at 800 nm. X-ray diffraction (XRD) and grazing incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD) data were collected from a Rigaku SmartLab diffractometer, where Cu Kα radiation was used (λ = 1.5406 Å) and a scan rate was 4º/min with 0.02º/step. GIXRD were measured with the incident angle of 1º, 2º, 3º and 4º in the range of 5º -40º with 0.01º/step. The GIXRD penetration depth depending on incidence angles was calculated from eq 1, 1 τ1/e = sin θ/μ (1)  where τ1/e is the depth at which the intensity of radiation on a material is attenuated to 1/e (37%) and μ is the linear absorption coefficient, μ = μmρ (μm is the mass absorption coefficient and ρ is the mass density). ρ for cubic unit cell crystal structure could be calculated using eq 2, ρ = M/(a 3  NA) ( 2 ) where M is the molar mass of FAPbI3 (632.98 g/mol), NA is Avogadro's number (6.022  10 23 ), a is the edge length of unit cell (a = 6.35694 Å for cubic FAPbI3 determined from XRD analysis). The mass density ρ was calculated to be 4.092 g/cm  3  . According to the NIST standard reference database,  2  the μm of FAPbI3 is 246.9 cm 2 /g at 8000 eV photo energy. According to the eq 1, the penetration depth τ1/e of FAPbI3 under incidence angle of 1°, 2°, 3°, 4°and 5° are 172.7 nm, 345.4 nm, 518.0 nm, 690.5 nm and 862.7 nm, respectively. Light-intensity-dependent photocurrent mappings (PCM) were obtained using an atomic force microscope (AFM, NX10, Park System) equipped with a white LED light source (maximum power: 3.3 W), where light intensity was modulated from 0% (dark) to 20% (0.66 W), 40% (1.32 W), 60% (1.98 W) and 80% (2.64 W). The sub-mode of the PCM was Variable-Enhanced Conductive AFM (VECA) using the cantilever (SD-CDTP-NCHR) and 1 V DC bias voltage was applied to the substrate. The current images were obtained under the ambient condition. The depth profile of the perovskite film on FTO substrate was recorded using time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS, model TOF-SIMS 5 of ION-TOF, Germany) in negative polarity. The pulsed primary Bi + ion source was operated at 25 keV and pA scale on a 40 μm  40 μm area to bombard the sample surface to produce secondary ions. The sputtering was performed with a Cs + ion beam operated at 1 keV and 45 nA on a 150 μm  150 μm area. Defect density was estimated using hole-only devices with the structure of FTO/PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Au. The devices were measured from -0.1 V to 2 V in the dark. The observed response was analyzed according to space-charge-limited current (SCLC) theory. Defect density (Ndefects) was estimated using the relation VTFL = eNdefectsd 2 /2r0,  3  where VTFL is the trap-filled-limit voltage, e is electron charge (1.602  10 -19 C), r is relative dielectric constant, 0 is the vacuum permittivity (8.8542  10 -14 F/cm) and d is the perovskite film thickness. The dielectric constant was calculated using the equation of r = Cd/A0, where C is capacitance at high frequency (~10 4 Hz) and A is area.  4, 5  Raman spectra were collected in back-scattering geometry. The 514.5 nm (2.41 eV) line of an Ar ion laser was used as an excitation source. The laser beam was focused on the surface of the solution in a petri-dish by a 50× microscope objective lens (0.8 NA). The scattered light was collected and collimated by the same objective in the backscattering geometry. The scattered signal was dispersed by a Jobin-Yvon Horiba iHR550 spectrometer (2400 grooves/mm) and detected with a liquid-nitrogencooled back-illuminated charge-coupled-device (CCD) detector. To approach the low-frequency range below 100 cm -1 , volume holographic filters (Optigrate) were used to clean the laser line and reject the Rayleigh-scattered light. The laser power was kept below 100 μW in order to avoid local heating. Surface and cross-sectional morphologies were investigated by scanning electron microscope (SEM) (JSM-7600F, JEOL). Absorption spectra were measured using an UV/visible spectrometer (Lambda 45, Perkin Elmer). Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images and selected area electron diffraction (SAED) patterns of the cross-sectioned full cells were obtained using a high-resolution transmission electron microscope (JEOL JEM-2100F) at an acceleration voltage 200 kV. The specimens for TEM were prepared by vertical etching using focused ion beam (FIB) equipm ent (JEOL JIB-4601F) with the cell structure glass/FTO/SnO2/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD. Before preparing the specimens, Pt and carbon layers were deposited on the spiro-MeOTAD layer to protect the samples from milling damage. A thick plate was extracted from the bulk sample at 30 kV and 3,000~30,000 pA, which was welded on Cu grid (omniprobe grid) by using probing system. The thick plate was first thinned at 30 kV and 50~1,000 pA and then lower current of 10~30 pA. Finally, the specimen was completed by thinni ng at lower voltage of 1 kV and 30~50 pA after beam showering at 3 kV and 10~30 pA. MACl were added into the perovskite precursor solution to fabricate the perovskite film. From the XRD pattern in Figure  S2a , the peaks at 11.7 o correspond to δ-phase, where the 20 mol% MACl doped perovskite film shows almost no δ-phase. The appearance of δ-phase is indicative of degradation due to α → δ phase transition under humidity condition (fresh samples did not show δ-phase). Thus the suppression of δ-phase for the 20 mol% MACl doped perovskite film indicates that α-phase is relatively stable for this content. The (100) peak position at 13.92 o for α-phase FAPbI3 is not altered by the MACl content, which indicates that MA ion might not be involved in the crystal lattice. However, in Figure  S2b  and S2c of the UV-vis absorption and PL spectra, the PL peak and UV-vis absorption are shift to lower wavelength, indicative of a partial substitution of FA + with MA + in FAPbI3.  6  The optical bandgap of 0 mol%, 10 mol%, 20 mol%, 30 mol% and 40 mol% are 1.527 eV, 1.539 eV, 1.545 eV, 1.539 eV and 1.539 eV, respectively. PL peak is shift from 818 nm to 802 nm with MACl addition. However, it is noted that the EQE onset edge position is observed at about 840 nm regardless of MACl content (Figure  S2d ).  might be related to difference in composition along the film depth. Figure  S3a  shows the grazing incidence angle (ω)-dependent XRD patterns of the annealed FAPbI3 film formed from the synthesized powder with 20 mol% MACl, where the depth in perovskite film can be increased with ω as illustrated in Figure  S3b .  7  The penetration depth τ1/e of FAPbI3 under incidence angle of 1°, 2°, 3°, 4°and 5° are 172.7 nm, 345.3 nm, 517.9 nm, 690.2 nm and 862.4 nm, respectively. As shown in Figure  S3a  and S3b, the (100) peak is deconvoluted into two peaks at 13.86° (red color) and at ~14.0° (blue color). The detailed parameters are summarized in the Table  S1 . The red peak corresponds to FAPbI3 but the blue peak might be related to incorporation of smaller MA in the larger FA site. The peak position at 13.86° is unchanged with increasing ω, however, another peak (blue color) shifts from 14.10° to 14.02°. In addition, the peak area ratio of red to blue is increased from 0.88 to 1.18 as the incidence angle is increased from 1° to 5°. This indicates that the underlying MA-incorporated phase is probably located on the surface of the film rather than on the bottom of the film. The full width at half maximum (FWHM) is decreased with increasing ω, which underlines that the FAPbI3 perovskite grain size is increased going from top surface to the bulk film. From the PL measurement illuminated on different side in Figure  S3c , no change in PL emission peak position is observed regardless of illumination side for the FAPbI3 film without MACl (Figure  S3d ). On the other hands, a slight change in PL peak position is observed for the 20 mol% MACl case, where the glass side illumination results in PL emission at a slightly longer wavelength, which is indicative of difference in composition between top and bottom of the film. According to GIXRD and illumination-side-dependent PL, MACl assists to increase grain size of FAPbI3 and exists near the surface of FAPbI3 rather than incorporation into bulk FAPbI3, which can explain the reason why the onset wavelength in EQE together with the (100) peak position in XRD were unchanged with MACl. We also measured time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectroscopy (TOF-SIMS) to investigate the position of residual Cl inside the film. As shown in Figure  S4 , due to MA cation located near perovskite surface, the Cl content decreases going from the to p to the bottom in the perovskite layer. However, the Cl content sharply increases when approaching the SnO2 layer, which indicates that most of Cl is located near SnO2 layer and this location of Cl was reported to improve stability. 8        H ybrid organic-inorganic all-solid-state perovskite solar cells (PSCs) are currently attracting increasing interest because of their low cost and high performance. A surge of recent research activity in PSCs has been triggered by the first report of a solid-state PSC with a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 9.7% and a 500 h stability without encapsulation,  1  following two seed reports on perovskite-sensitized solar cells.  2, 3  Rapid progress in PCE has been made, and most of the PCEs over 20% are based on mixed-cation and mixed-anion perovskites comprising formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) as a major component.  [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9]  By far, the certified record PCE of 25.2% 10 surpasses PCEs of copper-indium-gallium-selenide (CIGS) and CdTe solar cells. Because the Shockley-Queisser (S-Q) limit efficiency is over 30% based on the bandgap energy of 1.6 eV,  11  further improvement in PCE is expected. FAPbI 3 is currently one of the most promising perovskite materials for high-efficiency solar cells owing to its optimal bandgap of 1.47 eV, high absorption coefficient exceeding 10 4 cm -1 , and a carrier diffusion length of a few hundred micrometers.  12, 13  However, the photoactive "black phase" (αphase) is less stable under ambient conditions because its photoinactive "yellow phase" (δ-phase) is more favorable.  14  A partial substitution of FA + with MA + or Cs + was reported to be an efficient way to stabilize the α-phase of FAPbI 3 at ambient conditions,  8, [15] [16] [17] [18]  which however leads to increasing the bandgap energy and thereby narrowing the absorption spectrum. Nonreproducibility in photovoltaic performance in PSCs has been often reported, which might stem from the precursor preparation and film formation procedure when using PbI 2 (usually high purity ∼99.99%).  5, 7, 17, 19, 20  This conventional "precursor mixture" method is likely to cause the fractional deviations in stoichiometry because of impurity and/or nonperovskite phase, leading to low reproducibility.  21  In addition, using the expensive PbI 2 is not a cost-effective way to scale up PSCs. Thus, a cost-effective approach is also required to guarantee the reproducibility of high-efficiency PSCs. The perovskite powder approach is more beneficial for reproducibility of photovoltaic performance of PSCs than the precursor mixture method because the underlying nonstoichiometry of the resulting perovskite film can be avoided. Perovskite powders were reported to be synthesized by either mechanochemistry or wet chemistry methods.  19, [22] [23] [24] [25] [26]  The mechanochemically prepared MAPbI 3 powder was used as a precursor for the coating solution, which resulted in a PCE of 17.5%, which was better than the PCE obtained from the precursor mixture of MAI and PbI 2 .  22  The grinded or ballmilled powder of perovskite with mixed cation and/or mixed anion showed a PCE of about 19%.  23  Perovskite powders were synthesized by wet chemistry based on antisolvents  24  or lowsolubility solvents such as 2-proponal,  25  acetonitrile,  26  or 2methoxyethanol.  19  Among the reported PCEs based on the synthesized FAPbI 3 crystal or powder,  5, 8, 19, 27  powder-based PSCs achieved a certified PCE of around 23%.  5, 19  However, these perovskite powders were synthesized using a costineffective high-purity PbI 2 and production yield was low. In our previous report,  26  we first attempted to synthesize highyield MAPbI 3 and FAPbI 3 powders in acetonitrile using lowgrade PbI 2 at room temperature. We obtained α, δ, and α/δ mixed-phase FAPbI 3 powders by controlling the ratio of PbI 2 to FAI. However, the average PCE of FAPbI 3 PSCs was still as low as 17.21% because of the phase purity issue. Thus, an advanced method is required to synthesize pure δ-phase FAPbI 3 powder for higher PCE reproducibly, which has been successfully performed via a synthetic procedure including a washing process. Here we report the materials and methods for reproducible high-efficiency PSCs based on the room-temperature-synthesized FAPbI 3 powder using homemade or inexpensive lowgrade PbI 2 . The average PCE of 20.71% is achieved from the 130 devices based on the synthetic powder-based FAPbI 3 films fabricated in different batches, and the quasi-steady-state PCE of 21.07% is certified. The photovoltaic performance and reproducibility of the powder-based devices are compared with those of the expensive high-grade PbI 2 (99.9985%) based the precursor mixture-based conventional method, from which the former is confirmed to be much superior to the latter. Synthesis and Properties of FAPbI 3 Powder. Because the quality of PbI 2 varies from different batches and the high-purity (99.9985%) PbI 2 is still cost-ineffective,  26  the cost-effective materials leading to reproducible high efficiency are highly required for commercialization. Figure  1a  shows a schematic procedure of synthesizing FAPbI 3 powder at room temper-  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20519</offset>
      <text> ACS Energy Letters Letter ature, where the quality of FAPbI 3 powder is found to be independent of the PbI 2 purity. As compared to our previous report,  26  we have synthesized FAPbI 3 using homemade PbI 2 and improved purity of FAPbI 3 powder by modifying the synthetic procedure (see Experimental Section in the Supporting Information for more details). To further reduce the material cost, PbI 2 is synthesized by reacting potassium iodide (KI) with lead(II) nitrate (Pb(NO 3 ) 2 ) and recrystallization. Chemical reaction of the synthesized PbI 2 with FAI produces the yellow FAPbI 3 powder with yield ∼93%. From the X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images, the synthesized PbI 2 shows a pure hexagonal system with space group of P3m1, along with hexagonal plate morphology (Figure  1b, d ). The synthesized yellow FAPbI 3 powder is determined to be hexagonal system with P6 3 mc space group (Figure  1c ), corresponding to the δphase, and an asymmetric rod-type morphology is observed (Figure  1e ). Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) in Figure  S1a  shows that the synthesized FAPbI 3 powder loses FAI at 304-363 °C. On the other hand, FAI starts to be evaporated at the lower temperature of 234 °C for the conventional precursor mixture (FAI and PbI 2 mixed), which is attributed to the decomposition of the unreacted free FAI to FA, followed by a weight loss corresponding to loss of HI molecules.  28  In addition, a single endothermic peak appears at 178 °C for the synthesized FAPbI 3 in differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), whereas two endothermic peaks along with multiple exothermic peaks are detected for the precursor mixture (Figure  S1b ). The complex DSC profile for the precursor mixture is due to the large specific surface area induced by nonstoichiometric reaction to form δ and α phases.  29  TGA and DSC studies reveal the thermodynamic phase purity of the synthesized FAPbI 3 . The yellow powder shows high stability at ambient temperature, which is beneficial for long-term storage and commercialization. Single Powder versus Conventional Precursor Mixture. When preparing the coating solution, methylammonium chloride (MACl) is added for the purpose of enhancing the crystallinity and grain size of the perovskite.  27, 30  The 20 mol % MACl is optimal concentration, which is determined from the results of the dependence of photovoltaic performance on the MACl concentration (Figures  S2-S4  and Table  S1 ). It is noted in terms of the role of the additive MACl that MACl contributes to increasing the crystallinity and exists near the surface of FAPbI 3 rather than incorporation into FAPbI 3 . It is observed from the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra that the onset wavelength of about 840 nm is not changed even after addition of MACl. The FAPbI 3 film characteristics and its photovoltaic performance are compared between the synthesized powder-based coating solution and the conventional precursor mixture-based one (PbI 2 with purity of 99.9985% is used for the precursor mixture method). The XRD pattern reveals that the powder-based solution produces a pure αphase FAPbI 3 film but the δ-phase FAPbI 3 at 11.4°and the unreacted PbI 2 coexist in the precursor mixture-based film (Figure  2a ). The absorption coefficient, obtained from UV-vis  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23864</offset>
      <text> ACS Energy Letters Letter spectra, is compared in Figure  2b . The sharp shoulder without a tail near the optical bandgap (1.55 eV) region is observed for the powder precursor case, while an additional absorption tail (called the Urbach tail) appears after the bandgap for the conventional precursor case. Absence of an Urbach tail for the powder-based FAPbI 3 film is indicative of no deep trap states, whereas a distinct Urbach tail for the conventional precursor mixture-based FAPbI 3 film underlines the presence of deep trap states.  31, 32  Little difference in Raman spectra (Figure  S5 ) is found, which indicates that the main chemical species in the solution are the same. In the Raman spectra for films, the powder-based FAPbI 3 shows the main peak position of 235 cm -1 , while a redshift to 226 cm -1 for the precursor mixturebased perovskite film is attributed to the small amount of δphase FAPbI 3 .  14, 33  Panels c and d of Figure  2  show steady-state photoluminescence (PL) and time-resolved PL (TRPL), where TRPL fitting results are obtained using a biexponential decay equation,  34, 35  and average lifetime (τ ave ) is estimated using a time constant and weight factor (Table  S2 ).  36  The steady-state PL intensity of the powder method is markedly higher than that of the conventional one. τ ave is also significantly enhanced from 142 to 306 ns, which implies that the FAPbI 3 film fabricated from the single powder-based solution has many fewer defects than the one using the conventional precursor mixture. We further measure the photocurrent mapping of the films formed on the FTO substrate using photocurrent atomic force microscopy (AFM),  37  where white light with different intensity (0%-80%) is illuminated on the film under bias voltage of 1 V (Figure  3 ). The two perovskite films show a similar morphology but a large difference in the surface photocurrent (Figure  3a, b ). Contrary to a large inhomogeneity in the surface photocurrent of the precursor mixture-based film, a highly homogeneous photocurrent is detected from the powder-based FAPbI 3 film. In Figure  3c , the average photocurrent of the perovskite film based on the powdered FAPbI 3 is higher than that of the one based on the conventional precursor in the dark conditions (0% light intensity). As LED light intensity increases from 20% to 80% of the maximum power, the powder-based FAPbI 3 film shows uniform current output at the given light intensity, while a large variation in current response is observed for the conventional precursor mixturebased one. Besides, the extent of increase in surface photocurrent with light intensity is lower for the powder case than for the precursor mixture one. Because the inhomogeneity of photocurrent is related to different crystal facets and the density of trap states,  37  uniform and steady increase in photocurrent for the powder case underlines that homogeneous crystal facets with controlled trap states are arranged on the surface of the powder-based perovskite film. The homogeneous surface current is attributed to phase stability and low FA defect of the powder-based FAPbI 3 film as confirmed by the transmission electron microscopy (TEM) analysis in Figure  S6 . It is noted from the TEM studies that the synthesized powder-based FAPbI 3 film in the device contains cubic perovskite α-phases without any sign of degradation and no trace amount of PbI 2 , while the precursor mixture-based one is already shown to be in the middle of degradation without observing the α-FAPbI 3 phase at all during e-beam irradiation of TEM measurements. Photovoltaic Performance and Reproducibility. Photovoltaic performance is investigated using a device structure of glass/ FTO/SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Ag (Figure  S7 ). No significant difference in the perovskite film morphology is observed by the cross-sectional SEM, while photovoltaic performance of the device based on the powder method is significantly higher than that of the one based on the precursor mixture method. Figure  4a  shows the reverse-scanned (RS)  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27947</offset>
      <text> ACS Energy Letters Letter and forward-scanned (FS) J-V curves measured under simulated one sun illumination (photovoltaic parameters are listed in Table  S3 ), where the powder-based FAPbI 3 exhibits higher V oc and FF. For the powder method, the RS PCE is 21.72% with J sc of 24.15 mA/cm 2 , V oc of 1.114 V, and FF of 0.808, while the precursor mixture method shows the RS PCE of 17.87% with J sc of 23.48 mA/cm 2 , V oc of 1.052 V, and FF of 0.723. The integrated J sc from EQE shows 24.44 and 23.71 mA/cm 2 for the powder method and the conventional precursor mixture one, respectively, which is well consistent with the measured J sc values (Figure  4b ). Light-dependent J sc and V oc are plotted in Figure  4c ,d to investigate recombination in device.  38  The slope in J sc versus light intensity (Figure  4c ) is calculated to be 1.00 and 1.03 for the powder and the precursor mixture cases, respectively, suggesting good dissociation probabilities at short-circuit conditions, indicative of negligible bimolecular recombination in the devices.  39  Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) recombination is related to the slope of the light-dependent V oc ,  40  where SRH recombination becomes lower as the slope is close to unity. The powder-based device is estimated to be 1.48 kT/q, which is much lower than the 2.25 kT/q for the precursor mixture-based one (k is the Boltzmann constant, T the temperature, and q the electric charge). The results indicate that the powder-based device exhibits better junction and interfaces because of the highquality FAPbI 3 film with lower trap-assisted nonradiative recombination. The defect density of the powder-based perovskite film is estimated to be 0.84 × 10 16 cm -3 , which is 22% lower than that of the precursor mixture-based film (1.08 × 10 16 cm -3 ) as measured by the space charge limited current (SCLC) method (Figure  S8  and Table  S4 ). Little dependency of J-V hysteresis on the scan rate is observed for the powderbased device as compared with the precursor mixture-based one (Figure  4e ,f), which is attributed to fewer defects in the powder-based FAPbI 3 film.  41, 42  Photovoltaic parameters on scan rate-dependent data are summarized in Tables  S5  and S6 . To check the reproducibility of the powder precursor, 130 devices are fabricated in different batches. As shown in Figure  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30293</offset>
      <text> ACS Energy Letters Letter 4g, the average PCE of 20.71% is obtained from the reversescanned PCE of 21.30% (J sc = 23.71 mA/cm 2 , V oc = 1.12 V, and FF = 0.803) and the forward-scanned PCE of 20.11% (J sc = 23.70 mA/cm 2 , V oc = 1.09 V, and FF = 0.777). The certified quasi-steady-state PCE from the Newport PV Laboratory as a proxy for National Renewable Energy Laboratory is 21.07% (Figure  S9 ). Because the stability of the device is also an important issue, the stability is roughly estimated by measuring J-V of the devices stored in the dark with the relative humidity of about 20%. As shown in Figure  S10 , the PCE of the device retains 80% of the original PCE after 30 days. To compare the devices' operation stability under illumination, output PCEs are measured at maximum power point tracking under continuous one sun illumination (AM 1.5G, 100 mW/cm 2 ) in ambient conditions (30% humidity) without any encapsulation for over 60 min. As shown in Figure  S11 , the PCE of the precursor mixture-based device decreases from 17.23% to 10.21% within 67 min, while the powder-based device retains over 92% of the initial PCE (PCE from 21.48% to 19.92%) after 100 min of illumination. This proves that the powder approach is better in stability than the precursor mixture method. For comparison, we also prepared PSC from the FAPbI 3 powder synthesized using the commercial PbI 2 with 95% purity. As shown in Figure  S12 , the FAPbI 3 powder synthesized using the low-grade PbI 2 results in PCEs of 21.96% and 20.54% for reverse and forward scan, respectively. This result indicates that the quality of the synthesized FAPbI 3 is independent of the purity of PbI 2 . We have explored materials for reproducible high-efficiency PSCs. The room-temperature-synthesized FAPbI 3 with δ-phase was found to be superior to the conventional precursor mixture in terms of PCE, reproducibility, cost-effectiveness, and underlying scalability. The reproducibility of photovoltaic performance for the PSCs fabricated based on the synthesized FAPbI 3 powder was attributed to composition stoichiometry and low defects in the resulting perovskite films. Average and certified PCEs of about 21% were obtained from the PSCs using the synthesized FAPbI 3 powder. Because FAPbI 3 was synthesized at room temperature and the synthesized powder was stable, the "powder method" is strongly believed to be a highly efficient approach toward the reproducible highefficiency and scalable PSCs and modules. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32784</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32808</offset>
      <text> * S Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.9b02348 . Experimental details of powder synthesis, solar cell fabrication, and characterizations (J-V, EQE, TRPL, XRD, GIXRD, PCM, Raman, SEM, and TEM); additional figures of the optimizing condition details, Raman spectra, TEM with FFT patterns, cross-sectional SEM, certificated report, and device stability data; additional tables of GIXRD parameters, TRPL parameters, and scan rate dependency of photovoltaic parameters (PDF) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33373</offset>
      <text> ■ AUTHOR INFORMATION Corresponding Author *E-mail: npark@skku.edu. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33443</offset>
      <text> ORCID Hyunjung Shin: 0000-0003-1284-9098 Hyeonsik Cheong: 0000-0002-2347-4044 Nam-Gyu Park: 0000-0003-2368-6300 Notes Figure S1 .Figure S2 . S1S2 Figure S1. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) and differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) obtained at heating rate of 10 °C/min under N2 atmosphere. (a) TGA along with DTA and (b) DSC for the conventional PbI2 and FAI precursor mixture and the synthesized FAPbI3 powder. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33860</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. (a) grazing incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD) of the perovskite film measured with different incidence angle from 1° to 5°. (b) Schematic representation of the GIXRD geometry. ω is an incidence angle, where the detected depth is deeper if ω is larger. (c) Schematic representation showing laser incident on the perovskite (PSK) side and the glass side. The excitation wavelength was 464 nm. (d) Steady-state PL of the perovskite films based on the annealed FAPbI3 formed from the synthesized FAPbI3 powder without and with 20 mol% MACl. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34430</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 . S4 Figure S4. Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectroscopy (TOF-SIMS) profiles of the perovskite film based on the synthesized FAPbI3 powder with 20 mol% MACl. Depth profiling was performed from the perovskite layer to the FTO substrate in negative polarity. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34704</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 . S5 Figure S5. Raman spectra of solutions and films based on the conventional precursor mixture and the synthesized FAPbI3 powder. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34847</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 . S6 Figure S6. Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images of cross-section of the device based on powder precursor and conventional precursor. (a) Cross-sectional TEM bright field image (Top left) with a selected area electron diffraction (SAED) pattern (Top right) showing clear refraction spots corresponding to PbI2 in yellow circles of FAPbI3 prepared by conventional solution spin coating method. Series high resolution TEM images (bottom three) showed unidentified pores in the films moving progressively during observation in the microscope. (b) Cross-sectional TEM bright field image (Top left) with a SAED pattern (Top right) showing cubic -phase diffraction spots in red circles along with not-allowed spots in blue circles (Top right) of a FAPbI3 film prepared by powder precursor method. High resolution TEM lattice image (bottom left) with corresponding Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) pattern (bottom right). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35785</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 . S7 Figure S7. Cross-section image of PSCs with the FAPbI3 perovskite layer formed from (a) the conventional precursor mixture and (b) the synthesized powder. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35956</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. Dark current-voltage of the hole-only devices with the structure of FTO/PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Au based on (a) precursor mixture and (b) single powder. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36146</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 . S9 Figure S9. Certificated results from the Newport as a proxy for National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). (a) The certificate of the perovskite solar cell based on the synthesized FAPbI3 powder. The photovoltaic parameters are summarized in the table on the certificate with the PCE of 21.07%. The area of aperture mask is 0.1234 cm 2 . The device was measured without encapsulation. (b) The certificate I-V curve with Voc of 1.122 V, Jsc of 25.18 mA/cm 2 , FF of 74.61% and PCE of 21.07% obtained by the quasi-steady-state measurement to show the stable and reliable performance. (c) Normalized EQE measured under a white light bias. The EQE was measured to verify linearity of operation and determine spectral correction factor. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36896</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 .Figure S11 . S10S11 Figure S10. (a-d) Normalized photovoltaic parameters as a function of time to determine that stability of PSCs based on the synthesized FAPbI3 powder. The initial PCE of the device was 20.95% with Jsc of 23.89 mA/cm 2 , Voc of 1.11 V, FF of 0.79. The devices were stored in the desiccator in the dark under the relative humidity of 10% -20%. The relative humidity of the J-V measurement condition was around 20%-50%. The device performance was recorded using the reverse scan at scan rate of 130 mV/s. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37431</offset>
      <text> Figure S12 . S12 Figure S12. Reverse and forward scanned J-V curves of PSC based on the FAPbI3 powder synthesized using a commercial low-grade (95%) PbI2. The scan rate was 130 mV/s. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37615</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Synthetic procedure and characteristics of FAPbI 3 powder. (a) FAPbI 3 powder synthesis: (I) FAI is dissolved in acetonitrile (ACN) (solution color: transparent). (II) PbI 2 is slowly added into the solution, and extra ACN is added (orange). (III) Stirring of the solution starts (dark brown). (IV) The solution turns bright yellow after stirring for over 24 h. (V) Yellow powder was collected by washing and drying. (b and c) X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns and (d and e) scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images of the synthesized PbI 2 and FAPbI 3 powders. Inserts in the XRD patterns are the photographs of the synthesized powders. The scale bars in the SEM images are 10 μm. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38322</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Properties of perovskite films fabricated from single powder and precursor mixture. (a) X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns, (b) absorption coefficient, (c) steady-state photoluminescence, and (d) time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) for perovskite films prepared using the synthesized single powder and the conventional precursor mixture (FAI + PbI 2 ). MACl (20 mol %) was included in each coating solution. For the XRD, the perovskite film was prepared on an FTO/SnO 2 substrate. The 10× magnified XRD patterns at low angle are shown as insets. SEM images of the corresponding perovskite films are also shown as insets. The excitation wavelength for the steady-state PL and TRPL measurement was 464 and 375 nm, respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39074</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Light-intensity-dependent surface photocurrent of perovskite films: powder vs precursor mixture. Different light intensity photocurrent mapping of the perovskite films based on (a) the conventional precursor mixture and (b) the synthesized single powder. (c) Light-intensity-dependent average photocurrent extracted from the photocurrent mapping. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39445</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Photovoltaic performance and statistical data. (a) Current density-voltage (J-V) curves. (b) Corresponding EQE along with the integrated current density. Light intensity dependence of (c) J sc and (d) V oc . (e, and f) Scan-rate-dependent J-V curves. (g) Statistical J sc , V oc , FF, and PCE of the powder-based PSCs obtained from 130 devices from different batches. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39837</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 The summary of the fitted XRD peak under different incidence angle. Incidence angle (°) Peak position (°) Peak Height (a.u.) Integrated area (a.u.) FWHM (°) 5 14.02 13.86 6792.30 5535.42 1220.08 1031.59 0.17 0.18 4 14.04 13.86 5647.32 4757.40 1124.44 1016.00 0.19 0.20 3 14.05 13.86 4457.54 4047.02 941.36 991.25 0.20 0.23 2 14.08 13.86 3446.87 3201.81 785.78 862.88 0.21 0.25 1 14.10 13.86 2303.72 2196.20 581.59 664.40 0.24 0.28 films y0 x0 A1 τ1 (ns) A2 τ2 (ns) τave (ns) Precursor mixture 4.13 20.70 777.30 8.75 569.90 152.52 142.09 powder 7.60 20.64 595.08 17.89 723.59 319.47 306.20 Table S2 . TRPL fitting results obtained using bi-exponential decay equation y = y0 +A1exp(-(x-x0)/τ1) + A2exp(-(x-x0)/τ2), in which τ1 is time constant for fast decay component and τ2 is time constant for slow decay component. Average lifetime was estimated from τave = (A1τ1 2 + A2τ2 2 )/(A1τ1+ A2τ2). The excitation wavelength is 375 nm. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40797</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 Photovoltaic parameter of PSCs based on the synthesized powder and the precursor mixture with the structure of glass/FTO/SnO2/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Ag under AM 1.5G one sun illumination (100 mW/cm 2 ) at scan rate of 130 mV/s. Device Scan direction Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) Voc (V) FF PCE(%) Powder reverse scan forward scan 24.148 24.113 1.1139 1.0896 0.8076 0.7806 21.72 20.51 Precursor mixture reverse scan forward scan 23.479 23.584 1.0522 1.0107 0.7234 0.6774 17.87 16.15 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41281</offset>
      <text> Table S4 . S4 Capacitance (C), area (A), thickness (d), trap-filled-limit voltage (VTFL), relative dielectric constant (ε), defect density (Ndefect) of perovskite films based on the synthesized powder and the precursor mixture. Devices C (F) A (cm 2 ) d (nm) VTFL (V) r Ndefects (cm -3 ) powder 1.34  10 -8 0.2034 627.0 0.64 46.7 0.84  10 16 precursor mixture 1.36  10 -8 0.1985 604.6 0.76 46.8 1.08 10 16 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41704</offset>
      <text> Table S5 . S5 Scan rate dependent photovoltaic parameter of PSCs based on the precursor mixture with the structure of glass/FTO/SnO2/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Ag. Scan rate Direction a Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) Voc (V) FF PCE(%) 1300 mV/s RS FS 23.974 23.986 1.0259 1.0043 0.7438 0.7377 18.29 17.77 650 mV/s RS FS 23.847 23.884 1.0227 1.0037 0.7398 0.7335 18.04 17.58 130 mV/s RS FS 23.635 23.731 1.0269 1.0048 0.7331 0.7139 17.79 17.02 65 mV/s RS FS 23.478 23.627 1.0251 1.0007 0.7289 0.6922 17.54 16.37 26 mV/s RS FS 23.206 23.590 1.0279 1.0120 0.7249 0.6510 17.29 15.54 13 mV/s RS FS 22.910 23.365 1.0271 1.0130 0.7240 0.6456 17.04 15.28 6.5 mV/s RS FS 22.478 23.022 1.0297 1.0213 0.7208 0.6466 16.68 15.20 a Scan direction, RS represent reverse scan and FS represent forward scan. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42477</offset>
      <text> Table S6 . S6 Scan rate dependent photovoltaic parameter of PSCs based on the synthesized powder with the structure of glass/FTO/SnO2/perovskite/spiro-MeOTAD/Ag. Scan rate Direction a Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) Voc (V) FF PCE(%) 1300 mV/s RS FS 23.963 23.969 1.0954 1.0759 0.8301 0.7942 21.79 20.48 650 mV/s RS FS 24.075 24.085 1.0981 1.6960 0.8158 0.7887 21.57 20.32 130 mV/s RS FS 23.985 24.030 1.1047 1.0707 0.8120 0.7872 21.51 20.25 65 mV/s RS FS 24.016 24.002 1.1075 1.0712 0.8040 0.7813 21.39 20.09 26 mV/s RS FS 23.989 23.902 1.1083 1.0674 0.7945 0.7723 21.12 19.70 13 mV/s RS FS 23.929 23.902 1.1082 1.0671 0.7832 0.7471 20.77 19.05 6.5 mV/s RS FS 23.852 23.888 1.1088 1.0589 0.7688 0.7281 20.33 18.42 a Scan direction, RS represent reverse scan and FS represent forward scan. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43251</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:47:18 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles.</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
