<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001229312HGDAAD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 33</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>Surface Defect Formation and Passivation in Formamidinium Lead Triiodide (FAPbI 3 ) Perovskite Solar Cell Absorbers</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>126</offset>
      <text>Defect formation energies (DFEs) in Pb-rich, I-rich, and moderate growth conditions On the PbI 2 terminated surface, only FA i has low formation energy under Pb-rich conditions while I i , FA Pb , and FA i defects have low formation energy under I-rich conditions. Under moderate conditions, the formation energy of V Pb , I Pb , I i , and FA Pb defects is lower than 1 eV. On the other hand, FAI terminated surface is very stable against defect formation under all growth conditions. Only I i defect has low formation energy under moderate conditions. Lastly, PbI terminated surface is vulnerable against various types of defect formations under all conditions. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>789</offset>
      <text> Calculated formation energies as a function of E F under different growth conditions On the PbI 2 surface in Fig.  S2 , FA I , Pb i , and FA i have low formation energy around the p-type region while FA Pb and I i become dominant around the n-type region under Pb-rich conditions. Under I-rich conditions, I Pb is dominant along the bandgap. I i and FA Pb are dominant in the n-type region while FA I , Pb i , and FA i become dominant in the p-type region. These trends are the same under moderate conditions for PbI 2 surface. To sum up, intrinsic donor defects (FA I , Pb i , and FA i ) are dominant in the p-type region while intrinsic acceptor defects (I i ,I Pb, and FA Pb ) are effective in the n-type region. Similar assessments can also be performed for PbI, FAI, and I terminated surfaces in    </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1594</offset>
      <text> Effect of molecule additives on DOS of PbI 2 terminated surface with deep defects The effect of additive molecules on the DOS of FA i , Pb i , FA Pb , and I Pb defects on PbI 2 terminated surface can be respectively seen in Fig. S (6-9). The black dashed lines represent DOS of the only defective surface while blue solid lines are DOS of the surface and passivating agent. The insets show the final structure of the surface and molecule after geometry optimization.     </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2066</offset>
      <text> Molecule additive and defect interaction energies: The interaction energy between the surface defect and molecule additive is calculated from , where is the energy of the defective surface with the ∆𝐸 𝑖𝑛𝑡 (𝑒𝑉) = 𝐸 𝑑+𝑚 -(𝐸 𝑑 + 𝐸 𝑚 ) 𝐸 𝑑+𝑚 molecule additive, is the energy of the defective surface and is the energy of the 𝐸 𝑑 𝐸 𝑚 molecule in the gas-phase. The results are shown in Table  S1 . Here, we only considered interactions between the donor(acceptor) defect and acceptor(donor) molecule, or neutral molecule and donor/acceptor defect.  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2673</offset>
      <text> Chemical Potential Calculations The chemical potentials of Pb, I, and FA are calculated from , where is the µ = µ 0 + ∆µ µ 0 "intrinsic" chemical potential, calculated from the stable cell energy of the material, and ∆µ is the "external" chemical potential of the material depending on the environmental (growth) conditions. The allowed external chemical potential values of Pb, I, and FA for the FAPbI 3 formation in the thermal equilibrium condition are calculated by following the work of Yin et al. [1]. Here, the following set of equations are needed to be satisfied; (S.  , fcc phase of Pb, bcc phase FA, and tetragonal phase of I 2 is considered in the formation energy and internal chemical potential calculations. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3406</offset>
      <text> Energy Corrections Freysoldt-Neugebauer-van de Walle (FNV) type correction scheme is considered for the finite-size corrections [2,3], in which lattice correction and potential alignment term 𝐸 is the potential 𝐸 𝑞 𝑝𝑒𝑟,𝑚 ∆𝑉 alignment of the charged defect relative to the model periodic lattice potential far from the defect [2,3]. A static dielectric constant value of 7.5, obtained from the DFT-based optical spectrum calculations, was considered in lattice energy calculations. We observed that due to only relatively small deformations in the supercells for different types of defects, 𝐸 𝑞 𝑙𝑎𝑡𝑡 correction only differs by the charge state for varying defects. Therefore, we considered the same value for the same q charge state for all lattice correction calculations. The 𝐸 𝑞 𝑙𝑎𝑡𝑡 lattice energy correction terms are predicted using Coffee software [4]. Given the computational complexity of the potential alignment calculations in slab systems and excessive number of surfaces/defects (27 surfaces in total) we considered, we found that it is more appropriate to use a typical value of for the potential alignment. The article is well presented with a clear description of the methods employed in the calculations. The conclusions derived from the results are significant and can provide additional information to improve the stability and efficiency of the solar devices prepared with this material. However, I consider that the novelty of the article is not enough to be published in JPC Letters. Other similar studies have been previously published in other journals (Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 2018,20, 6800-6804) which decrease their suitability for JPC Letters. I recommend to publish this article in a sister journal as JPC C in its current form. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5227</offset>
      <text> Reviewer: 2 Comments to the Author In this study, the authors investigated the defect formation in FAPbI3 surface by the first-principles calculations. And calculated the surface energies of FAPbI3 to determine the stability of different types of surface terminations. The formation energies of 12 native point defect types which could form on a certain surface are then calculated. A strong correlation between the surface energy and defect formation energy is found amongst different surface types. The charge transition levels of the defects and corresponding formation energies are concurrently discussed to identify harmful defects. The authors finally proposed several healing scenarios for those harmful defects via the introduction of passivating molecule additives to the FAPbI3 surfaces. But still have problem below： 1. In Figure  3 , the authors presented the formation energy of defects with respect to the Fermi level，What is the benchmark for determining the stability of defects? How much higher than the defect formation in Figure  3  is considered unstable? A reasonable explanation of the relationship between Fermi energy levels and defect formation energy? And the logical relationship between the effect of Fermi energy levels on defect formation energy throughout the article? </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6532</offset>
      <text> 2. Pbi and FAi are donor defects，why use anions to passivate rather than cations？ </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6619</offset>
      <text> 3. The calculation result shows that the surface energy of FAI-termination is about 1.5eV/nm2, and the surface energy of I-termination is about 5.8eV/nm2, according to this, why can it be obtained that FAI-termination is found to be 3 times stable when compared to I-termination? on Page 3, Line 2-3. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6921</offset>
      <text> 4. For Formula 1 and Formula 2, why the surface area selected for the cleavage energy (unrelaxed) is not consistent with the surface area selected for the cleavage energy (relaxed)? The former is A and the latter is 2A. In addition, if these two formulas refer to other author's paper, the source should be noted. If the authors derive it by themselves, the authors should briefly explain the derivation process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7335</offset>
      <text> 5. In Figure  S6 , we can see that acetic acid seems to have a pretty good passivation effect on FAI defects. In addition, the authors have prepared ten kinds of additives, the workload is relatively sufficient, but why in S6 and S7, there are only four kinds of additives. Finally, we hope to see more analysis of the mechanism of additive passivation of defects, there are few explanations about the passivation mechanism in the article. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7776</offset>
      <text> Author's Response to Peer Review Comments: Reviewer #1: Oner et al. report a comprehensive theoretical characterization of the termination surfaces of the FAPbI3 perovskite together with all possible defect formation. The article is well presented with a clear description of the methods employed in the calculations. The conclusions derived from the results are significant and can provide additional information to improve the stability and efficiency of the solar devices prepared with this material. However, I consider that the novelty of the article is not enough to be published in JPC Letters. Other similar studies have been previously published in other journals (Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 2018,20, 6800-6804) which decrease their suitability for JPC Letters. I recommend to publish this article in a sister journal as JPC C in its current form. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8632</offset>
      <text> Response: We appreciate the reviewer's suggestion. The paper provided by the reviewer is included in our reference list (ref. 27). The reference focuses on only defect formation in 12 point defects in bulk FAPbI3, while, in our manuscript, we reveal the defect formation on the FAPbI3 surface. We agree that "bulk" defect studies have currently been a standard calculation. However our study significantly differs; While many studies have focused on the bulk properties of perovskites, thin film surfaces, grain boundaries and interfaces can cause significant charge-loss and device instabilities [J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 7, 4764-4794, 2016]. Studies have shown that surface trap density is two orders of magnitude larger in surfaces then in bulk. Therefore, if they are not properly understood and managed, they can be the major source of performance loss [Nat. Energy, 2, 16207, 2017]. Moreover, DFE and transition levels can differ in bulk and surface. Even if the Ii defect has similar formation energy of 1.66 eV and 1.75 eV in bulk and surface, respectively, the formation energy of FAi is strongly dependent on the medium: 1.31 eV in bulk and -0.12 eV in PbI2-terminated surface. Similarly the formation energy of FAI is 0.19 eV in bulk and 1.3 eV in surface [Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 2018,20, 6800-6804]. FAPbI3 type perovskites is considered to be the most promising semiconductor material and it currently holds the highest single-junction pvsk solar-cell PCE record (25.6%) [Nature, 592, 1-5, 2021]. Due to this, there is specifically an increasing interest in engineering the interface and surface features of FAPbI3 type perovskite (e.g., [Science, 366, 1509-1513, 2019.], [J. Am. Chem. Soc., 143, 6781-6786, 2021] as a means to enhance the device performance even further. However, the surface properties and the nature of surface defect formations in FAPbI3 are still not well understood. Therefore, a complete theoretical study that identifies the nature of all possible FAPbI3 surface defects was immediately necessary. As far as we know our study is also unique in a sense that, apart from other similar DFT studies [J. Phys. Chem. Lett, 8, 742-746, 2017], we provided complementary calculations, by; (i) identifying stable surfaces likely to form in thin-films, (ii) determining the most detrimental surface defects and (iii) revealing the passivation mechanism of such defects by surface additives. Therefore, our intention is not primarily to provide a library of calculations, but rather to reveal the physical mechanism behind the surface defect formation and passivation. Therefore, we believe that our study is novel and timely and we hope that this revised version of the manuscript deserves publication in JPCL. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11369</offset>
      <text> Reviewer #2: In this study, the authors investigated the defect formation in FAPbI3 surface by the first-principles calculations. And calculated the surface energies of FAPbI3 to determine the stability of different types of surface terminations. The formation energies of 12 native point defect types which could form on a certain surface are then calculated. A strong correlation between the surface energy and defect formation energy is found amongst different surface types. The charge transition levels of the defects and corresponding formation energies are concurrently discussed to identify harmful defects. The authors finally proposed several healing scenarios for those harmful defects via the introduction of passivating molecule additives to the FAPbI3 surfaces. But still have problem below ： 1. In Figure  3 , the authors presented the formation energy of defects with respect to the Fermi level ， What is the benchmark for determining the stability of defects? How much higher than the defect formation in Figure  3  is considered unstable? A reasonable explanation of the relationship between Fermi energy levels and defect formation energy? And the logical relationship between the effect of Fermi energy levels on defect formation energy throughout the article? </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12655</offset>
      <text> Response: We appreciate the reviewer for pointing out this issue. We consider 1 eV as the benchmark for determining the stability of defects, however, it would be more convenient to mention the defects as "more stable" or "less stable". Based on the reviewer's concern, we revised the definition of stability of defects by considering them relative to each other as it is done by Yin et. al. (2014) and Liu et. al. (2018)  rather than by determining a specific reference energy value. We choose to visually color them by considering if they can have a dominant or significant role of being a stable defect in both electron-rich and hole-rich conditions. It is considered by looking at the least defect formation energies relative to each other for different Fermi energy levels corresponding to those conditions. As can be seen in formula (3) defect formation energy linearly depends on the Fermi level for the charged states. For negatively or positively charged defects, electrons are transferred at certain Fermi levels from the reservoir to form the charged defect or vice versa, respectively. Here the electron chemical potential "mu_e" (i.e., qE_F) is conventionally referenced to the valence band maximum energy (i.e., q(E_F+E_VBM) ) [Rev. Mod. Phys. 86, 253, 2014]. This mu_e = q(E_F+E_VBM) makes sense because for the electron-poor environment (i.e., p-type region or hole-rich) E_F ~ 0 so that mu_e ~ qE_VBM, and similarly for the electron-rich environment (i.e., n-type region) E_F ~ E_g so that mu_e ~ qE_CBM. Explanations on the relationships discussed above have been added to related places in the article. 2. 𝑃𝑃𝑃𝑃𝑖𝑖 and 𝐹𝐹𝐹𝐹𝑖𝑖 are donor defects, why use anions to passivate rather than cations ？ </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14406</offset>
      <text> Response: We appreciate the reviewer for the question. We choose anions and neutral agents to avoid any repulsive force between cationic defects (Pbi and FAi) and the passivating agents. This approach enabled more stable interaction between the surface and the agents according to our geometry optimizations. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14716</offset>
      <text> 3. The calculation result shows that the surface energy of FAI-termination is about 1.5eV/nm2, and the surface energy of I-termination is about 5.8eV/nm2, according to this, why can it be obtained that FAI-termination is found to be 3 times stable when compared to I-termination? on Page 3, Line 2-3. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15018</offset>
      <text> Response: We apologize if any inconvenience is caused. Surfaces are considered to be relatively stable if the surface energies are relatively less. In our study, we have found that the surface energy of FAI-termination is approximately 3 times less than the I-termination suggesting that FAI-termination is 3 times more stable than the I-termination. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15370</offset>
      <text> 4. For Formula 1 and Formula 2, why the surface area selected for the cleavage energy (unrelaxed) is not consistent with the surface area selected for the cleavage energy (relaxed)? The former is A and the latter is 2A. In addition, if these two formulas refer to other author's paper, the source should be noted. If the authors derive it by themselves, the authors should briefly explain the derivation process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15784</offset>
      <text> Response: We appreciate the reviewer for the question. When you look at the formula (1), it is the cleavage energy required to cut the bulk structure from the top and bottom and create a surface. That's why it's divided by 2 (since it's both a lower and upper surface). Formula (2) is only the relative relaxation surface energy of the formed surface. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16137</offset>
      <text> 1- Heifets We now mention these references in the revised manuscript. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16208</offset>
      <text> 5. In Figure  S6 , we can see that acetic acid seems to have a pretty good passivation effect on FAI defects. In addition, the authors have prepared ten kinds of additives, the workload is relatively sufficient, but why in S6 and S7, there are only four kinds of additives. Finally, we hope to see more analysis of the mechanism of additive passivation of defects, there are few explanations about the passivation mechanism in the article. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16649</offset>
      <text> Response: We appreciate the reviewer for the question. In our manuscript, we suggest 10 passivation agents. Among these 10 agents, there are 2 anions and 2 neutral molecules, and the rest of these molecules are cations. We applied these 4 agents (anion and neutral) to donor defects. The remaining 6 cations and 2 neutral passivation agents were applied to acceptor defects. We have added the topics discussed above regarding passivation to the relevant places in the article. * sı Supporting Information ABSTRACT: Formamidinium lead iodide based hybrid perovskite materials with improved efficiency and stability still lack well-understood surface defect formation mechanisms. Controlling the surface termination and defects has the potential to improve the performance of both conventional 3D and latterly reduced-dimensional perovskites photovoltaics. Here, we characterized the termination and all possible defect formations in FAPbI 3 surface by the first-principles calculations. We found that, among the surfaces we considered, FAI-termination exhibits the most stable surface with a high defect tolerance. The PbI 2 -terminated surface is also found to be relatively stable; however, certain defects, such as electron-donating FA-interstitial and Pb-interstitial defects, can create deep-level stable charge-traps, potentially limiting the optoelectronic performance. We further investigate the surface treatment on these deep defects by model small molecule additives. We found that benzene additive with delocalized electron distribution can effectively passivate the deep FA-interstitial and Pb-interstitial defects by electron donating to the surface defect through charge-transfer. P erovskite semiconductor materials have attracted a lot of attention because of their potential properties, such as strong light absorption, excellent carrier diffusion lengths, high open circuit voltages, low electron and hole effective masses, bipolar charge transport, and solution processability.  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5]  Although the reported power conversion efficiency (PCE) for perovskite solar cells are about 25% inside the lab,  6  they are currently below the thermodynamic PCE limit of about 30%, predicted for such systems.  7  There are many ongoing attempts to enhance the performance of the hybrid perovskite solar cells not only by tailoring the growth/fabrication processes but also by engineering the atomic structure. Surface management and grain-control, such as through molecular functionalization or doping, are widely used strategies in order to improve the stability, charge-extraction, and charge-migration.  3, 6  One of the major factor limiting the device performance is the inevitable defect formation in the bulk film, surfaces, and grain boundaries.  [8] [9] [10]  Previous studies showed that hybrid perovskites contain largely shallow defects; 6,11 however, several controversial studies represent some defects can introduce deep-level trap states.  [12] [13] [14]  For example, iodine vacancy (V I ) and iodine interstitial (I i ) defects are generally known as benign since they create only shallow trap states;  11, 13, 15  however, other studies reported that both V I and I i are deeplevel traps and nonradiative recombination centers.  14, 16  These discrepancies can be caused by the distinct defect formation mechanisms on the surface  3, 6  since such unavoidable surface defects can cause nonradiative charge-recombination, chargemobility reduction, and ionic diffusion. Moreover, 2D and 2D/ 3D multidimensional perovskite structures are emerged in recent years, for instance, which differs from conventional 3D perovskites by having an additional larger organic separator cation (OSC) layer isolating the inorganic metal halide octahedra layers to form quantum well superlattices; 17 however, limited charge transport of these multidimensional perovskites frustrate their usage in perovskite solar cells and necessitate further research on the formation of defects on such surfaces.  18  Therefore, understanding, characterizing, and passivating (or neutralizing) these surface defects in perovskite materials are of great importance in terms of device optimization.  10, [19] [20] [21] [22]  For this, density-functional theory (DFT) based defect description is one of the most appropriate strategy since experimental identification of such defects/traps is quite challenging.  3, 23  For instance, computational analysis can suggest with a good sensitivity what kind of growth condition (such as, the rate of element composition) should be considered to identify detrimental defects or to reduce defect formations.  24  H. Uratani and K. Yamashita suggested, with their DFT calculations on MAPbI 3 perovskite, that surface defect formation can be minimized in a lead-rich environment.  25  On the other hand, Liu et al. have suggested that the preparation of FAPbI 3 film in "iodine" rich medium is necessary to prevent deep level defects.  26  This result is quite consistent with increasing PCE with excess iodide ions as additives in the FA-based bulk systems.  24  On the other hand, the majority of research had been focused on methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI 3 ) because of its highly promising photovoltaic properties and the incredibly rapid improvements in power conversion efficiency in last years.  27  However, they are susceptible to deterioration due to humidity and high temperatures since they transform into hydrated perovskite phases as soon as they are exposed to moisture.  [28] [29] [30]  In addition, they can be easily transformed from tetragonal phase to cubic phase at around 55 °C and rapidly decompose above 85 °C by thermal effects.  [31] [32] [33]  Therefore, MAPbI 3 type perovskite materials have stability problems and this has been the biggest obstacle to the technological use of such materials. In extensive studies recently conducted, formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) type perovskite solar cells have been recently proposed as an alternative to MAPbI 3 and that FAPbI 3 -based solar cells can have a maximum power conversion efficiency of 23.7%.  27  When MA is replaced by FA, the perovskite was found to have a band gap of 1.48 eV and a higher decomposition temperature and, therefore, a higher thermal stability.  [33] [34] [35] [36]  Thus, the surface construction and surface defect formation mechanisms in FAPbI 3 should be well-understood to maximize the performance and stability of FAPbI 3 -based solar cells. In this study, we investigate the defect formation in FAPbI 3 surface by the first-principles calculations. We, first, calculated the surface energies of FAPbI 3 to determine the stability of different types of surface terminations. The formation energies of 12 native point defect types that could form on a certain surface are then calculated. A strong correlation between the surface energy and defect formation energy is found among different surface types. The charge transition levels of the defects and corresponding formation energies are concurrently discussed to identify harmful defects. We finally propose several healing scenarios for those harmful defects via the introduction of passivating molecule additives to the FAPbI 3 surfaces. First-principles calculations were performed based on the density functional theory (DFT) using a plane-wave basis set and the projected augmented wave (PAW) method, as implemented in the VASP package.  37, 38  Generalized-gradientapproximation type cost-effective  39, 40  Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) functional is used for the exchange-correlation functional in all geometry optimization and self-consistent field calculations. A plane wave basis with a 300 eV energy cutoff and 4 × 4 × 1 Γ-centered k-mesh is used for the geometry optimizations. Site positions and cell volumes were allowed to relax using a conjugate gradient algorithm, until all residual forces are smaller than 0.02 eV/Å. A further single-point energy calculations on the optimized geometries with 400 eV cutoff and 8 × 8 × 1 k-mesh were performed in order to improve the accuracy of the energy calculations. The FAPbI 3 slabs for the defect formation calculations are created in the [001] crystallographic direction along with a 10-15 Å of vacuum layer. We generated four different types of 2 × 2 slabs: (i) PbI 2 , (ii) FAI-terminated surfaces, (iii) I-terminated surface, where FAs are removed from the FAI terminated surface, and (iv) PbI-terminated surface (see Figure  1 ). The surface energies are then calculated from σ = σ cl + σ relax , where σ cl is the cleavage energy when forming the clean (unrelaxed) slab and σ relax is the surface energy due to surface relaxation. We obtained the σ cl and σ relax from: E E n A 2 i i i cl slab unrel bulk σ μ = - +∑ (1 ) E E A relax slab rel slab unrel σ = - ( 2 ) where A is the surface area and E slab unrel and E slab rel are the energies of the unrelaxed and relaxed slabs, respectively.  41  E bulk is the energy of the bulk structure. n i is the number of Pb, I, and FA exchanged by the reservoir to generate the surface with the corresponding chemical potentials μ i . Intrinsic point defects are generated in one side of the slabs. Vacancy (V X ), antisite (X Y ), and interstitial (X i ) defect types are appropriately considered. The defect formation energies of the relaxed slabs are calculated using the following formula: H E E n q E E E ( ) d q d q i i i pr F VBM corr ∑ μ Δ = - + + + + (3) Here, q and d represent charge state and defect type, respectively. E pr is the energy of the pristine slab, and n i is the number change in element exchange from the reservoir to generate the corresponding defect. μ i , E F , and E VBM is the chemical potential, Fermi energy, and the energy of the valence-band maximum, respectively. E corr is the energy correction due to finite supercell sizes considered in formation energy calculations (see the SI for details). Because of the unique optoelectronic properties of FAPbI 3 , the majority of high-performance PSCs are based on a FAPbI 3dominant composition,  19, 24  however, its metastable nature makes it vulnerable to degradation mechanisms.  33, 36, 42  Therefore, understanding the surface termination process and its effect on the intrinsic point defects is crucial to solve the instability issues of FAPbI 3 -based PSCs. Moreover, controlling the surface termination should play a key role in 2D, 3D, and 2D-3D multidimensional perovskite structures which need robust surface engineering. Thus, we focus on the termination and defect formation in (100) FAPbI 3 surface. We first calculated the surface energy of four different termination type; PbI 2 , FAI, I, and PbI, as can be seen in Figure  1 . We find that FAI-termination has the lowest surface energy, that is, most stable surface among the four investigated termination types. This is a significant outcome, because the vast majority of The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters multidimensional perovskites are schematically represented by the I-termination even if the surface termination around the 2D-3D junction remained something of a puzzle, to the best of our knowledge. While we report that the FAI-termination is found to be 3 times stable when compared to I-termination, we should note that FAI-termination may not be the dominant surface because of its high volatility, according to other studies on organic cation-I terminated surfaces.  25, 40  Thus, we can speculate that FA and organic separator cations, such as butylammonium (BA) and octylammonium (OCA), can coexist at the surface and can collectively create the multidimensional junction. We investigate the formation of point defects at the surface of FAPbI 3 perovskite depending on the surface termination. We presented our results for the case of Pb-rich growth condition, since Pb-rich is typically considered for highperformance perovskite solar cells.  3, 6  The formation energies for other growth conditions (moderate and I-rich conditions) are represented in Supporting Information. We investigate the formation of 12 types of crystallographic point defects can present at the surfaces: three vacancy (V Pb , V I , V FA ), three interstitial (Pb i , I i , FA i ), and six antisite (Pb I , I Pb , FA I , I FA , FA Pb , Pb FA ). The number of investigated defects depends on the type of the termination, for example, we consider 9 different types of defects for PbI 2 -terminated surface in Figure  2a , while only four type of defects can be studied for surface in Figure  2d . On the PbI 2 surface in Figure  2a , only FA i has low formation energy. The formation energies of all other eight defects are larger than 1 eV. The high stability of PbI 2 surface against the defect formation is readily understood by considering the surface energy of PbI 2 -term is one of the smallest subsequent to that of FAI-term. On the other hand, FAI is the most suitable surface termination from the viewpoint of defect formation energies in Figure  2b , as well as the surface energy. The lowest formation energy belongs to I i , which is about 2 eV and still higher than I i formation energies for other three termination type. Also, we should note that the iodine defects are generally benign and they can be overcome by various surface treatment methods.  21  In Figure  2c , I-termination is found to be the most vulnerable surface against all types of defect formations as well it is one of the most energetically unfavorable surface. In Figure  2d , PbIterminated surface is likely to host V Pb , Pb i , and I i . It is only suitable for avoiding the formation of V I . Hereby, we report a strong correlation between the surface energy and the defect formation energy. FAI and PbI 2 terminations have lower surface energies and higher defect formation energies when compared to that of PbI and I terminations. A low surface energy corresponds to more stable structure against the defect formations. However, the formation energy of defects is not the sole parameter influences the performance of PSCs. The trap states of the defects play a critical role on carrier dynamics and consequently the photovoltaic performance. Some types of defects can have lower formation energy but it can be benign if the energy states of the defects are out of the band gap or vice versa. In Figure  3 , we present the formation energy of defects with respect to the Fermi level to examine the effects of the electrochemical potential on the formation of these intrinsic defects for Pb-rich growth condition (see SI for moderate and I-rich conditions). Defects with relatively high formation energies, that is, unstable ones, are displayed as gray dashed lines. The valence band maxima (VBM) and conduction band minima (CBM) are shown by colored backgrounds, while the remaining white regions are band gaps. In Figure  3a , on PbI 2terminated surface, FA I , Pb I , and FA i are dominant defects when the host material is p-type (E F &lt; 0.5 eV), whereas FA Pb and I i become dominant for n-type (E F &gt; 0.5 eV) host material. On FAI-terminated surface in Figure  3b , defect V I is stable for p-type material, while V FA and I i defects become dominant when the host material is n-type. In Figure  3c  and d , all investigated defects are stable in any region of the band gap of PbI-and I-terminated surfaces. As can be seen in Figure  3 , the defect formation energies are strongly correlated with the Fermi energy levels. For negatively or positively charged defects electrons are transferred at certain Fermi levels from the reservoir to form the charged defect or vice versa, respectively. From eq 3, the electron chemical potential μ e (i.e., qE F ) is conventionally referenced to the valence band maximum energy (i.e., q(E F + E VBM )). This μ e = q(E F + E VBM ) makes sense because for the electron-poor environment (i.e., p-type region or hole-rich) E F ∼ 0 so that μ e ∼ qE VBM , and similarly for the electron-rich environment (i.e., n-type region) E F ∼ E g so that μ e ∼ qE CBM . In this last part, we aim to clarify the types of surface defects responsible for carrier trapping by calculating the charge transition levels. The Fermi level where the defect state can accept/donate electrons is called as the charge transition level of a defect, which can be "shallow" or "deep" level according to its position in the band gap. Specifically, deep level defects have a major impact on the device performance in two ways: (1) they can act as Shockley-Read-Hall recombination centers and (2) the scattering effect of charged defects can influence carrier migration and reduce the conductivity.  26  In Figure  4 , we present the charge transition levels of the defects. In Figure  4a , on PbI 2 -terminated surface, most defects create deep transition levels. Even if the formation energies of most defects on PbI 2 -terminated surface are relatively high, the low formation energies of FA i (-0.20 eV) and Pb i (0.42 eV) can The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters pubs.acs.org/JPCL Letter make them effective recombination centers. On the other hand, the FAI-terminated surface has deep transition levels created by Pb i , FA I , and Pb I in Figure  4b ; however, their formation energies are relatively high so they can be considered benign. In Figure  4c , PbI-terminated surface has deep transition levels created by V Pb , Pb i , and V I , and the formation energies of V Pb and Pb i are relatively low. Similarly, on I-terminated surface in Figure  4d , most investigated defects create deep transition levels and their formation energies are quite low. We should note that we represent the formation energies and transition levels belong to the Pb-rich condition throughout the text while those of moderate and I-rich growth conditions are given in Supporting Information. Among the studied surface types, FAI-termitaion at first seems an appropriate surface type in terms of stability and achieving high photovoltaic performance owing to its low surface energy, high defect formation energy, and shallow charge transition levels. In reality, however, FA molecules can abandon the FAI-terminated surface due to their delicate nature against environmental conditions such as heat or moisture. In this case, the surface termination can ultimately be transformed into the I-termination (as well as mobile FAs would inhibit performance), which potentially makes the surface unstable and vulnerable against defect formations as shown in Figure  3d . This is also evidenced from relatively low formation energy of V FA shown in Figure  3b . Alternative to the  The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters FAI-termination, PbI 2 -terminated surface is another candidate since the surface energy of PbI 2 -termination is one of the smallest subsequent to that of FAI-termination. Indeed, recent studies also reported that a controlled PbI 2 -termination enhances the solar cell performance due to its appropriate band gap and lack of volatile FAs.  6, 43  On the other hand, electron donating FA i and Pb i defects are dominant in the hole-rich region (low Fermi-energy) on the PbI 2 -terminated surface. Thus, certain passivation treatments on the defects creating deep transition levels on the PbI 2 -terminated surface may further enhance the performance of FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells. To complement our findings we demonstrate a possible deep trap defect passivation scenario for surfaced FAPbI 3 . Ten model small molecule passivation agents are taken into account (see Figure  5a ). The molecules are taken to be neutral, cation and anions in terms of their charge-states and linear, cyclic and aromatic in terms their molecular structures. Therefore, a wide range of possible electrostatic defect-molecule interactions are being considered. Among these 10 passivation agents, there are 6 cation, 1 anion, and 3 neutral molecules. We applied 1 anion passivation agent to donor defects and 6 cation passivation agents were applied to acceptor defects. The remaining 3 neutral molecules were applied on both donor and acceptor defects. These agents are contacted with the deep defects (see Figure  5d  and e ), which is a widely used strategy for surface defect passivation.  3, 20, 23, 44  We choose anions and neutral passivating agents on cationic defects to avoid any repulsive force between them. Likewise, for the anionic defects, we choose cation and neutral agents. This approach enabled more stable interaction between the surface and the agents according to our geometry optimizations. We first focused on the electron donor, FA i defect in PbI 2terminated surface and introduced neutral pyridazinone, benzene, SO 3 , and lactate anion molecules. We first relaxed the slab geometries and calculated the density-of-states (DOS) for each case, shown in Figure  5d  and e . DOS of FA i has a narrower band gap relative to that of defect-free DOS; trap states above the VBM and below the CBM are visible. We observed that (i) a weak O•••H hydrogen bond between pyridazinone and FA i on the surface, (ii) a nonbonded electrostatic interaction between benzene and FA i , (iii) a separate O•••H hydrogen bond between lactate and FA i and a Pb-O covalent bond between Lactate and surface Pb 2+ are formed and (iv) SO 3 interacts much strongly with the neighboring Pb 2+ , instead of FA i , most likely due to stronger valency of lead compared to FA cation. The details of the structures are shown in Figure  S6 . We calculated the interaction energies of pyridazinone, benzene, lactate, and SO 3 with the FA i surface defect and found to be -1.06, -0.67, -4.38, and -5.51 eV, respectively. When the FA i defect reacts with the aforementioned additives traps in both sides were effectively passivated, as presented in Figures  5d  and S6 . Among the additives, benzene molecule seems to exhibit the best FA i passivation. Pyridazinone, lactate, and SO 3 addition under-passivate the defect, even though they interact more strongly with the electron donor defect. For the other deep electron donor Pb i defect we consider, we observed that the deep trap state near the VBM is eliminated by the benzene additive, as shown in Figure  5e . However, pyridazinone, lactate, and SO 3 , which were covalently bond to the surface defect, does not passivate the defect level at all (Figures S7 and Table  S1 ). Here, we attribute the passivation of FA i and Pb i defects with benzene to the charge-transfer between the molecule and the defect and the delocalized chargedistribution in benzene. Charge-density difference (CDD) analysis can be used to quantify the charge-transfer between the defect (d) and the passivating additive (p) using Δρ = ρ dp -(ρ d + ρ p ), where ρ dp , ρ d , and ρ p are the charge density of defective surface with additive, defective surface only, and additive only, respectively. Figure  5f -g shows the CDD isosurface distributions of FA i and Pb i defects interacting with benzene. We see that in both cases negative Δρ is distributed around benzene indicating a systematic electron depletion, in other words, large amount of electrons are transferred to the defective surface, thereby, clearing the trap states in the aforementioned defects.  23, 45    </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39961</offset>
      <text> The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters We investigated intrinsic point defect formations in FAPbI 3 surface with four types of terminations, PbI 2 , FAI, I, and PbI, by first-principles calculations. Among the termination types, FAI surface is the most favorable termination in terms of surface energy. Also, FAI-terminated surface is the most stable one against the defect formation and it is followed by PbI 2 termination as in the surface energies, which indicates a strong correlation between surface energy and defect formation. Also, FAI-term is the best candidate by having shallow charge transition levels rather than deep ones. Although the PbI 2terminated surface can host some defects creating deep transition levels, their treatments can be possible by the passivating agents. Especially, benzene additive with delocalized electron distribution can effectively passivate the deep FAinterstitial and Pb-interstitial defects, which could significantly enhance the performance of perovskite solar cells. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40978</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT * sı Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c03645 . Additional passivation implementations, defect formation energies, defect interaction energies, chemical potential, and energy correction calculations (PDF) Transparent Peer Review report available (PDF) ■ AUTHOR INFORMATION Corresponding Author I. Yavuz -Department of Physics, Marmara University, 34722 Istanbul, Turkey; orcid.org/0000-0002-3268-6268; Email: ilhan.yavuz@marmara.edu.tr Figure S1 : S1 Figure S1: Defect formation energies (DFEs) on PbI 2 , FAI, and PbI surfaces under Pb-rich, I-rich, and moderate growth conditions </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41681</offset>
      <text> Fig. S(3-5) below. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41701</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 : S2 Figure S2: DFEs as a function of E F on PbI 2 surface under different growth conditions </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41805</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 : S4 Figure S4: DFEs as a function of E F on FAI surface under different growth conditions </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41907</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 : S6 Figure S6: Density-of-states plots for FA i defect with additives. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41990</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 : S7 Figure S7: Density-of-states plots for Pb i defect with additives. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42073</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 : S8 Figure S8: Density-of-states plots for FA Pb defect with additives. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42157</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 : S9 Figure S9: Density-of-states plots for I Pb defect with additives. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42240</offset>
      <text> ( The first term in Eq. (S.4) is the lattice energy correction at the qth charge-state lattice energy of the isolated defect in the dielectric medium, and𝐸 𝑞 𝑖𝑠𝑜,𝑚is the model energy of the defect in the periodic structure. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42483</offset>
      <text> [5,6] ∆𝑉 = 0. 3 𝑉 jz-2021-03645q.R1 Name: Peer Review Information for "Surface Defect Formation and Passivation in Formamidinium Lead Triiodide (FAPbI&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) Perovskite Solar Cell Absorbers" First Round of Reviewer Comments Reviewer: 1 Comments to the Author Oner et al. report a comprehensive theoretical characterization of the termination surfaces of the FAPbI3 perovskite together with all possible defect formation. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42919</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Schematic representations of the FAPbI 3 surface termination types and their surface energies. PbI 2 -, FAI-, I-, and PbI-terminated surfaces are given in panels a-d, respectively, while their surface energies can be seen in panel e. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43177</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Formation energies of all possible intrinsic neutral point defects in (a) PbI 2 -, (b) FAI-, (c) I-, and (d) PbI-terminated surfaces. Pb-rich growth condition is considered in all cases. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43388</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Formation energies of intrinsic point defects in (a) PbI 2 -, (b) FAI-, (c) PbI-, and (d) I-terminated surfaces. Defects with unfavorable high formation energies are displayed as gray dashed lines. Pb-rich growth condition is considered in all cases. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43663</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Charge transition energy levels of intrinsic defects in (a) PbI 2 -, (b) FAI-, (c) PbI-, and (d) I-terminated surfaces. The formation energies of the defects are represented in related columns. Pb-rich growth condition is considered in all cases. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43934</offset>
      <text> Figure 5 . 5 Figure 5. Passivation procedure of the deep FA i and Pb i defects on PbI 2 -terminated surface conceived by density of states calculations. (a) List of all passivation agents we considered. Surface structure of (b) FA i and (c) Pb i . Density of states of (d) FA i and (e) Pb i defect with and without the benzene additive. The trap states before introducing the benzene molecule to the surface are highlighted by red dashed circles. (f-g) Chargedensity difference (CDD) distributions with benzene addition. Negative CDDs are in turquoise and positive CDDs are in yellow. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44520</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 List of interaction energies between the surface defect and molecule additives. The energies are in eV units. Defect molecule q-state FA i Pb i FA Pb I Pb 1 benzene 0 -0.67 -0.60 +0.40 -0.54 2 pyridazinone 0 -1.06 -4.00 +0.07 -0.32 3 sulphur trioxide 0 -5.51 -4.32 4 lactate - -4.38 -3.83 5 methyl ammonium + -4.40 -3.80 6 ethyl ammonium + -4.57 -3.70 7 methoxyl ammonium + -4.25 -3.67 8 azetidinium + -4.51 -3.86 9 azolium + -3.07 -2.87 10 pyridinium + -0.51 -2.16 </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45001</offset>
      <text> 2  </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45005</offset>
      <text> , E., et al. "Ab initio modeling of surface structure for SrTiO 3 perovskite crystals." Physical Review B 64.23 (2001): 235417. 2- Xue, Jingjing, et al. "Crystalline liquid-like behavior: surface-induced secondary grain growth of photovoltaic perovskite thin film." Journal of the American Chemical Society 141.35 (2019): 13948- 13953. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45342</offset>
      <text>			 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c03645 J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2022, 13, 324-330</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
