<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>241114001345880CFBAGE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">4</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">4</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 126</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Inhibition of defect-induced α-to-δ phase transition for efficient and stable formamidinium perovskite solar cells</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>128</offset>
      <text>Inhibition of defect-induced -to-phase transition for efficient and stable formamidinium perovskite solar cells </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>240</offset>
      <text> REVIEWER COMMENTS Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author): See Attachment</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>310</offset>
      <text>This communication reveals the effect of various defects on inducing the α-toδ phase transition in FAPbI3, which are not well known before. The influence law of defects on the phase-stabilities and optoelectronic properties are quite different. They found the VI has both the low formation energies and energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition, which is most likely to lead to the FAPbI3 degradation. A stable PbC2O4 surface was prepared to restrain the mobile I to stabilize the α phase. The champion PSCs efficiency reached 25.4% with an independent certified 24.92%. The results are exciting and timely, and conclusion is supported by experimental results. Before it can be acceptable in Nature Communication, a minor revision is needed: (1) This work fabricates FAPbI3 by one-step method. We noted that the FACl instead of the common MACl was used as the additive to deposit the FAPbI3 films. Is there any advantage for this component? (2) It is better to give the cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy image of the devices with and without passivation. (3) Line 161. The author found the PbC2O4 is "around 10 nm on the top of LOS perovskite", while during the DFT calculation, they only using one PbC2O4. How to interpret the discrepancy of between theory and experiment? (4) In addition, some details should be added: The defect formation energies of native point defects on the Pb-rich perovskite surface (Figure  1c ) should be clearly listed in the Table . The material information of H2C2O4 should be added at "Materials". Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author): The α-δ phase transition is an important factor that affects the stability of FA-based perovskite solar cells. In the manuscript, DFT was used to reveal the degradation pathway of the α-δ phase transition of FAPbI3.PbC2O4 was introduced to suppress the transition and the target FAPbI3 solar cells delivered a certified efficiency of 24.92%. Moreover, the device stability at MPP was enhanced. The work provides some interesting insights on the defects inducing α-δ phase transition. However, the investigation of the passivation mechanism is not in-depth and there are some issues needed to be clarified before it can be accepted. (1)In the first-principles calculations, how does the PbC2O4 layer bind with FAPbI3? The binding picture from the atomic level should be provided. In addition, experimental evidence such as HADDF is suggested to confirm the interface binding. (2)According to the calculation, reducing the I vacancies is the most effective strategy for suppressing the α-δ phase transition. However, many substances have been reported to significantly reduce the I vacancies and what's the advantage of PbC2O4? (3)It is difficult to observe the crystal lattice from Figure  2c, d . (4)Are there any peaks corresponding to PbC2O4 in the XRD pattern of LOS perovskite films? Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author): This paper reported the pathway of α-to-δ phase and the effect of various defects on the phasetransition degradation of FAPbI3 perovskite. They found that among the defects, the I vacancies easily generated on the surface and decreased the energy barrier of phase-transition, thus they are most likely to induce the α-FAPbI3 degradation. Followed the DFT theoretical framework, a water-insoluble and stable lead oxalate was designed to stabilize the α-phase due to reduce the I vacancies and I migration. The resultant devices show very high efficiency and robust soaking stability. It is worthy publication in Nature Communications. Before it could be accepted, several points need to be clarified: (1) There is lacking of a clear description on the interaction between H2C2O4 and FAPbI3. How about the uniformity of PbC2O4 layer on the perovskite? The PL mappings of the control and target films are also indispensable. (2) The effect of bare IPA on the device performance should be studied to excluding the role of IPA. (3) The IPA was rarely used as an anti-solvent to achieve high efficiency PSC. Most used diethyl ether or CB in one-step method. More detail about this method is needed. (4) Besides VI, how about the changes of the other defect formation energies after introducing the LOS? (5) Some English need correction. Such as Line 38 "various …… composition…… developed." Line 72 "which are easily generated", Line 168 "the LOS perovskite exhibited to three chemically". </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4722</offset>
      <text> Responses to Reviewer We sincerely thank the reviewer for the constructive and positive comments and suggestions to improve our manuscript. We have addressed all issues below in detail and made appropriate changes in the Revised Manuscript and Revised Supplementary Information. Please see the following responses to your questions raised. Original referee comments are reproduced in black; our responses are marked in blue and corrections are highlighted by a yellow background here and in Revised Manuscript as well as Revised Supplementary Information. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5279</offset>
      <text> Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author): This communication reveals the effect of various defects on inducing the α-to δ phase transition in FAPbI3, which are not well known before. The influence law of defects on the phase-stabilities and optoelectronic properties are quite different. They found the VI has both the low formation energies and energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition, which is most likely to lead to the FAPbI3 degradation. A stable PbC2O4 surface was prepared to restrain the mobile I to stabilize the α phase. The champion PSCs efficiency reached 25.4% with an independent certified 24.92%. The results are exciting and timely, and conclusion is supported by experimental results. Before it can be acceptable in Nature Communication, a minor revision is needed: General response: We sincerely thank the reviewer's positive comments and we have comprehensively revised the manuscript according to the reviewer's valuable suggestions. Please see the following responses. (1) This work fabricates FAPbI3 by one-step method. We noted that the FACl instead of the common MACl was used as the additive to deposit the FAPbI3 films. Is there any advantage for this component? Response: Thanks for the comment. In fact, N. G Park et al. have demonstrated that the FACl additive has benefits over MACl because it will not change the bandgap of FAPbI3 (Sol. RRL, 2020, 4, 2000331). In this work, we repeated their experiments for pursuing better base-line of PSCs performance. It was found that the FACl additive resulted in a much larger grain of perovskite films than the MACl additive (Supplementary Fig.  12 ). As shown in UV-Vis spectra, the results showed that the FACl perovskite has a narrower bandgap than MACl perovskite (Supplementary Fig.  13 ), which is consistent with the results of N. G Park et al. We further investigated the dependence of photovoltaic performance on the additives of FACl and MACl in FAPbI3-based perovskite solar cells (PSCs). From the typical J-V in Supplementary Fig.  14 , as compared with the device with MACl-additive, the Jsc is improved for FACl additive device, which is consistent with the previous reports (Sol. RRL, 2020, 4, 2000331). Thus, we believe that the FACl is a better additive for PSCs performance. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7548</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: We used formamidinium chloride (FACl) as the additive instead of methylamine (2) It is better to give the cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy image of the devices with and without passivation. Response: Thanks very much for the suggestion. We have given the crosssectional scanning electron microscopy images of the control (without passivation) and LOS devices (with passivation), as shown in "Supplementary Fig.  18" . </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8003</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: The cross-sectional SEM images of the post-optimized control and LOS devices are shown in Supplementary Fig.  18 . (3) Line 161. The author found the PbC2O4 is "around 10 nm on the top of LOS perovskite", while during the DFT calculation, they only using one PbC2O4. How to interpret the discrepancy of between theory and experiment? </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8362</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Response: Thanks for the comment. Though the PbC2O4 layer is around 10 nm, only the first layer PbC2O4 on perovskite surface is chemical adsorption, more other PbC2O4 form on the first layer PbC2O4 with the amorphous state. Thus, to simulate the 10 nm amorphous PbC2O4 is beyond the state-of-art of DFT calculation ability, while it is more suitable to simplify the model to one-layer PbC2O4 on perovskite surface. The previous reports generally adopted the similar simplification (Science, 2019, 365, 473-478). Besides, from our simulation, we can find that the one-layer PbC2O4 can play a key role to the phase degradation kinetic in theory. A thicker PbC2O4 layer will protect the FAPbI3 perovskite more effectively in the device in experiment. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>9125</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: In the surface model, the FAPbI3 surface are 4 layers, the bottom one-layer atom fixed which mimics the bulk of FAPbI3 while the top three-layer can move freely during the optimization. The PbC2O4 layer is 1 ML on the I-terminal FAPbI3 surface with the Pb bonded with one I and four O. (4) In addition, some details should be added: The defect formation energies of native point defects on the Pb-rich perovskite surface (Figure  1c ) should be clearly listed in the Table . The material information of H2C2O4 should be added at "Materials". Response: Thanks for your suggestions, we have listed the defect formation energies of native point defects (Fig.  1c ) in the "Supplementary Table  1 " and added the material information of H2C2O4 at "Materials" as follow. The α-δ phase transition is an important factor that affects the stability of FAbased perovskite solar cells. In the manuscript, DFT was used to reveal the degradation pathway of the α-δ phase transition of FAPbI3.PbC2O4 was introduced to suppress the transition and the target FAPbI3 solar cells delivered a certified efficiency of 24.92%. Moreover, the device stability at MPP was enhanced. The work provides some interesting insights on the defects inducing α-δ phase transition. However, the investigation of the passivation mechanism is not in-depth and there are some issues needed to be clarified before it can be accepted. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10553</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10578</offset>
      <text> Supplementary General response: We sincerely thank the reviewer for reviewing the manuscript and giving valuable comments. It is really helpful to improve this work. In the revised manuscript, we give more evidences to clarify the passivation mechanism. (1) In the first-principles calculations, how does the PbC2O4 layer bind with FAPbI3? The binding picture from the atomic level should be provided. In addition, experimental evidence such as HADDF is suggested to confirm the interface binding. Response: Thanks for your valuable suggestions. The binding picture of PbC2O4 layer on FAPbI3 surface in our DFT calculation is added to Supplementary Fig. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  8c  and d   </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11277</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: We performed DFT simulation for the interface binding between FAPbI3 and PbC2O4, as shown in Supplementary Fig.  1 . The high-angle annular dark field scanning transmission electron microscopy (HAADF-STEM) was used to probe the interface between PbC2O4 and FAPbI3 and it can be clearly observed that there is a crystalline FAPbI3 region and an amorphous PbC2O4 region (Supplementary Fig.  8 ). (2) According to the calculation, reducing the I vacancies is the most effective strategy for suppressing the α-δ phase transition. However, many substances have been reported to significantly reduce the I vacancies and what's the advantage of PbC2O4? Response: Thanks for your valuable comments. Many materials have been really reported to reduce the I vacancies on perovskite surface. For example, the use of an organic halide salt, such as phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI), alkylammonium bromide and n-Octylammonium Iodide (OAI) et al., on perovskite films for surface passivation was a generally strategy to reduce the I vacancies. In comparation with organic halide salt, there are no I ions in PbC2O4 that will move during device operation. Namely, the halogen ions in the organic halide salt passivator will still move and form VI while the large C2O4  2-  oxalate with strong chelation in PbC2O4 is much stable. The steric hindrance of PbC2O4 can also impede the movement of mobile I ions from perovskite layer. Besides, PbC2O4 is chemically stable and insoluble in water that can protect the perovskite surface from the moisture corrosion. The solubility of PbC2O4 in water is merely 0.00065 g liter -1 , which is even lower than that of PbSO4. However, most reported organic halide salt passivator, such as PEAI and OAI, are unstable under the moisture corrosion. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13071</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: In comparation with the organic halide salt passivator, such as phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) and n-Octylammonium Iodide (OAI) et al, PbC2O4 without mobile halogen ions is chemically stable and insoluble in water that can stabilize the perovskite surface well under the stimuli of moisture and electric field. (3) It is difficult to observe the crystal lattice from Figure  2c, d . Response: Thanks for your suggestions. We have observed the crystal lattice of control and LOS perovskite by HAADF-STEM as shown in Supplementary (4) Are there any peaks corresponding to PbC2O4 in the XRD pattern of LOS perovskite films? Response: Thanks for your suggestions. According to the XRD curves of Control-0 h and LOS-0 h in Fig.  3d , there is no any peaks corresponding to PbC2O4 (Fig.  R1 ). We reason that the PbC2O4 is amorphous state as observed in the HAADF-STM images (Supplementary Fig.  8 ). (1) There is lacking of a clear description on the interaction between H2C2O4 and FAPbI3. How about the uniformity of PbC2O4 layer on the perovskite? The PL mappings of the control and target films are also indispensable. Response: Thanks for your suggestions. H2C2O4 has been generally used to combine metal ions to form precipitation in other fields. In our work, we have demonstrated the reaction between the oxalic acid and FAPbI3 perovskite. After mixing oxalic acid and FAPbI3 solution, a large amount of white-colored sediment was yielded which were identified as pure PbC2O4 materials through X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns (Supplementary Figs.  2  and 3 ). Here, we give a description on the interaction as the following chemical equations: H2C2O4 + FAPbI3 = PbC2O4 + FAI + HI. We believe that the FAI can be dissolved in the IPA and thus removed during the preparation process. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14882</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: Thus, a thin and compact PbC2O4 can be rapidly generated on the surface of the perovskite films through immersing the perovskite film into the oxalic acid solution or spin-coating the oxalic acid solution on perovskite, according to the following chemical equations: H2C2O4 + FAPbI3 = PbC2O4 + FAI + HI. The FAI can be dissolved in the IPA and thus removed during the preparation process. As for the uniformity of PbC2O4, we have observed some small white particles (PbC2O4) uniformly distributed on the perovskite surface in Fig.  2b . We further surveyed the perovskite film with a high concentration oxalic acid treatment by SEM (Fig.  R2 ). The results confirmed that there is a uniform reaction layer on the perovskite surface. In addition, we measured the PL mapping of control and target films, as shown in Supplementary Fig.  11 . The PL intensity of LOS films was higher than that of control film in the whole 10 × 10 µm 2 region, further clarifying that the generated PbC2O4 uniformly passivate the perovskite film.  Revision in manuscript: In the PL mapping images, the intensity of LOS film in the whole 10 × 10 µm 2 region was higher than that of control film (Supplementary Fig.  11 ), clarifying that the PbC2O4 uniformly passivates the perovskite film. (2) The effect of bare IPA on the device performance should be studied to excluding the role of IPA. Response: Thanks for your suggestions. We have compared the performance for the devices with and without IPA treatment. 40 μL IPA was spin-coated on perovskite surface at 4000 rpm for 30 s. As shown in Fig.  R3 , there is no obvious effect of IPA on the device performance. It is well known that IPA is a general passivation solvent, which is not destructive to the perovskite layer in short time (Nature Photonics, 2019, 13, 460-466). (3) The IPA was rarely used as an anti-solvent to achieve high efficiency PSC. Most used diethyl ether or CB in one-step method. More detail about this method is needed. Response: Thanks for your suggestions. In fact, the IPA has been used as antisolvent to prepare the perovskite film (A general approach to high-efficiency perovskite solar cells by any antisolvent, Nature communications, 2021, 12, 1878). It demonstrated that IPA antisolvents result in polycrystalline perovskite films with a remarkably high degree of preferred orientation. Inspired by this work, we further developed the type of method through adding a little of MACl in the IPA to achieve better crystalline quality perovskite film. We have also compared performance of PSCs based on different anti-solvents. Through XRD and SEM characterization of perovskite layers fabricated by different antisolvents, we identified that IPA can achieve better crystalline quality of perovskite films (Supplementary Figs.  15  and 16 ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17714</offset>
      <text> Revision in manuscript: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-41853-y   Inhibition of defect-induced α-to-δ phase transition for efficient and stable formamidinium perovskite solar cells Tian Chen 1,2 , Jiangsheng Xie 1,2 , Bin Wen 1,2 , Qixin Yin 1,2 , Ruohao Lin 1,2 , Shengcai Zhu 1 &amp; Pingqi Gao 1,2 Defects passivation is widely devoted to improving the performance of formamidinium lead triiodide perovskite solar cells; however, the effect of various defects on the α-phase stability is still unclear. Here, using density functional theory, we first reveal the degradation pathway of the formamidinium lead triiodide perovskite from α to δ phase and investigate the effect of various defects on the energy barrier of phase transition. The simulation results predict that iodine vacancies are most likely to trigger the degradation, since they obviously reduce the energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition and have the lowest formation energies at the perovskite surface. A water-insoluble lead oxalate compact layer is introduced on the perovskite surface to largely suppress the α-phase collapse through hindering the iodine migration and volatilization. Furthermore, this strategy largely reduces the interfacial nonradiative recombination and boosts the efficiency of the solar cells to 25.39% (certified 24.92%). Unpackaged device can maintain 92% of its initial efficiency after operation at maximum power point under simulated air mass 1.5 G irradiation for 550 h. The power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs) has reached a certified record value of 26% 1 . Since 2015, the state-ofthe-art PSCs prefer to adopt formamidinium lead triiodide (FAPbI 3 ) perovskite as light absorption layer since it possesses the excellent thermal-stability and has a preferred bandgap closer to the Shockley-Queisser limit  [2] [3] [4]  . Unfortunately, the FAPbI 3 films thermodynamically undergo a phase transition from the black α-phase to a yellow nonperovskite δ-phase at room temperature  5, 6  . Various complex perovskite compositions have been developed to prevent the formation of the δ-phase. The most common strategies to overcome this problem is mixing FAPbI 3 with a combination of methylammonium (MA + ), cesium (Cs + ) and bromide (Br -) ions  [7] [8] [9]  . Nevertheless, mixed perovskites suffer an enlarged bandgap and light-induced phase segregation which will compromise the performance and operational stability of the resulting PSCs  [10] [11] [12]  . Recently, it is demonstrated that the pure FAPbI 3 single crystal without any alloying can own excellent stability due to its excellent crystallinity and low defects  13, 14  . Thus, defects reduction through improving the crystallinity of bulk FAPbI 3 is an essential strategy for achieving efficient and stable PSCs  2, 15  . However, degradation to undesirable yellow hexagonal non-perovskite δ-phase during the operation of FAPbI 3 PSCs can still occur  16  . This process is generally initialized from the surfaces and grain boundaries, which is more vulnerable under water, heat and light due to the exist of numerous defect sites  17  . Consequently, surface/grain boundary passivation is required to stabilize the black-phase FAPbI 3 18 . Many strategies of defects passivation, including introducing low dimensional perovskite, Lewis acid/base molecules and ammonium halide salts etc., have achieved great progress for the formamidinium PSCs  [19] [20] [21] [22]  . To date, almost all studies focus on the role of various defects in determining the optoelectronic properties, such as carrier recombination, diffusion lengths and energy band structure in solar cells  [22] [23] [24]  . Such as using density functional theory (DFT), the formation energies and trap level of various defects are theoretically predicted, which has been widely used to guide the practical passivation design  20, 25, 26  . The device stability generally seems to improve as the defects decrease. However, the impact mechanism of various defects on the phase-stabilities and optoelectronic properties should be completely different in formamidinium PSCs. To our knowledge, a fundamental understanding of how the defects induce the cubic-to-hexagonal (α-to-δ) phase transition and the role of surface passivation on phase stability of α-FAPbI 3 perovskite are still not well-known. Herein, by using DFT, we revealed the degradation pathway of the FAPbI 3 perovskite from black α-phase to yellow δ-phase and the effect of various defects on the energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition. It is predicted that the I vacancies, which easily generated during the film preparation process and device operation, are most likely to trigger the α-to-δ phase transition. Thereby, we introduced a water-insoluble and chemically stable lead oxalate (PbC 2 O 4 ) compact layer on the top of FAPbI 3 through in-situ reaction. The lead oxalate surface (LOS) suppressed the formation of I vacancies and retarded the migration of I ion under stimuli of heat, light and electric field. As a result, the LOS largely reduced the interfacial nonradiative recombination and boosted the efficiency of FAPbI 3 PSCs to 25.39% (certified 24.92%). Unpackaged LOS devices maintained 92% of their initial efficiency after operation at maximum power point (MPP) under simulated air mass (AM) 1.5 G irradiation for over 550 h. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23113</offset>
      <text> Results </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23122</offset>
      <text> First-principles calculations studies First, we performed first-principles calculations to find the degradation pathway of FAPbI 3 perovskite transition from α to δ-phase. From the detailed phase transition process, it is found that the transition of a 3D corner sharing [PbI 6 ] octahedron in cubic α-phase FAPbI 3 to a facesharing 1D line [PbI 6 ] octahedron in hexagonal δ-phase FAPbI 3 is enabled by breaking 9 Pb-I bonds in the first step (Int-1) with energy barrier as high as 0.62 eV/cell, as shown in Fig.  1a . By the octahedrons shear along [0 11] direction, the hexagonal short chains extend from 1 × 1 to 1 × 3, 1 × 4, and eventually transit to δ-phase. The orientation relation of the whole pathway is (011) α //(001) δ + [100] α //[100] δ . While from the energy profile, we can find that after the δ-phase FAPbI 3 nucleation, the energy barrier become lower relative the α-phase in the following steps, meaning the phase transition will speed up. Obviously, if we want to inhibit the α-phase degradation, the manipulation of the first step of phase transition is critical. Then, we systematically investigated the effect of various native point defects (including anti-site occupations of Pb FA , I FA , Pb I , and I Pb ; interstitials of Pb i , and I i ; vacancies of V I , V FA , and V Pb ), which were regarded as the key factor to trigger the phase degradation at atomic and energy level, as shown in Fig.  1b  and Supplementary Table  1 . Interestingly, not all the defects will reduce the energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition (Fig.  1b ). We believe that the defects which both have low formation energy and reduce the energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition are considered to be harmful to the phase stability. As previous reports, Pb-rich surface is typically considered in efficient formamidinium PSCs  27  . Thus, we focused on the (100) surface with PbI 2 termination in a Pb-rich condition. The defect formation energies of native point defects on the surface are shown in Fig.  1c  and Supplementary Table  1 . Considering the energy barrier (EB) of phase transition and formation energy (FE), these defects were divided into three types. Type-I (Low EB-High FE): Although I Pb , V FA and V Pb largely reduce the energy barrier of phase transition, they have high formation energies. Thus, we thought these types of defects have limited effect on the phase transition since they rarely formed. Type-II (High EB): The Pb I , I FA and Pb FA antisite defects will not be detrimental to the phase stability of α-FAPbI 3 perovskite due to the improved energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition. Type-III (Low EB-Low FE): V I, I i and Pb i defects with relatively low formation energies will induce the degradation of the black phase. Particularly lowest FE and EB of V I taken into consideration, we think that the most effective strategy is reducing the I vacancies. In order to reduce the V I , we designed a PbC 2 O 4 compact layer to reinforce the FAPbI 3 surface. In comparation with the organic halide salt passivator, such as phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) and n-Octylammonium Iodide (OAI), etc., PbC 2 O 4 without mobile halogen ions is chemically stable and insoluble in water that can stabilize the perovskite surface well under the stimuli of moisture and electric field. The solubility of PbC 2 O 4 in water is merely 0.00065 g liter -1 , which is even lower than that of PbSO 4 28 . More importantly, the compact and uniform LOS layer can be mildly prepared on the perovskite film through in-situ reaction (see below). We performed DFT simulation for the interface binding between FAPbI 3 and PbC 2 O 4 , as shown in Supplementary Fig.  1 . The defect formation energies after introducing the LOS were given in Supplementary Table  2 . We found that the LOS not only increases the V I defect formation energy from 0.69 eV to 1.53 eV (Fig.  1d ), but also improves the activation energies for I migration on the surface and migration escaping the surface (Fig.  1e ). For the first step, the I ion migrate on the perovskite surface leaving V I in the lattice site with an energy barrier of 0.61 eV; while the activation energy for I ionic migration increase to 1.28 eV after introducing LOS due to the steric-hindrance effect. For the I ionic migration escaping the perovskite surface, the energy barrier in LOS is also higher than that in control sample (Fig.  1e ). The schematic views of I ionic migration path in the control and LOS FAPbI 3 are shown in Fig.  1f , g, respectively. The simulation results illustrate that the LOS can suppress the V I defects formation and I volatilization, which will in turn hinder the α-to-δ phase transition nucleation. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27850</offset>
      <text> Characterization of lead oxalate on the perovskite surface The reaction between the oxalic acid and FAPbI 3 perovskite was tested. After mixing oxalic acid and FAPbI 3 solution, a large amount of whitecolored sediment was yielded, as shown in Supplementary Fig.  2 . The powder products were identified as pure PbC 2 O 4 materials through X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns (Supplementary Fig.  3 ) and fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) (Supplementary Fig.  4 ). We found that oxalic acid can be dissolved in isopropanol (IPA) well at room temperature with a solubility of approximately 18 mg mL -1 , as shown in Supplementary Fig.  5 . It is beneficial to the post-treatment, since the IPA as a general passivation solvent is not destructive to the perovskite layer in short time  29  . Thus, a thin and compact PbC 2 O 4 can be rapidly generated on the surface of the perovskite films through immersing the perovskite film into the oxalic acid solution or spincoating the oxalic acid solution on perovskite, according to the following chemical equations: H 2 C 2 O 4 + FAPbI 3 = PbC 2 O 4 + FAI + HI. The FAI can be dissolved in the IPA and thus removed during the preparation process. The thickness of the LOS can be controlled by the reaction time and precursor concentration. The scanning electron microscopies (SEM) of control and LOS perovskite films are shown in Fig.  2a, b . The results show that the perovskite surface morphology maintained well and a mass of small particles deposited on the surface of crystalline grain, which should be the PbC 2 O 4 layer generated through in-situ reaction. The LOS perovskite films have a slight smoother surface (Supplementary Fig.  6 ) and a larger water contact angle than the control films (Supplementary Fig.  7 ). Cross-sectional high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) was used to distinguish the surface product layers. As compared to the control film (Fig.  2c ), a uniform and compact thin layer with a thickness of around 10 nm on the top of LOS perovskite could be clearly discerned (Fig.  2d ). The high-angle annular dark field scanning transmission electron microscopy (HAADF-STEM) was used to probe the interface between PbC 2 O 4 and FAPbI 3 and it can be clearly observed that there is a crystalline FAPbI 3 region and an amorphous PbC 2 O 4 region (Supplementary Fig.  8 ). X-ray photoemission spectroscopy (XPS) measurements were carried out to characterize the perovskite surface composition after oxalic acid treatment, as shown in Fig.  2e-g . In Fig.  2e , the C 1s peaks around 284.8 eV and 288.5 eV belonged to the specific signals of C-C and FA, respectively. Compared with the control film, an additional peak at 289.2 eV attributed to the C 2 O 4 2-was observed in the LOS film. In the O 1s spectra, the LOS perovskite exhibits three chemically distinct O 1s peaks at 531.7 eV, 532.5 eV, and 533.4 eV corresponding to the O atoms of deprotonated COO, C=O and OH components of the intact oxalate group  30  (Fig.  2f ). For the control sample, only a slight O 1s peak is observed which can be attributed to the chemisorbed oxygen on the surface. The characteristic Pb 4f 7/2 and Pb 4f 5/2 were located at 138.4 eV and 143.3 eV for the control film, respectively. We observed that the LOS perovskite shows a ~0.15 eV shift of the Pb peaks toward larger binding energies, which indicates the stronger interaction between C 2 O 4 2and Pb atom (Fig.  2g ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31310</offset>
      <text> Stabilizing the pure α-phase FAPbI 3 Based on DFT results, V I defects and I migration are theoretically predicted to be liable to induce the α-to-δ phase transition. Previous reports have demonstrated that a fast release of I 2 from the FA-based perovskite films during light soaking, after exposing films under the stress of light and heat  [31] [32] [33]  . To confirm the lead oxalate stabilizing effect on the α-phase perovskite, we immersed the control and LOS perovskite films into transparent glass bottle filled with toluene, respectively, and then illuminated them under 1-sun illumination for 24 h. The ultraviolet-visible (UV-Vis) absorption of the toluene solution was measured, as shown in Fig.  3a . It is observed a much lower I 2 absorption intensity in the LOS perovskite case in comparison with the control sample, illustrating that the compact LOS could suppress the release of I 2 from the perovskite films during light soaking. The photograph of the aged control and LOS perovskite films is shown in the inset of Fig.  3b  and c . The LOS perovskite still maintained black while most region of the control film has already turned yellow. The UV-Vis absorption spectra of the immersed films were presented in Fig.  3b, c . We observed that the absorption corresponding to the α-phase in control film showed an obvious decrease. The XRD measurement was carried out to record the crystal structure evolution. A strong yellow δphase signal (11.8°) was observed in the control perovskite after 24 h illumination while the LOS perovskite still maintained the black-phase well (Fig.  3d ). We performed scanning electron microscopy (SEM) measurements to observe the microstructure changes of perovskite films after 24 h illumination, as shown in Fig.  3e, f . For the control film, the large crystal grains were damaged and converted to small needles which are consistent to the morphology of δ-phase FAPbI 3 product 17 (Fig.  3e ). For the LOS film, the perovskite crystal grains maintained well (Fig.  3f ). The results confirmed that the loss of I obviously induced the transition from black to yellow phase while the PbC 2 O 4 stabilized the black phase through impeding the I loss. Owing to the much higher vacancy density at the surface than in the bulk of the grains  34  , this phase transition is more likely to happen at the surface of the grains along with the release of iodine and the generation of V I . As the DFT predicted, the LOS could suppress the formation of V I defects and block the I ions migration at the perovskite surface. In addition, we studied the effect of PbC 2 O 4 layers on the moisture resistance of perovskite films in ambient air (30-60% relative humidity). As presented in Supplementary Fig.  9 , the LOS perovskite still remained black after 12 days, while the control film has already turned yellow. In XRD measurements, the control film exhibited strong peak at 11.8°corresponding to δ-phase FAPbI 3 while the LOS perovskite maintained black α-phase well (Supplementary Fig.  10 ). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34360</offset>
      <text> Carrier extraction and photovoltaic performance The steady-state photoluminescence (PL) and time-resolved PL (TRPL) were performed to investigate the passivation effect of lead oxalate on the perovskite surface. Figure  4a  shows the LOS film has an enhanced PL intensity. In the PL mapping images, the intensity of LOS film in the whole 10 × 10 µm 2 region was higher than that of control film (Supplementary Fig.  11 ), clarifying that the PbC 2 O 4 uniformly passivates the perovskite film. The carrier lifetimes are determined through fitting the TRPL decays to a mono-exponential function (Fig.  4b ). The LOS film shows a carrier lifetime of 5.2 μs which is much longer than the control film with a carrier lifetime of 0.9 μs, demonstrating the reduced nonradiative recombination at the surface. To study the effect of lead oxalate layer on the device performance, a conventional n-i-p structure of FTO/TiO 2 /SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/Au was adopted. We used formamidinium chloride (FACl) as the additive instead of methylamine hydrochloride (MACl) in the perovskite precursor to achieve better device performance since FACl can result into better crystalline quality and avoid broadening the bandgap of FAPbI 3  35  (detailed comparisons are shown in Supplementary Figs. 12-14). The IPA was selected as an antisolvent since it resulted in better crystal quality and higher preferred orientation in perovskite films in comparation with the diethyl ether (DE) or chlorobenzene (CB)  36  (Supplementary Figs.  15  and 16 ). The thickness of PbC 2 O 4 was carefully optimized through regulating the oxalic acid concentrations to well balance the defect passivation and charge transport (Supplementary Fig.  17 ). The cross-sectional SEM images of the post-optimized control and LOS devices are shown in Supplementary Fig.  18 . The typical current density-voltage (J-V) curves of the control and LOS devices are shown in Fig.  4c , with the extracted parameters given in Supplementary Table  3 . The control cell had a maximum power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 23.43% (22.94%) with a J sc of 25.75 mA cm -2 (25.74 mA cm -2 ), a V oc of 1.16 V (1.16 V) and a fill factor (FF) of 78.40% (76.69%) from reverse (forward) scan. The LOS PSC had a maximum PCE of 25.39% (24.79%) with a J sc of 25.77 mA cm -2 (25.77 mA cm -2 ), a V oc of 1.18 V (1.18 V) and an FF of 83.50% (81.52%) from reverse (forward) scan. The LOS device achieved a certified photovoltaic performance of 24.92% at a credible third-party photovoltaic laboratory (Supplementary Fig.  19 ). The external quantum efficiency (EQE) yielded an integrated J sc of 24.90 mA cm -2 for the control and 25.18 mA cm -2 for the LOS PSCs, respectively, which matched well with the measured J sc under AM 1.5 G standard  As shown in Fig.  4e , the relationship between V oc and light intensity was calculated to investigate the effect of PbC 2 O 4 on trapassisted surface recombination. The slope of the fitting line for LOS device was 1.16 k B T/q, which was lower than that of control device (1.31 k B T/q), confirming that LOS was beneficial to suppress the trapassisted surface recombination. We employed the space charge limited current (SCLC) technique to quantitatively measure the defect densities of the perovskite films through measuring the dark I-V curves of hole-only devices (ITO/PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/spiro-OMe-TAD/Au), as shown in Fig.  4f . The trap densities were calculated through employing the formula of N t = 2ε 0 εV TFL /eL 2 , where ε is the relative dielectric constant of perovskite film, ε 0 is the vacuum permittivity, V TFL is the trap filled limit voltage, e is the charge, and L is the thickness of the perovskite film (650 nm). The defect density of LOS device was calculated to be1.450 × 10 15 cm -3 , which was lower than that of the control device with 1.795 × 10 15 cm -3 . </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38242</offset>
      <text> Stability of PSCs The unencapsulated devices were tested at the maximum power point (MPP) under full-sun illumination in a nitrogen atmosphere to explore its long-term operational stability (Fig.  5a ). The LOS device maintained 92% of its maximum efficiency after 550 h, while the control device degraded to 60% of its initial performance. The elemental distributions in the aged device were measured by time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectrometry (ToF-SIMS) measurement (Fig.  5b, c ). Large accumulations of iodine can be seen for the control device along the top gold region. The inert gases protected condition ruled out environmental degradation factors, such as moisture and oxygen, indicating that intrinsic mechanisms (i.e., ion migration) were responsible. According to the ToF-SIMS results, I -and AuI 2 -ions were found in the Au electrode, indicating that I diffused from perovskite to Au. Both the signal intensities of I -and AuI 2 -ions in control device were approximately ten times higher than those of LOS sample. Previous report demonstrated that the ion penetration can lead to rapid degradation in hole conductivity of spiro-OMeTAD and chemical corrosion of the top electrode layer, which deteriorates the interface contact in the devices  37, 38  . We peeled the Au electrode and washed the spiro-OMeTAD layer from the substrates by chlorobenzene solution. Then, we performed grazing incidence x-ray diffraction (GIXRD) characterization on the films (Fig.  5d ). The results showed that an obvious diffraction peak located at 11.8°in the control film while there was no new peak in the LOS sample. It demonstrated that the massive loss of I ions from the control films induced the generation of δ-phase while this process was obviously suppressed in the LOS films. The temperature dependent conductivity was measured to confirm that ion migration can be suppressed by the PbC 2 O 4 (Supplementary Fig.  21 ). The activation energy (E a ) for the ion migration was determined by measuring the conductivity (σ) changes of FAPbI 3 films at different temperatures (T) with the Nernst-Einstein relation: σT = σ 0 exp(-E a /k B T), where σ 0 is a constant, k B is the Boltzmann's constant.  We derived E a values from the slope of the ln(σT) versus 1/T of ~0.283 eV for the control and 0.419 eV for the LOS device. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40585</offset>
      <text> Discussion In summary, we give the theoretical framework for revealing the degradation pathway of the FAPbI 3 perovskite and the effect of various defects on the energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition. Among these defects, V I defects are theoretically predicted to be liable to induce the α-to-δ phase transition. The water-insoluble and chemically stable PbC   </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40956</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication The ITO or FTO substrates (1.5 × 1.5 cm 2 ) were cleaned ultrasonically with detergent, acetone, and ethanol for 10 min, respectively, then drying under nitrogen flow. A dense blocking layer of TiO 2 was deposited onto FTO substrate using titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) in ethanol (1/25, v/v) at 500 °C for 60 min. The SnO 2 colloidal dispersion was diluted with deionized water in a volume ratio of 1:5. The clean substrate that treated under UV-Ozone for 20 min was spin-coated with a thin layer of SnO 2 nanoparticle film at 4000 rpm for 30 s, then it was preheated at 150 °C for 30 min. For the perovskite precursor solution, 275.2 mg FAI, 737.6 mg PbI 2 , and FACl (20% mol) were dissolved in an DMF/DMSO (15/1) mixed solvent. The perovskite layer was fabricated by spin-coating 40 μL perovskite precursor solution on top of the UV-Ozone treated SnO 2 layer at a speed of 5000 rpm for 25 s in ambient air. At 5 s from the last, 50 μL MACl IPA solution (4 mg mL -1 ) as an antisolvent was rapidly dropped onto the substrate. Then the as fabricated film was annealed at 150 °C for 20 min, and followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. After the perovskite film was cooled down to room temperature, H 2 C 2 O 4 solution (1, 2, 4 mg in 1 mL IPA) was spin-coated at 4000 rpm for 30 s for passivating perovskite surface. The spiro-OMeTAD solution prepared by mixing 72.3 mg spiro-OMeTAD, 1 mL CB, 27 μL tBP and 17.5 μL Li-TFSI (520 mg in 1 mL acetonitrile) was spin-coated on the films at 4000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, 100 nm Au layer was evaporated under vacuum at rates of 0.05 nm s -1 (0~1 nm), 0.1 nm s -1 (2~15 nm) and 0.5 nm s -1 (16~100 nm). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42647</offset>
      <text> Device characterization The J-V characteristics of perovskite solar cells were measured using a Keithley 2400 meter under the illumination of the solar simulator (SS-X50) at a light intensity of 100 mW cm -2 as checked with a calibrated standard silicon solar cell. Unless otherwise stated, the J-V curves were all measured in a nitrogen-filled glovebox with forward and reverse scan modes (voltage steps of 20 mV and a delay time of 10 ms) at room temperature (~25 °C). A shadow mask was used to define an effective area of 0.067 cm 2 for the measured PSCs. EQE measurements were performed in ambient air using a PVE300-IVT210 system (Industrial Vision Technology (s) Pte Ltd) with monochromatic light focused on a device. For the device stability, the test of the non-encapsulated solar cell was carried in a nitrogen glovebox under 100 mW cm -2 without UV filter. The ToF-SIMS was measured by PHI nanoTOFII Time-of-Flight SIMS. The depth profiling was obtained through a 4 KV Ar ion gun of 400 × 400 µm area. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43663</offset>
      <text> Film characterization X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurement was carried out on a Thermo-VG Scientific (ESCALAB 250) system with a monochromatized Al Kα (for XPS mode) under a pressure of 5.0 × 10 -7 Pa. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) was performed on a JEOL-JSM-6330F system. The surface morphology and roughness of the perovskite film were collected by atomic force microscope (AFM) (Bruker Dimension FastScan). STEM and HAADF-STEM was performed on FEI titan Themis STEM. UV-Vis absorption spectra were measured by UV-3600Plus (Shimadzu). Space charge limited current (SCLC) was recorded on Keithley 2400 meter. Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) and time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) decay for carrier lifetime were measured via a Photoluminescence Spectrometer FLS 1000. PL mapping images were measured by Horiba LabRam HR Evolution Raman system. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) was performed by Thermo-Fisher Nicolet NXR 9650 system. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44642</offset>
      <text> Pathway sampling In this work, we utilized the SSW pathway sampling method to explore the phase transition pathway of α-phase to δ-phase. In the SSW method, the movement on the potential surface is guided by the random soft mode (second derivative) direction, which is capable to explore potential energy surface exhaustively and unbiasedly. In this work, the pathway sampling is carried out in a 72-atom supercell, and more than 100 pairs of initial state /final state (IS/FS) are collected in DFT level. Based on the IS/FS pairs datasets, the pathways connecting the initial structure and the final structure can be determined in an atom-to-atom correspondence, then the transition state can be seamlessly located by using the variable-cell double-ended surface walking approach (VC-DESW). After transition state searching, the lowest energy barrier pathways can be determined by sorting the energy barriers. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45556</offset>
      <text> DFT calculations All DFT calculations were performed using VASP (5.3.5 version), where the electron-ion interaction of C, N, H, Pb and I atoms were represented by the projector augmented wave (PAW) scheme. The exchange-correlation functional was described by the generalized gradient approximation in the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof parametrization  39  . The energy cutoff of the plane wave was set to 400 eV. The Monkhorst-Pack k-point mesh is set to (2 × 2 × 1). For all the structures, both lattice and atomic positions were fully optimized until the maximal stress component is below 0.1 GPa and the maximal force component below 0.02 eV/Å. In the surface model, the FAPbI 3 surface are 4 layers, the bottom one-layer atom fixed which mimics the bulk of FAPbI 3 while the top three-layer can move freely during the optimization. The PbC 2 O 4 layer is 1 ML on the I-terminal FAPbI 3 surface with the Pb bonded with one I and four O. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46493</offset>
      <text> Reporting summary Further information on research design is available in the Nature Portfolio Reporting Summary linked to this article. hydrochloride (MACl) in the perovskite precursor to achieve better device performance since FACl can result into better crystalline quality and avoid broadening the bandgap of FAPbI3 36 (detailed comparisons are shown in Supplementary Figs. 12-14). Supplementary Figure 12. SEM images of the perovskite films with (a) FACl and (b) MACl as the perovskite precursor additive. The FACl perovskite film has larger grains than the MACl film. Supplementary Figure 13. UV-vis absorption spectra of the perovskite films with FACl and MACl additive, respectively. The FACl perovskite film showed higher absorbance than MACl perovskite and broaden absorption band edge. Supplementary Figure 14. Typical J-V curves of PSCs using FACl and MACl as the perovskite precursor additive, respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47414</offset>
      <text> Figure 18 . 18 The cross-sectional SEM images of the (a) control and (b) LOS devices. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47501</offset>
      <text> 1 . 1 In the surface model, the FAPbI3 surface are 4 layers, the bottom one-layer atom fixed which mimics the bulk of FAPbI3 while the top three-layer can move freely during the optimization. The PbC2O4 layer is 1 ML on the I-terminal FAPbI3 surface with the Pb bonded with one I (from FAPbI3 surface) and four O (from C2O4 2-). </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47831</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Figure 1 .Supplementary Figure 8 . 18 , high-angle annular dark-field (HAADF) STEM has been used to observe the interface between PbC2O4 and FAPbI3 at atomic level. A pronounced perovskite lattice can be observed and the crystalline region with an interplanar spacings of 0.32 nm was identified as the (200) domain of α-FAPbI3 (Supplementary Fig. 8d) (Nature Energy, 2021, 6, 419-428. Science 2023, 379, 288-294). There was an amorphous region in another side, which should be the PbC2O4. The boundary between FAPbI3 and PbC2O4 can be observed. However, the interface binding at atomic level is not clear since the PbC2O4 layer is amorphous. Similar phenomenon was found in previous reports (Science 365, 473-478 (2019)). The binding picture PbC2O4 on FAPbI3 in DFT. HAADF-STEM of (a) control and (c) LOS perovskite. (b) and (d) are the enlargement of the area within the yellow square in (a) and (b), respectively. The inter-planar spacing of 0.38 nm (b) and 0.32 nm (d) matches the (111) and (002) reflection of the cubic α-FAPbI3 perovskite phase, respectively. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48913</offset>
      <text> Fig. 8 .Supplementary Figure 8 . 88 Fig. 8. Both in control and LOS films, the pronounced perovskite lattice can be observed. The crystalline region with an interplanar spacings of 0.36 nm and 0.32 nm was identified as the (111) and (200) of α-FAPbI3, respectively. (Nature Energy, 2021, 6, 419-428. Science 2023, 379, 288-294) </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49243</offset>
      <text> Figure R1 .Reviewer # 3 ( R13 Figure R1. XRD patterns of the control and LOS films. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49328</offset>
      <text> Figure 2b . 2b Figure 2b. Top-view SEM image of LOS perovskite film. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49398</offset>
      <text> Figure R2 . R2 Figure R2. SEM image of LOS perovskite films treated with a higher concentration of oxalic acid of 4 mg mL -1 . </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49526</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure R3. J-V curves of PSCs without and with bare IPA treated. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49599</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | First-principles calculations studies. a The phase transformation process from left to right is black-phase FAPbI 3 (α-phase), the first interrupting of Pb-I bonds (Int-1), further breaking of Pb-I bonds (Int-2, Int-3, and Int-4), and yellowphase FAPbI 3 (δ-phase). b The energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition of FAPbI 3 based on various native point defects. The dashed line shows the energy barrier of perfect crystal (0.62 eV). c The defect formation energies of native point defects on the Pb-rich perovskite surface. The abscissa is energy barrier of α-to-δ phase transition and the ordinate is the formation energy of defects. The gray, yellow and green shaded parts are Type-I (Low EB-High FE), Type-II (High FE) and Type-III (Low EB-low FE), respectively. d The defect formation energies of V I in control and LOS FAPbI 3 . e The I ion migration barrier in control and LOS FAPbI 3 . f, g The schematic views (left: top views; right: cross-section views) of I ionic migration (orange balls) in f control and g LOS FAPbI 3 (gray, lead; purple (orange), iodine (mobile iodine); brown, carbon; light blue, nitrogen; red, oxygen; light pink, hydrogen). Source data are provided as a Source Data file. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50834</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Morphology and XPS spectra of control and LOS perovskite films. Topview SEM images of a control and b LOS perovskite films. Cross-sectional highresolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) of c control and d LOS perovskite films. High-resolution XPS of e C 1s, f O 1s and g Pb 4f for the perovskite films. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51217</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Stability test of the FAPbI 3 films. a UV-Vis absorption spectra of the toluene solutions in which control and LOS films were immersed under 1-sun illumination for 24 h. Inset is the picture of the vials in which each film was immersed into an equal volume of toluene. UV-Vis absorption spectra of b the control and c LOS films before and after immersed under 1-sun illumination for 24 h. Inset is the picture of the tested films. d XRD patterns of the control and LOS films before and after exposing for 24 h. SEM images of e the control and f LOS films after exposing for 24 h. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51866</offset>
      <text> Fig. 5 | 5 Fig. 5 | Stability of control and LOS PSCs. a Continuous MPP tracking for 575 h of unsealed devices in a nitrogen atmosphere under 1-sun illumination without UV filter. ToF-SIMS of the b I -and c AuI 2 -ions distributions in the control and LOS MPP-aged devices. The yellow, green and orange shadings corresponding to Au, Spiro-OMeTAD and perovskite. d GIXRD of the perovskite films after MPP test. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52325</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 The energy barrier of phase transition and formation energies of native point defects on the surface. Materials: Oxalic acid (H2C2O4, 99.9%) was purchased from Macklin. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52507</offset>
      <text> Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author): </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52545</offset>
      <text> Fig.4| Carrier extraction and photovoltaic characteristics. PL of a steady-state PL and b time-resolved PL spectra of perovskite films on glass substrates. c J-V curves of devices (FTO/TiO 2 /SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/Au). d EQE spectrum and J sc integrated from the EQE spectrum of the best-performing devices. e Light-intensity dependence on V oc plots for the perovskite devices. f The typical SCLC analysis with the hole-only device of ITO/PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/PCBM/Au. V TFL is the trap filled limit voltage. From the data we calculated the trap densities (N t ). Source data are provided as a Source Data file.recombination and boosted the efficiency of the solar cells to 25.39% with improved operation stability. Our results provide the guideline for achieving efficient and stable formamidinium PSCs through inhibiting the defect-induced α-to-δ phase transition. 0 Titanium(IV) isopropoxide (TTIP, 99.999%) was purchased from 0.01 0.1 1 ) s t i n u . Control a b ) LOS s t i n u b r a ( y t i s n e t n I L P . b r a ( y t i Methods s n Materials e t n I Control ave = 0.9 μs 5000 LOS ave = 5.2 μs Sigma-Aldrich. Hydrochloric acid (HCl, 35.0-37.0%) and ethanol 700 750 800 850 900 (anhydrous) were purchased from Guangzhou Chemicals. The SnO 2 10000 c ( -2 ) m c A m y t i s n e d t n e r r u C 20 25 0.0 5 15 10 0 0.2 Control-F 0.4 Control-R 0.6 LOS-F LOS-R 0.8 1.0 1.2 Wavelength (nm) (15 wt% colloidal dispersion tin(IV) oxide) was purchased from Alfa 300 400 500 600 700 800 900 0 20 40 60 80 100 Wavelength (nm) ) % ( E Q E Control LOS 0 5 10 15 20 25 ) d e 1.14 1.16 1.18 ) Aesar. Lead (II) iodide (PbI 2 , 99.99%) was purchased from TCI Shanghai Control LOS 1.16 k B T/q Time (ns) (China). Formamidinium iodide (FAI, ≥99.5%), Formamidinium Chlor-ide (FACl, ≥99.5%), methylamine hydrochloride (MACl, ≥99.5%), 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis-(N, N-di-p-methoxyphenylamine)-9,9′spirobifluorene sc (mA cm -2 1.08 1.10 1.12 V oc V ( 1.31 k B T/q (Spiro-OMeTAD, ≥99.5%), bis(trifluoromethane) sulfon imide lithium salt (Li-TFSI, 99.95%), 4-tertbutylpyridine (tBP, 96%) were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corp. (China). N,Ndi-methylformamide (DMF, 99.8%), dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO, 99.9%), Integrated J isopropanol (IPA, 99.8%), chlorobenzene (CB, 99.8%), acetonitrile 1.06 20 40 Light Intensity (mW cm 60 (ACN) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Oxalic acid (H 2 C 2 O 4 , 10 -2 ) 99.9%) was purchased from Macklin. All chemicals were used as 80 100 ) A ( t n e r r u C f Voltage (V) 0.1 Control 1 Voltage (V) V TFL = 0.173 V 0.01 -5 -4 -3 -2 -1 10 10 10 10 10 10 0 10 1 10 2 LOS N t = 1.450 x 10 15 cm -3 V TFL = 0.214 V N t = 1.795 x 10 15 cm -3 received without any other refinement. </text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55268</offset>
      <text>			 Nature Communications | (2023) 14:6125</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
