<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025026683AFIHEA</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">3</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">3</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 24&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Accelerated aging of all-inorganic, interface-stabilized perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>92</offset>
      <text>To understand degradation routes and improve the stability of perovskite solar cells (PSCs), accelerated aging tests are needed. Here, we use elevated temperatures (up to 110°C) to quantify the accelerated degradation of encapsulated CsPbI 3 PSCs under constant illumination. Incorporating a two-dimensional (2D) Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 capping layer between the perovskite active layer and hole-transport layer stabilizes the interface while increasing power conversion efficiency of the all-inorganic PSCs from 14.9 to 17.4%. Devices with this 2D capping layer did not degrade at 35°C and required &gt;2100 hours at 110°C under constant illumination to degrade by 20% of their initial efficiency. Degradation acceleration factors based on the observed Arrhenius temperature dependence predict intrinsic lifetimes of 51,000 ± 7000 hours (&gt;5 years) operating continuously at 35°C. A lthough the power-conversion efficiencies (PCEs) of metal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) can now exceed 25%, long-term operational instability issues must be addressed before they can be commercialized  (1) (2) (3) . The most stable and efficient PSCs have reported T 80 lifetimes (the time at which the PCE drops to 80% of its initial value) of just a few hundred or thousand hours (4-7) under continuous illumination, versus the &gt;20-year lifetimes required for most commercial applications. Despite an encouraging report of PSCs with a T 80 of more than 1 year, the PCE of the solar cells is relatively low (&lt;13%)  (8) . Accelerated aging tests can facilitate rapid PSC stability screening  (9) (10) (11) . An effective accelerated stress test can quantify the lifetime acceleration factor (AF) that relates the lifetime under a defined standard operating condition to the lifetime under elevated stress conditions. Thermal and highintensity illumination stress tests with AFs have been developed for organic-and siliconbased PVs  (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) , but developing robust AFs for PSCs is challenging given their complex sensitivities to temperature, light, and electrical bias  (10, 16, 17) . Here, we thermally accelerated the degradation of encapsulated CsPbI 3 PSCs operating under constant illumination at their maximum power point (MPP) with temperatures from 35°to 110°C. The PCE degradation rate followed an Arrhenius temperature dependence that was slowed substantially by incorporating a two-dimensional (2D) Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 capping layer between the perovskite active layer and the hole transport layer (HTL). This 2D layer stabilized the perovskite/HTL interface and suppressed ion migration into the HTL, resulting in a T 80 lifetime of &gt;2100 hours at 110°C. With an experimentally determined AF of 24.2 ± 3.5, this lifetime corresponds to an extrapolated T 80 of 5.1 ± 0.7 × 10 4 hours-or more than 5 years of continuous operation at 35°C. The most efficient PSCs have been based on hybrid organic-inorganic perovskites, which contain volatile organic cations, such as methylammonium (MA + ) and formamidinium (FA + ). To maximize the thermal stability and photostability of our solar cells, we chose inorganic CsPbI 3 as the photoabsorber  (18) (19) (20) , despite its solar cells exhibiting slightly lower efficiencies. Inorganic CsPbI 3 PSCs with the structure shown in Fig.  1A  were fabricated both with (capped) and without (uncapped) a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer between the CsPbI 3 absorber and the CuSCN HTL. The all-inorganic stack that includes TiO 2 , Al 2 O 3 , and CuSCN transport layers, as well as fluorinated tin oxide (FTO) and Cr/Au electrodes, was designed to maximize the thermal stability and photostability of these devices, as discussed in supplementary text  1   the highest among fully inorganic PSCs in which all the functional materials in the stack are inorganic. Depositing a thin 2D perovskite capping layer can stabilize the surfaces of organicinorganic hybrid perovskites, such as FAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3  (21) , but this approach has not yet been successfully implemented with inorganic perovskites. This challenge stems from the stronger binding strength of Cs + compared to MA + or FA + , which prevents cation exchange between the Cs + of CsPbI 3 and the organic ligands in the applied hybrid organic-inorganic 2D perovskite precursor solution  (22) (23) (24) (25) . To avoid this problem, we deposited a fully inorganic Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 2D layer by treating the CsPbI 3 surface with a CsCl solution followed by thermal annealing. Grazing-incidence wideangle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) patterns (Fig.  2A  and fig.  S4 ) showed two new reflections emerging on CsPbI 3 films after CsCl treatment corresponding to the (002) and (004) reflections of 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 . Increasing the incident angle of the x-ray beam resulted in a decrease in the relative intensity of these reflections (Fig.  2B ), suggesting that the 2D layer formed preferentially on the CsPbI 3 surface. The interfacial nature of this 2D layer was also confirmed by cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) imaging of the device (fig.  S5 ). We esti-mated the thickness of the capping layer to be 20 nm by tracking chlorine content on the film surface with x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) while depth etching (Fig.  2C ). To study the surface passivation effect of this capping layer, we measured time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) transients (Fig.  2D ). The lifetime of the device increased from 14 to &gt;62 ns in the presence of the capping layer, suggesting that it effectively suppressed nonradiative recombination at the CsPbI 3 surface and extended the lifetime and diffusion length of charge carriers  (26) . This observation is consistent with the observed V OC increase in capped PSCs (Fig.  1B ), whose PV characteristics are tabulated in table  S1 . This trend was also comparable to previous reports of 2D and 3D PSCs based on organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites that benefited from surface passivation  (26) (27) (28) . To evaluate the stability of capped and uncapped PSCs, N 2 -encapsulated solar cells (fig.  S6 ) with both structures were aged at their MPP under illumination from a metal halide solar simulator (spectrum shown in fig.  S7 ) at 35°, 59°, 85°, and 110°C. Our stability studies used solar cells having the same device configuration as those for PV characterization, including encapsulation and the light aperture. The evolution of the normalized PCE (averaged from three subcells) for both device types at these operating temperatures, and the evolution for the unnormalized data, normalized short-circuit current (J SC ), V OC , FF, and external quantum efficiency (EQE), are shown in figs. S8 to S10. Figure  S11  shows the operational stability of 2D and 3D PSCs without encapsulation operating at 110°C, confirming the robustness of our solar cell packaging. Heating the solar cells reversibly reduced their PCEs  (29) , which accounts for the differences in the initial PCE of the unnormalized data set in fig.  S8 . We observe a clear temperature dependence of the PCE degradation rate that can be fitted to a biexponential function of the form PCE t ð Þ ¼ A1Ãexp Àk fast Â t ð Þ þ A2Ãexp Àk slow Â t ð ÞþB ð1Þ with a fast and slow degradation rate, k fast and k slow . Here, A1, A2, and B are constants and t is time. We fit the data collected across the temperature range using this function with an R 2 &gt; 0.95, except for the data acquired on the capped solar cells operating at 35°C because no PCE degradation was observed, even after 3531 hours of continuous operation (Fig.  3B ). To estimate an activation energy for the degradation processes corresponding to k fast and k slow , we assume an Arrhenius temperature dependence to the degradation rates k T ð Þ ¼ Aexp ÀE a k B T ð2Þ where k(T) is a degradation rate at temperature T, A is constant, E a is the activation energy of degradation, and k B is Boltzmann's constant  (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) . Rearranging Eq. 2, the activation energy is equivalent to the slope: E a ¼ À @ln k T ð Þ ð Þ @ 1 kBT ð3Þ The temperature-dependent degradation rates were plotted as a function of inverse temperature in Fig.  3C  and fitted to Eq. 3. Degradation rates could be adequately described by a single Arrhenius function across the entire temperature range. This finding suggested that the same degradation mechanism dominated the entire temperature range, which is an important criterion for a reliable accelerated aging test  (9) . We observed that the activation energies associated with the fast and slow degradation of each type of PSC were comparable, suggesting that the two degradation rates probed a single physical process. As we will discuss in detail below, we speculate that ion migration is the dominant degradation mechanism. The E a 's that describe the degradation for capped PSCs are nearly twice those for uncapped PSCs, suggesting that the 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer stabilizes the devices against thermal degradation stemming from ion migration.  To extract a meaningful degradation rate at standard operating conditions, k ref , from the accelerated degradation rate at high temperatures, k acc , we define an AF  (11) : AF ¼ k acc k ref ¼ exp E a k B 1 T ref À 1 T acc ð4Þ where T acc and T ref are the operating temperatures during aging at accelerated and standard operating conditions (defined as 1 sun intensity, 35°C). Because k slow is primarily responsible for long-term degradation and the E a 's of the two rates are nearly identical, we used the E a extracted from k slow and Eq. 4 to obtain AFs for each T acc (specifically 59°, 85°, and 110°C) (Fig.  3D ). On the basis of these AFs, we can define an equivalent operating time at T ref = 35°C for devices aged at elevated temperatures by multiplying their aging time by the acceleration factor (Fig.  3, E  and F ). When processed in this manner, all of the data collapsed onto a universal curve for both capped and uncapped solar cells, which further confirmed that the same mechanism, albeit hastened at elevated temperatures, was responsible for degradation across the entire temperature range. With this dataset, we can make T 80 lifetime predictions for capped devices operating at 35°C. This estimate is critical because devices aged at these conditions do not show any PCE degradation, even after continuous operation for 3531 hours. Given that the average experimentally measured T 80 for capped solar cells operating continuously at 110°C is 2100 hours (Fig.  3B ), and the AF for the capped solar cells at 110°C is 24.2 ± 3.5, we estimated a T 80 of 5.1 ± 0.7 × 10 4 hours at 35°C. To investigate the origins of PSC degradation, we aged full-stack devices at 110°C under continuous illumination before peeling off their top electrodes and characterizing the structure of the active layers with x-ray diffraction (XRD). As shown in Fig.  4, A  and B , the reflection at 2q = 16.15°corresponding to the (003) reflection of CuSCN in the XRD trace of the uncapped PSCs became broader and less intense after 2000 hours of aging, which suggested a decrease in the CuSCN crystallite size. Clear degradation of the CuSCN surface in aged, uncapped PSCs was also visible in the SEM images in fig.  S12 , which show the formation of pinholes and decreased film uniformity. Correspondingly, the I 3d signal increased substantially in the XPS spectrum of the aged HTL surface (Fig.  4C ). These results suggest that iodine migration from the CsPbI 3 active layer was responsible for the structural changes in CuSCN in uncapped solar cells, as discussed in supplementary text 2 and figs. S13 and S14. By contrast, the film structure and morphology of CuSCN in capped PSCs did not show appreciable changes after the same duration, as shown in their XRD patterns and SEM images (Fig.  4 , A and B, and fig.  S12 ), and we did not observe any appreciable I 3d signal in the XPS spectrum of the HTL surface of capped PSCs (Fig.  4C ). To quantify the ease of ion migration in capped and uncapped films, we measured the temperature-dependent conductivity in two-terminal lateral devices, a widely used method for characterizing ion migration in perovskite films  (4, 30, 31) . The activation   s T ð Þ ¼ s 0 T exp ÀE a;ion k B T ð5Þ where s 0 is a temperature-independent prefactor  (30, 31) . Plotting 1/T versus ln(sT), two distinct regions were present in both capped and uncapped films corresponding to two dis-tinct transport regimes. The high-temperature linear regime, corresponding to ion-dominated transport, was used to extract an approximate E a,ion (Fig.  4D ). Similar to the activation of degradation, the E a,ion of the capped film is nearly twice that of the uncapped film, indicating that the 2D cap frustrated ion migration. Suppressed ion migration likely stems from passivation of iodine vacancies at the surface of the perovskite active layer in the presence of a 2D capping layer (  Although the power-conversion efficiencies (PCEs) of metal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) can now exceed 25%, longterm operational instability issues must be addressed before they can be commercialized (1-3). The most stable and efficient PSCs have reported T 80 lifetimes (the time at which the PCE drops to 80% of its initial value) of just a few hundred or thousand hours (4-7) under continuous illumination, versus the &gt;20 year lifetimes required for most commercial applications. While there is an encouraging report of PSCs with a T 80 of more than one year, the PCE of the solar cells is relatively low (&lt;13%)  (8) . Accelerated aging tests can facilitate rapid PSC stability screening  (9) (10) (11) . An effective accelerated stress test can quantify the lifetime acceleration factor (AF) that relates the lifetime under a defined standard operating condition to the lifetime under elevated stress conditions. Thermal and high-intensity illumination stress tests with AFs have been developed for organic-and silicon-based PVs  (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) , but developing robust AFs for PSCs is challenging given their complex sensitivities to temperature, light, and electrical bias  (10, 16, 17) . Here, we thermally accelerated the degradation of encapsulated CsPbI3 PSCs operating under constant illumination at their maximum power point (MPP) with temperatures from 35° to 110°C. The PCE degradation rate followed an Arrhenius temperature dependence that was slowed substantially by incorporating a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 capping layer between the perovskite active layer and the hole transport layer (HTL). This 2D layer stabilized the perovskite/HTL interface and suppressed ion migration into the HTL, resulting in a T 80 lifetime of &gt; 2100 hours at 110°C. With an experimentally determined AF of 24.2 ± 3.5, this lifetime corresponds to an extrapolated T 80 of 5.1 ± 0.7 × 10 4 hours-or more than 5 yr of continuous operation at 35°C. The most efficient PSCs have been based on hybrid organic-inorganic perovskites, which contain volatile organic cations, such as methylammonium (MA + ) and formamidinium (FA + ). To maximize the thermal and photostability of our solar cells, we chose inorganic CsPbI 3 as the photo-absorber  (18) (19) (20) , despite its solar cells exhibiting slightly lower efficiencies. Inorganic CsPbI 3 PSCs with the structure shown in Fig.  1A  were fabricated both with (capped) and without (uncapped) a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer between the CsPbI 3 absorber and the CuSCN HTL. The all-inorganic stack that includes TiO 2 , Al 2 O 3 , and CuSCN transport layers as well as fluorinated tin oxide (FTO) and Cr/Au electrodes was designed to maximize the thermal and photostability of these devices, as discussed in supplementary text 1 and fig.  S1 . Photovoltaic characterization of representative as-fabricated devices are shown in Fig.  1, B  and C , fig.  S2 , and listed in table  S1 ; with population statistics as shown in fig.  S3 . Capped PSCs have improved fill factors (FF's) and open-circuit voltages (VOC's), leading to a champion PCE of 17.4% compared with 14.9% for uncapped devices. This PCE is the highest among fully-inorganic PSCs in which all the functional materials in the stack are inorganic. Depositing a thin 2D perovskite capping layer can stabilize the surfaces of organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites, such as FAPbI3 and MAPbI 3  (21) , but this approach has not yet Accelerated aging of all-inorganic, interface-stabilized perovskite solar cells Xiaoming Zhao 1 , Tianran Liu 1,2 , Quinn C. Burlingame 3 , Tianjun Liu 4 , Rudolph Holley III 1 , Guangming Cheng 5 , Nan Yao 5 , Feng Gao 4 , Yueh-Lin Loo 1 * 1 Department of Chemical and Biological Engineering, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544, USA. 2 Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544, USA. 3 Andlinger Center for Energy and the Environment, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544, USA. 4 Department of Physics, Chemistry, and Biology (IFM), Linköping University, Linköping, SE-58183, Sweden. 5 Princeton Institute for the Science and Technology of Materials, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544, USA. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CsPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:16:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="326" length="7"/>
        <text>CsPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Dicesium diiodo dichloro plumbate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-21T02:42:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="405" length="15"/>
        <text>Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:41:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="605" length="4"/>
        <text>17.4</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">copper(I) thiocyanate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:43:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="3498" length="5"/>
        <text>CuSCN</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Titanium dioxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:43:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="3547" length="5"/>
        <text>TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17260</offset>
      <text> *Corresponding author. Email: lloo@princeton.edu To understand degradation routes and improve the stability of perovskite solar cells (PSCs), accelerated aging tests are needed. Here, we use elevated temperatures (up to 110 Celsius) to quantify the accelerated degradation of encapsulated CsPbI 3 PSCs under constant illumination. Incorporating a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 capping layer between the perovskite active layer and hole-transport layer stabilizes the interface while increasing power conversion efficiency of the all-inorganic PSCs from 14.9% to 17.4%. Devices with this 2D capping layer did not degrade at 35 Celsius and required &gt;2100 hours at 110 Celsius under constant illumination to degrade by 20% of their initial efficiency. Degradation acceleration factors based on the observed Arrhenius temperature dependence predict intrinsic lifetimes of 51,000 ± 7,000 hours (&gt;5 years) operating continuously at 35 Celsius. been successfully implemented with inorganic perovskites. This challenge stems from the stronger binding strength of Cs + compared to MA + or FA + , which prevents cation exchange between the Cs + of CsPbI 3 and the organic ligands in the applied hybrid organic/inorganic 2D perovskite precursor solution  (22) (23) (24) (25) . To avoid this problem, we deposited a fully inorganic Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 2D layer by treating the CsPbI 3 surface with a CsCl solution followed by thermally annealing. Grazing-incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) patterns (Fig.  2A  and fig.  S4 ) showed two new reflections emerging on CsPbI 3 films after CsCl treatment corresponding to the (002) and (004) reflections of 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 . Increasing the incident angle of the x-ray beam resulted a decrease in the relative intensity of these reflections (Fig.  2B ), suggesting that the 2D layer formed preferentially on the CsPbI 3 surface. The interfacial nature of this 2D layer was also confirmed by crosssectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) imaging of the device (fig.  S5 ). We estimated the thickness of the capping layer to be 20 nm by tracking chlorine content on the film surface with x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) while depth etching (Fig.  2C ). To study the surface passivation effect of this capping layer, we measured time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) transients (Fig.  2D ). The lifetime of the device increased from 14 ns to &gt;62 ns in the presence of the capping layer, suggesting that it effectively suppressed non-radiative recombination at the CsPbI3 surface and extended the lifetime and diffusion length of charge carriers  (26) . This observation is consistent with the observed V OC increase in capped PSCs, (Fig.  1B ), and whose PV characteristics are tabulated in table  S1 . This trend was also comparable to previous reports of 2D/3D PSCs based on organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites that benefited from surface passivation  (26) (27) (28) . To evaluate the stability of capped and uncapped PSCs, N2-encapsulated solar cells (fig.  S6 ) with both structures were aged at their maximum power point (MPP) under illumination from a metal halide solar simulator (spectrum shown in fig.  S7 ) at 35°, 59°, 85°, and 110°C. Our stability studies employed solar cells having the same device configuration as those for PV characterization, including encapsulation and the light aperture. The evolution of the normalized PCE (averaged from 3 subcells) for both device types at these operating temperatures, and the evolution for the unnormalized data, normalized short-circuit current (JSC), V OC , FF, and EQE is shown in figs. S8 to S10. Figure  S11  shows the operational stability of 2D/3D PSCs without encapsulation operating at 110°C, confirming the robustness of our solar cell packaging. Heating the solar cells reversibly reduced their PCEs  (29) , which accounts for the differences in the initial PCE of the un-normalized data set in fig.  S8 . We observe a clear temperature dependence of the PCE degradation rate that can be fitted to a bi-exponential function of the form: ( ) ( ) ( ) 1*exp 2*exp fast slow PCE t A k t A k t B = - × + - × + (1) with a fast and slow degradation rate, k fast and k slow . Here, A1, A2 and B are constants and t is time. We fit the data collected across the temperature range using this function with an R 2 &gt; 0.95, except for the data acquired on the capped solar cells operating at 35°C because no PCE degradation was observed, even after 3531 hr of continuous operation (Fig.  3B ). To estimate an activation energy for the degradation processes corresponding to k fast and k slow , we assume an Arrhenius temperature dependence to the degradation rates: ( ) a B E k T Aexp k T   - =     (2) where k(T) is a degradation rate at temperature T, A is constant, E a is the activation energy of degradation, and k B is Boltzmann's constant  (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) . Rearranging Eq. (  2 ), the activation energy is equivalent to the slope: ( ) ( ) ln 1 a B k T E k T ∂ = -   ∂     (3) The temperature-dependent degradation rates were plotted as a function of inverse temperature in Fig.  3C  and fitted to Eq.  (3) . Degradation rates could be adequately described by a single Arrhenius function across the entire temperature range. This finding suggested that the same degradation mechanism dominated the entire temperature range, which is an important criteria for a reliable accelerated aging test  (9) . We observed that the activation energies associated with the fast and slow degradation of each type of PSC were comparable, suggesting that the two degradation rates probed a single physical process. As we will discuss in detail below, we speculate that ion migration is the dominant degradation mechanism. The Ea that describe the degradation for capped PSCs are nearly twice those for uncapped PSCs, suggesting that the 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer stabilizes the devices against thermal degradation stemming from ion migration. To extract a meaningful degradation rate at standard operating conditions, k ref , from the accelerated degradation rate at high temperatures, k acc , we define an AF (11): 1 1 exp acc a ref B ref acc k E AF k k T T       = = -           (4) where T acc and T ref are the operating temperatures during aging at accelerated and standard operating conditions (defined as 1 sun intensity, 35°C). Because k slow is primarily responsible for long-term degradation and the E a s of the two rates are nearly identical, we used the E a extracted from k slow and Eq. (  4 ) to obtain AFs for each T acc (specifically 59°, 85°, and 110°C) (Fig.  3D ). Based on these AFs, we can define an equivalent operating time at T ref = 35°C for devices aged at elevated temperatures by multiplying their aging time by the acceleration factor (Fig.  3, E  and F ). When processed in this manner, all of the data collapsed onto a universal curve for both capped and uncapped solar cells, which further confirmed that the same mechanism, albeit hastened at elevated temperatures, was responsible for degradation across the entire temperature range. With this data set, we can make T 80 lifetime predictions for capped devices operating at 35°C. This estimate is critical since devices aged at these conditions do not show any PCE degradation, even after continuous operation for 3531 hr. Given that the average experimentally measured T 80 for capped solar cells operating continuously at 110°C is 2100 hours (Fig.  3B ), and the AF for the capped solar cells at 110°C is 24.2 ± 3.5, we estimated a T 80 of 5.1 ± 0.7 × 10 4 hr at 35°C. In order to investigate the origins of PSC degradation, we aged full-stack devices at 110°C under continuous illumination before peeling off their top electrodes and characterizing the structure of the active layers with x-ray diffraction (XRD). As shown in Fig.  4, A  and B , the reflection at 2θ = 16.15° corresponding to the (003) reflection of CuSCN in the XRD trace of the uncapped PSCs became broader and less intense after 2000 hours of aging, which suggested a decrease in the CuSCN crystallite size. Clear degradation of the CuSCN surface in aged, uncapped PSCs was also visible in the SEM images in fig.  S12 , which show the formation of pinholes and decreased film uniformity. Correspondingly, the I 3d signal increased substantially in the XPS spectrum of the aged HTL surface (Fig.  4C ). These results suggest that iodine migration from the CsPbI3 active layer was responsible for the structural changes in CuSCN in uncapped solar cells, as discussed in supplementary text 2 and figs. S13 and S14. In contrast, the film structure and morphology of CuSCN in capped PSCs did not show appreciable changes after the same duration, as shown in their XRD patterns and SEM images (Fig.  4, A  and B , and fig.  S12 ), and we did not observe any appreciable I 3d signal in the XPS spectrum of the HTL surface of capped PSCs (Fig.  4C ). To quantify the ease of ion migration in capped and uncapped films, we measured the temperature-dependent conductivity in two-terminal lateral devices, a widely used method for characterizing ion migration in perovskite films  (4, 30, 31) . The activation energy of ion migration (Ea,ion) values were extracted by fitting the measured temperature-dependent conductivity (σ) to the Nernst-Einstein equation, ( ) , 0 σ σ exp a ion B E T T k T -   =     (5) where σ 0 is a temperature-independent pre-factor  (30, 31) . Plotting 1/T vs. ln(σT), two distinct regions were present in both capped and uncapped films corresponding to two distinct transport regimes. The high-temperature linear regime, corresponding to ion-dominated transport, was used to extract an approximate E a,ion (Fig.  4D ). Similar to the activation of degradation, the E a,ion of the capped film is nearly twice that of the uncapped film indicating that the 2D cap frustrated ion migration. Suppressed ion migration likely stems from passivation of iodine vacancies at the surface of the perovskite active layer in the presence of a 2D capping layer  (4, 32, 33) , as shown in fig.  S15 .    &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:48:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="17403" length="188"/>
        <text>accelerated aging tests are needed. Here, we use elevated temperatures (up to 110 Celsius) to quantify the accelerated degradation of encapsulated CsPbI 3 PSCs under constant illumination.</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Dicesium diiodo dichloro plumbate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-21T02:42:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="17611" length="15"/>
        <text>Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">14.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:46:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="17803" length="4"/>
        <text>14.9</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:46:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="17812" length="5"/>
        <text>17.4%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2100</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:48:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="17898" length="4"/>
        <text>2100</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">110</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T05:48:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="17912" length="3"/>
        <text>110</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">80</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:07:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="17955" length="14"/>
        <text>degrade by 20%</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-21T02:44:24Z</infon>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27457</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27481</offset>
      <text> Materials PbI2 (99.99%) was purchased from TCI America. CsI (99.5%) was purchased from Sigma Aldrich. DMF (&gt;99.8%), DMSO (&gt;99.8%), MeOH (&gt;99.8%) and IPA (&gt;99.8%) were purchased from Acros Organics. Acetylacetone (&gt;99%), Polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP, Mw 10,000), titanium diisopropoxide (75 wt. % in isopropanol), aluminum acetylacetonate (99.999%), CuSCN (&gt;99%), diethyl sulfide (98%), HI aqueous solution (57 wt%) were purchased from Sigma Aldrich. Acetone, ethanol and other solvents were purchased from Fisher Scientific. All chemicals were used as-received without further purification. We used pre-patterned fluorine-doped tin-oxidecoated (FTO) glass (7 Ω /square) obtained from Yingkou Advanced Election Technology Co., Ltd as substrates. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28226</offset>
      <text> Synthesis CsPbI3 crystals were synthesized following modification to a reported procedure  (34) . Briefly, CsI and PbI2 with molar ration of 1:1.05 were dissolved in HI aqueous solution at a concentration of 30 mg/mL by stirring at 80 °C overnight. The obtained solution was slowly cooled from 80 °C to 30 °C at a rate of 1 °C/h to result in needle-like yellow crystals, which were filtered and washed by copious amount of diethyl ether. The crystals were grounded and dried in a vacuum oven overnight at 40°C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28744</offset>
      <text> Preparation of CsPbI3 precursor solutions and spin-coating procedures CsPbI3 precursor solutions were prepared in an nitrogen-filled glovebox following modification to a method reported in the literature  (35) . Briefly, 20 w% of PVP in a DMF/DMSO (V/V=4:6) mixture was stirred for 30 min at room temperature. 0.6 M CsPbI3 precursor solution was prepared by dissolving CsPbI3 powder in the abovementioned solution and stirring at 70 °C for 1 hour. To prepare nanocrystalline CsPbI3 films, the precursor solution was cast on a 100 °C pre-heated substrate and then spun at 3000 rpm for 30 s. Then the films were thermally annealed at 300 °C for 5 minutes. After cooling down to room temperature, the films were immersed in IPA for 1 hour to remove PVP. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29500</offset>
      <text> Device Fabrication Perovskite solar cells were fabricated on pre-patterned FTO glass substrates. The substrates were cleaned with deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol and UV-Ozone cleaner, each step taking substrate to increase the penetration depth. A custom-made Pilatus-800K detector was placed at the distance of 257 mm from the sample to capture 2D-GIWAXS images with an exposure time of 10 s. All 2D-GIWAXS images have been background subtracted. Ion migration activation energies were measured and extracted following reported methods  (30, 37, 38) . We used lateral devices with structures of Au/perovskite/Au with channel length of 100 μm for these measurements. The conductivity of these devices was measured by applying a 20 V bias, corresponding to an average electrical field of 0.2 V/μm, under 10 -6 Torr vacuum on a Lake Shore tabletop cryogenic probe station with a Keithley 4200-SCS semiconductor parameter analyzer. Sample temperature was controlled in a close-circle cryostat from 150 to 350 K. We first cooled the device to 150 K and waited an hour for the temperature to stabilize. Subsequently, the device was heated to and stabilized at each temperature for 10 min before current measurements were performed. To avoid transient current spikes, which occurred in the first few seconds after bias, the conductivity was extracted from the device current at 120s after the bias was applied. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30919</offset>
      <text> Solar Cell Characterization The current density-voltage (J-V) characteristics of the photovoltaic devices were measured using a Keithley 2635 source-measurement unit. A 300 W Xe arc lamp with an AM 1.5G filter was used as a solar simulator for calibrated photovoltaic efficiency measurements. The intensity of the lamp was calibrated with an NIST-traceable Si photodetector, leading to a mismatch factor, M (39, 40), of 1.01 when measuring PSCs. A light aperture the size of the active area (0.16 cm 2 ) was used. The device substrate and light mask were of the same size to ensure alignment. External quantum efficiency measurements were performed using a 300 W Xenon arc lamp (Newport Oriel) without bias light, with light filtered with a Cornerstone 260 1/4 M double-grating monochromator (Newport 74125). A silicon photodiode (model 71580) calibrated at Newport was used as the reference cell. The step size for EQE measurements is 5 nm. The J-V and EQE measurements of all devices were performed on encapsulated cells in ambient without any preconditioning. The scan rate and dwell time were 0.01 V s -1 and 0.05 s (reverse scan: 1.3 to -0.2 V, forward scan: -0.2 to 1.3 V), respectively. The J-V and EQE measurements of all devices were performed on encapsulated cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32197</offset>
      <text> Encapsulation and stability measurements under continuous illumination Devices were encapsulated in a nitrogen glovebox. A photograph of an encapsulated solar cell and its associate scheme are shown in Figure  S6 . PMMA (20 mg mL -1 in toluene) was first spin-coated on the surface of cells. Then, Cytop was blade-coated atop PMMA. Finally, the device stacks were encapsulated using a cover glass with a UV-curable epoxy (Epoxy Technology, OG159-2) applied along its perimeter. A piece of black tape was attached to the exterior of the cover glass to protect the solar cell during UV curing. Stability studies were conducted according to the ISOS-L-3 protocol  (9) . Encapsulated devices were mounted on homebuilt printed circuit boards and connected to a Keithley 2401 and a Keithley 2700 with two 7705 multiplexer units. Devices were aged under continuous illumination from a Philips metal-halide lamp (Philips MSR 1200 HR). The lamp spectrum shown in Figure  S7  was monitored by a calibrated Ocean Optics spectral radiometer throughout the aging test and no significant changes in the spectrum were observed. The EQE spectra of cells were regularly measured (Figure  S10 ) to account for lamp intensity fluctuations during aging. For testing at 35 ± 2 °C, the devices were mounted directly on the solar station. For testing at 59 ± 1, 85 ± 2 and 110 ± 3 °C, these devices were mounted on hotplates. The temperature of the solar cells was measured on the top cell surface using a thermocouple regularly. The relative humidity of our solar stability testing station was recorded daily with a calibrated hygrometer (SensorPush HTP.XW). The current density versus voltage (J-V) characteristics were measured every 60 minutes. The initial values at the maximum power point (MPP) were obtained from each J-V sweep, and then the devices were kept at the MPP during operation by an active load system developed by infinityPV ApS.              These under-coordinated lead (and halide vacancies) can cause donor defects on the surface, resulting in downward band bending and an increased number of recombination centers  (54, 55) . In the Pb4f XPS spectrum of capped films, we observed a shift of the main Pb peaks toward higher binding energies, which is indicative of the formation of stronger ionic bonding (4), likely due to stronger bonding between Pb 2+ and Cl -ions compared to that between Pb 2+ and I -ions. The smaller peaks were absent, which we interpret as passivation of surface under-coordinated Pb ions (iodine vacancies) in the presence of the 2D capping layer. Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Device structure and photovoltaic characterization. (A) Illustration of the capped device structure used in this work with a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer atop the 3D perovskite active layer. (B) Current-density versus voltage (J-V) characteristics under reverse voltage scan (inset: stabilized power output) and (C) external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra and integrated J SC of capped and uncapped champion solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35217</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Characterization of 2D perovskite capping layers. (A) GIWAXS patterns of a Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 /CsPbI 3 perovskite stack taken at a surface-sensitive incident angle of 0.15°. Characteristic reflections of Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 are indicated. (B) Azimuthally integrated GIWAXS traces collected on uncapped and capped samples at incident angles of q = 0.15°(more surface-sensitive) and q = 0.30°(less surface-sensitive). For reference, the critical angle is q = 0.24°. The diamond indicates the (002) reflection of Cs 2 PbCl 2 I 2 and the clover indicates the (110) reflection of CsPbI 3 . (C) XPS Cl 2p depth profiling of the Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 /CsPbI 3 stack. (D) Transient photoluminescence of capped and uncapped films on glass, excited from the film side. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35988</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Accelerated aging of PSCs operating at elevated temperatures. Operational stability of (A) uncapped and (B) capped PSCs operating at 35°, 59°, 85°, and 110°C, with standard deviation envelopes. The encapsulated devices were held at their MPP under constant full-spectrum simulated sunlight (power density ≈ 120 mW/cm 2 ) in (65 ± 26)% relative humidity air. Data points represent average PCE of three devices fabricated and tested under the same condition. The solid lines are biexponential fits to the data. (C) Natural logarithm of degradation rates (k fast and k slow ) versus 1/k B T obtained from biexponential fits to PCEs for uncapped and capped PSCs, where T is the aging temperature. Linear fits used to extract the activation energy (E a ) from each exponential are shown as the dash lines. Because the capped solar cells operating at 35°C did not show noticeable degradation over the time interval studied, their fitted values were not included. (D) Natural logarithm of AF versus 1/k B T with the standard deviation represented by the shaded area around each line. Standard operating conditions for the AF calculation were defined as 1 sun illumination and T ref = 35°C. (E and F) Normalized PCE of uncapped and capped PSCs plotted against the equivalent aging time at 35°C, defined as aging time (in units of hours) multiplied by the acceleration factor, for PSCs under all temperatures studied in this work. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37441</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Degradation and stabilization mechanism. (A) XRD traces of uncapped and capped PSCs before and after aging for 2000 hours, with (B) the region corresponding to CuSCN (003) diffraction magnified. (C) XPS I 3d spectra of the CuSCN surface in uncapped or capped PSCs with aging time on removal of the top electrode. For studies in (A) to (C), full-stack, functional devices were sealed in N 2 and placed under full-sun illumination at 110°C for the specified time before the electrodes were peeled off prior to measurement. (D) Temperature-dependent conductivity (s) of uncapped and capped films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38057</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 .Fig. 2 . 12 Fig. 1. Device structure and photovoltaic characterization. (A) Illustration of the capped device structure used in this work with a 2D Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 layer atop the 3D perovskite active layer. (B) Current-density vs. voltage (J-V) characteristics under reverse voltage scan (inset: stabilized power output) and (C) external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra and integrated J SC of capped and uncapped champion solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38503</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Accelerated aging of PSCs operating at elevated temperatures. Operational stability of (A) uncapped and (B) capped PSCs operating at 35°, 59°, 85°, and 110°C, with standard deviation envelopes. The encapsulated devices were held at their MPP under constant full-spectrum simulated sunlight (power density ≈ 120 mW/cm 2 ) in (65 ± 26) % relative humidity air. Data points represent average PCE of three devices fabricated and tested under the same condition. The solid lines are bi-exponential fits to the data. (C) Natural logarithm of degradation rates (k fast and k slow ) versus 1/k B T obtained from biexponential fits to PCEs for uncapped and capped PSCs, where T is the aging temperature. Linear fits used to extract the activation energy (E a ) from each exponential are shown as the dash lines. Since the capped solar cells operating at 35°C did not show noticeable degradation over the time interval studied, their fitted values were not included. (D) Natural logarithm of AF versus 1/k B T with the standard deviation represented by the shaded area around each line. Standard operating conditions for the AF calculation were defined as 1 sun illumination and T ref = 35°C. (E and F) Normalized PCE of uncapped and capped PSCs plotted against the equivalent aging time at 35°C, defined as aging time (in units of hours) multiplied by the acceleration factor, for PSCs under all temperatures studied in this work. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39956</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Degradation/stabilization mechanism. (A) XRD traces of uncapped and capped PSCs before and after aging for 2000 hours, with (B) the region corresponding to CuSCN (003) diffraction magnified. (C) XPS I 3d spectra of the CuSCN surface in uncapped or capped PSCs with aging time on removal of the top electrode. For studies in Fig. 4a-c, full-stack, functional devices were sealed in N 2 and placed under full-sun illumination at 110°C for the specified time before the electrodes were peeled off prior to measurement. (D) Temperaturedependent conductivity (σ) of uncapped and capped films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40567</offset>
      <text> Figure S1 . S1 Figure S1. (a) Photographs (the scale bar is 1 cm) and (b) XRD patterns of nanocrystalline CsPbI3films in this study before and after aging at 120 ℃ in nitrogen. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40748</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 . S2 Figure S2. Forward and reverse J-V characteristics of (a) an uncapped champion cell and (b) a capped champion cell. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40881</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. Solar cell performance statistics of capped and uncapped PSCs. Values were extracted from testing 20 devices at each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41037</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 . S4 Figure S4. GIWAXS patterns of a Cs2PbI2Cl2/CsPbI3 perovskite stack taken at an incident angle of 0.30°. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41159</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 . S5 Figure S5. Cross-sectional SEM image showing the device stack. Device surface was protected by a layer of carbon coating before exposure to ion beam. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41326</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 . S6 Figure S6. Photograph of an encapsulated solar cell (the scale bar is 1 cm) and the associated scheme showing the cross section of the device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41486</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 . S7 Figure S7. Measured irradiance spectrum of the metal-halide lamp used for lifetime measurements in this study. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41614</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. Associated stability data with actual PCE plotted on the y-axis corresponding to the data presented in Figures 3a and b in the main text. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41780</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 . S9 Figure S9. Normalized photovoltaic parameters (i.e., JSC, VOC, and FF) as a function of operation time of uncapped and capped PSCs at different temperatures. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41955</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 . S10 Figure S10. EQE spectra of uncapped and capped PSCs measured every 1000 hr during aging at 85 ℃. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42073</offset>
      <text> Figure S11 . S11 Figure S11. Operational stability of 2D/3D PSCs without encapsulation operating at 110°C. The unencapsulated devices were held at their MPP under constant full-spectrum simulated sunlight in 42% relative humidity air. The capped devices without encapsulation degraded quickly within 20hr. That our encapsulated devices have substantially higher operational stability implies that moisture and oxygen ingress did not play a significant role in determining their lifetimes. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42565</offset>
      <text> Figure S12 . S12 Figure S12. Top-view SEM images of CuSCN surface in uncapped and capped PSCs (the scale bar is 200 nm). The mobile iodine species are extremely corrosive (48), so can react with or dissolve HTLs (49), which can result in pinholes and non-uniformity in the HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42845</offset>
      <text> Figure S14 . S14 Figure S14. Hole mobility of CuSCN, as measured in a single-carrier diode configuration, as a function of exposure to iodine. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42990</offset>
      <text> Figure S15 S15 Figure S15 XPS Pb 4f spectra of CsPbI3 (uncapped) and Cs2PbI2Cl2/CsPbI3 (capped) 2D perovskite films. The Pb 4f XPS spectrum of the uncapped film exhibited two peaks located at 138.7 and 143.6 eV, and another pair of smaller peaks at 136.8 and 141.7 eV, the latter of which has been attributed to the presence of under-coordinated Pb ions and halide vacancies (50-53).</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
