<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025034168GIIIHF</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 61&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>In Situ Observation of Vapor-Assisted 2D-3D Heterostructure Formation for Stable and Efficient Perovskite Solar Cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>130</offset>
      <text>The heterogeneous stacking of a thin two-dimensional (2D) perovskite layer over the three-dimensional (3D) perovskite film creates a sophisticated architecture for perovskite solar cells (PSCs). It combines the remarkable thermal and environmental stabilities of 2D perovskites with the superior optoelectronic properties of 3D materials which resolves the chronic stability issue with no compromise on efficiency. Herein, we propose the vapor-assisted growth strategy to fabricate highquality 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films by introducing long-chain organoamine gases in which the 2D layers have a uniform and tunable thickness. The 3D to 2D transformation of the widely adopted MAPbI 3 (MA = methylammonium) film is initiated by the butylamine vapor and monitored through the in situ grazing-incidence X-ray diffraction technique. A variety of 2D species are observed and rationalized by the different collapsing and reconstruction models of the Pb-I octahedra. The PSC devices based on the optimized 2D/3D heterostructures show significant improvements in photovoltaic performances, owing to better energy level alignments, longer carrier lifetimes, and less defects as compared to their 3D analogues. In addition, both the butylamine vapor-treated perovskite films and the derived PSC devices demonstrate exceptional long-term stabilities.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium lead iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:41:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="819" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylamine vapor</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:48:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="874" length="16"/>
        <text>butylamine vapor</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylamine vapor</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:48:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="1366" length="10"/>
        <text>butylamine</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1483</offset>
      <text>T he stunning progresses made in the development of organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have attracted tremendous attention in the photovoltaic community, witnessed by the remarkable advancement of device power conversion efficiency (PCE) in the past decade.  [1] [2] [3] [4]  The main obstacle hindering their commercialization is rooted in the intrinsic instability against heat, light, moisture, and oxygen of the APbI 3 (A = methylammonium, MA; formamidinium, FA; Cs) perovskite materials under device operating conditions. Long-chain organic molecules are thus cast into three-dimensional (3D) perovskite lattices to form twodimensional (2D) or quasi-2D structures, serving as interlayer spacers, passivation agents to reduce defects, and barriers to resist moisture exploiting their hydrophobic nature.  [5] [6] [7] [8]  Longchain alkyl or phenyl-ammonium halides, such as n-butylammonium (BA) iodide or phenylethylammonium iodide, were blended into perovskite precursors to prepare 2D Ruddlesden-Popper perovskites with significantly improved long-term stability.  9, 10  Despite all of the intense efforts on film quality optimizations including morphology control and crystal orientation manipulation, the efficiencies of 2D perovskitebased devices still lack far behind their 3D counterparts, mainly due to their inferior optoelectronic properties, such as higher exciton binding energy and shorter charge diffusion length.  [11] [12] [13]  Recently, the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure is proposed in which a thin 2D perovskite capping layer is deposited onto the 3D perovskite film.  [14] [15] [16] [17]  This unique structure combines the merits of the remarkable thermal and humidity stabilities of 2D perovskites and the superior optoelectronic properties (such as strong light absorption and long charge carrier lifetime) of 3D perovskite materials.  [18] [19] [20] [21]  To date, the 2D/3D heterostructures are usually fabricated through wet-chemical approaches by spincoating long-chain organic amine or organoammonium halide salt solutions onto 3D perovskite films.  [22] [23] [24]  The applied solvents (e.g., isopropanol, IPA) will inevitably affect the quality of the underlying perovskite film and the spin-coating process hardly produces a uniform layer which prevents large-scale deployment.  14  New strategies are thus imperative for preparing high-quality 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films. Organoamine vapors have been successfully employed to aid the fabrication of high-quality 3D perovskite films.  [25] [26] [27] [28] [29]  The organoamine molecules can interact with the 3D perovskite lattices through the dative bonds between N and Pb ions or they can induce cation replacements through redox reactions. Zong et al. exposed MAPbI 3 films to the methylamine vapor and found that the reversible adsorption and desorption of methylamine molecules could significantly improve the morphology of perovskite films.  25  Zhou et al. introduced the formamidine vapor to convert MAPbI 3 films, which led to rapid replacement of MA + by FA + cations in perovskite lattices. The resultant FAPbI 3 film retained the morphology of the original MAPbI 3 film and exhibited remarkable optoelectronic properties.  26  Herein, we propose the vapor-assisted growth strategy to fabricate high-quality 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films by introducing long-chain organoamine gases. Upon exposure to the butylamine vapor (BAV), the 3D MAPbI 3 films undergo a progressive phase transition from 3D perovskite to 2D/3D heterostructure and finally to 2D structures. To unravel the underlying reaction mechanism, synchrotron-based in situ grazing-incidence X-ray diffraction (GI-XRD) technique is employed to monitor the entire phase transition process. Both the ionic redox exchange and the coordination reaction between BAV molecules and perovskites are visualized, where the previously reported 2D structures of (BA) 2 PbI 4 and BAPbI 2 and the new 2D species of (BA) 2 Pb 2 I 6 are all encountered. The production of different 2D species is rationalized by various collapsing and reconstruction models of the Pb-I octahedra. Photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy further reveals that the 3D to 2D transition occurs from the surface to the bottom of the 3D film in a layer-by-layer manner. This enables a uniform 2D capping layer forming on top of the 3D perovskite film with a controllable thickness. Guided by the in situ observations, the optimal 2D/3D heterostructure is constructed for solar cell applications. The devices based on the optimized 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films show higher PCEs than their 3D analogues. The efficiency enhancement is mainly ascribed to better energy level alignments, longer charge carrier lifetimes, and less defects in the 2D/3D heterostructure films. Remarkably, the 2D/3D perovskite-based devices also demonstrate significantly improved thermal and environmental stabilities. In Situ GI-XRD Studies. The widely adopted "solvent engineering" method is applied to prepare the polycrystalline 3D MAPbI 3 films which are subsequently exposed to BAV to initiate the 3D to 2D transition process. As the reaction proceeds, the color of the film gradually changes from dark brown to light brown, and then to yellow (see Figure  S1 ). We expect that BAV molecules will diffuse into and react with the MAPbI 3 film and induce 2D species formation. To uncover the underlying mechanism, the synchrotronbased GI-XRD technique is employed to monitor the entire vapor-assisted reaction process. The MAPbI 3 film is installed in a specially designed characterization cell with Kapton windows to allow the transmission of X-rays and a gas-circulating system to generate the BAV atmosphere and discharge the possible gaseous product.  30  The 2D GI-XRD patterns are collected at an interval of 10 s and selectively presented in Figure  S2 . By integrating the 2D GI-XRD patterns and plotting along the time domain, the 2D intensity-time color mapping can be obtained as shown in Figure  1a , which reveals the crystal structure evolution of the film. Figure  1b  presents the typical horizontal line cuts taken at the specific time points denoted as I, II, III in Figure  1a . Clearly, three distinct states of the sample are encountered during the reaction process. Initially, in the first 2 min of reaction, there are five dominant diffraction peaks at 14.1°, 20.0°, 23.5°, 24.5°and 28.4°, ascribing to the tetragonal MAPbI 3 .  30  Notably, the absence of other diffraction peaks could not preclude the commencing of the reaction. We propose that at this stage of the reaction, BAV molecules start to interact with MAPbI 3 , but there is no large coherent crystalline domain formed to give X-ray diffraction signals. From 2 to 6 min, the film shows the 2D/3D composite features. Besides the diffraction peaks of the 3D perovskite (represented by A in Figure  1b ), new peaks in the lower diffraction angle (2θ) range at 5.7°, 6.4°and 7.8°(denoted as C, B and D respectively at point II in Figure  1b ) emerge. The peak B at 6.4°and the minor peak at 14.6°could be well indexed to the 2D perovskite BA 2 PbI 4 with n = 1 in the general formula of (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n represents the number of Pb-I layers in each inorganic slab).  31  However, the peaks C and D could not be indexed to any of the previously reported 2D (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 perovskite species. It was found that the formation of BA 2 PbI 4 from MAPbI 3 degradation was accompanied by the production of PbI 2 .  32  We thus assign peak C to the adduct of BA 2 PbI 4 and PbI 2 and peak D to a PbI 2 related 2D species which we will verify in the following section. As the reaction goes beyond 6 min, a new feature at 5.2°( denoted as E at point III in Figure  1b ) appears while peak C and the 3D peak A disappear. At this stage, the film shows the pure 2D characters, indicating the completion of the 3D to 2D transition. The 2D intensity-time color mapping also enables exclusive visualization of the intensity evolution of each species. Figure  1c  shows the areal intensities of peaks A-E as a function of reaction time (along the vertical direction in Figure  1a ). There are apparently three phase stages (3D, 2D/3D, and 2D) and two transitions for the whole reaction process. During the 3D stage, there is only a slight decrease in the intensity of peak A,  indicating the slow reaction rate. The 3D to 2D transition is further witnessed by the gradual decrease of the peak A intensity and the emergence of peaks B, C, and D. This indicates that BAV molecules first react with MAPbI 3 to form BA 2 PbI 4 (species B) and two other 2D species C and D. After the depletion of the 3D perovskite, the intensity of peak C sharply decreases accompanied by the increase of peaks B and D and the emergence of peak E. We propose that species C further reacts with BAV to form species B, D, and E. The GI-XRD patterns taken at points II and III and the intensity distributions of the Bragg peaks for species B-E plotted along the azimuthal direction are shown in Figure  1d . Evidently, there is a preferential orientation with a single peak centered at 90°for all the 2D species, indicating the horizontal growth of the 2D crystal planes. The pronounced growth tendency of 2D species is related to their formation energy.  33  We propose a Pb-I octahedron collapsing and reconstruction model to rationalize the complex reaction products formed in the 3D to 2D transition process. Upon exposing MAPbI 3 to BAV, redox reactions start with the oxidization of BA to BA + and the reduction of MA + to MA. The subsequent replacement of MA + ions by the larger BA + cations causes the destruction of the 3D tetragonal perovskite lattices by slicing along the (110) planes.  31  In this process, as schematically illustrated in Figure  2 , a layer of iodine atoms shared by two adjacent layers of Pb-I octahedra would redistribute to form two kinds of Pb-I slabs: one is iodine sufficient (denoted as IS) which consists of cornersharing [PbI 6 ] 2-octahedra and electrostatically anchored BA + cations, and the other is iodine deficient (denoted as ID) which consists of corner-sharing [PbI 4 ] octahedra with iodine vacancies. The two different Pb-I slabs are expected to reconstruct in three ways to form distinct 2D products which we assign to species B, C, and D as observed in the in situ GI-XRD study. The stacking of ISs directly forms BA 2 PbI 4 corresponding to species B in the XRD pattern. The collapsing and rearrangement of IDs generate edge-shared PbI 2 which would further interact with BAV via the coordination of the Pb 2+ ion and the lone-pair electrons on N in the BAV molecule to form the Lewis acid-base adduct of BAPbI 2 .  34  It has the smallest lattice spacing (d) along the out-of-plane direction in all three possible products, which we assign to species D with 2θ of 7.8°and d of 11.2 Å. Moreover, the equimolar mixing of IDs and ISs would likely lead to the alternative stacking of BA 2 PbI 4 and the edge-shared PbI 2 to form the 2D product of BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 . The thick BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 is assigned to species C in view that simply adding the thicknesses of BA 2 PbI 4 (13.7 Å) and the edge-shared PbI 2 (1.8 Å) will result in a d-spacing of ∼15.5 Å which is in good accordance with that of species C (2θ of 5.7°and d of 15.5 Å). To verify our hypotheses and confirm the structures of reaction products, two experiments are designed and conducted, namely, (1) exposing the PbI 2 film to BAV and (2) preparing a film with equimolar of BA 2 PbI 4 and PbI 2 and then exposing it to BAV. The in situ GI-XRD results of experiment (1) is presented in Figure  3a . The as-prepared hexagonal PbI 2 film shows the characteristic diffraction peak at 12.6°. After being treated with BAV, a new peak centered at 7.8°emerges which is identical to that of species D. This confirms PbI 2 interacts with BAV to form the adduct of BAPbI 2 . Notably, BAPbI 2 is not stable in the excess BAV and could form a liquidlike film as indicated by a scattering halo in the XRD pattern at the end of experiment (1). The dissolution of PbI 2 in amines was also observed elsewhere.  35  The film prepared in experiment (2) by mixing equimolar of BA 2 PbI 4 and PbI 2 in the precursor solution exhibits intense diffraction peaks at 5.7°, which is in high accordance with that of species C (Figure  3b ). This affirms that species C has the crystal structure of the alternative stacking of BA 2 PbI 4 and edge-shared PbI 2 with the chemical formula of BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 . By further exposing the BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 film to BAV, the intensity of the peak at 5.7°gradually decreases, while the main peaks at 5.2°, 6.4°, and 7.8°emerge, corresponding to species E, B, and D, respectively. This reveals that (BA) 2 Pb 2 I 6 would further interact with BAV to form (BA) 2 Pb 2 I 6 •xBA, BA 2 PbI 4 , and BAPbI 2 . The assignment of the species B-E is further confirmed by the well matching of the large-angle diffraction peaks shown in Figure  S3 . Ex Situ PL and SEM Studies. While the in situ GI-XRD studies can provide a wealth of information about the crystalline contents in the 3D to 2D transition process, the PL technique is more sensitive to substances of low crystallinity and could gain additional information on the reaction. We perform ex situ PL measurements on the MAPbI 3 films treated by BAV for various time durations. As shown in Figure  3c , the PL spectra are taken by illuminating the samples from both the perovskite and substrate (quartz) sides. In accordance with the GI-XRD data, the 3D to 2D transition is observed as the PL peak shifts from 780 nm originating from the 3D MAPbI 3 to 525 nm corresponding to the 2D species (we note that both BA 2 PbI 4 and BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 exhibit the PL peak at 525 nm while BAPbI 2 shows no PL signal). The discrepancy between the PL spectra taken from two illumination directions indicates that the 3D to 2D transition initiates from the top of the 3D film and progresses toward the substrate, which results in the heterogeneous stacking of a 2D layer over the 3D perovskite. Interestingly, the PL peaks centered at 572, 608, and 665 nm, ascribable to the (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 perovskites for n = 2, 3 and 4, respectively, are also observed during the 3D to 2D transition.  36  We attribute the 2D perovskites with large n values to the intermediate states where BAV molecules penetrate and slice the 3D perovskite lattice to first form discrete multilayer Pb-I slabs followed by thinning down the Pb-I slabs. The small quantity and discrete nature of the n = 2, 3, and 4 perovskites restrain their observation in the in situ GI-XRD experiments.  33  SEM measurements are further carried out to verify the reaction direction and obtain additional morphological information. Figure  3d  presents the cross-sectional SEM images of the initial 3D, intermediate 2D/3D, and final 2D films. The initial 3D film (top image of Figure  3d ) shows the typical features of polycrystalline perovskite films with the grain size of several hundred nanometers and the film thickness of around 300 nm. After the BAV treatment, the intermediate film (middle image of Figure  3d ) shows a clear phase separation with the 2D capping layer on top of the 3D film. A uniform and seamless interface is formed between the 2D and 3D layers, which could benefit the charge carrier shuttling in the 2D/3D film. The final 2D film (bottom image of Figure  3d ) has ∼3 times larger thickness as compared to the initial 3D film which further confirms the insertion of BAV molecules into the 3D perovskite lattices to form 2D species. Photovoltaic Performance. Through the BAV treatment, a uniform and seamlessly connected 2D capping layer forms directly onto the 3D perovskite film. Previously, various solution-processing approaches have been followed to realize the surface modification of 3D perovskite films.  24, 37  The 2D perovskite layers could effectively eliminate defects and improve humidity and thermal stabilities of perovskite films.  18, 22  We subsequently employ the BAV-treated perovskite films to fabricate PSC devices and optimize the 2D/3D heterostructure by tuning the BAV exposure time. The BAV treatment for the device application follows the similar procedure as for the in situ experiment, which is described in Methods. The devices feature a typical n-i-p structure consisting of indium tin oxide (ITO)/ SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/Ag. The photovoltaic analyses ascertain the BAV treatment could effectively enhance device performances. As given in Table  S1 , the PSC devices based on the 2D/3D heterostucture films with 1 min of the BAV treatment show the best PCE, while the extended treatment adversely affects device performances. The SEM images in Figure  4a ,b show the surface morphology of the 3D and 1 min BAV treated 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films. Apparently, a thin 2D layer is formed on the 3D perovskite film following the BAV treatment. The minute thickness of the 2D capping layer allows efficient charge carrier shuttling within the heterostructure film and to the hole transport layer (HTL).  4  As shown by the atomic force microscope (AFM) images of the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured films in Figure  S4 , the film becomes smoother following the BAV treatment, which is beneficial for device applications.  38  The cross-sectional SEM image of the optimized device is shown in Figure  4c . The statistical photovoltaic performances of the devices based on the 2D/3D heterostructure films with the optimal BAV treatment are summarized in Figure  4d -g, taking the 3D perovskite-based devices as references. The devices with the BAV treatment exhibit a narrower efficiency distribution and a 10% increase in the average PCE, mainly ascribed to the higher open circuit voltage (V oc ) and fill factor (FF). The increases in V oc and FF are related to the suppression of nonradiative charge recombination in the devices, demonstrating the defect-passivation effect of the BAV-induced 2D capping layer.  39  Meanwhile, the average short circuit current density (J sc ) also increases slightly, indicating the undisturbed charge carrier transporting in the 2D/3D heterostructure film. Moreover, the improved hysteresis behavior and the elevated stabilized power output of the devices with the BAV treatment further demonstrate the outstanding photovoltaic performances of the 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films (Figure  S5 ). Optical and Electrical Characterizations. In order to rationalize the superior performances of the BAV treated films, we first investigate the energy level alignments in the devices based on the 2D/3D heterostructure films. The optical bandgaps of the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films are obtained from the Tauc plots (Figure  5a ) taken by ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) reflectance spectroscopy.  16  Both the 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films have the absorption edge at 1.55 eV ascribed to MAPbI 3 . However, an additional bandgap at 2.35 eV is found in the 2D/3D perovskite film, originating from the BAV-induced 2D species. The much larger bandgap of the 2D species is mainly due to the quantum confinement effect.  40  The ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) results in Figure  5b  show that the 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films have the valence band maxima at -5.6 and -5.48 eV, respectively. As shown in Figure  5c , the energy level diagram is constructed schematically based on the measured bandgap and valence band maximum values. Notably, introducing a 2D capping layer   between the 3D perovskite and HTL is beneficial to photovoltaic application. The higher conduction band of the 2D capping layer could effectively block the back transfer of the photoexcited electrons from the 3D perovskite to HTL, while its well-aligned valence bands ensure efficient hole transporting.  14  We further conduct the steady-state and time-resolved PL measurements to examine the optical properties of the BAVtreated perovskite films. As shown in Figure  5d , compared to the 3D film, the BAV-treated 2D/3D heterostructure film shows 5 times higher peak intensity and a slight blueshift from 776 to 769 nm of the PL peak, which is ascribed to the reduction of trap/ defect states in the film.  41, 42  The time-resolved PL spectra (Figure  5e ) further demonstrate the outstanding defect passivation capability of the BAV treatment. The fitting parameters for the time-resolved PL spectra from the 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films are listed in Table  S2 .  16  The average PL lifetime increases from 129.0 ns for the 3D film to 165.5 ns for the 2D/3D heterostructure film. We subsequently conduct electrical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements to probe the charge transporting processes in the PSC devices. As shown in Figure  5f , the Nyquist plots show two distinguishable arcs in the high and low frequency ranges. The highfrequency arc is related to the charge transfer resistance (R ct ) at the perovskite and charge transport layer interfaces, while the low-frequency arc is related to the charge recombination resistance (R rec ) in the device. The 3D and 2D/3D perovskite film-based devices show the similar R ct values, indicating the 2D capping layer has a negligible effect on the charge transfer from the perovskite layer to HTL. The R rec value of the 2D/3D heterostructure film-based device is much higher than that of its 3D counterpart (Table  S3 ), which further confirms the suppressed recombination and lower defect density in the BAV-treated films.  43  The recombination lifetime can be determined by τ rec = R rec × C rec and the calculated τ rec of the 2D/3D film-based device (536 μs) is much longer than that of its 3D counterpart (240.8 μs), which further affirms the lower defect density in the 2D/3D heterostructured film-based device.  44  The PL and EIS results clearly demonstrate the passivation effect of the BAV treatment for perovskite films which rationalizes the superior photovoltaic performances (higher V oc and FF) of the corresponding devices. Stability Tests. In addition to photovoltaic performance enhancement, the BAV-induced 2D capping layer is expected to act as an effective barrier to protect perovskite films from moisture and heat. We first investigate the film thermal and environmental stabilities by aging the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructure films at 85 °C in nitrogen atmosphere and in air at room temperature (relative humidity of 30-40%), respectively. We trace the XRD pattern evolutions of the films under different aging conditions, where the degradation of perovskite is signified by the emergence of the PbI 2 diffraction peak (2θ = 12.6°). As shown in Figure  6a  and Figure  S6 , the 2D/ 3D heterostructure film exhibits better heat resistance as the PbI 2 diffraction peak intensity and its relative ratio to the (110) Bragg peak (2θ = 14.1°) intensity of MAPbI 3 are smaller than those of the 3D film. The 2D/3D heterostructure film also demonstrates better environmental stability because there is no discernible sign of degradation after 60 days, whereas there is a strong PbI 2 peak for the 3D film (Figure  6b ). The significant improvements in stabilities of the 2D/3D heterostructure films are ascribed to the 2D capping layers induced by the BAV treatment that could form potential barriers against the escape of volatile species from the perovskite films and the invasion of water molecules into the perovskite films.  45, 46  We also investigate the stabilities of solar cell devices based on the 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films under the same aging conditions. The devices retain 60% of the initial PCE after aging at 85 °C for 125 h (Figure  6c ) and 92% of the initial PCE in air for 600 h (Figure  6d ), outperforming the PSC devices based on the 3D films. Compared to the protective approaches containing insulating polymers or reactive organic halide salts, the BAVinduced 2D layer is effective in charge transport and immune to heat and moisture.  2, 47  Discussion. We have developed an effective vapor-assisted growth strategy to fabricate high-quality 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films in which the 2D layers have a uniform and tunable thickness. In situ GI-XRD technique is employed to monitor the entire 3D to 2D transition process, where a variety of 2D species are observed and rationalized by the different collapsing and reconstruction models of the Pb-I octahedra. In situ GI-XRD and ex situ PL and SEM studies further reveal that BAV converts the 3D MAPbI 3 into a series of 2D species from the surface down to the bottom of the perovskite film in a layerby-layer manner. The PSC devices based on the optimized 2D/ 3D heterostructure films show significant enhancements in photovoltaic performances, owing to better energy level alignments, longer carrier lifetimes, and less defects as compared to their 3D analogs. In addition, both the BAV-treated perovskite films and the derived PSC devices demonstrate remarkable thermal and environmental stabilities. This work represents a significant step toward highly efficient and stable PSCs that are commensurate with real-world applications. In light of the viable choices of organoamines for 2D perovskites, the current study also paves a new avenue to create novel 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures for high-performance optoelectronic devices with technologically relevant long-term stability. Methods. Materials. All reagents were used without any purification. MAI, PbI 2 , and BAI were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis(N,N-di-p-methoxyphenylamine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) was purchased from Borun. Chlorobenzene, N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), 4-tertbutylpyridine (tBP), acetonitrile (ACN), Li-TFSI, and butylamine were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. γ-butyrolactone (GBL) was purchased from Acros. BA 2 PbI 4 crystal powders were synthesized following the reported procedure.  31  Film Preparation for the in Situ Experiments. For the MAPbI 3 film, the 1.3 M precursor solution was prepared by dissolving equimolar of CH 3 NH 3 I and PbI 2 in a mixed solvent of GBL and DMSO (7:3 (v/v)). The solution was spun at 2000 rpm for 20 s and 4000 rpm for 40 s on a glass substrate in a N 2 filled glovebox. Two hundred microliters of chlorobenzene was dripped onto the rotating film at 20 s before the end of the spinning process. The film was then annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. For the PbI 2 film, the 1 M precursor solution was prepared by dissolving PbI 2 in a mixed solvent of DMF and DMSO with the volume ratio of 9:1. The solution was spin-coated onto a glass substrate at 5000 rpm for 20 s. The film was then annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. For the BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 film, the BA 2 Pb 2 I 6 films were obtained by spin-coating the precursor solution containing 0.225 M PbI 2 and 0.225 M BA 2 PbI 4 crystal powders in DMF at 7000 rpm, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. Device Fabrication. Characterizations. The GI-XRD measurements were carried out at beamline BL14B1 of Shanghai Synchrotron Radiation Facility (SSRF). The incident photon energy was 10 keV (wavelength = 1.2398 Å) at an incident angle of 0.4°and the diffracted X-rays were collected at an interval of 10 s using the 2D Mar225 CCD detector. The sealed cell for the GI-XRD characterization contained a Kapton window allowing the transmission of X-rays and a gas-circulating system to provide and maintain inert atmosphere. During the in situ experiments, BAV was generated by placing an open bottle filled with butylamine liquid in the sealed cell at room temperature. Nitrogen was purged at the rate of 200 mL/min during the experiments to maintain the BAV/N 2 atmosphere. PL measurements were conducted using a HORIBA Scientific Fluorolog-3 photoluminescence spectrometer with an excitation light wavelength of 350 nm. The reflection spectra were obtained using an Agilent Technologies Cary Series UV-vis-NIR Spectrophotometer. Quartz substrates were employed for the PL and UV-vis measurements. The morphology of perovskite films and devices was characterized by the Joel 7800 SEM. UPS measurements were carried out using ThermoFisher ESCA-LANTM 250Xi and the He I (21.22 eV) emission line was employed for excitation. The UPS data were acquired at a bias of -10 V. The J-V measurements for solar cell devices were performed using a Keithley 2400 digital source meter under the illumination of a solar simulator (SS-F5-3A, Enlitech) whose intensity was calibrated by the certified standard silicon solar cell (SRC-2020, Enlitech) at 100 mW/cm 2 . The J-V behaviors were recorded at the reverse scan direction at a rate of 30 mV/s. The active area of the cells was 0.059 cm 2 defined by a metallic shadow mask. The EQE spectra were obtained by employing the solar cell spectral-response measurement system (QE-R, Enlitech) under the direct current mode. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylamine vapor</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:48:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="4930" length="16"/>
        <text>butylamine vapor</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylamine vapor</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:48:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="4948" length="3"/>
        <text>BAV</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium lead iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:48:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="4961" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium lead iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T14:51:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="7056" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:00:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="17924" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:01:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="17954" length="57"/>
        <text>indium tin oxide (ITO)/ SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD/Ag</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylamine vapor</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:03:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="23709" length="28"/>
        <text>BAV-induced 2D capping layer</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOST</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:03:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="23863" length="7"/>
        <text>thermal</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:07:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="23875" length="25"/>
        <text>environmental stabilities</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:03:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="23952" length="5"/>
        <text>85 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:04:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="23995" length="16"/>
        <text>room temperature</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">30</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:04:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="24034" length="2"/>
        <text>30</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">40</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:04:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="24037" length="3"/>
        <text>40%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:06:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="25201" length="3"/>
        <text>60%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">125</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:06:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="25249" length="7"/>
        <text>125 h (</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.92</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:07:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="25273" length="3"/>
        <text>92%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">600</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:07:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="25307" length="5"/>
        <text>600 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:08:11Z</infon>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:08:27Z</infon>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30552</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30577</offset>
      <text> * sı Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.nanolett.9b04759 . Figures for digital photographs of the BAV-treated perovskite films for different exposure times, typical 2D GI-XRD patterns of the sample taken during the 3D to 2D transition at different times, XRD patterns of different species, AFM images, photovoltaic properties of the typical devices, the peak area ratios between the PbI 2 (002) peak, and the perovskite (110) peak for the 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films; tables for the photovoltaic parameters of the devices based on the 2D/3D perovskite films with the BAV treatment for various durations, the parameters obtained from fitting the time-resolved PL spectra of the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films, the parameters obtained from fitting the EIS spectra for the PSC devices based on the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films (PDF)       Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. (a) Two-dimensional intensity-time color mapping following the 3D to 2D transition of the MAPbI 3 film under the BAV treatment. (b) XRD patterns of the perovskite film taken at points I, II, and III as denoted in (a). (c) Time evolutions of the intensities of the diffraction peaks marked as A-E in (b). (d) Two-dimensional GI-XRD patterns of the perovskite film taken at points II and III and the integrated and normalized intensities of peaks B-E plotted along the azimuthal angle. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32043</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Schematic illustration of the Pb-I octahedron collapsing and reconstruction model. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32151</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. (a, b) Two-dimensional intensity-time color mapping following the exposure of PbI 2 (a) and BA 2 PbI 4 and PbI 2 mixture (b) to BAV. (c) PL spectra of the MAPbI 3 film taken at different stages during the BAV treatment. Samples are illuminated from both the perovskite (red dotted lines) and substrate (blue lines) sides. (d) Cross-sectional SEM images of the 3D, 2D/3D, and 2D perovskite films, respectively. The scale bars are 500 nm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32613</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (a, b) SEM images of the MAPbI 3 film taken before and after the BAV treatment. (c) Cross-sectional SEM image of the device featuring the 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite film. (d-g) The statistical distributions of the photovoltaic parameters of PCE, V oc , J sc , and FF of the PSC devices based on the 3D and optimized 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films. All the scale bars in the SEM images are 200 nm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33051</offset>
      <text> Figure 5 . 5 Figure 5. (a) Tauc plots and (b) UPS spectra of the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films. (c) Schematic energy level diagram of the PSC device based on the 2D/3D heterostructure film. (d) Steady-state and (e) time-resolved PL spectra of the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films (the solid lines are the theoretical fittings in (e)). (f) Nyquist plots of the PSC devices based on the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films recorded at 0 V in the dark. The equivalent circuit has the elements of R s , R ct , R rec , C ct , and C rec representing the series resistance, charge transfer resistance, charge recombination resistance, charge transfer capacity, and charge recombination capacity, respectively (the solid lines represent the fitted data). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33842</offset>
      <text> Figure 6 . 6 Figure 6. (a) Thermal and (b) environmental stability tests on the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films (tracked by the evolution of XRD patterns). (c) Thermal and (d) environmental stability tests of the PSC devices based on the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films (tracked by the evolution of the normalized PCEs). The samples are aged at 85 °C in nitrogen for the thermal stability tests in panels a and c and in air at room temperature (relative humidity of 30%-40%) for the environmental stability tests in panels b and d. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:09:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="34218" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34407</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. The XRD patterns taken at points II and III (denoted in Figure 1a) are compared with those of species A, B, C, D and E. The purple rhombus, orange solid circle, green hollow circle, red hollow square and blue solid square represent the typical diffraction peaks of species A, B, C, D and E, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34740</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 . S4 Figure S4. The AFM images of 3D and 2D/3D perovskite films. The scale bar is 1 μm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34841</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 . S5 Figure S5. (a) J-V curves, (b) EQE, and (c) stabilized power output (SPO) of the typical PSC devices based the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35017</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 . S6 Figure S6. The peak area ratios between the PbI2 (002) peak and the perovskite (110) peak for the 3D (black line) and 2D/3D (red line) perovskite films as a function of aging time at 85 o C in N2 atmosphere. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35242</offset>
      <text> To fabricate solar cells, ITO substrates were cleaned by successively sonicating in detergent solution, , and isopropanol. The SnO 2 layer was then deposited by spin-coating the 2.5 wt % SnO 2 nanoparticle solution precursor at 3000 rpm for 30 s, followed by annealing at 150 °C for 30 min in ambient air. The SnO 2 coated substrate was then transferred into a glovebox where the MAPbI 3 film is further deposited employing the method described above. To conduct the BAV treatment for device application, the MAPbI 3 films were placed in a sealed box which contained an open bottle filled with butylamine liquid (it is noted that the glovebox can provide N 2 atmosphere to protect perovskite films, which avoids N 2 purge used in the in situ GI-XRD experiments). The different 2D/3D stacking films were then prepared by varying the BAV treatment time. The spiro-OMeTAD HTL layer was deposited on top of the perovskite films by spin-coating the precursor solution at 3000 rpm for 30 s. The precursor solution of the HTL contains 72.3 mg of spiro-OMeTAD and 9.1 mg of Li-TFSI in 17.5 μL of ACN and 28.8 μL of tBP in 1 mL of chlorobenzene. The 60 nm Ag layer was then deposited using a thermal evaporator at the rate of 0.5 Å/s. Nano Letters pubs.acs.org/NanoLett Letter acetone &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36524</offset>
      <text> School of Physical Science and Technology, ShanghaiTech University, Shanghai 201210, China; Shanghai Synchrotron Radiation Facility, Shanghai Institute of Applied Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 201204, China; orcid.org/0000-0001-8112-3579; Email: gchen@ shanghaitech.edu.cn ■ AUTHOR INFORMATION Corresponding Author Gang Chen - &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36872</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 The parameters obtained from fitting the EIS spectra for the PSC devices based on the 3D and 2D/3D heterostructured perovskite films, the sample area in square centimeter. Samples Parameters Rct (Ω) Rrec (Ω) Rs (Ω) Cct (F) Crec (F) 3D 96.4 5.6ⅹ10 6 5.4 2.1ⅹ10 -8 4.3ⅹ10 -7 2D/3D 100.0 8ⅹ10 6 2.8 2.4ⅹ10 -8 6.7ⅹ10 -7 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37219</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.9b04759 Nano Lett. 2020, 20, 1296-1304 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:42:35 (UTC). See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37490</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.9b04759Nano Lett. 2020, 20, 1296-1304</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
