<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025037449GFBEBC</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 78&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>103</offset>
      <text>The band gap of formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI3) perovskites allows broader absorption of the solar spectrum compared to conventional methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3). The optoelectronic properties of perovskite films are closely related to the film-quality, so depositing dense and uniform films is crucial for fabricating high-performance perovskite solar cells (PSCs). We report an approach for depositing high-quality FAPbI3 films, involving FAPbI3 crystallization by the direct intramolecular exchange of dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO) molecules intercalated in PbI2 with formamidinium iodide. This process produces FAPbI3 films with (111)preferred crystallographic orientation, large-grained dense microstructures, and flat surfaces without residual PbI2. Using films prepared by this technique, FAPbI3-based PSCs with maximum power conversion efficiency of over 20% were fabricated.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="119" length="25"/>
        <text>formamidinium lead iodide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="146" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="530" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="554" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">dimethylsulfoxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:27:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="618" length="17"/>
        <text>dimethylsulfoxide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">dimethylsulfoxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:27:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="637" length="4"/>
        <text>DMSO</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>992</offset>
      <text>The tremendous improvements in device architecture (1-3), high-quality film formation methodologies  (4) (5) (6) , and compositional engineering of perovskite materials (7-9) over the last 3 years have led to rapid improvements in the power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs). Although solar-to-electric PCE of up to 18% has been reported for PSCs  (10) , developing technologies further to achieve PCEs near theoretical values continues to be among the most important challenges in the solar cell industry to achieve economic feasibility. Formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI3) is a perovskite material that can potentially provide better performance than methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3) because of its broad absorption of the solar spectrum. In addition, FAPbI3 with the n-i-p architecture (the n-side is illuminated with solar radiation) exhibits negligible hysteresis with sweep direction during current-voltage measurements  (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) . However, compared to MAPbI3, it is more difficult to form stable perovskite phases and high-quality films of FAPbI3. Various methodologies such as sequential deposition (4), solventengineering  (5) , vapor-assisted deposition  (14) , additiveassisted deposition  (15, 16) , and vacuum evaporation  (6)  can now produce high-quality films of MAPbI3 with flat surfaces and complete surface coverage by controlling its rapid crystallization behavior and have led to substantial improve-ments in the PCE of MAPbI3based PSCs. Among these methodologies, two-step sequential deposition and solvent-engineering are representative wet processes that can yield perovskite films for high-performance PSCs. In the sequential deposition process, a thin layer of PbI2 is deposited on the substrate. methylammonium iodide (MAI) or formamidinium iodide (FAI) is then applied to the pre-deposited PbI2 to enable conversion to the perovskite phase. This process involves crystal nucleation and growth of the perovskite phase because of solution-phase or solid-state reaction between PbI2 and an organic iodide such as MAI or FAI  (4, 13, 17) . However, the sequential reaction of organic iodides with PbI2 that occurs from the surface to the inner crystalline regions of PbI2 has been ineffective in producing highperformance perovskite films that are &gt; 500 nm in thickness because of incomplete conversion of PbI2, peeling-off of the perovskite film in solution, and uncontrolled surface roughness. In contrast, the solvent-engineering process utilizes the formation of intermediate phases to retard the rapid reaction between PbI2 and organic iodide in the solution. While this process has been successfully used to form dense and uniform MAPbI3 layers, it has not been explored for FAPbI3  (5) . To deposit a uniform and dense FAPbI3 layer, Snaith et al. added a small amount of aqueous HI to a solution mixture containing PbI2, FAI, and dimethylformamide (DMF)  (11) . Very recently, Zhao et al. reported the deposition of highly uniform and fully covered FAPbI3 films using FAI and HPbI3, which is formed by the reaction of PbI2 and HI in DMF  (18) . The HI in the PbI2 layers retards the rapid reaction between FAI and PbI2. In addition, the release of HI from PbI2 at high temperatures allows the formation of a FAPbI3 layer by solid-state reaction with the neighboring FAI molecules. Stated differently, this process can be regarded as the transformation of PbI2-HI-FAI into FAPbI3, similar to the formation of MAPbI3 via the PbI2dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO)-MAI phase in the solventengineering process  (5) . However, we observed that the solvent-engineering process, which is effective for depositing dense and uniform MAPbI3 layers, yields FAPbI3 layers with pin-holes and a rough surface. Although the FAPbI3 film-quality including coverage and uniformity on the substrate have been improved, the performance of FAPbI3-solar cells still lag behind those of MAPbI3-based PSC  (8) , implying that more sophisticated deposition techniques are necessary for fabricating high-quality, thick FAPbI3 films (&gt; 500 nm), for achieving sufficient absorption up to a wavelength of 840 nm. As expected from the conversion of PbI2-DMSO-MAI to MAPbI3  (5) , the DMSO molecules intercalated in PbI2 can be easily replaced by external FAIs because of its higher affinity toward PbI2 compared to DMSO; the FAI molecules experience ionic interactions, whereas DMSO participates in van der Waals interactions  (5, 19) . Highly uniform and dense pre-deposited PbI2-(DMSO) layers could be directly converted to FAPbI3 because the inorganic PbI2 framework would be retained. FAPbI3 crystallization by the intramolecular exchange process (IEP) of DMSO intercalated in PbI2 with FAI was schematically shown in Fig.  1A . The intramolecular exchange between DMSO and FAI can be described as PbI2-DMSO + FAI → PbI2-FAI + DMSO ↑ (removal)  (1)  and does not induce volume expansion, unlike the FAP-bI3 formed with FAI intercalating into pristine PbI2 (discussed below) because the molecular sizes of DMSO and FAI are similar. In this work, we report on the synthesis of a PbI2-(DMSO) precursor with excellent capabilities for molecular exchange with FAI at low temperatures during the spinning process, as well as the fabrication of highly efficient FAPbI3based PSCs with certified PCEs exceeding 20%. To synthesize the PbI2-(DMSO) precursors, precipitates were obtained by pouring toluene as a non-solvent into 1.0 M PbI2 solution dissolved in DMSO. The x-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern of the resulting complex (Fig.  1Ba ) matched that of the PbI2(DMSO)2 phase  (5, 19) . The as-prepared PbI2(DMSO)2 was then annealed at 60°C for 24 hours in vacuum to obtain PbI2(DMSO) by removal of 1 mol DMSO. The XRD pattern of the vacuum-annealed powder (Fig.  1Bb ) did not match that of PbI2(DMSO)2, implying that the PbI2(DMSO)2 transformed into a different phase by releasing some DMSO molecules. The content of DMSO in the as-annealed powder was estimated by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA). TGA was suitable for this purpose because the only volatile species in the powder was DMSO. The TGA results of the PbI2(DMSO)2 and PbI2(DMSO) complexes are shown in Fig.  1C . The PbI2(DMSO)2 complex exhibited a two-step decomposition process with weight-loss of 12.6% at each step, whereas the vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) complex showed a singlestep decomposition. The decomposition of both the complexes was completed at the same temperature (138. 6°C). The powders obtained by vacuum-annealing PbI2(DMSO)2 complex at 60°C can be regarded as one of the most thermodynamically stable forms among the various crystalline PbI2-(DMSO)-based complexes, which are similar with PbBr2(DMSO) and PbCl2(DMSO)  (20) . The DMSO content of the vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) complex was also checked by elemental analysis (EA), which yielded H = 1.0% (1.1%); and C = 4.1% (4.4%), where the values expressed in parenthesis indicate the theoretical mass percent for a given element for C2H6SOPbI2. To fabricate FAPbI3-based PSCs through IEP between DMSO and FAI (MABr) using pre-deposited PbI2-DMSO layers and a FAI (MABr) solution, we first confirmed that the PbI2(DMSO) phase was retained even after spin-coating with the PbI2(DMSO) precursor dissolved in DMF. The XRD pattern for film coated on a fused silica substrate was compared with that of the initial precursor. As seen in Fig.  1Bc , the XRD pattern for the as-coated film was in consistent with that of the PbI2(DMSO) complex powder, although its crystallinity is lowered. The as-coated PbI2(DMSO) film also had a flat and dense surface, as shown in the field-emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM) image in fig.  S1    (21) . Next, we investigated the formation of mixed FAP-bI3/MAPbBr3 by IEP. We recently reported that the coexistence of MA/FA/I/Br in the PbI2 skeleton improved the phase-stability of FAPbI3  (10) . The formation of mixed FAP-bI3/MAPbBr3 layers via IEP was controlled by coating solution mixture with different mole ratios of MABr to FAI dissolved in isopropyl alcohol (IPA), on the pre-deposited PbI2(DMSO) layers (discussed below). It is evident from Fig.  1Da  that well-crystallized FAPbI3-based films were formed by IEP. The XRD pattern for the FAPbI3 film derived from the PbI2(DMSO) complex film exhibits dominant (-111) and (-222) diffraction peaks at 13.9° and 28.1°, respectively, corresponding to the FAPbI3 trigonal perovskite phase (P3m1), in contrast with the XRD patterns of the FAPbI3 powder (Fig.  1Db )  (13) . The intensity ratio of (-123) peak at 31.5 ° to the (-222) peak at 28.1° was 0.05. This value was much smaller than the corresponding intensity ratios (= 0.8) for the FAPbI3 power. Thus, IEP leads to high-quality pure FAPbI3-based films with preferred orientation along the [111] axis. Fig. S2  (21)  presents the current density-voltage (J-V) curves measured under standard air-mass 1.5 global (AM 1.5G) illumination, and the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the fabricated cells with FAPbI3-based layers fabricated with various amounts of MABr (0 to 20 mol%). The onset wavelength in the EQE spectra near 830 nm showed a non-linear blue shift with increasing amounts of MABr, indicating that there is unsymmetrical competition between FAI and MABr in forming the FAPbI3-MAPbBr3 perovskite phase through an intramolecular exchange reaction. Nevertheless, the highest PCE of 19.2% was achieved for the film fabricated from a FAI solution containing 15 mol% MABr. To accurately determine the composition of the FAPbI3-based layer, we investigated the lattice parameter using XRD and the band gap using the EQE for the film showing the best performance. Fig.  S3  (21) shows the pseudocubic lattice parameter for (FAPbI3)1-x(MAPbBr3)x as a function of x, in which the composition was controlled by a previously reported method  (10) . In this study, the pseudocubic lattice parameter of the FAPbI3/MAPbBr3 film fabricated by IEP with a FAI solution containing 15 mol% MABr is 6.348 Å. As indicated in fig.  S4    (21) , the lattice parameter can be assigned as x = ~ 5, corresponding to (FAP-bI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05. This result is in agreement with the value estimated using the band gap (1.49 eV) from EQE [fig. S3  (21) ], because pure FAPbI3 has a band gap of 1.47 eV and (FAPbI3)0.85(MAPbBr3)0.15, 1.55 eV  (10) . Fortunately, the simultaneous introduction of both MA + cations and Br -anions in FAPbI3 even after incorporating 5 mol% of MAPbBr3 serves to stabilize the perovskite phase  (10) . After comparing the absorption coefficients of FAPbI3 and MAPbI3 at wavelengths beyond 800 nm, we noted that the thickness of a FAPbI3 layer needed to be higher than the optimal thickness of a typical perovskite layer with a band gap of ~1.55 eV (300 to 400 nm) to guarantee fully lightharvesting around 800 nm  (20, 22) . We deposited FAPbI3based layers with thickness of ~ 500 nm, and fabricated devices consisting of fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)glass/barrier layer (bl)-TiO2/mesoporous (mp)-TiO2/perovskite/poly-triarylamine (PTAA)/Au (n-i-p architecture), as shown in the cross-sectional FESEM image of Fig.  2A . FESEM plane-view images of the device with film derived from PbI2(DMSO) complex and PbI2 films are shown in Fig.  2B . The FAPbI3 film derived from PbI2(DMSO) exhibited a dense and well-developed grain structure with larger grains than the FAPbI3 film derived from PbI2. Figure  2Ca  shows the J-V curves measured via reverse and forward bias sweep for one of the best-performing solar cell. The devices we fabricated also showed no hysteresis. Here, we believe that the hysteresis is highly dependent on the perovskite materials (FAPbI3 or MAPbI3) and cell architecture (n-i-p or p-i-n), although the ferroelectric properties of the perovskite itself are more likely to be the origin of the hysteresis in PSCs  (23, 24) . Thus, FAPbI3-based PSCs with n-i-p architecture show negligible hysteresis between the reverse and the forward scan in the I-V characteristics. In contrast, FAPbI3based cells consisting of FTO/NIO/ perovskite/PCBM/LiF/Al (p-i-n architecture) showed very strong hysteresis [fig.  S4 (21) ]. JSC, VOC, and FF determined from the J-V curves were 24.7 mA cm -2 , 1.06 V, and 77.5%, respectively, and correspond to a PCE of 20.2% under standard AM 1.5G illumination. Figure  2Cb  shows the EQE spectrum and integrated JSC for one of the best-performing solar cell. The high JSC is attributed to a very broad EQE plateau of &gt;85% in the illumination wavelength range of 400 to 780 nm and broad lightharvesting up to a long wavelength of 840 nm, owing to the relatively low band gap (1.47 eV) of FAPbI3. The JSC value (24.4 mA cm -2 ) obtained by integrating EQE spectrum agreed well with that derived from the J-V measurement. The PCE of the best-performing cell (20.2%) was certified by the standardized method in the PV calibration laboratory, which confirmed a PCE of 20.1% under AM 1.5 G full-sun illuminations [fig.  S5 (21) ]. To gain more insight into the enhanced performance of the FAPbI3-based PSCs, we compared the properties of the films fabricated by IEP with those obtained from a conventional sequential process. A sequential reaction such as inter-diffusion between FAI/MAI and PbI2 through thermal annealing in organic iodide/PbI2 multilayer films has been used to form perovskite FAPbI3/MAPbI3 films from inorganic PbI2 films in the conventional process  (17) . Thus, considerable volume expansion occurs in the sequential deposition process based on PbI2 because of the growth of perovskite crystals with the insertion of organic iodides into PbI2 skeleton  (14, 22) . As expected, an initial PbI2 film with thickness of ~ 290 nm was doubled to 570 nm for the film formed by the reaction of PbI2 with FAI [Table  1  and fig.  S6 (21) ]. In contrast, the change in thickness observed by the application of the FAI (MABr) solution to the pre-deposited PbI2-(DMSO) film was negligible. In fact, the reaction between FAI (MABr) and PbI2(DMSO) was completed within 1 min during spin-coating and the FAPbI3 perovskite phase was formed without sequential annealing. However, in a conventional process using PbI2 films, annealing at high temperature is required to achieve interdiffusion. Figure  3A  compares XRD patterns for as-formed and annealed films by IEP and conventional process from PbI2(DMSO) complex film and PbI2 film, respectively; there is no appreciable difference in XRD patterns between as-formed and annealed film. This result confirms that the FAPbI3-based layer is formed by the IEP of DMSO and FAI (MABr) without additional annealing process. In addition, such an exchange can considerably favor crystallization into perovskite, compared to conventional interdiffusion from PbI2, and led to an increase in the XRD peaks intensity after annealing at 150°C for 20 min. However, the as-formed film with PbI2 showed XRD patterns assigned to PbI2, FAI, and FAPbI3, and a (002) peak at 12.5° corresponding to the PbI2 still remains after annealing at same temperature and time with IEP. In particular, the FAPbI3 film prepared by IEP is remarkably preferred (111)-oriented compared to FAPbI3 film annealed after preparing it by conventional process. The advantages of IEP become further apparent upon comparing the J-V curves and PCEs of FAPbI3-based devices derived from PbI2(DMSO) complex films and conventional PbI2 films (Fig.  3, B  and C ). The devices based on FAPbI3 fabricated from PbI2(DMSO) showed superior PCEs with smaller deviations in the value, compared to those prepared from conventional PbI2 films. High-efficiency solar cells with average PCEs of over 19% could be produced with a high degree of reproducibility by using the IEP. This study provides an effective protocol for fabricating efficient and cost-effective inorganic-organic hybrid heterojunction solar cells.    The tremendous improvements in device architecture (1-3), high-quality film formation methodologies (4-6), and compositional engineering of perovskite materials (7-9) over the last 3 years have led to rapid improvements in the power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs). Although solar-to-electric PCE of up to 18% has been reported for PSCs  (10) , developing technologies further to achieve PCEs near theoretical values continues to be among the most important challenges in the solar cell industry to achieve economic feasibility. Formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI3) is a perovskite material that can potentially provide better performance than methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3) because of its broad absorption of the solar spectrum. In addition, FAPbI3 with the n-i-p architecture (the n-side is illuminated with solar radiation) exhibits negligible hysteresis with sweep direction during current-voltage measurements  (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) . However, compared to MAPbI3, it is more difficult to form stable perovskite phases and high-quality films of FAPbI3. Various methodologies such as sequential deposition (4), solventengineering (5), vapor-assisted deposition (  14 ), additiveassisted deposition  (15, 16) , and vacuum evaporation (  6 ) can now produce high-quality films of MAPbI3 with flat surfaces and complete surface coverage by controlling its rapid crystallization behavior and have led to substantial improve-ments in the PCE of MAPbI3based PSCs. Among these methodologies, two-step sequential deposition and solvent-engineering are representative wet processes that can yield perovskite films for high-performance PSCs. In the sequential deposition process, a thin layer of PbI2 is deposited on the substrate. methylammonium iodide (MAI) or formamidinium iodide (FAI) is then applied to the pre-deposited PbI2 to enable conversion to the perovskite phase. This process involves crystal nucleation and growth of the perovskite phase because of solution-phase or solid-state reaction between PbI2 and an organic iodide such as MAI or FAI  (4, 13, 17) . However, the sequential reaction of organic iodides with PbI2 that occurs from the surface to the inner crystalline regions of PbI2 has been ineffective in producing highperformance perovskite films that are &gt; 500 nm in thickness because of incomplete conversion of PbI2, peeling-off of the perovskite film in solution, and uncontrolled surface roughness. In contrast, the solvent-engineering process utilizes the formation of intermediate phases to retard the rapid reaction between PbI2 and organic iodide in the solution. While this process has been successfully used to form dense and uniform MAPbI3 layers, it has not been explored for FAPbI3  (5) . To deposit a uniform and dense FAPbI3 layer, Snaith et al. added a small amount of aqueous HI to a solution mixture containing PbI2, FAI, and dimethylformamide (DMF)  (11) . Very recently, Zhao et al. reported the deposition of highly uniform and fully covered FAPbI3 films using FAI and HPbI3, which is formed by the reaction of PbI2 and HI in DMF  (18) . The HI in the PbI2 layers retards the rapid reaction between FAI and PbI2. In addition, the release of HI from PbI2 at high temperatures allows the formation of a FAPbI3 layer by solid-state reaction with the neighboring FAI molecules. Stated differently, this process can be regarded as the transformation of PbI2-HI-FAI into FAPbI3, similar to the formation of MAPbI3 via the PbI2dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO)-MAI phase in the solventengineering process  (5) . However, we observed that the solvent-engineering process, which is effective for depositing dense and uniform MAPbI3 layers, yields FAPbI3 layers with pin-holes and a &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="1775" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:29:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="1791" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PbI2-(DMSO)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:39:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="6112" length="11"/>
        <text>PbI2-(DMSO)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-11T19:09:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="6290" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:42:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="10416" length="5"/>
        <text>19.2%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20650</offset>
      <text> High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange Woon Seok Yang, 1 * Jun Hong Noh, 1 * Nam Joong Jeon, 1 Young Chan Kim, 1 Seungchan Ryu, 1 Jangwon Seo, 1 Sang Il Seok 1,2 † 1 Division of Advanced Materials, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology, 141 Gajeong-Ro, Yuseong-Gu, Daejeon 305-600, Korea. 2 Department of Energy Science, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon 440-746, Republic of Korea. †Corresponding author. E-mail: seoksi@krict.re.kr (seoksi@skku.edu) *These authors contributed equally to this work. The band gap of formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI3) perovskites allows broader absorption of the solar spectrum compared to conventional methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI3). The optoelectronic properties of perovskite films are closely related to the film-quality, so depositing dense and uniform films is crucial for fabricating high-performance perovskite solar cells (PSCs). We report an approach for depositing high-quality FAPbI3 films, involving FAPbI3 crystallization by the direct intramolecular exchange of dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO) molecules intercalated in PbI2 with formamidinium iodide. This process produces FAPbI3 films with (111)preferred crystallographic orientation, large-grained dense microstructures, and flat surfaces without residual PbI2. Using films prepared by this technique, FAPbI3-based PSCs with maximum power conversion efficiency of over 20% were fabricated. rough surface. Although the FAPbI3 film-quality including coverage and uniformity on the substrate have been improved, the performance of FAPbI3-solar cells still lag behind those of MAPbI3-based PSC  (8) , implying that more sophisticated deposition techniques are necessary for fabricating high-quality, thick FAPbI3 films (&gt; 500 nm), for achieving sufficient absorption up to a wavelength of 840 nm. As expected from the conversion of PbI2-DMSO-MAI to MAPbI3 (5), the DMSO molecules intercalated in PbI2 can be easily replaced by external FAIs because of its higher affinity toward PbI2 compared to DMSO; the FAI molecules experience ionic interactions, whereas DMSO participates in van der Waals interactions  (5, 19) . Highly uniform and dense pre-deposited PbI2-(DMSO) layers could be directly converted to FAPbI3 because the inorganic PbI2 framework would be retained. FAPbI3 crystallization by the intramolecular exchange process (IEP) of DMSO intercalated in PbI2 with FAI was schematically shown in Fig.  1A . The intramolecular exchange between DMSO and FAI can be described as PbI2-DMSO + FAI → PbI2-FAI + DMSO ↑ (removal) (1) and does not induce volume expansion, unlike the FAP-bI3 formed with FAI intercalating into pristine PbI2 (discussed below) because the molecular sizes of DMSO and FAI are similar. In this work, we report on the synthesis of a PbI2-(DMSO) precursor with excellent capabilities for molecular exchange with FAI at low temperatures during the spinning process, as well as the fabrication of highly efficient FAPbI3based PSCs with certified PCEs exceeding 20%. To synthesize the PbI2-(DMSO) precursors, precipitates were obtained by pouring toluene as a non-solvent into 1.0 M PbI2 solution dissolved in DMSO. The x-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern of the resulting complex (Fig.  1Ba ) matched that of the PbI2(DMSO)2 phase  (5, 19) . The as-prepared PbI2(DMSO)2 was then annealed at 60°C for 24 hours in vacuum to obtain PbI2(DMSO) by removal of 1 mol DMSO. The XRD pattern of the vacuum-annealed powder (Fig.  1Bb ) did not match that of PbI2(DMSO)2, implying that the PbI2(DMSO)2 transformed into a different phase by releasing some DMSO molecules. The content of DMSO in the as-annealed powder was estimated by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA). TGA was suitable for this purpose because the only volatile species in the powder was DMSO. The TGA results of the PbI2(DMSO)2 and PbI2(DMSO) complexes are shown in Fig.  1C . The PbI2(DMSO)2 complex exhibited a two-step decomposition process with weight-loss of 12.6% at each step, whereas the vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) complex showed a singlestep decomposition. The decomposition of both the complexes was completed at the same temperature (138. 6°C). The powders obtained by vacuum-annealing PbI2(DMSO)2 complex at 60°C can be regarded as one of the most thermodynamically stable forms among the various crystalline PbI2-(DMSO)-based complexes, which are similar with PbBr2(DMSO) and PbCl2(DMSO)  (20) . The DMSO content of the vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) complex was also checked by elemental analysis (EA), which yielded H = 1.0% (1.1%); and C = 4.1% (4.4%), where the values expressed in parenthesis indicate the theoretical mass percent for a given element for C2H6SOPbI2. To fabricate FAPbI3-based PSCs through IEP between DMSO and FAI (MABr) using pre-deposited PbI2-DMSO layers and a FAI (MABr) solution, we first confirmed that the PbI2(DMSO) phase was retained even after spin-coating with the PbI2(DMSO) precursor dissolved in DMF. The XRD pattern for film coated on a fused silica substrate was compared with that of the initial precursor. As seen in Fig.  1Bc , the XRD pattern for the as-coated film was in consistent with that of the PbI2(DMSO) complex powder, although its crystallinity is lowered. The as-coated PbI2(DMSO) film also had a flat and dense surface, as shown in the field-emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM) image in fig.  S1 (21) . Next, we investigated the formation of mixed FAP-bI3/MAPbBr3 by IEP. We recently reported that the coexistence of MA/FA/I/Br in the PbI2 skeleton improved the phase-stability of FAPbI3  (10) . The formation of mixed FAP-bI3/MAPbBr3 layers via IEP was controlled by coating solution mixture with different weight ratios of MABr to FAI dissolved in isopropyl alcohol (IPA), on the pre-deposited PbI2(DMSO) layers (discussed below). It is evident from Fig.  1Da  that well-crystallized FAPbI3-based films were formed by IEP. The XRD pattern for the FAPbI3 film derived from the PbI2(DMSO) complex film exhibits dominant (-111) and (-222) diffraction peaks at 13.9° and 28.1°, respectively, corresponding to the FAPbI3 trigonal perovskite phase (P3m1), in contrast with the XRD patterns of the FAPbI3 powder (Fig.  1Db )  (13) . The intensity ratio of (-123) peak at 31.5 ° to the (-222) peak at 28.1° was 0.05. This value was much smaller than the corresponding intensity ratios (= 0.8) for the FAPbI3 power. Thus, IEP leads to high-quality pure FAPbI3-based films with preferred orientation along the [111] axis.   (10) . Fortunately, the simultaneous introduction of both MA + cations and Br -anions in FAPbI3 even after incorporating 5 mol% of MAPbBr3 serves to stabilize the perovskite phase  (10) . After comparing the absorption coefficients of FAPbI3 and MAPbI3 at wavelengths beyond 800 nm, we noted that the thickness of a FAPbI3 layer needed to be higher than the optimal thickness of a typical perovskite layer with a band gap of ~1.55 eV (300 to 400 nm) to guarantee fully lightharvesting around 800 nm  (20, 22) . We deposited FAPbI3based layers with thickness of ~ 500 nm, and fabricated devices consisting of fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)glass/barrier layer (bl)-TiO2/mesoporous (mp)-TiO2/perovskite/poly-triarylamine (PTAA)/Au (n-i-p architecture), as shown in the cross-sectional FESEM image of Fig.  2A . FESEM plane-view images of the device with film derived from PbI2(DMSO) complex and PbI2 films are shown in Fig.  2B . The FAPbI3 film derived from PbI2(DMSO) exhibited a dense and well-developed grain structure with larger grains than the FAPbI3 film derived from PbI2. Figure  2Ca  shows the J-V curves measured via reverse and forward bias sweep for one of the best-performing solar cell. The devices we fabricated also showed no hysteresis. Here, we believe that the hysteresis is highly dependent on the perovskite materials (FAPbI3 or MAPbI3) and cell architecture (n-i-p or p-i-n), although the ferroelectric properties of the perovskite itself are more likely to be the origin of the hysteresis in PSCs  (23, 24) . Thus, FAPbI3-based PSCs with n-i-p architecture show negligible hysteresis between the reverse and the forward scan in the I-V characteristics. In contrast, FAPbI3based cells consisting of FTO/NiO/ perovskite/PCBM/LiF/Al (p-i-n architecture) showed very strong hysteresis [fig.  S4  (21) ]. JSC, VOC, and FF determined from the J-V curves were 24.7 mA cm -2 , 1.06 V, and 77.5%, respectively, and correspond to a PCE of 20.2% under standard AM 1.5G illumination. Figure  2Cb  shows the EQE spectrum and integrated JSC for one of the best-performing solar cell. The high JSC is attributed to a very broad EQE plateau of &gt;85% in the illumination wavelength range of 400 to 780 nm and broad lightharvesting up to a long wavelength of 840 nm, owing to the relatively low band gap (1.47 eV) of FAPbI3. The JSC value (24.4 mA cm -2 ) obtained by integrating EQE spectrum agreed well with that derived from the J-V measurement. The PCE of the best-performing cell (20.2%) was certified by the standardized method in the PV calibration laboratory, which confirmed a PCE of 20.1% under AM 1.5 G full-sun illuminations [fig.  S5 (21) ]. To gain more insight into the enhanced performance of the FAPbI3-based PSCs, we compared the properties of the films fabricated by IEP with those obtained from a conventional sequential process. A sequential reaction such as inter-diffusion between FAI/MAI and PbI2 through thermal annealing in organic iodide/PbI2 multilayer films has been used to form perovskite FAPbI3/MAPbI3 films from inorganic PbI2 films in the conventional process  (17) . Thus, considerable volume expansion occurs in the sequential deposition process based on PbI2 because of the growth of perovskite crystals with the insertion of organic iodides into PbI2 skeleton  (14, 22) . As expected, an initial PbI2 film with thickness of ~ 290 nm was doubled to 570 nm for the film formed by the reaction of PbI2 with FAI [Table  1  and fig.  S6 (21) ]. In contrast, the change in thickness observed by the application of the FAI (MABr) solution to the pre-deposited PbI2-(DMSO) film was negligible. In fact, the reaction between FAI (MABr) and PbI2(DMSO) was completed within 1 min during spin-coating and the FAPbI3 perovskite phase was formed without sequential annealing. However, in a conventional process using PbI2 films, annealing at high temperature is required to achieve interdiffusion. Figure  3A  compares XRD patterns for as-formed and annealed films by IEP and conventional process from PbI2(DMSO) complex film and PbI2 film, respectively; there is no appreciable difference in XRD patterns between as-formed and annealed film. This result confirms that the FAPbI3-based layer is formed by the IEP of DMSO and FAI (MABr) without additional annealing process. In addition, such an exchange can considerably favor crystallization into perovskite, compared to conventional interdiffusion from PbI2, and led to an increase in the XRD peaks intensity after annealing at 150°C for 20 min. However, the as-formed film with PbI2 showed XRD patterns assigned to PbI2, FAI, and FAPbI3, and a (002) peak at 12.5° corresponding to the PbI2 still remains after annealing at same temperature and time with IEP. In particular, the FAPbI3 film prepared by IEP is remarkably preferred (111)-oriented compared to FAPbI3 film annealed after preparing it by conventional process. The advantages of IEP become further apparent upon comparing the J-V curves and PCEs of FAPbI3-based devices derived from PbI2(DMSO) complex films and conventional PbI2 films (Fig.  3, B  and C ). The devices based on FAPbI3 fabricated from PbI2(DMSO) showed superior PCEs with smaller deviations in the value, compared to those prepared from conventional PbI2 films. High-efficiency solar cells with average PCEs of over 19% could be produced with a high degree of reproducibility by using the IEP. This study provides an effective protocol for fabricating efficient and cost-effective inorganic-organic hybrid heterojunction solar cells.    T he tremendous improvements in device architecture (1-3), high-quality film formation methodologies (4-6), and compositional engineering of perovskite materials (7-9) over the past 3 years have led to rapid improvements in the power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs). Although solarto-electric PCEs of up to 18% have been reported for PSCs  (10) , developing technologies further to achieve PCEs near theoretical values (&gt;30%) continues to be an important challenge in making the solar cell industry economically competitive. Formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) is a perovskite material that can potentially provide better performance than methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI 3 ) because of its broad absorption of the solar spectrum. In addition, FAPbI 3 with the n-i-p architecture (the n-side is illuminated with solar radiation) exhibits negligible hysteresis with sweep direction during current-voltage measurements  (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) . However, it is more difficult to form stable perovskite phases and highquality films with FAPbI 3 than with MAPbI 3 . Various methodologies such as sequential deposition (4), solvent engineering (  5 ), vapor-assisted deposition (  14 ), additive-assisted deposition  (15, 16) , and vacuum evaporation (  6 ) can now produce high-quality films of MAPbI 3 with flat surfaces and complete surface coverage by controlling its rapid crystallization behavior and have led to substantial improvements in the PCE of MAPbI 3based PSCs. Among these methodologies, two-step sequential deposition and solvent engineering are representative wet processes that can yield perovskite films for high-performance PSCs. In the sequential deposition process, a thin layer of PbI 2 is deposited on the substrate; methylammonium iodide (MAI) or formamidinium iodide (FAI) is then applied to the predeposited PbI 2 to enable conversion to the perovskite phase. This process involves crystal nucleation and growth of the perovskite phase because of solution-phase or solidstate reaction between PbI 2 and an organic iodide such as MAI or FAI  (4, 13, 17, 18) . However, the sequential reaction of organic iodides with PbI 2 that occurs from the surface to the inner crystalline regions of PbI 2 has been ineffective in producing high-performance perovskite films that are &gt;500 nm in thickness because of incomplete conversion of PbI 2 , peeling off of the perovskite film in solution, and uncontrolled surface roughness. In contrast, the solvent-engineering process uses the formation of intermediate phases to *These authors contributed equally to this work. †Corresponding author. E-mail: seoksi@krict.re.kr Table  1 . Comparison of layer thickness before and after FAPbI 3 phase is formed by conventional and intramolecular exchange process (IEP). The thin PbI 2 and PbI 2 (DMSO) layers were deposited on a fused quartz glass, and their layer thickness was measured by alpha-step IQ surface profiler. retard the rapid reaction between PbI 2 and organic iodide in the solution. Although this process has been successfully used to form dense and uniform MAPbI 3 layers, it has not been explored for FAPbI 3  (5) . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35905</offset>
      <text> Method To deposit a uniform and dense FAPbI 3 layer, Snaith et al. added a small amount of aqueous hydrogen iodide (HI) to a solution mixture containing PbI 2 , FAI, and dimethylformamide (DMF)  (11) . Very recently, Zhao et al. reported the deposition of highly uniform and fully covered FAPbI 3 films using FAI and HPbI 3 , which is formed by the reaction of PbI 2 and HI in DMF  (19) . The HI in the PbI 2 layers retards the rapid reaction between FAI and PbI 2 . In addition, the release of HI from PbI 2 at high temperatures allows the formation of a FAPbI 3 layer by solid-state reaction with the neighboring FAI molecules. Stated differently, this process can be regarded as the transformation of PbI 2 -HI-FAI into FAPbI 3 , similar to the formation of MAPbI 3 via the PbI 2 -dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO)-MAI phase in the solvent-engineering process  (5) . However, we observed that the solventengineering process, which is effective for depositing dense and uniform MAPbI 3 layers, yields FAPbI 3 layers with pinholes and a rough surface. Although aspects of FAPbI 3 film quality, including coverage and uniformity on the substrate, have   SCIENCE sciencemag.org &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37075</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH | REPORTS Downloaded from  https://www.science.org  at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 been improved, the performance of FAPbI 3 solar cells still lags behind that of MAPbI 3 -based PSCs  (8) , implying that more sophisticated deposition techniques are necessary for fabricating highquality, thick FAPbI 3 films (&gt;500 nm) that would enable sufficient absorption up to a wavelength of 840 nm. As expected from the conversion of PbI 2 (DMSO)-MAI to MAPbI 3  (5) , the DMSO molecules intercalated in PbI 2 can be easily replaced by external FAIs because of their higher affinity toward PbI 2 relative to DMSO; the FAI molecules experience ionic interactions, whereas DMSO participates in van der Waals interactions  (5, 20) . Highly uniform and dense predeposited PbI 2 -DMSO layers could be directly converted to FAPbI 3 because the inorganic PbI 2 framework would be retained. FAPbI 3 crystallization by the intramolecular exchange process (IEP) of DMSO intercalated in PbI 2 with FAI was schematically shown in Fig.  1A . The intramolecular exchange between DMSO and FAI can be described as PbI 2 -DMSO þ FAI → PbI 2 -FAI þ DMSO ↑ ðremovalÞ ð1Þ and does not induce volume expansion, unlike the FAPbI 3 formed with FAI intercalating into pristine PbI 2 (discussed below), because the molecular sizes of DMSO and FAI are similar. In this work, we report on the synthesis of a PbI 2 (DMSO) precursor with excellent capabilities for molecular exchange with FAI at low temperatures during the spinning process, as well as the fabrication of highly efficient FAPbI 3based PSCs with certified PCEs exceeding 20%. To synthesize the PbI 2 (DMSO) precursors, we obtained precipitates by pouring toluene as a nonsolvent into 1.0 M PbI 2 solution dissolved in DMSO. The x-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern of the resulting complex [Fig.  1B(a) ] matched that of the PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 phase  (5, 20) . The as-prepared PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 was then annealed at 60°C for 24 hours in vacuum to obtain PbI 2 (DMSO) by removal of 1 mol DMSO. The XRD pattern of the vacuum-annealed powder [Fig.  1B(b) ] did not match that of PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 , implying that the PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 transformed into a different phase by releasing some DMSO molecules. The content of DMSO in the as-annealed powder was estimated by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA). TGA was suitable for this purpose because the only volatile species in the powder was DMSO. The TGA results of the PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 and PbI 2 (DMSO) complexes are shown in Fig.  1C . The PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 complex exhibited a two-step decomposition process with weight loss of 12.6% at each step, whereas the vacuumannealed PbI 2 (DMSO) complex showed a singlestep decomposition. The decomposition of both the complexes was completed at the same temperature (138.6°C). The powders obtained by vacuum-annealing PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 complex at 60°C can be regarded as one of the most thermodynamically stable forms among the various crystalline PbI 2 (DMSO)-based complexes, which are similar to those of PbBr 2 (DMSO) and PbCl 2 (DMSO)  (21) . The DMSO content of the vacuum-annealed PbI 2 (DMSO) complex was also checked by elemental analysis, which yielded H = 1.0% (1.1%); and C = 4.1% (4.4%), where the values expressed in parentheses indicate the theoretical mass percent for a given element in C 2 H 6 SOPbI 2 . To fabricate FAPbI 3 -based PSCs through IEP between DMSO and FAI (MABr) using predeposited PbI 2 (DMSO) layers and a FAI (MABr) solution, we first confirmed that the PbI 2 (DMSO) phase was retained even after spin-coating with the PbI 2 (DMSO) precursor dissolved in DMF. The XRD pattern for film coated on a fused silica substrate was compared with that of the initial precursor. As seen in Fig.  1B(c ), the XRD pattern for the as-coated film was consistent with that of the PbI 2 (DMSO) complex powder, although its crystallinity was lower. The as-coated PbI 2 (DMSO) film also had a flat and dense surface, as shown in the field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM) image in fig.  S1    (22) . Next, we investigated the formation of mixed FAPbI 3 /MAPbBr 3 by IEP. We recently reported that the coexistence of MA/FA/I/Br in the PbI 2 skeleton improved the phase stability of FAPbI 3  (10) . The formation of mixed FAPbI 3 /MAPbBr 3 layers via IEP was controlled by coating the solution mixture with different weight ratios of MABr to FAI, dissolved in isopropyl alcohol, on the predeposited PbI 2 (DMSO) layers (see below). It is evident from   the FAPbI 3 -MAPbBr 3 perovskite phase through an intramolecular exchange reaction. Nonetheless, the highest PCE of 19.2% was achieved for the film fabricated from a FAI solution containing 15 wt% MABr. To accurately determine the composition of the FAPbI 3 -based layer, we investigated the lattice parameter using XRD and the band gap using the EQE for the film showing the best performance. Figure S3  (22)  shows the pseudocubic lattice parameter for (FAPbI 3 ) 1-x (MAPbBr 3 ) x as a function of x, in which the composition was controlled by a previously reported method  (10) . In this study, the pseudocubic lattice parameter of the FAPbI 3 / MAPbBr 3 film fabricated by IEP with a FAI solution containing 15 wt% MABr is 6.348 Å. As indicated in fig.  S4    (22) , the lattice parameter can be assigned as x = ~5, corresponding to (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 . This result is in agreement with the value estimated using the band gap (1.49 eV) from EQE [fig.  S3 (22) ], because pure FAPbI 3 has a band gap of 1.47 eV and (FAPbI 3 ) 0.85 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.15 has a band gap of 1.55 eV  (10) . Fortunately, the simultaneous introduction of both MA + cations and Br -anions in FAPbI 3 even after incorporating 5 mol% of MAPbBr 3 serves to stabilize the perovskite phase  (10) . After comparing the absorption coefficients of FAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 at wavelengths beyond 800 nm, we noted that the thickness of a FAPbI 3 layer needed to be higher than the optimal thickness of a typical perovskite layer with a band gap of ~1.55 eV (300 to 400 nm) to guarantee full light harvesting around 800 nm  (21, 23) . We deposited FAPbI 3 -based layers with thickness of ~500 nm, and fabricated consisting of fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)-glass/barrier layer (bl)-TiO 2 /mesoporous (mp)-TiO 2 /perovskite/ polytriarylamine (PTAA)/Au (n-i-p architecture), as shown in the cross-sectional FESEM image of Fig.  2A . FESEM plane-view images of the device with film derived from PbI 2 (DMSO) complex and PbI 2 films are shown in Fig.  2B . The FAPbI 3 film derived from PbI 2 (DMSO) exhibited a dense and well-developed grain structure with larger grains than the FAPbI 3 film derived from PbI 2 . Figure  2C(a)  shows the J-V curves measured via reverse and forward bias sweep for one of the best-performing solar cells. The devices we fabricated also showed no hysteresis. Here, we believe that the hysteresis is highly dependent on the perovskite materials (FAPbI 3 or MAPbI 3 ) and cell architecture (n-i-p or p-i-n), although the ferroelectric properties of the perovskite itself are more likely to be the origin of the hysteresis in PSCs  (24, 25) . Thus, FAPbI 3 -based PSCs with n-i-p architecture show negligible hysteresis between the reverse and the forward scan in the I-V characteristics. In contrast, FAPbI 3based cells consisting of FTO/NiO/perovskite/ PCBM/LiF/Al (p-i-n architecture) showed very strong hysteresis [fig.  S4 (22) ]. Values of shortcircuit current density (J SC ), open-circuit voltage (V OC ), and fill factor (FF) determined from the J-V curves were 24.7 mA cm -2 , 1.06 V, and 77.5%, respectively, and correspond to a PCE of 20.2% under standard AM 1.5G illumination. Figure  2C(b)  shows the EQE spectrum and integrated J SC for one of the best-performing solar cell. The high J SC is attributed to a very broad EQE plateau of &gt;85% in the illumination wavelength range of 400 to 780 nm and broad lightharvesting up to a long wavelength of 840 nm, owing to the relatively low band gap (1.47 eV) of FAPbI 3 . The J SC value (24.4 mA cm -2 ) obtained by integrating EQE spectrum agreed well with that derived from the J-V measurement. The PCE of the best-performing cell (20.2%) was certified by the standardized method in the PV calibration laboratory, which confirmed a PCE of 20.1% under AM 1.5 G full-Sun illuminations [fig.  S5 (22) ]. To gain more insight into the enhanced performance of the FAPbI 3 -based PSCs, we compared the properties of the films fabricated by IEP with those obtained from a conventional sequential process. A sequential reaction such as interdiffusion between FAI/MAI and PbI 2 through thermal annealing in organic iodide/PbI 2 multilayer films has been used to form perovskite FAPbI 3 / MAPbI 3 films from inorganic PbI 2 films in the conventional process  (17, 18) . Thus, considerable volume expansion occurs in the sequential deposition process based on PbI 2 because of the growth of perovskite crystals with the insertion of organic iodides into PbI 2 skeleton  (14, 23) . As expected, an initial PbI 2 film with thickness of ~290 nm was doubled to 570 nm for the film formed by the reaction of PbI 2 with FAI [Table  1  and fig.  S6 (22) ]. In contrast, the change in thickness observed by the application of the FAI (MABr) solution to the predeposited PbI 2 (DMSO) film was negligible. In fact, the reaction between FAI (MABr) and PbI 2 (DMSO) was completed within 1 min during spin-coating and the FAPbI 3 perovskite phase was formed without sequential annealing. However, in a conventional process using PbI 2 films, annealing at high temperature is required to achieve interdiffusion. Figure  3A  compares XRD patterns for as-formed and annealed films by IEP and conventional process from PbI 2 (DMSO) complex film and PbI 2 film, respectively; there is no appreciable difference in XRD patterns between as-formed and annealed film. This result confirms that the FAPbI 3 -based layer is formed by the IEP of DMSO and FAI (MABr) without additional annealing process. In addition, such an exchange can considerably favor crystallization into perovskite, compared to conventional interdiffusion from PbI 2 , and led to an increase in the XRD peaks intensity after annealing at 150°C for 20 min. However, the asformed film with PbI 2 showed XRD patterns assigned to PbI 2 , FAI, and FAPbI 3 , and a (002) peak at 12.5°corresponding to the PbI 2 still remained after annealing at same temperature and time with IEP. In particular, the FAPbI 3 film prepared by IEP shows preferred orientation in the (111) direction compared to FAPbI 3 film annealed after preparing it by conventional process. The advantages of IEP become further apparent upon comparing the J-V curves and PCEs of FAPbI 3 -based devices derived from PbI 2 (DMSO) complex films and conventional PbI 2 films (Fig.  3, B  and C ). The devices based on FAPbI 3 fabricated from PbI 2 (DMSO) showed superior PCEs with smaller deviations in the value, compared to those prepared from conventional PbI 2 films. High-efficiency solar cells with average PCEs of &gt;19% could be produced with a high degree of reproducibility by using the IEP. This study provides an effective protocol for fabricating efficient and cost-effective inorganic-organic hybrid heterojunction solar cells. layer/mp-TiO 2 /bl-TiO 2 /FTO substrate at 3000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, an Au counter electrode was deposited by thermal evaporation; the active area of this electrode was fixed at 0.16 cm 2 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48587</offset>
      <text> Characterization The X-ray diffraction (XRD) spectra of the prepared films were measured using a Rigaku SmartLab X-ray diffractometer with an X-ray tube (Cu Kα, λ=1.5406Å). The morphology of the films was observed using a field-emission scanning electron microscope (MIRA3 LMU, Tescan). The elemental analysis (C, H, N and S) of the complex was performed using a FISONS EA_1108 CHN analyser. Thermal gravity (TG) analyses of the asprepare PbI 2 -(DMSO) complex powders were performed with a heating rate of 2 ºC/min from RT up to 300 ºC under nitrogen atmosphere using TA Instruments SDT 2960. External quantum efficiency (EQE) was measured by a power source (Newport 300W Xenon lamp, 66920) with a monochromator (Newport Cornerstone 260) and a multimeter (Keithley2001). The J-V curves were measured using a solar simulator (Newport, Oriel Class A, 91195A) with a source meter (Keithley 2420) at 100 mA/cm 2 illumination AM 1.5 G and a calibrated Sireference cell certificated by NREL. The J-V curves were measured by reverse (forward bias (1.2 V)  short circuit (0 V)) or forward (short circuit (0 V)  forward bias (1.2 V)) scan. The step voltage and the delay time were fixed at 10 mV and 40 msec, respectively. The delay time is a delay set at each voltage step before measuring each current. The J-V curves for all devices were measured by masking the active area with a metal mask (area of 0.096 cm 2 ).       Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. PbI2-complex formation and X-ray diffraction. (A) Schematics of FAPbI3 perovskite crystallization involving the direct intramolecular exchange of dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO) molecules intercalated in PbI2 with formamidinium iodide (FAI). The DMSO molecules are intercalated between edge-sharing [PbI6] octahedral layers. (B) XRD patterns of (a) as-prepared PbI2(DMSO)2 powders, (b) vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) powders, and (c) as-deposited film on fused quartz substrate using PbI2(DMSO) complex solution. (C) TGA of PbI2(DMSO)2 (red line) and PbI2(DMSO) (dark blue line). (D) XRD patterns of (a) as-formed film of FAPbI3 by IEP, and (b) FAPbI3 powder. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50684</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. SEM observation, I-V and EQE measurements. (A) Cross-sectional FESEM image of the device consisting of FTO-Glass/bl-TiO2/mp-TiO2/perovskite/PTAA/Au. (B) The comparison of FESEM surface images of FAPbI3-based layer formed on mp-TiO2 by IEP and conventional method. (C) (a) J-V curves of best device measured with a 40 ms scanning delay in reverse (from 1.2 V to 0 V) and forward (from 0 V to 1.2 V) modes under standard AM 1.5G illumination, and (b) EQE spectra for best device and integrated JSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51202</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Comparison of X-ray diffractions, performance, and reproducibility between IEP and conventional process. (A) XRD patterns of as-formed and annealed film for FAPbI3-based layers formed by IEP (red line) and conventional (blue line) process. α, #, and * denote the identified diffraction peaks corresponding to the FAPbI3 perovskite phase, PbI2, and FAI, respectively. (B) Representative J-V curves for FAPbI3-based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. (C) Histogram of solar cell efficiencies for each 66 FAPbI3-based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51804</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 (21) presents the current density-voltage (J-V) curves measured under standard air-mass 1.5 global (AM 1.5G) illumination, and the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the fabricated cells with FAPbI3-based layers fabricated with various amounts of MABr (0 to 20 wt%).The onset wavelength in the EQE spectra near 830 nm showed a non-linear blue shift with increasing amounts of MABr, indicating that there is unsymmetrical competition between FAI and MABr in forming the FAPbI3-MAPbBr3 perovskite phase through an intramolecular exchange reaction. Nevertheless, the highest PCE of 19.2% was achieved for the film fabricated from a FAI solution containing 15 wt% MABr. To accurately determine the composition of the FAPbI3-based layer, we investigated the lattice parameter using XRD and the band gap using the EQE for the film showing the best performance. Fig.S3(21) shows the pseudocubic lattice parameter for (FAPbI3)1-x(MAPbBr3)x as a function of x, in which the composition was controlled by a previously reported method(10). In this study, the pseudocubic lattice parameter of the FAPbI3/MAPbBr3 film fabricated by IEP with a FAI solution containing 15 mol% MABr is 6.348 Å. As indicated in fig.S4(21), the lattice parameter can be assigned as x = ~ 5, corresponding to (FAP-bI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05. This result is in agreement with the value estimated using the band gap (1.49 eV) from EQE [fig. S3 (21)], because pure FAPbI3 has a band gap of 1.47 eV and (FAPbI3)0.85(MAPbBr3)0.15, 1.55 eV &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53319</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. PbI2-complex formation and X-ray diffraction. (A) Schematics of FAPbI3 perovskite crystallization involving the direct intramolecular exchange of dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO) molecules intercalated in PbI2 with formamidinium iodide (FAI). The DMSO molecules are intercalated between edge-sharing [PbI6] octahedral layers. (B) XRD patterns of (a) as-prepared PbI2(DMSO)2 powders, (b) vacuum-annealed PbI2(DMSO) powders, and (c) as-deposited film on fused quartz substrate using PbI2(DMSO) complex solution. (C) TGA of PbI2(DMSO)2 (red line) and PbI2(DMSO) (dark blue line). (D) XRD patterns of (a) as-formed film of FAPbI3 by IEP, and (b) FAPbI3 powder. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53989</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. SEM observation, I-V and EQE measurements. (A) Cross-sectional FESEM image of the device consisting of FTO-Glass/bl-TiO2/mp-TiO2/perovskite/PTAA/Au. (B) The comparison of FESEM surface images of FAPbI3-based layer formed on mp-TiO2 by IEP and conventional method. (C) (a) J-V curves of best device measured with a 40 ms scanning delay in reverse (from 1.2 V to 0 V) and forward (from 0 V to 1.2 V) modes under standard AM 1.5G illumination, and (b) EQE spectra for best device and integrated JSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54507</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Comparison of X-ray diffractions, performance, and reproducibility between IEP and conventional process. (A) XRD patterns of as-formed and annealed film for FAPbI3-based layers formed by IEP (red line) and conventional (blue line) process. α, #, and * denote the identified diffraction peaks corresponding to the FAPbI3 perovskite phase, PbI2, and FAI, respectively. (B) Representative J-V curves for FAPbI3-based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. (C) Histogram of solar cell efficiencies for each 66 FAPbI3-based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55109</offset>
      <text> 1234 12 JUNE 2015 • VOL 348 ISSUE 6240 sciencemag.org SCIENCE 1 Division of Advanced Materials, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology, 141 Gajeong-Ro, Yuseong-Gu, Daejeon 305-600, Korea. 2 Department of Energy Science, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon 440-746, Korea. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55389</offset>
      <text> Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55490</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. PbI 2 complex formation and x-ray diffraction. (A) Schematics of FAPbI 3 perovskite crystallization involving the direct intramolecular exchange of DMSO molecules intercalated in PbI 2 with formamidinium iodide (FAI). The DMSO molecules are intercalated between edge-sharing [PbI 6 ] octahedral layers. (B) XRD patterns of (a) as-prepared PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 powders, (b) vacuum-annealed PbI 2 (DMSO) powders, and (c) as-deposited film on fused quartz substrate using PbI 2 (DMSO) complex solution. (C) TGA of PbI 2 (DMSO) 2 (red line) and PbI 2 (DMSO) (dark blue line). (D) XRD patterns of (a) as-formed film of FAPbI 3 by IEP, and (b) FAPbI 3 powder. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56159</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. SEM observations and J-V and EQE measurements. (A) Cross-sectional FESEM image of the device consisting of FTO-glass/bl-TiO 2 /mp-TiO 2 / perovskite/PTAA/Au. (B) The comparison of FESEM surface images of FAPbI 3 -based layer formed on mp-TiO 2 by IEP and conventional method. (C) (a) J-V curves of best device measured with a 40-ms scanning delay in reverse (from 1.2 V to 0 V) and forward (from 0 V to 1.2 V) modes under standard AM 1.5G illumination, and (b) EQE spectra for best device and integrated J SC . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56691</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1D(a) that well-crystallized FAPbI 3 -based films were formed by IEP. The XRD pattern for the FAPbI 3 film derived from the PbI 2 (DMSO) complex film exhibits dominant (-111) and (-222) diffraction peaks at 13.9°and 28.1°, respectively, corresponding to the FAPbI 3 trigonal perovskite phase (P3m1), in contrast with the XRD patterns of the FAPbI 3 powder [Fig. 1D(b)] (13). The intensity ratio of the (-123) peak at 31.5°to the (-222) peak at 28.1°was 0.05. This value was much smaller than the corresponding intensity ratios (0.8) for the FAPbI 3 powder. Thus, IEP leads to high-quality pure FAPbI 3based films with preferred orientation along the [111] axis. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57364</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 ( 22 ) 22 Fig. 3. Comparison of x-ray diffractions, performance, and reproducibility between IEP and conventional process. (A) XRD patterns of asformed and annealed film for FAPbI 3 -based layers formed by IEP (red line) and conventional (blue line) process. a, #, and * denote the identified diffraction peaks corresponding to the FAPbI 3 perovskite phase, PbI 2 , and FAI, respectively. (B) Representative J-V curves for FAPbI 3 -based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. (C) Histogram of solar cell efficiencies for each 66 FAPbI 3 -based cells fabricated by IEP and conventional process. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57982</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH | REPORTSDownloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58101</offset>
      <text> Fig. S1 . S1 Fig. S1. Plan-view FESEM image of PbI 2 (DMSO) complex film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58177</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. J-V curves and EQE spectra for cells fabricated using FAPbI 3 -based layer formed by adding MABr in FAI solution through IEP. Blue shift in EQE spectra was observed with increasing MABr content. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58396</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Pseudocubic lattice parameters for (FAPbI 3 ) 1-x (MAPbBr 3 ) x as a function of x. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58504</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4. J-V curves in reverse and forward sweep, with delay time for FTO/NiO(ptype)/FAPbI 3 /PCBM(n-type)/LiF/Al cell. Step voltage, delay time are 10 mV, 10 msec, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58685</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. Independent certification from Newport Corporation, confirming a PCE of 20.1 %. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58789</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. Cross-sectional SEM images before and after FAPbI 3 phase is formed by conventional and intramolecular exchange process &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58933</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . Comparison of layer thickness before and after FAPbI 3 phase is formed by conventional and intramolecular exchange process. 1 The thin PbI 2 and PbI 2 (DMSO) layers were deposited on a fused quartz glass, and their layer thickness was measured by alpha-step IQ surface profiler. Method Before After Conventional process (PbI 2 ) 290 nm 570 nm IEP (PbI 2 (DMSO)) 510 nm 560 nm Reports / sciencemag.org/content/early/recent / 21 May 2015 / Page 1 / 10.1126/science.aaa9272 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59416</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . Comparison of layer thickness before and after FAPbI 3 phase is formed by conventional and intramolecular exchange process. 1 The thin PbI 2 and PbI 2 (DMSO) layers were deposited on a fused quartz glass, and their layer thickness was measured by alpha-step IQ surface profiler.Woon Seok Yang, 1 * Jun Hong Noh, 1 * Nam Joong Jeon, 1 Young Chan Kim,1  Seungchan Ryu,1 Jangwon Seo,1 Sang Il Seok 1,2 †The band gap of formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 ) perovskites allows broader absorption of the solar spectrum relative to conventional methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI 3 ). Because the optoelectronic properties of perovskite films are closely related to film quality, deposition of dense and uniform films is crucial for fabricating high-performance perovskite solar cells (PSCs). We report an approach for depositing high-quality FAPbI 3 films, involving FAPbI 3 crystallization by the direct intramolecular exchange of dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO) molecules intercalated in PbI 2 with formamidinium iodide. This process produces FAPbI 3 films with (111)-preferred crystallographic orientation, large-grained dense microstructures, and flat surfaces without residual PbI 2 . Using films prepared by this technique, we fabricated FAPbI 3 -based PSCs with maximum power conversion efficiency greater than 20%. Method Before After Conventional process (PbI 2 ) 290 nm 570 nm IEP (PbI 2 (DMSO)) 510 nm 560 nm &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60836</offset>
      <text>			 February 2015; accepted 30 April 2015 Published online 21 May 2015 10.1126/science.aaa9272 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60932</offset>
      <text>			 February 2015; accepted 4 May 2015 10.1126/science.aaa8765 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60996</offset>
      <text>			 JUNE 2015 • VOL 348 ISSUE 6240</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
