<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025031051EIGDGH</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_review">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 46&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Visualization and suppression of interfacial recombination for high-efficiency large-area pin perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>129</offset>
      <text>Supplementary Figure 1. Coupled Optical and Shockley-Queisser-Modelling. Fill factor (FF) as a function of ITO thickness and device aspect ratio corresponding to the device simulation in Figure 2b. For ITO thicknesses of 150 nm with a sheet resistance 15 Ω/sq a theoretical FF of 80.2% (73.8%) can be achieved for an device aspect ratio of 0.16 (0.64), respectively. The trend is in good agreement with the experimental results in Figure  2a .&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>575</offset>
      <text>Supplementary Figure  2 . Fluence-dependent transient photoluminescence. (a, b) TRPL analysis of the bare perovskite absorber and (c, d) the PVK/C60 stack illuminated at 700 nm and 510 nm excitation through the front glass (bare perovskite) and C60 (perovskite/ C60). For the neat absorber the decay is faster for high generation levels due to radiative emission (and/or Auger contributions). At very low injection levels we can recover a single exponential decay, interpreted as the minority carrier SRH lifetime. For the perovskite/C60 stack, the decay times are generally much shorter while 510 nm excitation causes a fast initial drop of the PL intensity (almost an order of magnitude relative to 700 nm), indicating a significant early time loss of carriers at the interface between the perovskite and C60. For the bare perovskite, the initial decay is much smaller at 510 nm due to a much better interface to glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1498</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Note 1. Estimation of achievable Voc based on the monoexponential TRPL lifetime As recently demonstrated by Tress,  1  the achievable 𝑉 𝑂𝐶 in case of dominant Shockley-Read-Hall recombination can be predicted from the carrier lifetime (𝜏 SRH ) with the additional knowledge of the cells' short-circuit current density (~ 22 mA/cm 2 ), the bandgap (𝜖 G ~ 1.6 eV), the active layer thickness (𝑑 ~ 400 nm), and the electron (hole) effective masses (𝑚 * e(h) ~ 0.25 𝑚 e ).  1  𝑒𝑉 OC = 𝜖 G + 𝑘 B 𝑇 * ln ( 𝑛 e 𝑛 h 𝑁 C 𝑁 V ) (eq. 1) 𝑑𝑛 e 𝑑𝑡 = 𝐺 -𝑅 = 0 ~ 𝐺 -𝑛 e 𝜏 SRH  → 𝑛 e ~ 𝐺𝜏 SRH (eq. 2) Here, 𝑘 B 𝑇 𝑒 is the thermal voltage, 𝐺 and 𝑅 the generation and recombination rates (𝐺 is approximated by Quantum Efficiency (EQE) of our standard cells (ITO/PTAA/perovskite/C60/BCP/Cu) demonstrating a sharp absorption onset and Urbach tail of 14 meV. This allows the determination of a radiative recombination current J 0,rad of ~4x10 -21 Am -2 , which yields a radiative V OC limit of 1.345 V at room temperature and using a generation (short-circuit) current density of 22 mAcm -2 . Photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY), PL peak positions and average QFLS splitting values on 1cm  2  -sized films on glass to check the reproducibility of the results. We note a relatively large batchto-batch variation for PTAA/perovskite films indicating difficulties to reproduce high quality films using neat PTAA (without PFN). On the other hand, the quasi-Fermi level splitting of other films could be well reproduced. Films marked with "*" are shown and discussed in the main text. The thickness of all layers of the films is identical to the thicknesses used for the final solar cell stack. MAPI). In particular, our CsFAPbI3 perovskite cells compare exceptionally well to previously reported (MA/Br-free) FAPbI3 nip-cells; e.g. ~17.5% for neat FAPbI3 from Seok and co-workers 3 , 19.2% Wang et al.  4  for benzylamine-modified FAPbI3 cells, and Yu et al.  5  with 19.6% (18.1% forward scan) for FA0.8Cs0.2PbI3 cells. We note that all these studies employed nip cells with strongly doped spiroOMeTAD while we can achieve slightly higher efficiencies for pin-type cells with ultrathin undoped charge transport layers. Lastly, we note, that the application of the absolute PL recombination analysis allows us to confirm the improvements are a result of reduced interfacial recombination at both the n-and p-contact as shown as shown in Supplementary Table  2 .  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4061</offset>
      <text> Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4077</offset>
      <text> Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4093</offset>
      <text> Statistics Number of solar cells tested Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4139</offset>
      <text> No Overall we fabricated and tested more than 250 cells for this study. As for the small area (6 mm2-size) cells, we fabricated approximately 40 cells for each of the 4 studied device architectures. Supplementary Figure  8  shows the results of three fabricated device batches with 20 cells per device architecture. In addition, we fabricated approximately 20 1cm2-size cells for each of these 4 device configurations. We note that we observed very small efficiency losses when increasing the active area from 6 mm2 to 1 cm2, thus the results in Supplementary Figure  8  are also representative for the large cells (with the exception of the standard device architecture without interlayers where we experienced scaling difficulties due to the formation of pinholes as we discuss in the text). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4935</offset>
      <text> Statistical analysis of the device performance Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4988</offset>
      <text> No In Supplementary Figure  8 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5022</offset>
      <text> Long-term stability analysis &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5053</offset>
      <text> Type of analysis, bias conditions and environmental conditions For instance: illumination type, temperature, atmosphere humidity, encapsulation method, preconditioning temperature &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5235</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5241</offset>
      <text> No Long term MPP tracking was performed on encapsulated cells under 1 Sun equivalent white LED irradiation in air (25% relative humidity) for 100 hours. Thereby the cell is continuously held at 25°C and its maximum power voltage which was obtained from an initial JV scan. Maximum power output was ensured by applying a small voltage perturbation (+/-5 mV) to the cell every 5 seconds. Depending on which voltage gave a higher power output, the applied voltage was either increased or decreasing by 5 mV and then held at this voltage for the next 5 seconds.   4  Young Investigator Group Perovskite Tandem Solar Cells, Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin für Materialien und Energie GmbH, Berlin, Germany.  5  Department of Physics, Swansea University, Swansea, UK.  6  These authors contributed equally: Martin Stolterfoht, Christian M. Wolff. *e-mail: stolterf@uni-potsdam.de; unold@helmholtz-berlin.de; neher@uni-potsdam.de &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:57:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="5310" length="45"/>
        <text>1 Sun equivalent white LED irradiation in air</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:44:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="5356" length="4"/>
        <text>(25%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">100</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:45:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="5384" length="9"/>
        <text>100 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:45:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="5436" length="4"/>
        <text>25°C</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6161</offset>
      <text> Articles T he solution processability and potential for simple manufacturing from earth-abundant materials drives research into perovskite solar cells in the search for cheap, printable photovoltaic devices. The discovery that perovskites effectively sensitize titanium dioxide (TiO 2 ) in dye-sensitized solar cells in 2009  1  , and the demonstration of the first thin-film solid-state perovskite solar cells in 2012  2, 3  has spurred tremendous research efforts concerning the understanding and optimization of perovskite-based optoelectronic devices. Though power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) of perovskite solar cells  4  are rapidly approaching industrially engineered silicon and inorganic thin-film solar cells  5  , several key issues remain that need to be understood and overcome. These include fundamental questions regarding recombination losses  6  , long-term stability  7  and difficulties in scaling to large electrode areas  8  . Today it is well known that to unlock the full thermodynamic potential of perovskite solar cells it is imperative to suppress all non-radiative recombination losses, which manifest as increased dark currents and ideality factors greater than one, limiting both the cells' open-circuit voltage (V OC ) and fill factor  6, 9  . One of the most challenging tasks in this regard is being able to pinpoint the origin of these losses in a complete device under operational conditions. In general, recombination losses may occur either in the perovskite bulk  4, 6, 10  or close to the interface of an adjacent transport layer as a result of a higher density of trap states at the surface  11, 12  . Likewise, recombination may also occur across interfaces  [13] [14] [15]  between charges in the transport layer and minority carriers in the perovskite, or in the transport layers themselves  15  . The situation becomes more challenging for cells with a comparatively large area (for example, 1 cm 2 ), where additional losses come from inhomogeneities of the active perovskite absorber as well as at the interfaces to the transport layers, with transport resistances also becoming an issue  8  . Knowing the origin of the non-radiative recombination losses would greatly facilitate targeted improvements in device performance  13  . This is particularly relevant for planar perovskite devices in the pin configuration, which still lag behind the most efficient nip cells  4, 11, [16] [17] [18] [19]  due to their lower opencircuit voltage and higher non-radiative recombination losses (for example, 1.15 V for record pin cells 11 compared to more than 1.23 V for nip cells  13, 17  ). Nevertheless, pin-type cells are very attractive for single-junction solar cells as they require only ultrathin undoped charge transport layers (for example, 8 nm poly[bis(4-phenyl) (2,4,6-trimethylphenyl)amine] (PTAA), 30 nm C 60 )  9  without the need for extensive chemical doping  9  and annealing at temperatures above 100 °C. This renders their fabrication compatible with rollto-roll deposition on flexible plastic substrates. Moreover, a pin perovskite device architecture is required for Si/perovskite tandem applications in combination with well-established solar cell technologies based on p-type silicon  20, 21  . Thus, a detailed investigation of non-radiative recombination losses and which interface represents the bottleneck for cell efficiency is urgently needed. We use a combination of steady-state and time-resolved photoluminescence (PL and TRPL) measurements to pinpoint the origin of non-radiative recombination losses in pin-type perosvkite solar cells. In particular, we determine the recombination kinetics and quasi-Fermi-level splitting (QFLS) in sample stacks consisting of the perovskite absorber-only, and perovskite/charge transport layer heterojunctions on length scales relevant to our solar cells (1 cm 2 ). We identify the main limitation to higher performance to be minority carrier recombination at the heterojunction with the organic charge transport layers. These losses are found to be surprisingly similar at the electron-and hole-selective interfaces. We therefore The performance of perovskite solar cells is predominantly limited by non-radiative recombination, either through trap-assisted recombination in the absorber layer or via minority carrier recombination at the perovskite/transport layer interfaces. Here, we use transient and absolute photoluminescence imaging to visualize all non-radiative recombination pathways in planar pintype perovskite solar cells with undoped organic charge transport layers. We find significant quasi-Fermi-level splitting losses (135 meV) in the perovskite bulk, whereas interfacial recombination results in an additional free energy loss of 80 meV at each individual interface, which limits the open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of the complete cell to ~1.12 V. Inserting ultrathin interlayers between the perovskite and transport layers leads to a substantial reduction of these interfacial losses at both the p and n contacts. Using this knowledge and approach, we demonstrate reproducible dopant-free 1 cm 2 perovskite solar cells surpassing 20% efficiency (19.83% certified) with stabilized power output, a high V OC (1.17 V) and record fill factor (&gt; 81%). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11439</offset>
      <text> Visualization and suppression of interfacial recombination for high-efficiency large-area pin perovskite solar cells Martin NATURe eNeRgy | VOL 3 | OCTOBER 2018 | 847-854 | www.nature.com/natureenergy &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11642</offset>
      <text> Articles &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11653</offset>
      <text> Nature eNergy optimized the hole-selective interface through the use of a conjugated polyelectrolyte, which almost entirely suppressed interfacial recombination while simultaneously improving the wetting of the perovskite solution on the hole transport layer surface, delivering reproducible 1 cm 2 devices. With the knowledge that the V OC of the final device is now largely defined by the QFLS of the inferior perovskite/C 60 heterojunction we introduced an ultrathin layer of LiF (0.6-1 nm) between the absorber and the electron transport layer. This allowed us to reduce the interfacial recombination loss at the electron-selective interface by 35 meV. Suppressing the nonradiative recombination at both interfaces directly resulted in critical V OC and fill factor improvements in complete devices, allowing 1 cm 2 cells with ~20% efficiency, stabilized maximum power output and high reproducibility. This is currently the highest certified efficiency for a published 1 cm 2 perovskite solar cell structure. Last, numerical simulations highlight the importance of interface optimizations versus bulk optimizations for further perovskite solar cell developments. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Lithium Fluoride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:23:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="12133" length="3"/>
        <text>LiF</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12822</offset>
      <text> Device architecture Our work builds on recent advancements in the understanding and improvement of pin devices  11, 19, 22  . The chemical structures of PTAA, perovskite and C 60 as used in our standard cells with architecture [(indium tin oxide, ITO (150 nm)/PTAA (8 nm)/perovskite (400-500 nm)/C 60 (30 nm)/bathocuproine, BCP (8 nm)/Cu (100 nm)] are shown in Fig.  1a . For the active layer material, we chose the previously reported 'triple cation perovskite' mixture with the composition CsPbI 0.05 [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.89 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.11 ] 0.95 , as it delivers among the best photovoltaic performance. We note that though we focus on triple cation cells we have also generalized the results to methylammonium lead iodide MAPbI 3 and caesium formamidinium lead iodide (Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 )PbI 3 absorber layers, as discussed at the end of the manuscript. Figure  1b  displays a schematic energy level diagram based on the results from ultraviolet and inverse photoemission spectroscopy  15  , and proposes possible recombination mechanisms. One of the most important considerations for scaling the device area is the electrode architecture, due to the relatively high sheet resistance of the transparent conducting electrode (TCE)  8  . It is thus essential to minimize the distance carriers have to traverse through the comparatively high resistance electrode (that is, ITO versus copper). Figure  2a  shows the current-voltage characteristics of optimized 1 cm 2 cells with electrode widths of 8 mm and 4 mm, which demonstrate that the fill factor can be increased from 69% to 77.9% simply by reducing the width of the active area. This is also in agreement with numerical solutions of the Shockley equation for different electrode aspect ratios, as illustrated in Fig.  2b , which confirm a roughly 2% absolute efficiency gain through the fill factor (Supplementary Fig.  1 ). This approach is in principle scalable, as the rectangular cells can be connected using laser patterning  23  while the electrode width may be slightly increased using a lower-resistance ITO substrate (for instance, 10 Ω sq -1 ). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:49:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="13051" length="118"/>
        <text>(indium tin oxide, ITO (150 nm)/PTAA (8 nm)/perovskite (400-500 nm)/C 60 (30 nm)/bathocuproine, BCP (8 nm)/Cu (100 nm)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:49:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="13315" length="51"/>
        <text>CsPbI 0.05 [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.89 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.11 ] 0.95</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14932</offset>
      <text> Non-radiative recombination losses Among the most widely used and trusted techniques in the community to study the fate of photogenerated charges in perovskite solar cells is TRPL  24, 25  . At sufficiently low fluences a mono-exponential decay is usually observed, indicative of an underlying non-radiative trap-induced recombination that gradually reduces the density of emitting species, and hence the PL signal  6, 10, 26  . The fluence dependence of the TRPL signals is illustrated in Supplementary Fig.  2 . Figure  3  shows the result of such an experiment on a neat perovskite film, which displays a long PL lifetime of approximately half a microsecond, comparable to previously reported  16  perovskite films on TiO 2 . Considerably longer lifetimes have been reported in exceptional cases; for example, a lifetime of 8 µ s was recently realized through surface passivation of the perovskite with tri-n-octylphosphine (TOPO)  26  . As demonstrated  6  , the achievable V OC in the case of dominant Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) recombination can be predicted from the monoexponential carrier lifetime (τ SRH ). As we detail in Supplementary Note 1, a SRH lifetime of 500 ns (as deduced from the exponential PL decay of the neat perovskite layer) should limit the open-circuit voltage to approximately 1.215 V at room temperature. The measured V OC of the device is significantly lower, which suggests that addition of the charge transport layers induces substantial non-radiative recombination losses. Figure  3  demonstrates the large impact of the addition of charge transporting layers on the TRPL decay, which is consistent with other previously reported studies  16  . Notably, large reductions in PL lifetimes  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16657</offset>
      <text> Articles Nature eNergy are seen independent of whether the PTAA is added between the glass and the active material or coated on top of the perovskite film (on glass), indicating that differences in perovskite morphology related to the nature of the underlying substrate are of minor importance in determining the PL lifetime (see Supplementary Fig.  3 ). Interestingly, all samples comprising one or two transport layers exhibited a similar and fast bi-exponential decay. As pointed out previously  6, 27  , this may be due either to the rapid extraction of charges on (sub)nanosecond timescales (quenching) or increased non-radiative recombination losses-two processes that are inherently difficult to disentangle from the TRPL signal alone. However, unless one transport layer completely depletes the perovskite bulk of one carrier type, the impact of non-radiative interface recombination will still be visible in the signal. As the bulk recombination happens at rather long timescales (lifetimes of approximately 500 ns), it can be concluded that the TRPL signals from the films with the transport layers present are subjected to additional non-radiative interface recombination. Following this line of reasoning, we attribute the fast initial decay to the loss of carriers at the interfaces due to charge extraction to the transport layers and/or to interface recombination, and the second decay (for which the mono-exponential lifetimes are provided in Fig.  3 ) to interface recombination. In accordance with this, the initial decay becomes less pronounced and smeared out when increasing the excitation wavelengththat is, when light penetrates deeper into the perovskite layer (see Supplementary Fig.  2 ). The rather similar decays after the initial drop in the samples with either PTAA or C 60 indicate that the two perovskite/organic heterojunctions equally limit the V OC due to additional non-radiative recombination losses at the interfaces. After carriers reach a quasi-equilibrium distribution, the lifetime of the second decay (τ II ) can be described by an equilibrium between the bulk decay time (τ bulk ), the diffusion time to the surface , where d is the perovskite film thickness and D the diffusion constant  24, 27  . Using the bulk lifetime of 500-785 ns, a mobility of 30 cm 2 V -1 s -1 (ref.  28  ), d = 400 nm and the measured τ II value of 20-30 ns would result in an interface loss velocity of S 1 ~ 1.6 × 10 3 -2.1 × 10 3 cm s -1 at the interface between the charge transport layer and the perovskite. However, other processes may potentially influence the TRPL signal as well, such as a decelerating charge extraction, light-soaking effects  29  , photon recycling  24, 25  , or a graded generation profile. Thus, it is clear that though TRPL is a useful guide to recombination losses, it by no means provides a definitive mechanistic insight. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19541</offset>
      <text> Photoluminescence and QFLS A much more direct way to quantify the additional non-radiative recombination losses at the perovskite/organic interfaces is steadystate PL, as the absolute PL intensity (I PL ) is a direct measure of the QFLS (or ∆ E F )  [30] [31] [32] [33] [34] [35]  . Here, we use hyperspectral absolute photoluminescence imaging to create depth-averaged maps of the QFLS on the neat perovskite films in comparison to multilayer samples comprising one or both types of transport layer. This approach has been recently used by El-Hajje et al.  31  to spatially resolve the opto-electronic quality of evaporated methylammonium lead iodide junctions, and to study the hole blocking of different electron transport layers. Moreover, absolute PL has been recently applied to disentangle interfacial and bulk recombination losses in nip cells by Sarritzu et al.  33  , though the QFLS was not compared to the Reducing the active area width from 8 mm (aspect ratio 0.64) to 4 mm (aspect ratio 0.16) while keeping the active area the same improved the fill factor by approximately 9%, as indicated by the arrow. b, Simulated solar cell efficiencies using a combination of optical simulations of the obtainable short-circuit current, and the Shockley equation with a finite ITO series resistance depending on its thickness and the device aspect ratio. An internal cell resistance of 1.5 Ω cm 2 (for a 1 cm 2 cell) and an ideality factor of approximately 1.5 were assumed, as previously determined  9  . The two circled points correspond to the two devices from a.   30  , which describes the non-thermal radiation of a semiconductor: = π - -Δ ( ) I E E a E h c ( ) 2 ( ) 1 exp 1 (1) E E k T PL 2 3 2 F B Here, a(E) is the photon energy (E)-dependent absorptivity, c is the speed of light, h is the Planck constant and k B is the Boltzmann constant. Under the assumption that for emission energies above the PL maximum, a(E) approaches unity, equation (  1 ) can be simplified to              π = - + Δ I E h c E E k T E k T ln ( ) 2 (2) PL 3 2 2 B F B Equation (  2 ) allows one to deduce ∆ E F simply from fitting the high-energy slope of the PL emission  36  . By applying equation (  2 ) to every spectrum associated with each pixel (10 µ m in diameter) of the hyperspectral images, ∆ E F distribution maps can be created. Figure  4  shows the depth-averaged QFLS maps (1 cm 2 ) of the neat triple cation perovskite film, with either PTAA or C 60 alone, or both transport layers being present. The perovskite absorber exhibits a homogenous profile with a QFLS of approximately 1.21 eV (we note a 20 meV global systematic error on all maps). Though this value is remarkably close to the V OC obtained from the TRPL lifetime according to Supplementary Note 1, it is substantially below the radiative V OC of approximately 1.345 eV. The latter was estimated from the dark generation current J 0,rad ≈ 4 × 10 -21 A cm -2 (see Supplementary Fig.  4 ). This approach for calculating the radiative V OC limit has been extensively applied to perovskite solar cells, as shown in refs  [37] [38] [39]  , and dates back to Shockley and Queisser  40  . We also note that the emitted PL can be influenced by photon recycling  24, 25  . However, this does not affect our conclusions, because it is the external PL quantum yield that determines the QFLS and maximum achievable device V OC (ref.  41  ). Figure  4  also shows that the QFLS of the perovskite/C 60 film is reduced to approximately 1.136 eV ± 10 mV and the PTAA/perovskite film exhibits a QFLS of approximately 1.125 eV ± 10 mV. It is important to note that, compared to the neat absorber material with a PL quantum yield of ~0.5%, addition of PTAA or C 60 results in a large reduction of the average photoluminescence efficiency (for example, 0.017% for a perovskite/C 60 film), which also means a large increase in the nonradiative loss current (approximately 30-fold in case of perovskite/ C 60 compared to the neat absorber material). Yet, despite the different nature of these two interfaces, the non-radiative recombination losses at both interfaces are surprisingly similar (lowering the QFLS by ~80 meV compared to the neat absorber), which is consistent with the TRPL results. For the (unoptimized) pin stack (glass/PTAA/perovskite/C 60 ) we obtain a ∆ E F of approximately 1.121 V ± 10 mV, which perfectly matches the average V OC in complete cells under comparable illumination intensities (see below). Interestingly, this value lies only slightly below the QFLS of samples with only one transport layer present, which indicates that the  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24210</offset>
      <text> Articles Nature eNergy non-radiative recombination losses at each individual interface are both reducing the I PL (E), yet the QFLS only through the logarithm in equation (2). We also note a good reproducibility and homogeneity of the QFLS on the neat perovskite film and all films with C 60 , except for the glass/PTAA/perovskite heterojunctions, for which we observed a relatively large batch-to-batch variation (with the average QFLS ranging from 1.09 eV to 1.16 eV, see Supplementary Table  1 ). On the other hand, no difference in the QFLS was observed between a PTAA/perovskite film on a glass or an ITO substrate, which suggests no additional non-radiative recombination losses at the ITO/ PTAA interface (see Supplementary Fig.  5 ). Though Fig.  4  shows that the perovskite absorber imposes a substantial limitation on the V OC , we would expect that it is the weakest component of the (pin) stack that dominates the non-radiative loss current and sets the upper limit for the device V OC (in our case both interfaces equally). To further clarify the importance of interfacial optimizations in relation to bulk optimizations depending on the selectivity of the interlayers, we numerically simulated the opencircuit voltage of a pin device stack by varying the interface recombination velocities and the bulk lifetime using a drift-diffusion simulator (Supplementary Fig.  6 )  42  . Applying the measured interface-recombination velocity in our structures before optimization (that is, ~2,000 cm s -1 ) and bulk lifetime (500 ns) as input parameters, the simulation accurately describes the V OC of our standard cells. The simulations clearly show that even if we improved the perovskite bulk lifetime multiple times (to much greater than 500 ns), no V OC improvements are possible when the interface recombination velocities stay at 2,000 cm s -1 . We therefore conclude that the V OC of our cells is entirely limited by the interfaces, and any improvement of the bulk would be lost due to rapid interfacial recombination. Thus, it is essential to systematically improve the interfaces, as we discuss in the following. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26342</offset>
      <text> Suppression of interfacial recombination Following the approach proposed by Lee et al.  43  to improve the wettability of hydrophobic charge transport layers, we functionalized the PTAA layer with the interface compatibilizer poly[(9,9-bis(30-((N,N-dimethyl)-N-ethylammonium)-propyl)-2,7-fluorene)alt-2,7-(9,9-dioctylfluorene)] dibromide (PFN-P2)-a conjugated polyelectrolyte (CPE). In line with their findings  43  , the amphiphilic properties of PFN-P2 improved the wetting of the perovskite film on the hydrophobic PTAA, thus greatly enhancing the fabri cation yield of our cells without frequent pinhole formation. To reveal possible changes of the layer morphology as a function of the underlying substrate, we performed top and cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) measurements of perovskite films deposited on glass, glass/ITO/PTAA and glass/ITO/PTAA/PFN-P2. The images shown in Supplementary Fig.  7  demonstrate perovskite grains ranging from tens of nanometres to micrometres in size and indicate, at least qualitatively, only small changes of the perovskite bulk morphology across these substrates. Importantly, we find that PFN-P2 causes a substantial reduction of the recombination at the hole transport layer contact, as shown in Fig.  5a, b . This resulted in an average QFLS value (~1.19 eV) very close to the value for the neat perovskite (~1.21 eV) while simultaneously improving the homogeneity of the absolute PL image. To check whether PFN-P2 itself passivates the perovskite surface by reducing trap-assisted recombination independent of the presence of the hole transport layer/ perovskite interface, we compared QFLS maps of glass/perovskite and glass/PFN-P2/perovskite samples (Supplementary Table  1 ). No differences in the QFLS were found, which allows us to assign the increased QFLS of the hole transport layer/PFN-P2/perovskite junction to suppressed interfacial recombination. In accordance with this, we recorded a significantly slower TRPL decay on samples including PFN-P2 (Fig.  5c ). Motivated by this success, we aimed to reduce the detrimental recombination at the perovskite/electron transport layer interface. Different strategies have been reported to block holes at the n-interface, such as polystyrene  44  or choline chloride  11  for pin cells or Ga 2 O 3 for nip cells  13  . However, for our triple cation pin perovskite solar cells we found the most significant effect on the QFLS and device efficiency when inserting an ultrathin layer (0.6-1 nm) of LiF between the perovskite and C 60 , causing a reduction of the non-radiative interfacial recombination loss by 35 meV (Fig.  5d, e ). Again, as shown in Fig.  5f , the increase in QFLS was correlated with a slower mono-exponential TRPL decay (with a lifetime that increased from 26 ns to 180 ns for a perovskite/C 60 and perovskite/LiF/C 60 film on glass, respectively.) &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PFN-P2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:21:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="26569" length="111"/>
        <text>poly[(9,9-bis(30-((N,N-dimethyl)-N-ethylammonium)-propyl)-2,7-fluorene)alt-2,7-(9,9-dioctylfluorene)] dibromide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PFN-P2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:21:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="26682" length="6"/>
        <text>PFN-P2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PFN-P2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:21:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="26791" length="6"/>
        <text>PFN-P2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:25:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="27181" length="40"/>
        <text>glass/ITO/PTAA and glass/ITO/PTAA/PFN-P2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:22:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="28711" length="3"/>
        <text>pin</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Lithium Fluoride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:22:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="28857" length="3"/>
        <text>LiF</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29231</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic performance Introducing both interlayers led to considerable improvements of the cell efficiency (from an average of 18% to 20%) through an increase in V OC and fill factor (see Supplementary Fig.  8  for the performance of 6 mm 2 devices). Importantly, the average V OC of cells with both interlayers present is 1.16 V, which compares well with the average QFLS of the perovskite/LiF/C 60 stack and the complete device stack (~1.17 eV, see Supplementary Table  1 ). Measuring the V OC as a function of light intensity on cells with and without both interlayers reveals a similar ideality factor but a smaller dark recombination current density for the interlayer-containing device, indicating that these additional layers do affect the rate but not the overall nature of the recombination process (Supplementary Fig.  9 ). From the device manufacturing perspective, introducing PFN-P2 greatly improved the homogeneity of the perovskite films, allowing us to manufacture 1 cm 2 cells without the frequent pinhole formation encountered in our standard cells (without the interlayers), resulting in reproducible high efficiencies. Typically, without PFN-P2, only one out of three 1 cm 2 cells resulted in efficiencies above 18%, while this PCE could be safely achieved with 17 out of 18 cells in two batches with 9 cells each if PFN-P2 was included. Cells with PFN-P2 (but without LiF) reached efficiencies up to 19.6% (J SC = 21.85 mA cm -2 , V OC = 1.143 V, fill factor = 78.6% Supplementary Fig.  10 ) when measured with an aperture mask (1.018 cm 2 ) at 25 °C. The short-circuit current matched the integrated external quantum efficiency (EQE) and solar spectrum product (21.5 mA cm -2 ) within an error of less than 2% (Supplementary Fig.  11 ). This cell was certified by an independent accredited institute (Institute for Solar Energy, Fraunhofer Freiburg), which gave a stabilized PCE of 19.22% Supplementary Fig.  12 ) with a negligible mismatch to our J-V measurement in terms of current. Moreover, encapsulated cells were stable for at least 100 h under maximum power point (MPP) tracking conditions in air and constant illumination from a white light-emitting diode (LED) with 1 Sun equivalent light intensity, with only a small loss in efficiency (0.6% absolute) (Supplementary Fig.  13 ). We also note that using 10 Ω sq -1 ITO substrates instead of our standard 15 Ω sq -1 ITO substrates allowed us to achieve fill factors above 81%; values which, to our knowledge, are 3% higher than the highest reported fill factors for 1 cm 2 size cells (Supplementary Fig.  14 )  45  . As expected from the QFLS analysis, the V OC of the cells is significantly increased through the introduction of the LiF interlayer (~1.17 V), pushing the PCE of our 1 cm 2 cells up to a value of 20.0%, with virtually no hysteresis and a stable power output, as shown in Fig.  6 . However, compared to the highest certified 1 cm 2 cells 46 with a PCE of 20.9% (J SC of 24.9 mA cm -2 , geometry and structure currently unpublished) a remaining limitation of our cells is their relatively low short-circuit current. Thus, to lower the bandgap of the perovskite layer, we optimized the ratio of FAPbI 3 to MAPbBr 3 . We found that using a ratio of 89:11 allows a significant improvement in short-circuit current (0.5-1 mA cm -2 ) with surprisingly minimal loss in V OC and efficiencies up to 21.6% for small 6 mm 2 cells (J SC = 23.2 mA cm -2 , V OC = 1.156 V, fill factor = 80.4%) (Supplementary Fig.  8 ). As for the 1 cm 2 devices, Supplementary Fig.  15a  shows our present hero device with both interlayers 0.89 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.11 ] 0.95 perovskite with an efficiency of 20.3%, again with very small mismatch versus the integrated EQE-solar spectrum product (Supplementary Fig.  15b ). This cell was certified by Fraunhofer-ISE, resulting in a PCE of 19.83%, which is currently the highest certified efficiency of a 1 cm 2 perovskite cell with published geometry and structure (Supplementary Figs.  16  and 17 )  4  . We also highlight the important fact that the efficiency of our cells is stabilized, in contrast to most previous perovskite solar cell certifications, which are denoted as 'not stabilized'  4, 46  . Last, we note that our concept to identify and suppress interfacial recombination can be successfully generalized to other perovskite compositions, including the standard methylammonium lead iodide absorber (MAPI), where we reached efficiencies slightly above 20%; as well as Cs-containing formamidinium lead iodide perovskite cells (Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 )PbI 3 with close to 20% PCE (Supplementary Fig.  18 ).     &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:55:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="29558" length="6"/>
        <text>1.16 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PFN-P2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:58:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="30124" length="6"/>
        <text>PFN-P2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:58:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="30656" length="5"/>
        <text>19.6%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.143</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:58:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="30694" length="5"/>
        <text>1.143</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">100</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:57:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="31296" length="5"/>
        <text>100 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:57:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="31308" length="156"/>
        <text>maximum power point (MPP) tracking conditions in air and constant illumination from a white light-emitting diode (LED) with 1 Sun equivalent light intensity</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:57:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="31504" length="4"/>
        <text>0.6%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33866</offset>
      <text> Articles &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33877</offset>
      <text> Nature eNergy The latter system is particularly interesting as pure FAPbI 3 exhibits a bandgap of 1.47 eV, which is closer to the optimum bandgap in the Shockley-Queisser model  47  . However, reports of FAPbI 3 cells are rare and the efficiencies of such devices lag significantly behind the mixed perovskite systems  [47] [48] [49]  . Measurement of the absolute PL from the individual perovskite/charge transport layer junctions proves once again substantial reduction of interfacial recombination by the addition of PFN-P2 and LiF at the p-and n-interfaces, respectively (Supplementary Table  2 ). Notably, this allowed the devices to reach record efficiencies for MA/Br-free FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells, which further underlines the potential of our recombination analysis and interfacial engineering approach (Supplementary Fig.  18 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34724</offset>
      <text> Conclusions Hyperspectral photoluminescence imaging allowed us to identify the origin of non-radiative recombination loss channels through mapping of the QFLS of the relevant perovskite/transport layer combinations. We found significant non-radiative recombination losses in the neat perovskite layer that reduce the potential V OC by approximately 135 mV compared to the radiative limit of this type of perovskite (1.345 V). However, interface recombination at each individual hybrid interface (PTAA/perovskite and perovskite/C 60 ) dominates the non-radiative loss current in the stack and results in a significant reduction of the QFLS down to ~1.13 eV. In line with this interpretation, we achieved a considerable improvement of the device performance by applying PFN-P2 and LiF as interfacial layers, which suppressed the recombination losses by 65 meV and 35 meV at the p-and n-interfaces, respectively. The reduced recombination and increased QFLS splitting resulted in significant V OC and fill factor gains, which in combination with an optimized composition of the perovskite layer led to a PCE above 20% for 1 cm 2 cells, with a certified PCE of 19.83% and stabilized power output. This work demonstrates how interfacial recombination losses can be unambiguously identified and suppressed, and paves the way to reach the thermodynamic limit for perovskite solar cells through further minimization of interface and trap-assisted recombination in the absorber layer. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PFN-P2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:01:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="35493" length="6"/>
        <text>PFN-P2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Lithium Fluoride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:01:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="35504" length="3"/>
        <text>LiF</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36202</offset>
      <text> Methods Hyperspectral absolute photoluminescence imaging. Excitation for the PL imaging measurements was performed with two 450 nm LEDs equipped with diffuser lenses. The intensity of the LEDs was adjusted to ~1 Sun by illuminating a contacted perovskite solar cell (short circuit) and matching the current density to the short-circuit current measured in the J-V sun simulator (the measured shortcircuit current density of the solar cell under this illumination was 22.2 mA cm -2 ). The photoluminescence image detection was performed with a charge-coupled device (CCD) camera (Allied Vision) coupled with a liquid crystal tunable filter. The system was calibrated to absolute photon numbers in two steps in a similar way to the process described by Delamarre and colleagues  50  . For this purpose an infrared laser diode and a spectrally calibrated halogen lamp were coupled to an integrating sphere. The pixel resolution of the images corresponds to about 10 μ m in diameter. Sets of images from 650 nm to 1,100 nm taken at a step size of 5 nm were recorded. All absolute PL measurements were performed on films with the same thicknesses as used in the operational solar cells. A global systematic error of 20 meV (or equivalently an approximate factor of two in PL efficiency) was estimated on the basis of uncertainties in the optimum approach to calculate the QFLS (equation (  2 )), as well as small uncertainties in the estimation of the bandgap and the temperature. Time-resolved PL. PL data was acquired with a TCSPC system (Berger &amp; Lahr) after excitation with a pulse-picked and frequency-doubled output from a modelocked Ti:sapphire oscillator (Coherent Chameleon) with nominal pulse durations ~100 fs and a fluence of ~ 30 nJ cm -2 at a wavelength of 470 nm. The samples were excited from the side of the interface we sought to investigate (that is, the glass side for PTAA and the top side for the other samples). The short-wavelength excitation was chosen to specifically excite the samples close to the interface we were interested in. All TRPL measurements were performed on films with the same thicknesses as used in the operational solar cells. Device fabrication. Pre-patterned 2.5 × 2.5 cm² 15 Ω sq -1 ITO substrates (Automatic Research) were cleaned with acetone, 3% Hellmanex solution, deionized water and isopropanol, by sonication for 10 min in each solution. After a microwave plasma treatment (3 min, 200 W), the samples were transferred to a N 2 -filled glovebox. A thin (~8 nm) PTAA (Sigma-Aldrich) layer was spin-coated from a 1.5 mg ml -1 toluene solution at 6,000 r.p.m. for 30 s using an acceleration of 2,000 r.p.m. per second. The layers were subsequently annealed inside a nitrogenfilled glovebox ( &lt; 1 ppm H 2 O and O 2 ) at 100 °C for 10 min. After the substrate was allowed to cool for 5 min, a 60 µ l solution of PFN-P2 (0.5 mg ml -1 in methanol) purchased from 1-Material was added to the spinning substrate at 5,000 r.p.m. for 20 s, resulting in a film with thickness below the detection limit of our atomic force microscopy (less than 5 nm). The perovskite layer was prepared using an anti-solvent treatment and the concentration of the perovskite components in the solution and solvent ratios were detailed in a previous work  9  . We found an improvement in V OC and reproducibility by switching the anti-solvent from diethyl ether (DEE) to ethyl acetate, which is miscible with dimethylformamide:dimethyl sulfoxide (DMF:DMSO) mixtures and has a higher boiling point (77.1 °C) and an optimal polarity of approximately 4.5. Therefore, all cells reported here were fabricated using ethyl acetate as the anti-solvent. The perovskite layer was deposited by spin-coating at 4,000 r.p.m. for 35 s. Ten seconds after the start of the spinning process, the spinning substrate was washed with 300 µ l ethyl acetate for approximately 1 s (the anti-solvent was placed in the centre of the film). The perovskite film was then annealed at 100 °C for 1 h on a preheated hotplate. The samples were transferred to an evaporation chamber and LiF (6 Å to 1 nm), C 60 (30 nm), BCP (8 nm) and copper (100 nm) were deposited under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). After completion, the glass side of the 1 cm 2 cells was coated with a Brisbane Materials Technology (Australia Pty Ltd) anti-reflection coating optimized for a broadband spectral response in the AM1.5 window. Current density-voltage characteristics. J-V curves were obtained in a two-wire source-sense configuration with a Keithley 2400. An Oriel class AAA Xenon lamp-based sun simulator was used for illumination, providing approximately 100 mW cm -2 of AM1.5 G irradiation, and the intensity was monitored simultaneously with a Si photodiode. The exact illumination intensity was used for efficiency calculations, and the simulator was calibrated with a KG5-filtered silicon solar cell (certified by Fraunhofer ISE). A spectral mismatch calculation was performed based on the spectral irradiance of the solar simulator, the EQE of the reference silicon solar cell and three typical EQEs of our cells. This resulted in three mismatch factors of M = 0.9949, 0.9996 and 0.9976. Given the very small deviation from unity, the measured J SC was not corrected by the factor 1/M. All EQEs presented in this work were measured by ISE-Fraunhofer. Coupled optical and Shockley-Queisser modelling. We employed an optical modelling tool  51  to calculate the photogenerated current inside the perovskite material depending on the thickness of the ITO layer. To this end, we kept the other layer thicknesses constant (8 nm PTAA, 450 nm perovskite, 20 nm C 60 , 8 nm BCP, 100 nm copper). We employed measured spectral refractive indices n and k for all layers under normal incident illumination. The resulting short-circuit current was used to numerically solve the modified Shockley-Queisser equation (typical voltage steps are 1 mV) including an ideality factor of 1.5 (ref.  9  ), a shunt resistance of 4,000 Ω , a luminescent efficiency of 0.1% (ref.  15  ) a radiative current of 8 × 10 -20 A cm -2 and an internal series resistance of 1.5 Ω cm 2 in addition to the series resistance imposed by the ITO for any given thickness and geometry. Our standard ITO (Automatic Research GmbH, Germany) has a nominal sheet resistance of 15 Ω sq -1 with a thickness of 150 nm. We extrapolated the resulting sheet resistance starting from this value. 2 ⁄Figure 3 ,Supplementary Figure 4 . 234 𝑛 e/h density of electrons/holes in the conduction/valance band, and 𝑁 C/V ~ 𝑚 e(h) * 3 the effective density of states in the conduction and valence band (3.12x10 21 /m 3 ), respectively. Assuming equal densities for electrons and holes and setting 𝜏 SRH = 500 ns as deduced from the exponential PL decay in the recombination in the perovskite layer should limit the open-circuit voltage to approximately 1.215 V at room temperature. Supplementary Figure 3. Transient photoluminescence decays measured on glass/PTAA /perovskite and glass/perovskite/PTAA stacks. The very similar decays show that the fast recombination is determined by interfacial recombination at the interface to the transport layer and that possible changes of the perovskite morphology when prepared on different substrates (i.e. glass, or glass/PTAA) are of minor importance. The transients were measured at low fluences (~30 nJcm -2 ) and illuminated with a 470 nm laser through PTAA in both cases. Analysis of radiative recombination current in the dark. External &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43732</offset>
      <text> Stolterfoht 1,6 *, Christian M. Wolff 1,6 , José A. Márquez 2 , Shanshan Zhang 1,3 , Charles J. Hages 2 , Daniel Rothhardt 1 , Steve Albrecht 4 , Paul L. Burn 3 , Paul Meredith 5 , Thomas Unold 2 * and Dieter Neher 1 * &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43955</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Schematic device architecture and energetics. a, Cross-section of a full device comprising, from bottom to top: the glass and transparent conducting electrode (ITO), the hole-selective polymeric layer of PTAA, the perovskite absorber layer, the electron selective C 60 layer and the metallic top electrode (copper). Chemical structures are shown for PTAA, C 60 and a schematic perovskite crystal structure. The violet sphere represents Pb 2+ , and the blue sphere represents I -. b, Schematic energy level diagram and pathways of non-radiative recombination via traps in the perovskite bulk or at the interfaces as a minority carrier loss. Also shown is the extraction of majority carriers to the transport layers, the quasi-Fermi levels of electrons (E F,e ) and holes (E F,h ), the resulting quasi-Fermi-level splitting (∆ E F,pero ) in the perovskite, and the recombination-limited V OC . VBM, valence band maximum; CBM, conduction band minimum; HOMO, highest occupied molecular orbital; LUMO, lowest unoccupied molecular orbital. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45013</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig.2| Optimization of electrode design. a, Experimental J-V curves of 1 cm 2 cells comprising a PTAA/perovskite/C 60 stack with different electrode aspect ratios. Reducing the active area width from 8 mm (aspect ratio 0.64) to 4 mm (aspect ratio 0.16) while keeping the active area the same improved the fill factor by approximately 9%, as indicated by the arrow. b, Simulated solar cell efficiencies using a combination of optical simulations of the obtainable short-circuit current, and the Shockley equation with a finite ITO series resistance depending on its thickness and the device aspect ratio. An internal cell resistance of 1.5 Ω cm 2 (for a 1 cm 2 cell) and an ideality factor of approximately 1.5 were assumed, as previously determined 9  . The two circled points correspond to the two devices from a. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45843</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 4 Fig. 4 | Visualization of non-radiative interfacial recombination through absolute photoluminescence imaging. a,b, Quasi-Fermi level splitting maps (1 cm 2 ) (a) and corresponding energy histograms (b) on perovskite-only, perovskite/C 60 , PTAA/perovskite and PTAA/perovskite/C 60 films on glass.The neat perovskite absorber allows a QFLS (and thus potential V OC ) of approximately 1.208 eV (at 300 K), which is consistent with the transient photoluminescence decay (Fig.3) but significantly below the QFLS in the radiative limit (1.345 eV), as indicated by the arrow. Addition of only one transport layer (either PTAA or C 60 ) induces additional non-radiative recombination pathways, which lower the QFLS to approximately 1.125-1.135 eV. The pin junction with both transport layers adjacent to the perovskite absorber still has an average QFLS of approximately 1.121 eV. The arrow shows that interfacial recombination dominates the non-radiative recombination losses in the stack. The films were excited at 450 nm with a 1 Sun equivalent intensity and the histograms were recorded on 5 mm × 5 mm squares in the middle of the films without edge effects (PL quenching) due to the encapsulation glue, as visible in samples 1, 3 and 4. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47092</offset>
      <text> NATURe eNeRgy | VOL 3 | 3 OCTOBER 2018 | 847-854 | www.nature.com/natureenergy Articles Nature eNergy included (PFN-P2 and LiF) fabricated from a CsPbI 0.05 [(FAPbI 3 ) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47263</offset>
      <text> Fig. 5 | 5 Fig. 5 | Suppression of interfacial recombination through interlayers. a,b, QFLS map (1 × 1 cm) (a) and QFLS histogram (b) of a PTAA/PFN-P2/perovskite film on glass, demonstrating a comparatively high average QFLS of approximately 1.19 eV. This represents a significant enhancement of approximately 65 meV compared to the QFLS of the PTAA/perovskite film and approaches the QFLS potential of the neat perovskite within 20 mV. d,e, QFLS map (1 × 1 cm 2 ) (d) and QFLS histogram (e) of a perovskite/LiF/C 60 film on glass, demonstrating the reduced interfacial recombination loss at the n-contact. Importantly, the average QFLS of the perovskite/LiF/C 60 stack (1.169 eV) and the pin device stack (1.173 eV) are both almost identical to the V OC of our optimized cells (1.16-1.17 V). The histograms were recorded on a 5 mm × 5 mm square in the middle of the films, without edge effects (PL quenching) due to the encapsulation glue. c,f, TRPL transients highlighting the significant prolongation of the carrier lifetime when either PFN-P2 (c) or LiF (f) is added as an interlayer. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48357</offset>
      <text> Fig. 6 | 6 Fig. 6 | 20% efficient pin-type perovskite cells with 1 cm 2 active area. a, Photograph of a fabricated 1 cm 2 cell with a rectangular active electrode area.b, 1 cm 2 perovskite cells reaching 20% PCE were achieved using a combination of PFN-P2 and LiF interlayers (J SC = 21.7 mA cm -2 , fill factor = 78.6%, V OC = 1.17 V) as measured with an aperture mask (1.018 cm 2 ) at 25 °C. The inset shows the stabilized power output at 20.1%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48808</offset>
      <text> Table 1 : Average quasi-Fermi level splitting of perovskite films on glass 1 Film PLQY [%] PL peak QFLS [eV] maximum [eV] Perovskite* 5.02x10 -1 1.611 1.208 Perovskite 3.58x10 -1 1.630 1.211 PFN-P2/Perovskite 3.25x10 -1 1.621 1.206 -- PTAA/Perovskite* 2.61x10 -2 1.601 1.124 ITO/PTAA/Perovskite -- 1.123 PTAA/Perovskite 2.83x10 -2 1.632 1.157 PTAA/Perovskite -- 1.150 PTAA/Perovskite 6.56x10 -3 1.612 1.100 PTAA/Perovskite 4.48x10 -3 1.609 1.087 -- Perovskite/C60* 1.66x10 -2 1.625 1.136 Perovskite/C60* 1.77x10 -2 1.609 1.128 -- PTAA/Perovskite/C60* 2.14x10 -2 1.603 1.121 PTAA/Perovskite/C60 7.68x10 -3 1.631 1.123 -- PTAA/PFN-P2/Perovskite* 5.83x10 -1 1.59 1.191 PTAA/PFN-P2/Perovskite 1.83x10 -1 1.626 1.185 -- Perovskite/LiF/C60* 6.67x10 -2 1.625 1.166 Perovskite/LiF/C60 7.50x10 -2 1.629 1.169 -- PTAA/PFN-P2/Perovskite/LiF/C60 9.26x10 -2 1.612 1.173 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49667</offset>
      <text> Table 2 : Average quasi-Fermi level splitting of CsFAPbI3 perovskite films on glass 2 Sample PLQY [%] PL peak [eV] QFLS [eV] perovskite 8.51x10 -2 1.511 1.073 PTAA/perovskite 1.23x10 -2 1.489 1.023 PTAA/PFN/perovskite 6.98x10 -2 1.494 1.068 perovskite/C60 1.51x10 -2 1.496 1.028 perovskite/LiF/C60 4.59x10 -2 1.489 1.057 Supplementary References 1. Tress, W. Perovskite Solar Cells on the Way to Their Radiative Efficiency Limit -Insights Into a Success Story of High Open-Circuit Voltage and Low Recombination. Adv. Energy Mater. 7, 1602358 (2017). 2. Burgelman, M., Nollet, P. &amp; Degrave, S. Modelling polycrystalline semiconductor solar cells. 362, 527-532 (2000). 3. Photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY), PL peak positions and average QFLS splitting values for FAPbI3 perovskite films with and without hole and electron transport layers. The results confirm the substantially suppressed recombination at the interfaces through application of the proposed interlayers PFN-P2 and LiF. Moreover, the calculated QFLS of the perovskite/CTL junctions match within a small error the device open-circuit voltages with (~1.05V) and without interlayers (~1.0V). These findings highlight the general applicability of our approach to identifying and suppressing recombination losses at the interface between the perovskite absorber and the charge transporting layers. Yang , W. S. et al. High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange. Science (80-. ). 348, 1234-1237 (2015). 4. Wang, F. et al. Phenylalkylamine Passivation of Organolead Halide Perovskites Enabling High-Efficiency and Air-Stable Photovoltaic Cells. Adv. Mater. 28, 9986-9992 (2016). 5. Yu, Y. et al. Improving the Performance of Formamidinium and Cesium Lead Triiodide Perovskite Solar Cells using Lead Thiocyanate Additives. ChemSusChem 9, 3288-3297 (2016). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51533</offset>
      <text> https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-018-0219-8 1 Institute of Physics and Astronomy, University of Potsdam, Potsdam, Germany. 2  Department of Structure and Dynamics of Energy Materials, Helmholtz-Zentrum-Berlin, Berlin, Germany. 3  Centre for Organic Photonics &amp; Electronics (COPE), School of Chemistry and Molecular Biosciences, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51924</offset>
      <text> | Impact of transport layers on kinetics of charge recombination. voltage, and thus open-circuit voltage losses were not directly quantified. As recently discussed 32 , there are different approaches to calculate ∆ E F from absolute PL spectra, which are all based on Würfel's generalized Planck law Perovskite 1 τ~500 ns PTAA/perovskite Perovskite/C 60 PTAA/perovskite/C 60 Normalized TRPL 0.1 τ τ ~26 ~26 n s τ ~30 n s n s 0.01 0 5 0 1 00 150 2 00 Time (ns) Fig. 3 Mono-exponential TRPL decay of a neat perovskite film indicating the dominance of trap-assisted recombination in the bulk or the surface. The corresponding mono-exponential lifetime is around 500 ns, potentially allowing a V OC of 1.215 V (see Supplementary Note 1) if no additional interface recombination losses were present. The TRPL signals of perovskite/transport layer heterojunctions show a bi-exponential decay, indicating rapid charge extraction and interfacial recombination on different timescales. The films were illuminated at 470 nm (~30 nJ cm -2 ) through the organic layer, and through C 60 in the case of the pin stack. NATURe eNeRgy | VOL 3 | OCTOBER 2018 | 847-854 | www.nature.com/natureenergy Articles Nature eNergy device &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53144</offset>
      <text>			 NATURe eNeRgy | VOL 3 | OCTOBER 2018 | 847-854 | www.nature.com/natureenergy</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T14:59:20Z</infon>
      <node refid="18" role=""/>
      <node refid="19" role=""/>
      <node refid="20" role=""/>
      <node refid="15" role=""/>
      <node refid="16" role=""/>
      <node refid="17" role=""/>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
