<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025049069CCBHDB</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_review">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 134&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>was calculated to be -6.08 and -6.06 eV. The incorporation of GBA leads to a preferred energy level alignment that could be beneficial to hole extraction. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>169</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Note 3. The moisture stability enhancement of control and target perovskite films. The UV-vis spectroscopy and PL mapping measurements were carried out to assess the moisture stability of control and target perovskite films. The samples were aging in the air at a relative humidity of 55% and 20 ± 5℃. The control perovskite films display the absorption intensity of obvious decay during aging in a humid environment, while the absorption intensity of the target film was not decreased basically (Supplementary Fig.  11 ). The absorption intensity decay indicated the decomposition of the perovskite film. Similarly, PL mapping results show that the introduction of GBA can improve the photoluminescence intensity of perovskite films, and maintain a high luminescence intensity after aging in the air for 120 hours (Supplementary Fig.  12 ). The above results directly proved that the introduction of GBA is beneficial to enhance the perovskite film stability and avoiding the destruction of photoelectric properties by moisture.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1219</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Note 7. Calculation of carrier mobility and diffusion length. The carrier mobility (μ) is obtained according to the space charge limit current (SCLC) regions, and fitted by Mott-Gurney's law: μ= 8𝐽 D 𝐿 3 9εε 0 V 2 = 8𝐿 3 9εε 0 ( √𝐽 D 𝑉 ) 2 Where JD is the current density, ε the relative dielectric constant, 𝜀 0 the vacuum permittivity, V the applied voltage, L the thickness of the perovskite film (about 628 nm for our measurements). The diffusion length L were calculated according to the following equation: 𝐿 = √ K𝑇μ𝜏 𝑞 Where K is the Boltzmann's constant, T is the temperature in K (295 K in our case), q is the elementary charge, the carrier lifetime τ is obtained from the time-resolved TRPL measurements. The results were shown in Supplementary Table  3 . Supplementary Table  1 . The binding energy of H2O molecules with perovskite through H2O-FA + , H2O-Pb 2+ and H2O-I -approaches, when the structure with or without vacancy, and incorporated GBA. The fabrication of perovskite solar cells (PSCs) in ambient air can accelerate their industrialization. However, moisture induces severe decomposition of the perovskite layer, limiting the device efficiency. Here we show that sites near vacancy defects absorb water molecules and trigger the hydration of the perovskite, eventually leading to the degradation of the material. We demonstrate that guanabenz acetate salt eliminates both cation and anion vacancies, blocking the perovskite hydration and allowing the crystallization of a high-quality film in ambient air. With guanabenz acetate salt, we prepare PSCs in ambient air with a certified efficiency of 25.08%. The PSCs without encapsulation maintain around 96% of their initial efficiency after 2,000 hours of ageing in ambient air and after 500 hours of operating at the maximum power point under simulated air mass (AM) 1.5 G solar light in a N 2 atmosphere. The encapsulated devices retained 85% of their initial efficiency after 300 hours under damp heat conditions (85 °C and 85% relative humidity). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">guanabenz acetate salt</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:33:14Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:1">2601-&gt;2591</infon>
        <location offset="2591" length="22"/>
        <text>guanabenz acetate salt</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25.08</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:33:26Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:2">2865-&gt;2855</infon>
        <location offset="2855" length="6"/>
        <text>25.08%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:34:05Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:5">3059-&gt;3049</infon>
        <location offset="3049" length="61"/>
        <text>r simulated air mass (AM) 1.5 G solar light in a N 2 atmosphe</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:34:53Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:6">3158-&gt;3148</infon>
        <location offset="3148" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:34:45Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:7">3212-&gt;3202</infon>
        <location offset="3202" length="20"/>
        <text>damp heat conditions</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:34:59Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:8">3233-&gt;3223</infon>
        <location offset="3223" length="6"/>
        <text>(85 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:35:03Z</infon>
        <infon key="error:misaligned:9">3244-&gt;3234</infon>
        <location offset="3234" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3303</offset>
      <text> Configuration Metal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have attracted much research attention as a tremendous potential photovoltaic technology, with their power conversion efficiency (PCE) now exceeding 25.8% (refs. 1,2). Massive efforts-crystallization regulation, defect passivation and interface and structure design-have been devoted to improving the efficiency and stability of PSCs  [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9] [10] [11]  . However, the fabrication of these &gt;25% efficient and stable PSCs requires an inert atmosphere (for example, nitrogen glovebox)  [12] [13] [14]  , which restricts their large-scale production and practical applications. Therefore, the fabrication of high-performance PSCs in ambient air is expected to promote their practical applications and low-cost commercialization. Unfortunately, lead halide perovskite is extremely sensitive to moisture in ambient air, which can lead to initial hydration, followed by disruptive phase transitions, destruction of the crystal framework and decomposition  [15] [16] [17] [18] [19] [20]  . Hence, the fabrication of highly efficient PSCs is strictly limited to a glovebox; thus, it is difficult to fabricate them in a scaled and industrialized fashion. The space expansion of a glovebox is intractable from technical and economic perspectives. In an effort to obtain high-efficiency PSCs independent of the inert atmosphere, researchers have adapted the fabrication of PSCs to various environmental conditions  [21] [22] [23] [24] [25] [26] [27] [28] [29] [30] [31] [32]  . The additive strategy  25, 26  is a valid approach to optimizing perovskite crystallization and preventing moisture vulnerability in ambient air, such as 19.4% efficient PSCs enabled via PbS quantum dots at 40-60% relative humidity (RH)  26  . Antisolvent engineering and environmental condition control in the deposition process can also reduce the moisture impacts and accelerate perovskite crystallization, promoting PSCs with efficiencies exceeding 22% at 50-70% RH  [27] [28] [29] [30]  . Remarkably, the use of ionic liquids  4, 31, 32  is proposed to obtain stable perovskite in ambient air; the ionic liquids induce vertical lead iodide to achieve a fast transformation to stable α-FAPbI 3 and can produce PSCs with an efficiency of 24.1% at 80% RH  4  . However, an approach to truly throw off the impact State Key Laboratory of Alternate Electrical Power System with Renewable Energy Sources, School of New Energy, North China Electric Power University, Beijing, China.  2  These authors contributed equally: Luyao Yan, Hao Huang, Peng Cui. e-mail: mcli@ncepu.edu.cn Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01358-w  distortion of the perovskite structure was prevented. The formation of δ-FAPbI 3 is completely inhibited by incorporating GBA, even in ambient humidity as high as 80% RH. In addition, the intensity of the PbI 2 peak in the target perovskite XRD image is decreased compared with that of the control film (Supplementary Fig.  3  and Supplementary Note 1). These ideal film properties confirm that GBA can protect crystallization from moisture in ambient air, resulting in compact and α-FAPbI 3 -preferred perovskite films. We also evaluated the photoelectric property differences of perovskite films deposited in ambient air in terms of spatial uniformity and photoluminescence spectroscopy. Notably, the following control and target samples were prepared in ambient air under ~55% RH (~20 °C) unless specified. Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) measurements were carried out to examine the surface potential of the films (Fig.  2a, b  and Supplementary Fig.  4 ). The target film exhibits a higher potential than the control film, which could be attributed to the decreased surface electronic trap density  38  . The increase in surface potential is consistent with the ultraviolet photoelectron spectrometer results (Supplementary Figs.  5  and 6  and Supplementary Note 2). Additionally, the potential distribution of the target film is ~33 mV, which is smaller than that of the control film (~48 mV). From the photoluminescence (PL) images of both films, the target film clearly exhibits an enhanced PL intensity compared to that of the control film (Fig.  2c, d  and Supplementary Fig.  7 ). Specifically, the PL intensity distribution in the target film is more spatially uniform than that in the control film, which is consistent with the KPFM results. The uniform distribution of potential and PL intensity indicates that the incorporated GBA improves the quality of perovskite films. The photoluminescence quantum efficiency (PLQE) was measured to quantitatively evaluate the luminous efficiencies of both films deposited in ambient air (Fig.  2e ). The PLQE of the control film is 3.64 ± 2.14%, while the target film exhibits a significantly increased PLQE of 17.90 ± 1.49%, demonstrating its superior radiative ability after incorporating GBA. The carrier lifetime from time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) of the target film is prolonged from 0.77 μs to 2.26 μs (Fig.  2f ), indicating fewer trap states. In short, these remarkable structural and photoelectric phenomena verify that the incorporated GBA can decrease the sensitivity of perovskite crystallization to moisture, ensuring the formation of a high-quality perovskite film deposited in ambient air. To visually observe the decreased moisture sensitivity of the target film, water-soaking tests were conducted. The decomposition process under continuous spray soaking of perovskite films was observed in situ under an optical microscope (Fig.  2g ). The control and target films show an apparent decomposition difference in the time response. The control film degrades immediately under spray soaking, while the target film can maintain stability for up to 24 s, suggesting the moisture insensitivity resulting from the use of GBA. Additionally, harsher water dropping and immersing tests were carried out (Supplementary Figs.  8  and 9 ). When contacting the water, the control film shows a colour change from black to yellow within 3 s, while the target film can maintain the black colour for over 15 s, which is consistent with the results from the spray soaking tests. Subsequently, we performed a contact angle test, and the results showed that the control and target films had similar water drop contact angles (Supplementary Fig.  10 ). According to the contact angle tests, the reason for decreased moisture sensitivity of the target film is not supposed to be forming a hydrophobic surface. Considering the improved photoelectric property of the target film, we speculate that the decreased moisture sensitivity may be closely relevant to the eliminated vacancy that is reported to mainly exist in the grain boundary and surface  39, 40  (Supplementary Figs.  11  and 12  and Supplementary Note 3). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">guanabenz acetate salt</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:36:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="6100" length="3"/>
        <text>GBA</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10169</offset>
      <text> Confirmation of hydration blocking The reason for the high-quality perovskite film achieved in ambient air was examined; GBA blocks the hydration pathway, that is, the initial of moisture on the fabrication of PSCs to obtain an efficiency of over 25% in ambient air is lacking. We aim to design a strategy that focuses on the first stage of perovskite hydration to protect the perovskite from water. Hydration is generated more easily near the vacancy sites located on the perovskite surface and grain boundary, which can drastically accelerate the moisture-induced decomposition of perovskite films  33, 34  . Hence, eliminating the vacancies is a feasible approach to decreasing the perovskite sensitivity to water. The cation vacancies can be effectively filled by an organic group, which possesses suitable charges and a similar molecular size to formamidinium ions (FA + )  35, 36  . In addition, pseudohalide anions with strong electronegativities, such as HCOO -and CH 3 COO -, cannot only suppress anion-vacancy defects but also augment the crystallinity of films  14  . On the basis of the above analysis, guanabenz acetate salt (GBA) should be a suitable material; its structure includes acetate (AC -) and guanidine groups, which theoretically can suppress both cation and anion vacancies and synergistically optimize crystallization. GBA also includes a benzene ring that possesses a high electron cloud density to passivate perovskite neutral defects and a concrete molecular structure to maintain the guanidine group anchoring on the perovskite surface and grain boundary  37  . Here we report highly efficient PSCs fabricated fully in ambient air by blocking the hydration pathway of perovskite at the source using GBA. GBA significantly eliminates the vacancy and increases the binding energy of perovskite with H 2 O, removing the detrimental interference of moisture on perovskite crystallization. The resulting PSCs obtained an efficiency of 25.32% (certified 25.08%) with an aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 and maintained 97% of the initial PCE after 2,000 hours of ageing in ambient air without encapsulation. The unencapsulated PSCs retained 96% of the initial PCE after maximum power point (MPP) tracking under continuous illumination ( ~ 50 °C) in N 2 atmosphere for 500 hours. Moreover, the encapsulated PSCs exhibited excellent stability under damp heat tests (85 °C and 85% RH). These PSCs retained 85% of their original PCE values after 300 hours of testing at 85% RH. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.97</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:05:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="12207" length="3"/>
        <text>97%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12665</offset>
      <text> Characterization of perovskite films fabricated in air We deposited perovskite films in various humid atmospheres, and distinctive phenomena in structural and photoelectric properties with and without GBA (Supplementary Fig.  1  shows the chemical structure) were demonstrated. The quality of control perovskite films containing no GBA becomes very poor without inert atmosphere protection; this finding was confirmed by the morphology and crystallinity results (via scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIXRD)). In the control film, the number of pinholes and PbI 2 on the surface increases with increasing humidity (Fig.  1a  and Supplementary Fig.  2 ), which is consistent with previous reports  22  . Figure  1b, c  shows the 2D GIXRD ring patterns and the corresponding 1D integral spectra of the control films, respectively. When the deposition of perovskite films is exposed to moisture, the signal of the wide-bandgap yellow phase (δ-FAPbI 3 ) begins to be captured, and the integrated intensity of the α-FAPbI 3 peak located near 14° decreases. Additionally, the increase in humidity causes a shift of the peak in the 1D integral spectra, which indicates that the perovskite structure distortion is impacted by moisture. These undesirable structural deviations are worsened with increasing humidity, suggesting the adverse impacts of moisture on the crystallinity of perovskite, which impedes the formation of ideal α-FAPbI 3 and induces composition segregation  14, 18  . In contrast to the control films, the target films exhibit excellent quality even when their deposition process is exposed to moisture (incorporated 3% GBA). Their surface morphology shows no evident difference with increasing humidity (Fig.  1d ). The film deposited under ~80% RH (~20 °C) in ambient air still possesses a pinhole-free and dense characteristic. In Fig.  1e, f , the integrated intensity of the α-FAPbI 3 peak can maintain a remarkable consistency under different humidities, and Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01358-w  interaction stage between moisture and perovskite. Initially, the mechanism of moisture-induced decomposition was analysed (Fig.  3a, left ). An atom exposed by a vacancy in perovskite can bind with H 2 O molecules more easily in energetics  16, 33, 34, 39, 40  , which is the beginning of the hydration process. The subsequent process induces the escape of the FAI and collapse of the Pb 2 I 6 2-framework  19, 41  . To investigate the dominant impact of vacancies on hydration, density functional theory (DFT) studies were carried out to calculate the binding energy of H 2 O molecules with the perovskite (Fig.  3b  and Supplementary Table  1 ). I -and FA + vacancies are readily formed during film deposition  15  . When there is a FA + vacancy in the structure (Supplementary Fig.  13 ), the binding energies of H 2 O molecules with FA + , Pb 2+ and I -are -1.134 eV, -1.133 eV and -1.461 eV, respectively. When there is an I -vacancy (Supplementary Fig.  14 ), the binding energies of H 2 O with FA + , Pb 2+ and I -are -1.450 eV, -0.610 eV and -1.189 eV, respectively. Conversely, in an ideal perovskite structure (Supplementary Fig.  15 ), the binding energies of H 2 O molecules with FA + , Pb 2+ and I -are 1.020 eV, 1.446 eV and 1.774 eV, respectively. These results indicate that H 2 O molecules can be favourably absorbed near vacancy sites and induce perovskite decomposition, which suggests that eliminating vacancies is a feasible approach to decreasing the sensitivity of perovskites to moisture. GBA can eliminate vacancies through interaction with perovskite (Fig.  3a, right ). GBA is an aromatic amine salt, including AC -, which possesses strong coordination ability, and a terminated guanidine group in the benzene ring, which forms a greater number of effective hydrogen bonds than FA +42 . From the Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectra of GBA and the target film (Fig.  3c ), both the corresponding absorption peaks of C = O and C-O of GBA shift to a lower wavenumber after being incorporated into the perovskite film, implying that an interaction occurred between GBA and perovskite  43  . Specifically, the evident downshift of Pb 4f core levels in the target film also confirms the above interaction (X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy; Fig.  3d , Supplementary Fig.  16  and Supplementary Note 4), indicating that GBA can fill the I -vacancy through binding with the unsaturated Pb 2+44 . Additionally, the smaller binding energy of Pb 2+ -AC -demonstrates that the unsaturated Pb 2+ will preferentially connect with AC -through a stronger Pb-O bond rather than the H 2 O molecule upon comparison of the binding energies of Pb 2+ -AC -(-2.401 eV) and Pb 2+ -H 2 O (-0.610 eV) when I -vacancies are present (Supplementary Fig.  17  and Supplementary Table  2 ). Additionally, it was speculated that the FA + vacancy was filled by the terminated guanidine group of GBA based on the formed hydrogen q r (Å -1 ) q r (Å -1 ) q r (Å -1 ) q r (Å -1 ) q r (Å -1 ) q r (Å -1 ) 2θ (°) Intensity (a.u.) Intensity (a.u.) bond and energetic stability calculation. The I 3d core levels of the target film exhibited a downshift (Supplementary Fig.  18 ), implying the I -vacancy was filled by AC -and the formation of a hydrogen bond between the terminated guanidine group of GBA and the I atom  41  . In addition, the terminated guanidine group of GBA interacted with the PbI 2 film substrate through a hydrogen bond, which was also confirmed by the shift of C = N in the PbI 2 film-incorporated GBA (Supplementary Fig.  19 )  35  . From the view of energetics, after the terminated guanidine filled the FA + vacancy, the DFT calculation showed that I -vacancy formation was suppressed by 0.28 eV (Supplementary Fig.  20  and Supplementary Note 5), resulting in a stable perovskite lattice  33  . To verify that the incorporated GBA eliminates both I -and FA + vacancies in perovskite, we carried out deep energy level transient spectroscopy (DLTS) measurements (Fig.  3e ). The DLTS signals of the control film exhibited two peaks marked with T1 and T2, indicating two types of dominant traps. The Arrhenius plots were fitted (Fig.  3f ) to calculate the activation energy of the corresponding traps according to the following Arrhenius equation: ln(t au × V th × N c ) = E T -E V KT -ln(X P σ P ) where K is the Boltzmann constant, t au is the emission time constant, V th is the thermal velocity, N c is the effective density of states of the trap in cm -3 , X P is the entropy factor and σ P is the capture cross section, T is the temperature of test, E T is the energy level of the trap center and E V is the energy level of VBM. The trap activation energy (ΔE = E T - E V ) of T1 was calculated to be 0.51 eV and that of T2 was calculated to be 0.39 eV, which represent the FA + vacancy and I -vacancy in the control film, respectively  45, 46  . Remarkably, the DLTS signals of the target film did not exhibit any trap peaks, indicating that the incorporated GBA effectively eliminated the vacancy. The decreased trap density resulting from the GBA was also confirmed by the space-charge-limited current (SCLC) measurements (Supplementary Figs.  21  and 22  and Supplementary Note 6). In addition, we calculated the carrier mobility and diffusion length of the control and target films. The results showed that the carrier mobility and diffusion length of the target films increased from 1.98 cm 2 V -1 s -1 and 1.96 μm to 2.68 cm 2 V -1 s -1 and 3.92 μm, respectively (Supplementary Table  3  and Supplementary Note 7). The effects of the decreased moisture sensitivity of perovskite due to the elimination of vacancies by GBA were investigated. On the basis of the I -vacancy and FA + vacancy filled by the AC -and terminated guanidine groups of GBA, respectively, we calculated the binding energies of H 2 O molecules with FA + , Pb 2+ and I -to be 0.790 eV, 0.373 eV and 0.475 eV, respectively (Fig.  3g , Supplementary Fig.  23  and Supplementary Table  1 ). After incorporating GBA, the binding energy of H 2 O molecules with the perovskite transformed from negative (Fig.  3b ) to positive (Fig.  3g ), implying harder to bind. The positive value would indicate that the interaction of H 2 O molecules with the perovskite was not spontaneous or immediate. Hence, the intercepted perovskite hydration by GBA could effectively protect the perovskite crystallization from moisture, ensuring the deposition of high-quality perovskite films for fabricating efficient PSCs in ambient air (Fig.  3a ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21297</offset>
      <text> Performance of PSCs fabricated in ambient air We utilized high-quality perovskite films that incorporated GBA further to fabricate PSCs (FTO/c-TiO 2 /FA 0.98 MA 0.02 PbI 3 /o-F-PEAI/Spiro-OMeTAD/ Au) in ambient air. After exploring the influence of the GBA concentration on the PCE of PSCs (Supplementary Fig.  24  and Supplementary Table  4 ), we determined that the optimal concentration was 0.045 M (the molar ratio of GBA/PbI 2 is 3%). Figure  4a  displays the current density-voltage (J-V) curves (reverse) of the champion control and target PSCs, in which the aperture area is 0.08 cm 2 . The target PSCs reach a PCE of 25.32% with low hysteresis, while the PCE of the control PSCs is 23.13% (Supplementary Fig.  25  and Supplementary Table  5 ). Specifically, the target PSCs exhibit an open voltage (V OC ) of 1.174 V, which is much higher than that (1.141 V) of control PSCs. The stabilized PCE of the target PSCs is 25.03%, measured at the maximum power point (Supplementary Fig.  25 ). The corresponding external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the control and target PSCs are shown in Fig.  4b , in which the value of integrated short-circuit current density (J SC ) is basically consistent with that obtained from the J-V curves. The target PSCs also possess satisfactory reproducibility with an average PCE of 24.71% (Fig.  4c  and Supplementary Fig.  26 ). One of the best performing target PSCs was certified by an independent solar cell-accredited laboratory (National Institute of Metrology, China) and achieved a PCE of 25.08% (Supplementary Fig.  27 ). We directly compared reported PSCs fabricated fully in ambient air with those in our work (Supplementary Fig.  28  and Supplementary Table  6 ) and showed that the PCE of 25.32% obtained in our work significantly promoted the advances of ambient air-fabricated PSCs. The incorporated GBA ensures a uniform perovskite film deposited in ambient air, which is further used to fabricate PSCs with an aperture area of 1 cm 2 (Fig.  4d ). On the basis of the same composition and device structure, the control PSCs exhibit a PCE of 20.37%, with a J SC of 25.20 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.148 V and a fill factor of 71.23%. In contrast, the PCE of the target PSCs improved to 22.62%, with a J SC of 25.43 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.161 V and the fill factor increased to 76.60% (Supplementary   9 . Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01358-w   Fig.  29  and Supplementary Table  7 ). The effectively improved performance in large-area PSCs indicates the further potential of our work in scalable industrialization. It has been reported that there are various types and amounts of defect in different perovskite components  47, 48  . To verify the expandability of GBA in improving the performance of other perovskites, we also fabricated PSCs (FTO/c-TiO 2 /MA 0.75 FA 0.25 PbI 3 /o-F-PEAI/Spiro-OMeTAD/ Au, the aperture area is 0.08 cm 2 ) by the one-step method in ambient air. The target PSCs exhibit a PCE of 23.71%, which is higher than that (22.22%) of the control PSCs (Supplementary Fig.  30 , Supplementary Note 8 and Supplementary Table  8 ). In detail, the J SC of the target PSCs is 24.83 mA cm -2 , which shows a small variation with the integrated J SC of the corresponding EQE measurement. To investigate the effect of incorporated GBA on PSCs' intrinsic stability, the PCE evolution of unencapsulated PSCs under various conditions was monitored. We examined the long-term operational stability through MPP tracking of the unencapsulated PSCs under continuous AM 1.5 G (100 mW cm -2 ) solar light in a N 2 atmosphere at 50 ± 5 °C (Fig.  4e ). The target PSCs could maintain 96% of their initial PCE after 500 hours. Conversely, the control PSCs dropped to &lt;65% of the initial PCE in no more than 400 hours. GBA enhanced the operational stability of the PSCs due to the eliminated vacancy that was beneficial for ion migration, based on the reported degradation mechanism of PSCs during operation  46  . We further monitored the PCE evolution of unencapsulated PSCs stored in ambient air. The PCE of the target PSCs showed no evident decline after 2,000 hours of ageing, while the PCE of the control PSCs maintained only 68% of the initial value (Fig.  4f ). The enhanced air stability of the target PSCs could be ascribed to the decreased sensitivity of the perovskite film to moisture. The extrinsic stability of PSCs was also assessed following the International Summit on Organic Photovoltaic Stability standardized stability testing procedure  49  . Initially, we performed MPP tracking of the encapsulated PSCs under continuous AM1.5 G (100 mW cm -2 ) solar light in ambient air at 85% RH. As shown in Fig.  4g , the target PSCs maintained 85% of their initial PCE after 300 hours of operation at 85% RH. In contrast, the control PSCs dropped to &lt;60% of the initial PCE in no more than 90 h. Then, we conducted stricter stability measurements on the encapsulated PSCs, as shown in Fig.  4h . The target PSCs exhibited T85 &gt; 260 hours under the damp heat test (85 °C and 85% RH), while the control PSCs showed rapid decay. We also performed the accelerated degradation measurements of unencapsulated PSCs stored at 65% RH; the target PSCs show better moisture stability than control PSCs (Supplementary Fig.  31 ). On the basis of these results, GBA ensured the excellent stability of PSCs fabricated in ambient air, which enabled high-performance PSC fabrication that no longer required an inert atmosphere; this process could quickly lead towards the commercialization of these PSCs. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA0.98MA0.02Pbl3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:38:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="21448" length="21"/>
        <text>FA 0.98 MA 0.02 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:38:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="21480" length="12"/>
        <text>Spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.174</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:38:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="22116" length="7"/>
        <text>1.174 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:39:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="24113" length="61"/>
        <text>FTO/c-TiO 2 /MA 0.75 FA 0.25 PbI 3 /o-F-PEAI/Spiro-OMeTAD/ Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:00:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="24821" length="78"/>
        <text>PSCs under continuous AM 1.5 G (100 mW cm -2 ) solar light in a N 2 atmosphere</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:40:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="24903" length="9"/>
        <text>50 ± 5 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.96</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:00:50Z</infon>
        <location offset="24957" length="2"/>
        <text>96</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:03:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="24988" length="9"/>
        <text>500 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:04:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="25039" length="4"/>
        <text>&lt;65%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:02:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="25430" length="5"/>
        <text>2,000</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.68</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:03:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="25503" length="5"/>
        <text>68% o</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="30">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:07:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="25851" length="100"/>
        <text>performed MPP tracking of the encapsulated PSCs under continuous AM1.5 G (100 mW cm -2 ) solar light</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="31">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:07:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="25970" length="6"/>
        <text>85% RH</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="32">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:08:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="26028" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="33">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">300</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:08:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="26059" length="9"/>
        <text>300 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:41:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="26134" length="4"/>
        <text>&lt;60%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="37">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:10:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="26306" length="3"/>
        <text>T85</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">260</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T07:42:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="26312" length="9"/>
        <text>260 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="34">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:09:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="26332" length="14"/>
        <text>damp heat test</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="35">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:09:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="26348" length="5"/>
        <text>85 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="36">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:09:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="26358" length="5"/>
        <text>85% R</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R3">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:09:07Z</infon>
        <node refid="30" role=""/>
        <node refid="31" role=""/>
        <node refid="32" role=""/>
        <node refid="33" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:04:03Z</infon>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
        <node refid="24" role=""/>
        <node refid="25" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R4">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:10:28Z</infon>
        <node refid="34" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="37" role=""/>
        <node refid="35" role=""/>
        <node refid="36" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26877</offset>
      <text> Discussion In summary, high-efficiency PSCs were completely fabricated in ambient air by blocking hydration. On the basis of the critical role of the vacancy on perovskite hydration, perovskite crystallization was protected from moisture by eliminating the vacancy sites through the incorporation of GBA, ensuring the formation of high-quality perovskite films in ambient air. Due to the finely controlled perovskite crystallinity and decreased vacancy trap states, the PSCs fabricated in ambient air obtained a PCE of 25.32% (certified 25.08%); this is the highest value among the PSCs fabricated in the open environment up to date and rivals the state-of-the-art PSCs fabricated in a glovebox. In addition, unencapsulated PSCs exhibit excellent long-term stability, which can maintain 96% of their initial efficiency after 500 hours of operating at the maximum power point under simulated AM 1.5 G solar light. This work provides a feasible approach to enable high-performance PSC fabrication that no longer required an inert atmosphere and can quickly lead toward the commercialization of these efficient PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27993</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28003</offset>
      <text> Materials The materials consisted of the following: FTO glass substrate (12-14 ohm); TiCl 4 (Aladdin, 99.9%); lead iodide (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.9%); guanabenz acetate salt (Aladdin); DMF (Sigma-Aldrich); DMSO (Sigma-Aldrich); isopropanol (Acros, 99.8%); chlorobenzene (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.5%); acetonitrile (Acros, 99.9%); FAI, MAI, MACl, o-F-PEAI, Spiro-OMeTAD, lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonimide) and 4-tert-butylpyridine (Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corp). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28468</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication in ambient air Preparation of the FTO glass substrate: the FTO glass substrate was ultrasonically cleaned with deionized water, ethanol and deionized water for 15 min each. After drying the substrate with a high-purity N 2 stream, the substrate was treated with ultraviolet ozone for 15 min to obtain the hydrophilic surface. Preparation of the compact TiO 2 electron transport layer: to prepare the TiO 2 electron transport layers, TiCl 4 (3 ml) and deionized water (200 ml) were mixed and stirred to obtain a TiO 2 precursor. Then the FTO substrate was immersed into the precursor and stored in a water bath at 70 °C for 40 min to obtain the compact TiO 2 layer. Before spin coating the perovskite precursor, the FTO/TiO 2 substrate was treated with UV-ozone for 15 min to improve infiltration and passivate oxygen vacancy defect  50  . Preparation of perovskite via the two-step method with different humidities: a 1.5 M PbI 2 (DMF: DMSO, 9:1 volume/volume) precursor with different ratios of guanabenz acetate (GBA, the molar ratio of GBA/PbI 2 was 1%, 3%, 5%) was spin coated on the FTO/TiO 2 substrate at 1,500 r.p.m. for 30 s and then annealed at 70 °C for 60 s. After the PbI 2 film cooled to room temperature, ammonium salt (90 mg FAI, 9 mg MACl, 6.39 mg MAI in 1 ml IPA) was spin coated on the PbI 2 film at 2,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and then annealed at 150 °C for 15 min. The addition of MACl can inhibit the transformation from black ɑ-phase perovskite to yellow δ-phase non-perovskite, increasing the stability of the perovskite  51  . The characterization in the full text, and the champion PSCs, were fabricated via the two-step method. Preparation of perovskite by the one-step method: the 1.86 M FA 0.25 MA 0.75 PbI 3 (DMF: DMSO, 13:2 volume/volume) precursor with 3% GBA was spin coated on the FTO/TiO 2 substrate at 4,000 r.p.m. for 18 s, and 200 μl diethyl ether as an antisolvent was dripped on the centre of the film 12 s before the end of spin coating. Then the film was annealed at 110 °C for 10 min. The PSCs fabricated by the one-step method appear only in Supplementary Fig.  30 . Preparation of the o-F-PEAI layer: 10 mM o-F-PEAI dissolved in IPA was spin coated on the FTO/TiO 2 /perovskite surface at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s without further annealing. Preparation of the Spiro-OMeTAD hole transport layer: the Spiro-OMeTAD solution was prepared by mixing 72.3 mg Spiro-OMeTAD in 1 ml chlorobenzene with 26.6 μl 4-tert-butylpyridine and 18 μl lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonimide) (520 mg ml -1 in acetonitrile); this was spin coated at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s. Preparation of the Au electrode: Au electrode (60 nm) was deposited by thermal evaporation. SEM, XRD and GIXRD measurements: surface morphology was characterized by cold field-emission scanning electron microscopy (SEM, Hitachi S-4800). The crystallinity of perovskite films was measured by X-ray diffraction (XRD, Bruker-D8-Discover) and grazing incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD, Micromax-007HF). The XRD using Cu Kα (λ = 0.15406 nm) radiation (40 kV, 40 mA), the scan step was 0.01 s and the speed was 2° min -1 . The GIXRD pattern was collected using Mo Kα (λ = 0.709 Å) with a sample-detector distance of 217 nm, and the grazing angle of incidence is 0.5°. The morphology evolution of the perovskite film under continuous water spray was observed under an optical microscope (OLYMPUS, DSX500). UV-vis measurement: the absorption intensity of perovskite films was measured by Supplementary Fig. 13 . 13 Binding energy of H 2 O molecular with FAPbI 3 structure when there existed FA + vacancy. a, FA + -H2O. b, Pb 2+ -H2O. c, I --H2O. In the ball-andstick model, grey: Pb, violet: I, red: O, brown: C, blue: N, pink: H. The Eb represents binding energy in the inset. Supplementary Fig. 15. Binding energy of H 2 O molecular with ideal FAPbI 3 structure. a, FA + -H2O. b, Pb 2+ -H2O. c, I --H2O. In the ball-and-stick model, grey: Pb, violet: I, red: O, brown: C, blue: N, pink: H. The Eb represents binding energy in the inset. Supplementary Fig. 17. Binding energy of FAPbI 3 structure with AC -and H 2 O molecular when the structure existed I -vacancy. a, Pb 2+ -H2O. b, Pb 2+ -AC -. In the ball-and-stick model, grey: Pb, violet: I, red: O, brown: C, blue: N, pink: H. The Eb represents binding energy in the inset. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32815</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Fig. 23 . 23 Binding energy of H 2 O molecular with FAPbI 3 structure when there existed GBA. a, FA + -H2O. b, Pb 2+ -H2O. c, I --H2O. In the ball-and-stick model, grey: Pb, violet: I, red: O, brown: C, blue: N, pink: H. The Eb represents binding energy in the inset. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33099</offset>
      <text> Received: 13 13 September 2022 Accepted: 22 August 2023 Published online: 28 September 2023 Check for updates 1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33213</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Morphology and crystallinity characterization of perovskite films. a-f, Both control and target films are fabricated under different humidities (0-80% RH). a, SEM images of control films. b, 2D GIXRD ring patterns of control films. q r is the scattering vector. c, 1D GIXRD integral spectra of control films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33544</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Photoelectric property characterization of perovskite films. a,b, Surface potential images of control (a) and target (b) films. The statistical potential distributions of film surfaces are shown at the bottom. CPD, contact potential difference. c,d, PL mapping of control (c) and target (d) films. e, PLQE results of control and target films (five samples for each). The height of the box &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33955</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Characterization of the interaction between perovskite and GBA. a, Schematic illustration of the moisture-induced decomposition and the decreased moisture sensitivity caused by the addition of GBA. b, The binding energies of H 2 O molecules with perovskite through H 2 O-FA + , H 2 O-Pb 2+ and H 2 O-I - approaches when the structure contained FA + vacancies, I -vacancies and no vacancies. c, FTIR spectra of GBA and the target film. d, XPS characterization of Pb in the control and target films. The vertical dashed line is the position of C = O &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34525</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 4 Fig. 4 | Photovoltaic performance of control and target PSCs. a, J-V curves of the champion control and target PSCs with an aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 . Inset, a photograph of the PSC. b, EQE spectra of control and target PSCs. c, Histogram of the PCE value among 100 PSCs. d, J-V curves of the champion control and target PSCs with an aperture area of 1 cm 2 . e,f, Normalized PCE of the unencapsulated control and target PSCs measured at MPP under continuous 1 sun illumination in N 2 atmosphere (e) and stored in ambient air at 20% RH and 25 ± 5 °C in the dark (f). g,h, Normalized PCE of the encapsulated control and target PSCs measured at MPP under continuous 1 sun illumination at 85% RH (g) and stored at 85 °C and 85% RH in the dark (h). The horizontal dashed line is the 85% of initial PCE. The initial photovoltaic parameters of the control and target PSCs in the stability test were listed in Supplementary Table9. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:06:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="35068" length="3"/>
        <text>20%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:06:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="35079" length="9"/>
        <text>25 ± 5 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="29">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:06:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="35089" length="11"/>
        <text>in the dark</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35468</offset>
      <text> Table 3 . 3 The carrier mobility and diffusion length of control and target films deposited in ambient air. H 2 O-FA + H 2 O-Pb 2+ H 2 O-I - Ideal structure +1.020 eV +1.446 eV +1.774 eV Existed FA + vacancy -1.134 eV -1.133 eV -1.461 eV Existed I -vacancy -1.450 eV -0.610 eV -1.190 eV Incorporated GBA +0.790 eV +0.373 eV +0.475 eV &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35804</offset>
      <text> Table 4 . 4 Photovoltaic parameters for PSCs fabricated in ambient air with different concentrations of GBA. V OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) 0% 1.122 25.75 79.20 22.89 1% 1.148 25.87 80.57 23.93 3% 1.174 25.92 81.69 24.85 5% 1.161 25.90 80.21 24.12 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36063</offset>
      <text> Table 5 . 5 Photovoltaic parameters for target and control champion PSCs fabricated in ambient air with an aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 . Device V OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Target-Forward 1.174 25.90 83.26 25.32 Target-Reverse 1.161 25.87 82.88 24.89 Control-Forward 1.141 25.77 78.67 23.13 Control-Reverse 1.108 25.70 76.30 21.73 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36406</offset>
      <text> Table 6 . 6 Representative PCE of ambient-air fabricated PSCs in recent years (Corresponding to Supplementary Fig.28) Year RH a (%) AT b (°C) Method Device structure Perovskite Area (cm 2 ) PCE (%) Certificated PCE ref 2017 60-80 / Crystallization optimization p-i-n FAMAPbI 3 / 17.37 / 5 2018 25 / Crystallization optimization p-i-n MAPbI 3 0.1 16.00 / 6 2018 55-68 26-32 Crystallization optimization p-i-n MAPbI 3 0.04 18.30 / 7 2018 50 / Interface Engineering p-i-n MAPbI 4 / 16.94 / 8 2018 15-25 20-22 Cation Engineering p-i-n Cs x (FA 0.83 MA 0.17 ) (1-x) Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 0.025 20.80 / 9 2019 30-80 / Ionic liquids MAAc p-i-n MAPbI 3 / 20.05 / 10 2019 30-40 ~25 Leveraging processing temperature p-i-n CsPbI 2 Br 0.03 1 14.70 12.50 / 11 2019 / ~25 air-blading p-i-n MAPbI 3 0.09 1 20.08 19.12 / 12 2020 30 50 ~25 Self-Polymerizing Ionic Liquid p-i-n MAPbI 3 FAMAPbI 3 0.16 17 19.92 / 13 2020 20-70 / Ionic liquids MAAc p-i-n CsPbI 2.5 Br 0.5 0.05 17.00 / 14 2021 40-60 ~25 PbS QDs + MACl p-i-n FAPbI 3 0.12 19.4 / 1 2021 50-60 / PbSCN 2 +PbAc 2 p-i-n FAPbI 3 0.09 20.55 / 15 2021 / / Rapid Spray Plasma p-i-n modules Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 PbI 3 5.9 18.00 / 16 2021 20-90 25-100 Ionic liquids MAFa p-i-n FAMAPbI 3 0.05 24.10 / 17 2021 / / self-healing polysiloxane Flexible PSCs FAPbI 3 0.16 19.5 / 18 2021 20-88 / drop-casting p-i-n MAPbI 3 0.04 18.17 / 19 2021 / / Ionic liquids MAAc p-i-n MAPbBr 3 / 20.05 / 20 2021 50-60 ~25 air-knife-assisted p-i-n FA 0.6 MA 0.4 PbBrI 2 0.06 1 21.10 18.00 / 21 a RH, relative humidity; b AT, ambient temperature. Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37979</offset>
      <text> Table 7 . 7 Photovoltaic parameters for target and control champion PSCs fabricated in ambient air with an aperture area of 1 cm 2 . Device V OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Target-Forward 1.161 25.43 76.60 22.62 Target-Reverse 1.135 25.36 73.73 21.21 Control-Forward 1.135 25.20 71.23 20.37 Control-Reverse 1.096 25.14 69.99 19.27 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38319</offset>
      <text> Table 8 . 8 Photovoltaic parameters for target and control champion PSCs fabricated in ambient air by one-step with an aperture area of 0.08 cm 2 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38469</offset>
      <text> Device V OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Supplementary Target-Forward 1.151 24.83 82.96 23.71 Target-Reverse 1.109 24.82 81.26 22.37 Control-Forward 1.122 24.70 80.15 22.22 Control-Reverse 1.057 24.64 73.18 19.06 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38690</offset>
      <text> Table 9 . 9 The initial photovoltaic parameters of the control and target PSCs in the stability test.V &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38795</offset>
      <text> OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Supplementary Fig.4e Control Target 1.134 1.160 25.78 25.73 76.69 82.63 22.43 24.67 Fig.4f Control Target 1.121 1.148 25.90 25.96 77.08 83.13 22.39 24.76 Fig.4g Control Target 1.108 1.160 25.84 25.79 77.88 81.40 22.30 24.36 Fig.4h Control Target 1.134 1.160 25.77 25.86 76.49 81.62 22.30 24.50 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39129</offset>
      <text> Table 10 . 10 The parameters of α-FAPbI3 structure in DFT. a / Å b / Å c / Å Calculated value (this work) 6.396 6.304 6.376 Experimental value 32 6.362 6.362 6.362 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39299</offset>
      <text> Fabrication of perovskite solar cells in ambient air by blocking perovskite hydration with guanabenz acetate salt Luyao Yan 1,2 , Hao Huang 1,2 , Peng Cui 1,2 , Shuxian Du 1 , Zhineng Lan 1 , Yingying Yang 1 , Shujie Qu 1 , Xinxin Wang 1 , Qiang Zhang 1 , Benyu Liu 1 , Xiaopeng Yue 1 , Xing Zhao 1 , Yingfeng Li 1 , Haifang Li 1 , Jun Ji 1 &amp; Meicheng Li 1</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:06:48Z</infon>
      <node refid="22" role=""/>
      <node refid="23" role=""/>
      <node refid="26" role=""/>
      <node refid="29" role=""/>
      <node refid="28" role=""/>
      <node refid="27" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
