<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025029388HFGBAD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 37&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Regulating surface potential maximizes voltage in all-perovskite tandems&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>85</offset>
      <text>Regulating surface potential maximizes voltage in all-perovskite tandems &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>159</offset>
      <text> Reviewer Comments &amp; Author Rebuttals Reviewer Reports on the Initial Version: Referees' comments: Referee #1 (Remarks to the Author): The reduction of open circuit voltage (Voc) deficit in perovskite solar cells is a common issue for the community, especially for wide-bandgap bromine-rich perovskite solar cells. In this work, Chen et al. report a diammonium molecule, 1,3-propylene diammonium (PDA), to regulate surface potential and improve open-circuit voltage of wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells. The authors demonstrate that the PDA molecule has a much better ability for surface passivation/treatment, compared to the common monoammonium molecules. Consequently, tandem solar cells using the PDA-treated widebandgap perovskite solar cells deliver a very impressive NREL-certified efficiency with a very high Voc. Overall, the results are well discussed and solid. This work presents a highly important advance for the perovskite photovoltaic field. Therefore, I would recommend publishing this work after some revisions. Comments to the authors: 1) In Line 133, the authors claim no indication of reduced-dimensional perovskite formation nor of a perovskite polymorph. While I was wondering if the PDA cation can enter the perovskite lattices. The same or similar cation was reported to extend the unit cell and form a 3D "hollow" perovskite structure (&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1,3-propylene diammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:05:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="528" length="26"/>
        <text>, 1,3-propylene diammonium</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1,3-propylene diammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:05:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="556" length="3"/>
        <text>PDA</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1524</offset>
      <text>Parameter &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1535</offset>
      <text> Material &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1546</offset>
      <text> C60 Perovskite NiOx/SAM Thickness (nm) 30 400 50 Bandgap (eV) 2.4 1.78 3  63  Electron Affinity (eV) Various Various 2.5-2.92 (graded, logarithmic) Dielectric permittivity (relative) 2.2 24.1  64  11.9  65  Conduction band effective density of states (cm -3 ) 1E19  66  7.9E17  67  2.5E18  68  Valence band effective density of states (cm -3 ) 1E18 1E18  67  1.8E18  68  Electron mobility (cm 2 /Vs) 1E-2  16  2.2E1 69 1E-3 Hole mobility (cm  2   Total defect density (cm -3 ) -1E14 1E14 Supplementary Note 1 | Discussion of simulation parameters Thickness: Thicknesses were chosen to reflect our device architecture Bandgap: The bandgaps of C60 and NiOx were taken from UPS/IPES measurements and  63  respectively. The bandgap of perovskite (1.79 eV) was taken from EQE measurements. Electron affinity: The electron affinities of C60 and NiOx were taken from UPS measurements and  63  respectively. The electron affinity of the perovskite was determined from UPS/IPES measurements. Dielectric permittivity: The dielectric permittivity of perovskite, NiOx and C60 were taken from  [64] [65] [66]  respectively. Conduction/valence band effective density of states: The effective density of states for the conduction and valence bands (NC and NV respectively) were calculated using standard equations: 𝑁 = 2 2𝜋𝑚 * 𝑘𝑇 ℎ 𝑁 = 2 2𝜋𝑚 * 𝑘𝑇 ℎ where k is Boltzmann's constant, T is temperature and h is Planck's constant. The effective masses of electrons and holes (𝑚 * and 𝑚 * respectively) were found in the literature. For C60, the value for electrons was taken from  66  and for holes it was assumed to be the same as the absorber, an assumption used previously in  71  . For perovskite, values from  67  were used. For NiOx, values from  68  were used. Electron/hole mobilities: Mobilities for NiOx are the same as used for the HTL layers in  72  . The electron and hole mobility of C60 is taken from  16  . Mobilities for 3D perovskite are taken from  69  . Donor/acceptor densities: Our UPS results suggest that the perovskite is lightly p-type so have a low acceptor concentration of 1E15 cm -3 . The hole concentration of NiOx was taken from  70  . The electron concentration of C60 was taken to be 1E17 cm -3 similar to  22  . Bulk defects: Parameters concerning bulk defects were generated using the SCAPS standard settings which reflect real-world materials.  49  Supplementary Table  S2  | Interface parameters used for simulation in SCAPS-1D Interface defects: Parameters concerning defects were generated using the SCAPS standard settings which reflect real-world materials. The total defect density (cm -3 ) for the perovskite/ETL interface was increased from the 1E10 generated by SCAPS to 1E+14 based on  22  . For the perovskite HTL interface 1E13 was used, again using values from  72  . Editor's Comment to Author: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4415</offset>
      <text> Parameter Interfaces Perovskite We find that adding XRD to confirm whether there is a lattice change and including results of large-area solar cells will be particularly useful to improve the impact of the work. Response: In light of the Editor's feedback we now: 1) Provide XRD to ascertain whether there is a lattice change. 2) Provide results from large-area solar cells. In more detail: 1) Re: Provide XRD to ascertain whether there is a lattice change. We now provide bulk and also surface-sensitive GIWAXS of control and PDA-treated films in Figure  R2 . These reveal that while the control film peaks are broadened, there is neither a peak shift nor the formation of additional peaks at lower q-values after PDA treatment; one would have expected such a shift/additional peaks if a "hollow" perovskite structure had been formed at the surface (J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2019, 141, 21, 8627-8637, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018, 140, 17, 5728-5742). We now discuss the fact that the concentration of PDA spin-coated onto the perovskite surface is low and thus, from our data, does not appear to result in appreciable diffusion into the bulk. We have added Figure  R2  to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.  S12 ). 2) Re: Provide results from large-area solar cells. In light of the editor's feedback, we now report stabilized power output (SPO) data for a larger-area 1 cm 2 device (Figure  R1 ). The device delivered an SPO PCE of 25.1% SPO. We have added Figure  R1  to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.  S24 ), along with Supplementary Figure  S17  showing the J-V curve and stabilized power output (SPO) data for a 1 cm 2 single junction wide bandgap device. Reviewers' Comments to Author: Reviewer #1: The reduction of open circuit voltage (Voc) deficit in perovskite solar cells is a common issue for the community, especially for wide-bandgap bromine-rich perovskite solar cells. In this work, Chen et al. report a diammonium molecule, 1,3-propylene diammonium (PDA), to regulate surface potential and improve open-circuit voltage of wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells. The authors demonstrate that the PDA molecule has a much better ability for surface passivation/treatment, compared to the common monoammonium molecules. Consequently, tandem solar cells using the PDA-treated wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells deliver a very impressive NREL-certified efficiency with a very high Voc. Overall, the results are well discussed and solid. This work presents a highly important advance for the perovskite photovoltaic field. Therefore, I would recommend publishing this work after some revisions. 1) In Line 133, the authors claim no indication of reduced-dimensional perovskite formation nor of a perovskite polymorph. While I was wondering if the PDA cation can enter the perovskite lattices. The same or similar cation was reported to extend the unit cell and form a 3D "hollow" perovskite structure (ACS Energy Lett. 2018, 3, 1470-1476; Sci. Adv. 2017;3: e1701293). To confirm this, the authors can measure zoomed-in XRD patterns of the films and then check the change of the peak position and lattice parameters of the unit cell. 1) Response: We now provide bulk and also surface-sensitive GIWAXS of control and PDA-treated films in Figure  R2 . These reveal that while the control film peaks are broadened, there is neither a peak shift nor the formation of additional peaks at lower qvalues after PDA treatment; one would have expected such a shift/additional peaks if a "hollow" perovskite structure had been formed at the surface (J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2019, 141, 21, 8627-8637, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018, 140, 17, 5728-5742). We now discuss the fact that the concentration of PDA spin-coated onto the perovskite surface is low and thus, from our data, does not appear to result in appreciable diffusion into the bulk. We have added Figure  R2  to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.  S12 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8372</offset>
      <text> Figure R2. Summary of GIWAXS data. Surface sensitive a) and bulk b) GIWAXS spectra centered around the q = 1 Å -1 peak, demonstrating that though the control sample peaks are broadened, there is no overall peak shift between samples. c) Logarithmic plot demonstrating the lack of additional low q-value peaks at the surface of the treated sample. 2) It is reasonable to use a diammonium molecule rather than a monoammonium molecule. While the authors should also comment on that why use this PDA molecule not other diammonium molecules with longer or shorter chains. Response: We now compare the effects of perovskite post-treatments with similar concentrations of 1,2-ethane-diammonium iodide (EDA) and 1,4-butane-diammonium iodide (BDA), diammonium ligands with a shorter and longer chain length, respectively. We now report the PLQY of the treated films on ITO/HTL substrates with and without a C60 layer deposited onto the perovskite. Of these diammonium ligands, only PDA resulted in the retention of PLQY after the deposition of C60 (Figure  R3 ). We have added Figure  R3  to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.  S3 ) and the above discussion to the revised manuscript as shown below: "We also compared the effects of perovskite post-treatments with similar concentrations of 1,2ethane-diammonium iodide (EDA) and 1,4-butane-diammonium iodide (BDA), diammonium ligands with a shorter and longer chain length, respectively. Of these diammonium ligands, only PDA resulted in the retention of PLQY after the deposition of C60 (Supplementary Fig.  S3 )." (Lines 75-79) Figure  R3 . PLQY data from control, propane diammonium (PDA), ethane diammonium (EDA), butane diammonium (BDA), butylammonium (BA), and 3-fluoro phenethylammonium (3F-PEA) treated films with and without C60, on an ITO/HTL substrate. 3) The efficiencies of the small-area solar cells reported in this work are very impressive. However, the large-area solar cells are also recommended to be included. Response: We have added the J-V curve and stabilized power output (SPO) data for a largerarea 1 cm 2 device (Figure  R1  above). The device delivered a PCE of 26.0% (25.1% SPO). We have added Figure  R1  to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.  S24 ), along with Supplementary Figure  S17  showing the J-V curve and stabilized power output (SPO) data for a 1 cm 2 single junction wide bandgap device, which delivered a VOC of 1.35 V and PCE of 19.0%. 4) MPP tracking of single-junction wide-bandgap cells should be also provided. Response: We now provide MPP tracking under 1-sun illumination of the single-junction widebandgap cells in the revised supplementary materials (Figure  R4 , Supplementary Fig.  S21 ). The following discussion was added to the revised manuscript: "We followed the output of a PDA-treated WBG cell operating for 700 hrs at the maximum power point (MPP) to determine the impact of PDA on device stability (Supplementary Fig.  S21 ). After 700 hours of continuous operation under 1-sun illumination, the PDA-treated device exhibited no loss in PCE." (Lines 146-148) 5) I would recommend the authors change "BTA" to "BA" because the latter one is a more common abbreviation. Response: We thank the reviewer for this advice and have replaced BTA with BA in the revised manuscript. 6) In Line 92, the authors claim that BA and PDA make the surface more p-type and n-type, respectively. This description is inaccurate because both of the films are still p-type. One should be a stronger p-type and the other one should be a weaker p-type. Response: We have updated our description in the revised manuscript as follows: "To understand how both treatments affect interface energetics we used ultra-violet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) and found that BA induces a Fermi level downshift, whereas PDA induces a Fermi level upshift, resulting in stronger and weaker surface p-type doping, respectively." (Lines 80-82) 7) In Figure  S7 , the right y-axis should be QFLS. Response: We added the axis label to the figure in the revised supplementary materials (now Supplementary Fig.  S10 ). 8) Figure  S10 , the title: Positive ions are tracked in (a,b) and negative ions in (c,d). The order is reversed. Please correct it. Response: We have corrected this error (Supplementary Fig.  S5 ). 9) J-V etc. should be italic. Response: We italicized J-V, VOC, and JSC in the revised manuscript. 10) Figures in Supplementary materials should be discussed sequentially. Response: The figures in the revised supplementary materials are now discussed sequentially in the revised manuscript. 11) The manuscript is overall well written but there are still some typos. Response: We have thoroughly reviewed the manuscript to correct any remaining typos. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.35</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:34:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="10810" length="6"/>
        <text>1.35 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:34:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="10828" length="5"/>
        <text>19.0%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">700</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:34:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="11224" length="7"/>
        <text>700 hrs</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1,3-propylene diammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:35:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="11414" length="18"/>
        <text>PDA-treated device</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">100</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:13:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="11443" length="14"/>
        <text>no loss in PCE</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:50:06Z</infon>
        <node refid="3" role=""/>
        <node refid="4" role=""/>
        <node refid="5" role=""/>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13144</offset>
      <text> Reviewer #2: Chen et al. present a passivation approach, using molecule PDA for efficient treatment at the perovskite/C60 interface. The results show significantly reduced losses, benefiting from improved energy alignment at the perovskite/C60 interface. This results in much improved single-junction device performance as well as one of the highest certified PCEs for allperovskite tandem solar cell. The findings are well and clearly presented, and characterization techniques support the effectiveness of PDA layer, including statistics showing good reproducibility of the approach. The use of PDA is novel and with the benefits shown in this paper, I believe the manuscript will raise plenty of attention. There are some minor things to be considered and further clarifications to be made before the manuscript can be accepted for publication. 1) Line 57: HTL should be stated Response: We have now stated the HTL (NiOx/Me-4PACz) in the revised manuscript as follows: "We spin-coated WBG perovskite Cs0.2FA0.8Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 films atop ITO/hole transport layer (HTL) substrates with a structure of ITO/NiOx/Me-4PACz and measured their PLQY with and without a C60 layer (Fig.  1b )." (Lines 58-60) 2) Line 93-94: by how much is the band offset reduced? Response: The band offset is reduced by 60 meV. We now state this in the revised manuscript. "The latter change in the surface potential produces a lower minority carrier concentration at the interface and reduces the band offset between the perovskite and C60 by 60 meV. Driftdiffusion modelling suggests that this has the potential to increase QFLS by ~ 90 meV (Supplementary Fig.  S4 )." (Lines 82-85) 3) On page 7 (lines 116 to 140), the authors state that no reduced-dimensional perovskite formation is discovered, indicating that perovskite does not react with PDA. In what way does the PDA then improve the homogeneity of the surface and prevents the segregation? Response: XPS and GIWAXS spectra indicate that while no additional perovskite phase is formed after PDA treatment, the PDA does react with the surface of the perovskite to improve homogeneity, and it does so by removing PbI2 (Figure  R2c ). Diammonium cations have been shown to have a templating-effect on perovskite crystal growth (   2022 )). We have rewritten this discussion in the revised manuscript to include the following: "The suppression of surface phase segregation implies that while PDA does not induce the formation of a new crystal phase, it does react with the surface of the perovskite. This has been observed previously with diammoniums which template the growth of perovskite crystallization.  36, 37  " (Lines 121-124)  Response: Since the low-concentration post-treatment with PDA does not result in a peak-shift perceptible in the GIWAXS measurement, it is unlikely that the PDA molecules diffuse into the bulk perovskite. Additionally, the PDA signal in the TOF-SIMS results in Supplementary Fig.  S5d  rapidly decays, implying that PDA only resides as a very thin layer on the top surface of the perovskite. We also investigated the possibility that PDA prevents ion migration into the C60/metal electrode by comparing TOF-SIMS results for control and PDA-treated devices after annealing on a hot plate at 100 °C for 20 hours (Figure  R6 ). We found that PDA does slightly prevent ion migration, particularly the migration of Ag into the C60 and perovskite bulk. However, the effect is not significant.  Response: We accept the reviewer's advice that the spectrum of illumination for tandem stability is important. We now updated our MPP tracking data using an AM1.5G solar simulator (G2V sunbrick) for accurate current-matching under MPP conditions. We expect that the photogenerated current in this setup is equal to the EQE integrated Jsc (Figure  R6 ). The new tandem stability testing result using this setup is attached below in Figure  R8  and replaces Figure  4f  in the revised manuscript. The tandem solar cell, under AM1.5G illumination, retains 86% of its initial efficiency after 500 hours of continuous operation in ambient air at room temperature. We added the following text to the revised manuscript: "These tandems retain more than 86% of their initial PCE after 500 hrs operation." (Abstract, Lines 37-38) "We tested operating stability using MPP tracking of an encapsulated tandem in ambient air (Fig.  4f ). Under AM1.5G 1 sun illumination at the maximum power point, the device retained 86% of its initial PCE after 500 hours of continuous operation." (Lines 179-181) Response: In the revised manuscript, we now state the optimal PDA concentration used for devices (1 mg/ml). (Line 342) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17807</offset>
      <text> Reviewer Reports on the First Revision: Referees' comments: Referee #1 (Remarks to the Author): I have carefully read the revised manuscript. The authors have well addressed the reviewers' concerns. I am very satisfied with the revisions and would recommend the publication of this work in Nature as soon as possible. Congratulations on this great work！ Two final suggestions: 1) Line 441 and Figure  4a , please change SAM to Me-4PACZ, which will be easily understandable. 2) Some Figures in Supplementary Materials are not too clear and could use high-resolution images. The open-circuit voltage (V OC ) deficit in perovskite solar cells is greater in widebandgap (over 1.7 eV) cells than in perovskites of roughly 1.5 eV (refs.  1, 2  ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18552</offset>
      <text> Regulating surface potential maximizes voltage in all-perovskite tandems Hao Quasi-Fermi-level-splitting measurements show V OC -limiting recombination at the electron-transport-layer contact  [3] [4] [5]  . This, we find, stems from inhomogeneous surface potential and poor perovskite-electron transport layer energetic alignment. Common monoammonium surface treatments fail to address this; as an alternative, we introduce diammonium molecules to modify perovskite surface states and achieve a more uniform spatial distribution of surface potential. Using 1,3-propane diammonium, quasi-Fermi-level splitting increases by 90 meV, enabling 1.79 eV perovskite solar cells with a certified 1.33 V V OC and over 19% power conversion efficiency (PCE). Incorporating this layer into a monolithic all-perovskite tandem, we report a record V OC of 2.19 V (89% of the detailed balance V OC limit) and over 27% PCE (26.3% certified quasi-steady state). These tandems retained more than 86% of their initial PCE after 500 h of operation. The wide range of bandgaps achievable using metal-halide perovskites (around 1.2-3.0 eV) has enabled the development of tandem solar cells with silicon, copper indium gallium selenide and organic photovoltaics  [6] [7] [8] [9]  . Recently, all-perovskite tandems made from stacked wide-bandgap (WBG; approximately 1.8 eV) and narrow-bandgap (NBG; approximately 1.2 eV) layers surpassed the highest recorded power conversion efficiency (PCE) for a single-junction perovskite solar cell (PSC)  10, 11  . Despite rapid progress, the PCE of perovskite tandems is limited by the large open-circuit voltage (V OC ) loss of the WBG cell  1, 2  . Whereas single-junction PSCs of around 1.5 eV have demonstrated V OC deficits (the difference between the bandgap and device V OC ) as low as 0.3 V 12 , mixed iodide/bromide PSCs over 1.75 eV have yet to achieve V OC deficits lower than 0.5 V (Supplementary Fig.  1 )  13, 14  . The V OC deficit has been suggested to stem from increased trap density in perovskites with over 20% Br concentration, photoinduced halide segregation and poor energetic alignment with charge transport layers  15, 16  . The photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) of perovskites, once in contact with charge transport layers, tends to decrease markedly, suggesting that the perovskite-transport layer interface produces recombination pathways within the perovskite bandgap  [3] [4] [5]  . Several causes have been reported in efforts to uncover the origin of this phenomenon, including band misalignment  16  , energy-level pinning  5  and halide migration from the perovskite into the transport layer  17  . Here we examine the perovskite-C 60 interface because it is ubiquitous in perovskite tandems, is the most easily accessed interface when fabricating inverted (pin) PSCs and yet is still considered one of the worst offenders in regard to induction of trap states  5, 16  . We spin-coated WBG perovskite (Cs 0.2 FA 0.8 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) films on top of indium tin oxide (ITO)/hole transport layer (HTL) substrates with the structure ITO/NiOx/[4-(3,6-dimethyl-9H-carbazol-9-yl)butyl] phosphonic acid (Me-4PACz) and measured their PLQY with and without a C 60 layer (Fig.  1b ). Consistent with previous reports  3, 5  we found that, after C 60 deposition, the PLQY is two orders of magnitude lower, equivalent to a drop of about 100 meV in quasi-Fermi-level splitting (QFLS)  18  . Previous studies have focused on post treatments that reduce the defect density of the perovskite surface and thus increase the PLQY of films  [19] [20] [21] [22]  . Extending this practice to WBG perovskites, we found that treating the surface with the popular passivant butylammonium iodide (BA) increases PLQY but that the improvement was not retained following deposition of C 60 (Fig.  1b ). Indeed, the QFLS of the stack is probably pinned due to interfacial recombination rather than the inherent trap density of the perovskite  5  . Seeking a different approach, we reasoned that tuning the surface potential at the perovskite-C 60 interface would suppress this crossinterface recombination by reducing band offset between perovskite and C 60 , and by reducing the population of minority carriers at the interface. This effect is analogous to field-effect passivation in traditional Si solar cells  23, 24  . Thus, we turned our focus toward short-chain Photovoltaics Innovation and Commercialization, The University of Toledo, Toledo, OH, USA.  3  Department of Chemistry, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL, USA.  4  KAUST Solar Center, Physical Sciences and Engineering Division, King Abdullah University of Science and Technology, Thuwal, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.  5  Department of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.  6  National Renewable Energy Laboratory, Golden, CO, USA.  7  Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL, USA.  8  These authors contributed equally: Hao Chen, Aidan Maxwell, Chongwen Li, Sam Teale, Bin Chen. ✉ e-mail: yanfa.yan@utoledo.edu; ted.sargent@utoronto.ca Nature | Vol 613 | 26 January 2023 | 677 diammonium ligands, strong Lewis bases previously shown to induce n-type doping and surface dipoles that alter surface energetics in mixed Pb-Sn perovskites  [25] [26] [27]  . Treating the perovskite surface with 1,3-propane-diammonium iodide (PDA) (Fig.  1a ), the diammonium equivalent to BA, we observed only a slight increase in PLQY. However, following deposition of C 60 there was no marked drop in PLQY, suggesting that the recombination pathways induced by C 60 had been effectively suppressed. We also compared the effects of perovskite post treatments with similar concentrations of 1,2-ethane-diammonium iodide (EDA) and 1,4-butane-diammonium iodide, diammonium ligands with a shorter and longer chain length, respectively. Of these diammonium ligands, only PDA resulted in retention of PLQY after deposition of C 60 (Supplementary Fig.  3 ). To understand how both treatments affect interface energetics, we used ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) and found that BA induces a Fermi-level downshift whereas PDA induces a Fermi-level upshift, resulting in stronger and weaker surface p-type doping, respectively (Fig.  1c ). The latter change in surface potential produces a lower minority carrier concentration at the interface and reduces band offset between perovskite and C 60 by 60 meV. Drift-diffusion modelling suggests that this has the potential to increase QFLS by approximately 90 meV (Supplementary Fig.  4 ). Using time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (Supplementary Figs.  5  and 6 ), we found that PDA ligands are present on the film surface after treatment. Using density functional theory, we studied work function changes following PDA treatment of various surface structures (Supplementary Fig.  7  and Fig.  1d ). Among considered surface configurations, the pristine Pb-I-terminated surface with a bromide vacancy (V Br ), which exhibited a lower work function (by 0.44 eV) after PDA treatment (Supplementary Fig.  8 ), was in best agreement with the 0.1 eV shift obtained from experimental UPS data. Then, through density of states (DOS) analysis of BA and PDA surface treatments (Fig.  1e  and Supplementary Fig.  9 ) we found that, after PDA treatment, the in-gap surface states near the valence band maximum region were suppressed (Supplementary Materials), consistent with Fermi-level upshift relative to the valence band maximum (Fig.  1c ) observed in UPS measurements. Seeking to investigate how PDA affects films at the nanoscale, we used hyperspectral imaging to generate QFLS maps of perovskite films with and without C 60 (Fig.  2a ,b and Supplementary Fig.  10 ). From these maps we observed significantly greater spatial fluctuation than that observed for perovskites with narrower bandgaps (under 1.65 eV), which have a typical standard deviation (σ) in QFLS of around 10 meV  4, 28  . After PDA treatment, however, σ was lowered significantly (from 61 to 24 meV), suggesting that the treated film is more homogeneous. After C 60 deposition the QFLS of the control dropped (1.32 to 1.25 eV) and broadened further (σ = 77 meV), whereas that of the PDA film was maintained at 1.33 eV but with a slightly narrower distribution (σ = 22 meV). Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) (Fig.  2c, d  and Supplementary Fig.  11 ) suggested that this effect is correlated with the nonuniform contact potential of the control film, which will act to broaden interfacial electronic states when in contact with C 60 leading to increased recombination  5, 29  . PDA treatment narrowed contact potential distribution significantly (σ = 2.9 mV compared with 11.1 mV for the control), which is indicative of reduced recombination and improved carrier extraction  30, 31  . We used grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS) to show the crystallographic consequences of PDA treatment. Varying the incident angle of the X-ray beam, we compared the crystal structure of the film bulk (1.00°) and surface (0.15°) (Fig.  2e-h  and Supplementary Fig.  12 ). In contrast to previous perovskite systems treated with diammonium ligands, there exist no low-q-value peaks for the PDA-treated film and, thus, no indication of reduced-dimensional perovskite formation  32, 33  , nor of a perovskite polymorph  34  . The concentration of PDA spin-coated onto the perovskite surface is low and thus does not appear to result in appreciable diffusion into the bulk perovskite. Two structural differences between control and treated (30 devices for each type). d, Loss analysis for PCE and V OC of control and treated devices. PCE and V OC losses were extracted from pseudo-J-V measurements shown in Supplementary Fig.  18  and Supplementary Table  3 . 95% DB represents 95% of the detailed balance limit for V OC , and corresponding PCE. Nature | Vol 613 | 26 January 2023 | 679 films are apparent, however: (1) a peak at 0.88 Å -1 for the control that we ascribe to PbI 2 , which was entirely removed by PDA, and (2) a secondary peak with a q-space value of 1.03 Å -1 alongside the (1 1 0) perovskite peak (1.00 Å -1 ), indicative of a Br-rich phase. This secondary peak is more obvious when probing only the first 5 nm or so of film, suggesting that the film surface is segregated into PbI 2 -and Br-rich perovskite regions, the probable cause of the broad contact potential  35  . The suppression of surface phase segregation and removal of PbI 2 implies that, whereas PDA does not induce the formation of a new crystal phase, it does react with the surface of the perovskite. This has been observed previously with diammoniums that template the growth of perovskite crystallization  36, 37  , and is corroborated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images (Supplementary Fig.  13 ), transient absorption (Supplementary Fig.  14 ) and transient reflection spectra (Fig.  2i, j ). Transient reflection spectra show that two additional bleaches are present in the control compared with the PDA-treated sample: a peak around 500 nm (PbI 2 ) and a fast-decaying bleach at around 600 nm (approximately 85% Br-rich perovskite, which correlates exactly with the shift in q-space seen in GIWAXS)  38  . Encouraged by the reduced interfacial recombination and surface homogeneity imparted by PDA treatment, we fabricated WBG solar cells. The device structure was ITO/NiOx/Me-4PACz/perovskite/C 60 / ALD SnOx/Ag, in which Me-4PACz is a self-assembled monolayer of [4-(3,6-dimethyl-9H-carbazol-9-yl)butyl]phosphonic acid. Figure  3a  shows the forward and reverse J-V curves for champion control and PDA-treated 1.79 eV WBG PSCs (external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum shown in Supplementary Fig.  15 ), exhibiting an increase in V OC from 1.23 to 1.33 V, the highest value of V OC reported for PSCs of T 90 represents the time taken for the device efficiency to drop to 90% of its original value. The tandem device retained over 86% of initial efficiency after 500 h of operation. around 1.8 eV (Supplementary Fig.  1 ). Figure  3b  shows the J-V curve of a PDA-treated PSC exhibiting a V OC of around 1.33 V and PCE of 19.3%, as verified by the photovoltaic (PV) cell and module performance group at the National Renewable Energy Lab (NREL) (Supplementary Fig.  16 ). Improvements in device V OC , fill factor (FF) and PCE were consistent across 30 control and PDA-treated devices, as shown in Fig.  3c . We also fabricated 1 cm 2 WBG devices using PDA surface treatment, which delivered a V OC of around 1.35 V and PCE of 19.0% (Supplementary Fig.  17 ). We conducted transient photovoltage and photocurrent measurements of control and PDA-treated devices (Supplementary Fig.  19 ). The charge-recombination lifetime (τ r ) of the PDA-treated device was longer than that of the control device (2.0 µs compared to 0.4 µs), consistent with reduced carrier trapping at the C 60 interface after PDA post treatment (Supplementary Fig.  20  and Supplementary Table  4 )  39  . Calculating diffusion length (Supplementary Note 2), we found that PDA treatment resulted in a twofold increase, from 600 nm to 1.2 µm. We followed the output of a PDA-treated WBG cell operating for 700 h at the maximum power point (MPP) to determine the impact of PDA on device stability (Supplementary Fig.  21 ). After 700 h of continuous operation under 1 sun illumination, the PDA-treated device exhibited no loss in PCE. We attribute this to an increased ion migration barrier exhibited in PDA-treated films, calculated from thermal admittance spectroscopy (Supplementary Fig.  22 ). We used intensity-dependent PLQY measurements to conduct systematic loss analysis (pseudo-J-V) of control versus PDA-treated films (Fig.  3d  and Supplementary Table  3 )  40  . Both samples have similar bulk and HTL interface losses, but PDA treatment reduced V OC loss at the electron transport layer (ETL) from 104 to 16 mV. PDA also eliminated a 14 mV mismatch between the full-stack QFLS and device V OC present in the control sample, indicating a reduced band offset between perovskite and C 60 after treatment  16  , consistent with the band alignment analysis shown in Fig.  1 . In addition to reduced V OC loss, PDA-treated devices exhibited reduced transport (FF) losses compared with the control (3.4% abs. versus 8.0% abs. ) (Supplementary Table  3 ). This also suggests favourable band bending at the treated interface, resulting in improved carrier extraction. Using our high-V OC PDA-treated WBG active layer in combination with a Cs 0.05 FA 0.7 MA 0.25 Pb 0.5 Sn 0.5 I 3 NBG mixed Pb-Sn perovskite (approximately 1.2 eV), we fabricated monolithic all-perovskite tandem solar cells (Methods). The tandem device structure was ITO/ NiOx/Me-4PACz/WBG perovskite/C 60 /ALD SnOx/Au (1 nm)/poly(3, 4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate (PEDOT:PSS)/ NBG perovskite/C 60 /ALD SnOx/Ag (Fig.  4a ); the SEM cross-sectional image shows the thick Pb-Sn perovskite layer (approximate thickness 1.0 µm) needed for current matching (Fig.  4b )  10  . The integrated short-circuit current density (J SC ) values for WBG and NBG subcells from EQE measure ments of a tandem device were 15.4 and 15.2 mA cm -2 , respectively (Fig.  4c ). Bandgaps of WBG and NBG subcells calculated from the EQE spectra were 1.79 and 1.22 eV, respectively. Figure  4d  shows forward and reverse J-V scans of a champion tandem, WBG and NBG PSCs. A record PCE of 27.4% was achieved with a high V OC of 2.19 V, along with a J SC of 15.1 mA cm -2 and FF of 83.1%. The 2.19 V V OC represents a significant improvement over the previous highest reported V OC among the best all-perovskite tandems 10,41-44 because of the high V OC of the PDA-treated WBG subcell. We sent a tandem cell to an accredited independent PV calibration laboratory (NREL). The device delivered a certified PCE of 26.29% and V OC of 2.13 V (Fig.  4e  and Supplementary Fig.  23 ), representing a certified all-perovskite tandem that surpasses the record PCE (25.7%) of single-junction perovskite solar cells using the asymptotic maximum power (P max ) scan protocol  11, 45  . We also fabricated 1 cm 2 all-perovskite tandem solar cells, which delivered a PCE of 26.03% and V OC of 2.16 V (Supplementary Fig.  24 ). We note that there is still room for improvement, particularly in the J SC value of the tandem because J SC values of over 16.5 mA cm -2 have been reported  10  . Therefore, we anticipate that PCEs approaching 30% are already experimentally feasible. We tested operating stability using MPP tracking of an encapsulated tandem in ambient air (Fig.  4f ). Under global standard spectrum (AM1.5G) 1 sun illumination at MPP, the device retained 86% of its initial PCE after 500 h of continuous operation. This promising operating stability, in combination with high V OC and PCE enabled by diammonium surface modification, represents an important step towards the application of all-perovskite tandem solar cells. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2.19</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:40:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="19394" length="6"/>
        <text>2.19 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">26.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:40:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="19460" length="5"/>
        <text>26.3%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">86</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:13:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="19530" length="5"/>
        <text>86% o</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:41:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="19561" length="5"/>
        <text>500 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:50:06Z</infon>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35671</offset>
      <text> Online content Any methods, additional references, Nature Portfolio reporting summaries, source data, extended data, supplementary information, acknowledgements, peer review information; details of author contributions and competing interests; and statements of data and code availability are available at  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05541-z . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36025</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36035</offset>
      <text> Materials All materials were used as received without further purification. Commercial ITO substrates (20 Ω per square, 25 × 25 mm 2 ) were purchased from TFD, Inc. Organic halide salts (FAI, FABr, MAI, BAI) and 4-fluorophenethylammonium bromide (4F-PEABr) were purchased from GreatCell Solar Materials. PEDOT:PSS aqueous solution (no. Al 4083) was purchased from Heraeus Clevios). PbI 2 (99.99%), PbBr 2 (99.999%), CsBr (over 99.0%) and Me-4PACz were purchased from TCI Chemicals. CsI (99.999%), SnI 2 (99.99%), SnF 2 (99%), glycine hydrochloride (99%), guanidine thiocyanate (GuaSCN, 99%) and ethane-1,2-diammonium iodide (EDAI 2 , 98%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. C 60 , bathocuproine (BCP) and PDAI 2 were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. All solvents used in the process were anhydrous and purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Perovskite precursor solutions WBG perovskite. Wide-bandgap perovskite precursor solution (1.2 M, FA 0.8 Cs 0.2 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) was prepared by dissolving CsI, FAI, PbBr 2 and PbI 2 in a mixture of solvents DMF and DMSO at a volume ratio of 4:1. The precursor solution was stirred at 60 °C for 1 h and then filtered using a 0.22 µm polytetrafluoroethylene membrane before use. NBG perovskite. Narrow-bandgap perovskite precursor solution (1.8 M, Cs 0.05 FA 0.7 MA 0.25 Pb 0.5 Sn 0.5 I 3 ) was prepared by dissolving CsI, FAI, MAI, SnI 2 and PbI 2 in a mixture of DMF and DMSO at a volume ratio of 3:1. Tin powder (5 mg), GuaSCN (4 mg), SnF 2 (14 mg), 4F-PEABr (2 mg) and glycine hydrochloride (4 mg) were added to the precursor solution, which was then stirred at room temperature for 1 h. The precursor solution was filtered using a 0.22 µm polytetrafluoroethylene membrane before use. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37781</offset>
      <text> Solar cell fabrication Single junction wide bandgap perovskite solar cells. NiO x nanocrystal (10 mg ml -1 in H 2 O and 2-Propanol mixed solvent with volume ratio of 3:1) layers were first spin-coated on ITO substrates at 3,000 rpm for 25 s in air without any post-treatment, then the substrates were immediately transferred to the glovebox. The NiO x nanoparticles were prepared via the hydrolysis reaction of nickel nitrate referring to our previous work  46  . Me-4PACz (0.3 mg ml -1 ) in ethanol was spin-coated on the NiO x film at 3,000 rpm for 25 s and then annealed at 100 o C for 10 min. For the perovskite film fabrication, the substrate was spun at 4,000 rpm for 32 s with an acceleration of 1,000 rpm, 100 µL Anisole was dropped onto the substrate during the last 8 s of the spinning. The substrates were then transferred onto a hotplate and heated at 100 °C for 15 min. The organic salts surface treatment solutions were prepared by dissolving PDAI 2 , and BAI in IPA with different concentrations. The optimal concentration of PDAI 2 used in devices was 1 mg ml -1 . The surface treatment was finished by depositing 130 µl organic salts solution onto the perovskite film surface at a spin rate of 4,000 rpm for 25 seconds with a 1,000 rpm s -1 acceleration. The film was then annealed at 100 °C for 5 min. After cooling down to room temperature, the substrates were transferred to the evaporation system and a 20-nm-thick C 60 film was subsequently deposited on top by thermal evaporation at a rate of 0.2 A s -1 . The substrates were then transferred to the atomic layer deposition (ALD) system (Picosun) to deposit 20 nm SnO 2 at 90 ºC using precursors of tetrakis(dimethylamino) tin (iv) (99.9999%) and deionized water. A 140 nm Ag electrode was then deposited by thermal evaporation. Single-junction Pb-Sn perovskite solar cells. Prepatterned ITO glass substrates were sequentially cleaned using acetone and isopropanol. PEDOT:PSS was spin-coated on ITO substrates at 6,000 rpm for 30 s and annealed on a hot plate at 160 °C for 20 min in ambient air. After cooling we transferred the substrates immediately to a nitrogen-filled glovebox for deposition of perovskite films, which were deposited with a two-step spin-coating procedure: (1) 1,000 rpm for 10 s at acceleration 200 rpm s -1 and (2) 3,800 rpm for 45 s at acceleration 1,000 rpm s -1 ; 300 µl of chlorobenzene was dropped onto the spinning substrate during the second spin-coating step at 20 s before the end of the procedure. Substrates were then treated on the hot plate for 10 min at 100 °C. Post treatment with EDAI 2 was carried out by spin-coating a solution of 0.5 mg ml -1 EDAI 2 in 4:3 isopropyl alcohol (IPA)IPA:toluene at 4,000 rpm for 25 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 5 min. Next, 20 nm of C60, 8 nm of BCP and 140 nm of Ag were sequentially deposited on top of the perovskite layer by thermal evaporation  46  . All-perovskite tandem solar cells. Wide-bandgap perovskite solar cell fabrication was completed as described above until deposition of ALD SnO 2 , after which 1 nm of Au was deposited by thermal evaporation. Next, PEDOT:PSS (diluted at a 1:2 volume ratio in IPA) was spin-coated onto the WBG subcell at 4,000 rpm for 30 s and annealed at 120 °C for 10 min. Substrates were then cooled and transferred to a N 2 -filled glovebox for deposition of the NBG subcell. The NBG perovskite precursor solution was spin-coated onto substrates at 1,000 rpm for 10 s, followed by 3,800 rpm for 45 s. At 20 s before the end of the second step, 300 µl of chlorobenzene was dropped onto the substrate, which was then annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. Post treatment with EDA was carried out by spin-coating a solution of 0.5 mg ml -1 EDAI 2 in 4:3 IPA:toluene at 4,000 rpm for 25 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 5 min. Finally, C 60 (30 nm), ALD SnO 2 (20 nm) and Ag (140 nm) were sequentially deposited as described above. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41721</offset>
      <text> Device testing Current density-voltage (J-V) characteristics were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under illumination from a solar simulator (Newport, Class A) with a light intensity of 100 S5 mW cm -2 (checked with a calibrated reference solar cell from Newport). J-V curves were measured in a nitrogen atmosphere with a scanning rate of 100 mV s -1 (voltage step of 10 mV and delay time of 200 ms). The active area was determined by the aperture shade mask (0.049 cm 2 for small-area devices) placed in front of the solar cell. A spectral mismatch factor of 1.0 was used for all J-V measurements. For stabilized output measurements at MPP, the device testing chamber was maintained under ambient conditions. Solar cells were fixed at the MPP voltage (determined from J-V sweeps in both scanning directions) and current output was tracked over time. EQE measurements were performed in ambient air using a QuantX-300 Quantum Efficiency Measurement System (Newport), with monochromatic light focused on the device pixel and a chopper frequency of 20 Hz. For tandem solar cells, EQE measurements were performed in ambient air and bias illumination from bright LEDs, with emission peaks of 850 and 450 nm used for measurement of the front and back subcells, respectively. No bias voltage was applied during EQE measurement of tandem solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43077</offset>
      <text> Stability testing Devices were placed in a homemade stability-tracking station. For single-junction devices, the illumination source was a white light LED with intensity calibrated to match 1 sun conditions. For tandem solar cells, an AM1.5G solar simulator illumination source (G2V sunbrick) with an intensity of 100 mW cm -2 was used. For room temperature tests (ISOS-L-1I), the device chamber was sealed and supplied with continuous N 2 purging. MPPs were tracked by a perturb-and-observe algorithm that updates the MPP point every 10 s. Encapsulation was performed using a capping device with a glass slide, with ultraviolet-adhesive (Lumtec LT-U001) as sealant. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43746</offset>
      <text> GIWAXS GIWAXS measurements were conducted at the BXDS (LE-wiggler) beamline of the Canadian Light Source (CLS) using X-rays of wavelength λ = 0.82 Å, at a grazing incidence angle of either 0.15° or 1.00° and an exposure time of 5 s. Grazing incidence X-ray diffraction patterns were collected by a MarCCD 225 detector with a sample-detector distance of 430 mm, and are presented in q-coordinates using the equation q = 4πsinθ λ -1 , where θ is half of the diffraction angle. In the present grazing incidence X-ray diffraction data, q was calibrated by measurement of XRD from a Lanthanum hexaboride reference sample. Images were calibrated using LaB6 and processed via the Nika software package  47  and GIXSGUI MATLAB plug-in  48  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44490</offset>
      <text> Drift-diffusion simulations Simulations of perovskite solar cells were conducted in the heterojunction solar cell simulator SCAPS-1D, v.3.3.07 (ref.  49  ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44649</offset>
      <text> Transient-absorption/time-resolved spectroscopy Femtosecond laser pulses of 1,030 nm generated by a Yb:KGW laser at 5 kHz repetition rate (Pharos (Light Conversion)) were passed through an optical parametric amplifier (Orpheus (Light Conversion)) selected for 450 nm light. The beam passed through the parametric amplifier served as the pump pulse, whereas the probe pulse was generated by focusing the initial 1,030 nm pulse into a sapphire crystal, which resulted in a white light continuum (Helios (Ultrafast)). With a temporal resolution of the system of around 250 fs, each time step meant delaying the probe pulse with respect to the pump, with time steps that increased exponentially. Every other pump pulse was blocked with a chopper to determine the change in optical density. After passing through a grating spectrograph, pulses were measured by means of a charge-coupled device (Helios (Ultrafast)). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45562</offset>
      <text> Intensity-dependent PLQY measurements The excitation source was an unfocused beam of a 442 nm continuouswave diode laser. Photoluminescence was collected using an integrating sphere with a precalibrated fibre coupled to a spectrometer (Ocean Optics QE Pro) with an intensity of approximately 300 mW cm -2 . PLQY values were calculated by PLQY = P P A × S Ex , where A = 1 -P P L Ex represents absorption, P S is the integrated photon count of sample emission following laser excitation, P Ex is the integrated photon count of the excitation laser when the sample is removed from the integrating sphere and P L is the integrated photon count of the excitation laser when the sample is mounted in the integrating sphere and hit by the beam. A set of neutral-density filters were used to vary excitation density. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46375</offset>
      <text> Time-resolved photoluminescence spectroscopy Time-resolved photoluminescence measurements were performed using a Horiba Fluorolog time-correlated single-photon counting system with photomultiplier tube detectors. A pulsed laser diode (532 nm, 110-140 ps pulse width) was used as excitation source for steady-state and transient measurements. For transient measurements, a 160 ns period (0.28 nJ per pulse) was used to capture accurate carrier lifetimes. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46831</offset>
      <text> IPES and UPS For combined UPS and IPES measurements, an Excitech H Lyman-α photon source (10.2 eV) with an oxygen-filled beam path was used for excitation, coupled to a PHI 5600 ultrahigh vacuum system with a hemispherical electron energy analyser. A sample bias of -5 V and pass energy of 5.85 eV were used for UPS acquisition. IPES measurements were performed in Bremsstrahlung isochromat mode with electron kinetic energy below 5 eV and an emission current of 2 µA to minimize sample damage. A Kimball Physics ELG-2 electron gun with a BaO cathode was used to generate the electron beam, and emitted photons were collected with a bandpass photon detector that included an optical bandpass filter (280 nm for 3-fluoro-phenethylammonium (3F-PEA) and BA-treated films and 254 nm for control and phenethylammonium (PEA)-treated films) and a photomultiplier tube (R585, Hamamatsu Photonics). Samples were held at a -20 V bias during all IPES measurements and the UHV chamber was blacked out to exclude external light. Perovskite films sent for combined UPS/IPES were fabricated on ITO/NiO x /Me-4PACz substrates. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47946</offset>
      <text> Transient photovoltage and photocurrent These measurements were carried out according to ref.  50  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48049</offset>
      <text> KPFM Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) images were generated using an Asylum Cypher S atomic force microscope (Oxford Instruments) with a Ti-Ir-coated ASYELEC.01-R2 cantilever and k = 4 ± 0.5 N m -1 (Asylum Research). Scans were performed over 2 µm at 512 pixels and 0.5 Hz in a two-pass nap method, the first pass in tapping mode and the second in KPFM mode with a tip potential of 5 V and surface clearance of 5 nm. Cantilever calibration was performed using the Asylum Research GetReal database. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48555</offset>
      <text> Hyperspectral imaging Perovskite films were deposited on HTL/ITO films using the same method as for device fabrication, and the C 60 film was evaporated on top of the perovskite films to deliver a pin device stack. Absolute PL spectra of encapsulated samples were collected using a hyperspectral imaging system coupled to a microscope with 2 nm spectral resolution (Photon etc. IMA). Samples were excited from the top surface of perovskite (and C 60 layer) with a 405 nm laser at around 1 sun illumination  51  . The absolute calibration procedure of the setup is reported in detail elsewhere  52  . The collected data were analysed by home-built MatLab code using modified Würfel's generalized Plank law to acquire QFLS, ∆μ (refs.  [53] [54] [55] [56]  ): where A E θ ( , ) is the absorption probability of a photon with energy E, incident at angle θ with respect to the normal surface; k B T is the Boltzmann constant and temperature (equivalent to 25.7 meV at room temperature). Here, the θ cos factor represents emission from the sur- face following Lambert's law. Finally, fitting is applied to each data cube to construct the images with two-pixel averaging, giving a spatial resolution of about 0.6 µm per pixel. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49785</offset>
      <text> SEM High-resolution SEM images were obtained using a Hitachi S5200 microscope with an accelerating voltage of 1.5 kV. A low accelerating voltage and low beam current were deployed to reduce surface damage of perovskite films under electron beam bombardment. where S is sun-equivalent excitation intensity, J G the current density generated at 1 sun (taken from device J SC ) and J 0,rad the radiative recombination current in the dark (taken from the dark current value from Shockley-Queisser limit). Because the current density generated is proportional to excitation light intensity, an exponential current-QFLS curve is created that ideally follows the same functional dependence on voltage as the dark current-voltage curve of a diode with no series resistance. Subtracting this from a charge generation current density at 1 sun (J G ) creates a pJ-V &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50642</offset>
      <text> Pseudo-J-V curves Figure R1. 1 1 Figure R1. 1 cm 2 all-perovskite tandem device data. a) J-V curve and b) stabilized power output (SPO) for 200s of operation at the maximum power point. Inset is a picture of the 1 cm 2 tandem device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50878</offset>
      <text> Figure R4 . R4 Figure R4. 700-hour MPP tracking of PDA-treated WBG device in ambient air under 1-sun illumination. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50995</offset>
      <text> 4 ) 4 Line 148, exact bandgap could be stated Response: We now state the exact bandgap (1.79 eV, measured by device EQE) in the revised manuscript. (Line 133)We have also added FigureR5to the revised supplementary materials (Supplementary Fig.S15). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51246</offset>
      <text> Figure R5 . 5 ) R55 Figure R5. EQE curve of a PDA-treated WBG device, showing a bandgap of 1.79 eV. 5) Lines 167-168: What is the thickness of the PDA layer? Does it physically prevent ions to migrate into C60/metal electrode? &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51475</offset>
      <text> Figure R6 . R6 Figure R6. TOF-SIMS measurements of control and PDA treated devices before and after &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51577</offset>
      <text> Figure R7 . R7 Figure R7. EQE curves of the WBG and NBG subcells in the tandem device, with the summed EQE and 1-R curves superimposed. 7) How was stability testing of the tandem performed? Methods state white LED, which surely does not have a spectrum close to AM1.5 spectrum. How was the photogenerated current in both subcells determined for the stability test? &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51944</offset>
      <text> Figure R8 . 8 ) R88 Figure R8. MPP tracking of WBG and all-perovskite tandem solar cell. An AM1.5G solar simulator was used for the stability tracking of the tandem cell to ensure current matching within subcells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52160</offset>
      <text> Chen 1 , 8 , 18 Aidan Maxwell 1,8 , Chongwen Li 1,2,8 , Sam Teale 1,8 , Bin Chen 1,3,8 , Tong Zhu 1 , Esma Ugur 4 , George Harrison 4 , Luke Grater 1 , Junke Wang 1 , Zaiwei Wang 1 , Lewei Zeng 1 , So Min Park 1 , Lei Chen 2 , Peter Serles 5 , Rasha Abbas Awni 2 , Biwas Subedi 2 , Xiaopeng Zheng 6 , Chuanxiao Xiao 6 , Nikolas J. Podraza 2 , Tobin Filleter 5 , Cheng Liu 3,7 , Yi Yang 3,7 , Joseph M. Luther 6 , Stefaan De Wolf 4 , Mercouri G. Kanatzidis 3 , Yanfa Yan 2 ✉ &amp; Edward H. Sargent 1,3,7 ✉ &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52668</offset>
      <text> https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05541-z Received: 24 June 2022 Accepted: 8 November 2022 Published online: 15 November 2022 Check for updates 1 The Edward S. Rogers Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada. 2 Department of Physics and Astronomy and Wright Center for &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52998</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Analysis and strategies for the minimization of recombination between perovskite and ETL. a, Schematic crystal structure of perovskite surface treated with a PDA ligand. b, PLQY data from control, BA-and PDA-treated films, with and without C 60 , on an ITO/HTL substrate. c, Band alignment of control and BA-and PDA-treated films compared with C 60 (values from UPS/inverse photoelectron spectroscopy (IPES) measurements in Supplementary Fig. 2). Binding energy plotted with respect to vacuum level E Vac . d, Work function difference (ΔW) between an untreated and PDA-treated Pb-I-terminated surface with a bromide vacancy (V Br ), obtained by calculation of electrostatic potential difference: ΔW = ΔP = P untreated - P treated . As a result, positive and negative values for ΔW represent Fermi-level upshift and downshift, respectively. e, DOS calculated for bulk perovskite and different surface structures. Detailed DOS plots in the gap region are shown in zoomedin insets, in which the control (slab) DOS are represented by blue dashed lines. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54073</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 3 V 3 FF 40 Fig. 3 | 233403 Fig. 2 | Surface inhomogeneity and its remediation using surfaceadsorbed molecular layers. a, QFLS maps of control and PDA-treated films demonstrating increased homogeneity and resistance to C 60 -induced defects. b, Histograms of QFLS pixel values taken from larger (100 × 100 µm 2 ) images (Supplementary Fig. 10). c,d, KPFM images of control (c) and PDA-treated (d) films. e,f, GIWAXS patterns of control (e) and PDA-treated (f) films at 0.15° incident angle. g,h, Azimuthal integrations comparing surface (0.15°) and bulk (1.00°) crystal structures for control (g) and PDA-treated (h) films. i,j, Transient reflection measurements of control (i) and treated ( j) films showing the transient reflectivity change (measured in optical density) over a timescale of 8.0 ps. Films were encapsulated between two glass slides to mitigate environmental damage. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54973</offset>
      <text> 5 VFig. 4 | 54 Fig. 4 | PV performance and stability of perovskite tandem solar cells. a, Schematic diagram of tandem device structure. b, Cross-sectional SEM image of tandem device. c, EQE curves of WBG and NBG subcells within the tandem device, showing losses due to reflectance (1-R). d, J-V curves of champion NBG, WBG and all-perovskite tandem devices. e, NREL-certified J-V curve of all-perovskite tandem device (Supplementary Fig.23). f, MPP stability &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55434</offset>
      <text> Pseudo-J-V curves were plotted based on intensity-dependent PLQY measurements. First, QFLS is calculated based on PLQY values at various excitation light intensities:</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
