<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025023752EDCDIB</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 9&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>Defect Passivation of Organic-Inorganic Hybrid Perovskites by Diammonium Iodide towards High-Performance Photovoltaic Devices&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>137</offset>
      <text>All materials were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich without further purification unless stated specifically. CH 3 NH 3 I was synthesized by reacting 33 wt% CH 3 NH 2 in ethanol with 57% HI in water solution at a 2:1 molar ratio of CH 3 NH 2 to HI and 0ºC for 2h.  1  The product was collected by removing solvent through rotary evaporation, followed by diethyl ether washing until colorless and recrystallized twice in ethanol. The crystalline white powder was finally dried in a vacuum oven at 60 ºC for 24 h. NH 3 I(CH 2 ) 4 NH 3 I (C4), NH 3 I(CH 2 ) 8 NH 3 I (C8) and NH 3 I(CH 2 ) 2 O(CH 2 ) 2 O(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 I (EDBE) are synthesized and purified in a similar way except that NH 2 (CH 2 ) 4 NH 2 , NH 2 (CH 2 ) 8 NH 2 and NH 2 (CH 2 ) 2 O(CH 2 ) 2 O(CH 2 ) 2 NH 2 are mixed with HI at a 1:2.2 molar ratio in ethanol respectively. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1,8-diaminooctane diiodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-15T00:46:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="673" length="22"/>
        <text>NH 3 I(CH 2 ) 8 NH 3 I</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>972</offset>
      <text> Substrate cleaning, CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 film fabrication, and post treatment process: ITO (15 ohm/sq) glass substrates were cleaned sequentially with detergent, deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol under sonication for 10 min each. After drying under a N 2 stream,&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1239</offset>
      <text>substrates were further cleaned by a UV ozone treatment for 10 min. Cu-doped NiO x precursor were spin coated onto the cleaned ITO substrate at 3000 rpm for 60 s and annealed at 400 °C for 1 h in air. The perovskite precursor solution was made by dissolving an equimolar ratio of PbI 2 (1 M)   and CH 3 NH 3 I (1 M) into a mixed solvent of DMSO and GBL (volume ratio of 3:7) at 60°C and filtering through 0.45µm PTFE filter. Perovskite layers were formed by spin-coating the precursor solution at 1000 rpm for 15 s and 4000 rpm for 45 s sequentially. During the last 15 s of the second spin-coating step, the substrate was treated with toluene drop-casting (0.7 mL). The resulting thin films were annealed at 100 o C for 10 min. After annealing, the film was cooled down to room temperature. C4, C8 and EDBE were dissolved in IPA in a concentration of 1 mg/mL, 2 mg/mL and 2 mg/mL respectively. 20mL vials with 3mL solution in it were used for post treatment through 10s immersion. Following that the substrate was blow dried by N 2 blow gun and further immersed in a 20mL vial containing 3mL IPA for 2s washing followed by N 2 blow gun drying. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2388</offset>
      <text> 2D hybrid perovskite film fabrication The 2D hybrid perovskite precursor solution was made by dissolving an equimolar ratio of PbI 2 (0.3 M) and diammonium iodide (0.3 M) in DMF at 60°C and filtering through 0.45µm PTFE filter. Perovskite layers were formed by spin-coating the precursor solution at 3000 rpm for 60 s. The resulting thin films were annealed at 100 o C for 10 min. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2773</offset>
      <text> Device Fabrication and Characterization: ITO glass cleaning, Cu:NiOx deposition, and CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 film growth are discussed above. Atop the CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 film, PCBM (15 mg/ mL in chloroform (CF)) and C 60 -bis surfactant (2 mg/mL in IPA) were sequentially deposited by spin coating at 4k rpm for 30 s and 3k rpm for 30 s, respectively. Silver electrodes with a thickness of 150 nm were finally evaporated under vacuum (&lt;2 x 10 -6 Torr) through a shadow mask. The device area was defined as 3.14 mm 2 . All J-V curves were recorded using a Keithley 2400 source meter unit. The device photocurrent was measured upon illumination from a 450 W thermal Oriel solar simulator (AM 1.5G) calibrated with a standard Si photodiode detector equipped with a KG-5 filter, which can be traced back to the standard cell of the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3637</offset>
      <text> Characterization: X-ray diffraction (XRD) experiments were performed using a Bruker F8 Focus Powder XRD operating at 40 kV and 40 mA with a Cu K-alpha (1.54 A) X-ray source. Secondary electron images were taken with a FEI Sirion scanning electron microscope at 5 kV. Time-resolved PL decay traces were acquired by a time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) system (FluoTime 100, PicoQuant GmbH). Samples were photoexcited using a 467 nm laser beam (LDH-P-C-470, PicoQuant GmbH) pulsed at frequencies between 0.5-10MHz, with a pulse duration of 60 ps and fluence of ∼10 nJ/cm 2 . Perovskite films for PL studies were prepared on glass to highlight the intrinsic PL behavior before and after C8 treatment. The lifetime was obtained by fitting the PL measured from perovskite films with a bi-exponential decay function of the form:    O rganometal trihalide perovskites (OTPs) have under- gone a rapid development as promising photovoltaic materials with power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) increasing from 3.8% to 22% within just a few years.  [1] [2] [3] [4]  Besides high absorption coefficient, ambipolar charge transport, high charge carrier mobility, and long electron-hole diffusion lengths,  [5] [6] [7] [8] [9]  OTPs' compatibility with simple low-temperature solution processes provides great promise for future commercialization.  10  However, a consequence of solution processing is the polycrystallinity of prepared thin films, which results in substantial structural disorder and crystallographic defects.  11, 12  Several reports have identified the prevalence of vacancy and interstitial defects in OTP thin films due to their low formation energies.  [13] [14] [15] [16]  In principle, these defects incur trap-assisted nonradiative recombination losses and thus deteriorate the resulting photovoltaic performance. In addition, vacancy defects provide a pathway for ion migration, which adversely affects the charge collection and results in current-voltage hysteresis.  [17] [18] [19] [20]  Therefore, effective mitigation of defects in the solution-processed perovskite films is an important research subject to further enhance the performance of perovskite solar cells (PVSCs) toward their thermodynamic limits. Iሺtሻ = ‫ܣ‬ ଵ exp ൬- ‫ݐ‬ ߬1 ൰ + ‫ܣ‬ ଶ exp ሺ- ‫ݐ‬ ߬2 ሻ In an ionic crystal like OTP, dangling bonds at the surface and grain boundaries (GBs) introduce trap states and nonradiative recombination centers. The polycrystalline nature of solutionprocessed OTP films further aggravates this issue because of increased GB density and structural disorder, in contrast to a single-crystalline perovskite that shows an extremely long electron-hole diffusion length of 175 μm.  21  Several studies have indicated that surface defects and GBs can serve as photoluminescence (PL) quenching sites and thus result in loss of photogenerated carriers.  [22] [23] [24] [25]  Additionally, it has also been reported that ion migration becomes more pronounced in a polycrystalline material, due to higher diffusivity of ions across extended defects like GBs.  26  Thus, it is critical to develop effective methods that can passivate the defects at the film surface and GBs in OTPs. Recently, several approaches have been reported to be able to passivate the surface/interfaces and GBs of solution-processed OTP films. For example, PbI 2 preferably formed at GBs through high-temperature annealing creates a type I band alignment at GBs, resulting in defect passivation and retardation of carrier recombination.  [27] [28] [29]  Meanwhile, small molecules have also been employed to passivate dangling bonds in OTPs by exploiting the  associated intermolecular interaction.  [30] [31] [32]  Lately, we and several groups have discovered that the commonly used fullerene-based electron-transporting layers (ETLs) can also passivate surface trap states and GB defects in OTPs to eliminate trap states and suppress device hysteresis.  [33] [34] [35]  However, the role of fullerene in eliminating the dominant vacancy defects is limited. We and several groups have found that iodide in perovskites has the propensity to dope fullerene at the perovskite/fullerene interface.  33, 36, 37  In this case, iodo radicals would be inevitably generated after doping and then form iodine that can potentially sublime easily. As a result, new V I defects can possibly be generated inside the perovskite film. Thus, for fullerene-based inverted PVSCs, it would be ideal if the perovskite surface and GBs can be passivated without generating new defects due to perovskite fullerene interaction. In this study, a series of diammonium iodides, namely, C4, C8, and EDBE, were explored to passivate perovskite surface and GBs considering their bilateral ammonium iodide end can simultaneously passivatethe perovskite layer and dope the adjacent electron-transporting layer (PCBM herein) in derived PVSCs, as illustrated in Figure  1 . In pursuing the suitable materials for defect passivation, we surprisingly discovered that the molecular structure of diammonium iodide plays a critical role in affecting perovskite's surface morphology and phase purity. We found that both C4 and EDBE can induce three-dimensional (3D) to twodimensional (2D) perovskite phase transformation during post treatment. However, the activation energy for such transition can be modulated by tailoring the molecular structure of the diammonium iodides. The C8 can successfully passivate perovskite surface and GBs without causing 2D phase transformation of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 because of its unique anti-gauche isomerization, which may elevate the activation energy for the 3D-to-2D phase transformation. Consequently, the thin-film PVSC passivated by C8 shows a much improved power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 17.60% compared to 14.64% for the control device. Diammonium Iodides for Perovskite Passivation. To effectively passivate the above-mentioned defects, three diammounium iodides with different molecular structures, C4, C8, and EDBE (Figure  2a ), were selected because their bilateral ammonium iodide group is capable of simultaneously passivating perovskite surface/GBs and inducing PCBM doping without consuming iodides from bulk perovskite (Figure  1 ). We first try to investigate the effect of alkyl chain length on electron transfer from perovskite to PCBM by comparing C4 and C8. The EDBE is included in our exploration to study whether the hydrogen bonding between adjacent EDBE molecules  38  will influence the self-assembly kinetics between the organic species and perovskite for better passivation effects. The post-treatment procedure is illustrated in Figure  2a  and detailed in the Supporting Information. It is important to note that similar surface topology and bulk properties such as crystallinity and absorption coefficient of perovskite films should be retained if the diammonium iodide distributes only at the perovskite surface or in the GBs. To examine this, the evolution of surface morphology of post-treatment perovskite films is investigated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) (Figure  2b ). As clearly shown, only the C8-treated film showed surface morphology similar to that of the pristine film, which encompasses a compact and uniform film with grain sizes ranging from tens of nanometers to around 200 nm. However, the C4-and EDBE-treated films showed distinct morphology with striplike and branchlike features, respectively. The enormous change in surface morphology of C4-and EDBE-treated films prompt us to speculate the possibility of 3D-to-2D perovskite phase transformation due to the tendency of large-sized diammonium iodides to form 2D hybrid perovskites,  38, 39  which induce the morphological changes through dissolution-recrystallization.  40  To probe this, X-ray diffraction (XRD) and ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption of posttreated films were measured to study if the relatively larger organic cations diffuse into the pristine perovskite film and partially convert the perovskite from 3D to 2D. As clearly evidenced from the XRD data shown in Figure  2c , the characteristic diffraction corresponding to {200} planes of (C4)PbI 4 and (020) plane of (EDBE)PbI 4 are apparent in the C4-and EDBE-treated films, respectively. In addition, their corresponding UV-vis absorption spectra (Figure  2d ) clearly show the excitonic absorption peak, affirming the formation of 2D perovskite due to the intercalation of C4 and EDBE cations into the perovskite films. However, the C8-treated film seems to uniquely preserve its morphology and phase purity without going through such transition (Figure  2b-d ). The 3D-to-2D perovskite phase transformation induced by C4 and EDBE cations can be explained by the tendency of forming more thermodynamically stable 2D hybrid perovskite.  [41] [42] [43] [44]  The reaction rate for such 3D-to-2D phase transformation is in principle determined by its associated activation energy. Therefore, the inhibited phase transformation observed in C8-treated films might be due to two possible reasons: (i) The phase transformation from 3D MAPbI 3 to 2D (C8)PbI 4 occurs too slowly to be effectively observed during the fast 10 s treatment period. (ii) The (C8)PbI 4 in nature has a higher Gibbs free energy than MAPbI 3 . The distinction in morphological variation between C4/ EDBE-and C8-treated films further triggered us to ponder the structural difference of their corresponding 2D perovskites. Interestingly, Lemmerer and Billing 39 found that, among all of their studied 2D lead-halide-based perovskites incorporating diammonium cations, C8 is the only material that has gauche conformation in the middle of the alkyl chain while other diammomium cations consist of only the anti conformation. This gauche conformation has higher energy compared to the anti conformation, and the associated local energy minimum is metastable. Thus, it can be inferred that the middle part of the C8 diammonium cation needs to convert from its energetically stable anti form into the gauche conformation to intercalate into the 2D perovskite film. Such anti-gauche isomerization necessitates additional energy barrier for 3D-to-2D phase transformation, thereby slowing the conversion. To prove this hypothesis, the 2D hybrid perovskite (n = 1) thin films based on C4, C8, and EDBE were prepared accordingly by a simple spin-coating procedure (Supporting Information). As shown in Figure  3a , both spin-coated C4 and EDBE films convert immediately into a yellow color after being placed onto the preheated (100 °C) hot plate, whereas the C8 film remains clear after being annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. As previously reported by Lemmerer and Billing,  39  the single crystal of C8-PbI 4 possesses a yellow color as well, which is typical for lead-iodide-based 2D hybrid perovskites. Therefore, we can conclude that the elevated activation energy for forming the corresponding 2D C8-PbI 4 perovskite phase is the reason for forming the clear intermediate state (Figure  3c ; will be discussed later). Interestingly, it was discovered that exposing the C8 films in air facilitates the 2D phase transformation. As shown in Figure  3b , the C8 film turns into a yellow color after being stored in air overnight. Its corresponding XRD and UV-vis absorption results are presented in Figure  S1 , where the yellow phase is clearly identified to be the 2D C8-PbI 4 . However, the C8 film remains in the clear state even after being stored in N 2 for a week. This result suggests that moisture or/and oxygen play a critical role in lowering the activation energy for this phase transformation, and the exact mechanism is still under investigation. Because the 2D C8-PbI 4 film can be eventually formed (Figure  3b ) and is quite stable in air, we hypothesize that although anti-gauche isomerization may also raise the 2D C8-PbI 4 phase's Gibbs free energy, it still lower than that of the 3D MAPbI 3 phase. Hence, the change in Gibbs free energy should play a less important role than the elevation of activation energy in mediating 3D-to-2D perovskite phase transformation in C8 post treatment. A scheme showing the reaction mechanism of the studied diammonium salts is illustrated in Figure  3c . Our results reveal that owing to the higher thermodynamic stability of 2D perovskites, most organic salts with larger cations used for perovskite passivation will induce fast 3D-to-2D phase transformation (within 10 s) due to the low activation energy of this process. However, the extra anti-gauche isomerization energy for C8 slows the self-assembling process and thus limits itself to be distributed only at the perovskite surface and GBs. Defect Passivation Characterization. After elucidating that only C8 can successfully interact with pristine perovskite without affecting its bulk properties, we next examined its efficacy in defect passivation. Scanning Kelvin probe microscopy (SKPM)  45, 46  is employed to investigate the perovskite films before and after C8 treatment. Figure  4A  illustrates the topography (left column) and surface potential (SP) (right column) images of the perovskite films before (top row) and after (bottom row) treatment. The root-mean-square (RMS) roughness of perovskite films before and after treatment are 7.99 and 5.99 nm, respectively. As can be clearly seen, both films showed similar morphology, affirming no surface reconstruction of perovskite film after C8 treatment, which is consistent with the SEM image shown in Figure  2b . Notably, the small decrease in surface roughness of the treated film indicates that C8 did fill in the GBs and thus reduces the height difference between the grain surface and GB. Despite the similarity in surface morphology, the two films showed distinctly different SP. For the control film without treatment, most GBs showed SP higher than that of the interior grains, indicating a downward band-bending in the GBs which will cause electron trapping.  25, 27  However, the SP difference between GBs and interior grains is significantly reduced after treatment, indicating negligible band bending at this corresponding interface. This will facilitate electron transport across the GBs. It clearly validates effective perovskite passivation. In addition, the average SP of the treated film (-0.10 V) shows an increase of 0.24 V compared to that of pristine film (-0.34 V). This suggests a larger downward surface band-bending of the treated film, which can benefit charge carrier separation and facilitate the electron collection toward ETL in derived devices.  47  Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) has also been utilized to further examine the effects of defect passivation on resulting photophysical properties, as shown in Figure  4B . The average lifetime of perovskite film increased from 24 to 40 ns after C8-treatment with both improved fast and slow component, revealing the suppressed charge recombination in the treated film. The fitting and detailed parameters are summarized in Table  S1 .  &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1,8-diaminooctane diiodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-15T00:46:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="8291" length="2"/>
        <text>C8</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PCBM</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:12:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="8507" length="4"/>
        <text>PCBM</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:31:20Z</infon>
        <location offset="9168" length="15"/>
        <text>CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:10:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="9421" length="5"/>
        <text>17.60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">14.64</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:09:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="9440" length="5"/>
        <text>14.64</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PCBM</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:12:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="9804" length="4"/>
        <text>PCBM</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PCBM</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:13:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="9978" length="4"/>
        <text>PCBM</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18715</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic Performance Characterization and Recombination Kinetics Study. To examine how C8-passivation affects photovoltaic properties, planar heterojunction structure (PHJ) devices were fabricated in the configuration shown in Figure  5a . The detailed fabrication procedure is described in the Supporting Information, and the statistical device performance with standard deviation for control and C8-, C4-, and EDBE-treated devices is shown in Table  S2 . As expected, the PCE of the derived PVSC is significantly improved from 14.64% to 17.60% after C8-treatment (Figure  5b ) with a marked increase in all photovoltaic parameters (Table  S2 ). The steady-state current output of both devices is shown in Figure  S2 , and it matches well with our measured PCEs. Different from the C8-treated device, the C4-and EDBE-treated PVSCs showed inferior PCEs with a much lower short-circuit current (J SC ) and fill factor (FF). This can be attributed to the formation of bulk 2D perovskite, in which the intercalated insulating alkyl chains block electron transfer from perovskite to PCBM and thus impede efficient charge collection. To better understand the charge carrier dynamics and enhanced performance, we have studied the device recombination kinetics by measuring the dependence of J-V characteristics on light intensity.  48  Figure  5c  shows the dependence of J SC on light intensity of the studied devices, in which the fitted slope (in accordance to power law) is 0.918 and 0.944 for the control device and C8-treated device, respectively. This result clearly indicates that the reduced charge recombination loss for the C8-treated device is due to effective defect passivation. Figure  5d  shows the relationship between open-circuit voltage (V OC ) and light intensity of the studied devices. Notably, the control device possesses a slope of 1.186 kT/q throughout the entire range of light intensity, showing a bimolecular recombination dominant kinetics. This supports the respectable high PCE of the control device. Neverthelessly, the C8-treated PVSC showed a further reduced slope of 1.006 kT/q, suggesting a minimized trapassisted recombination in the device. In addition to the effective defect passivation, this significantly reduced recombination loss can also be attributed to the interfacial doping at the C8/PCBM interface.  33, 34, 49  The other end of C8 ammonium iodide can dope PCBM without the need of creating further V I defects inside the perovskite film, leading to a much improved device performance. In summary, we have successfully developed a simple and effective method to passivate the surface and GB defects of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 films by employing alkyl diammonium iodide. It was discovered that the molecular structure of used diammonium salt has a profound effect on influencing the surface morphology and phase purity of perovskite. Both C4-and EDBEdiammonium salts induce 3D-to-2D hybrid perovskite phase transformation during treatment, which is unfavorable for charge transport and device performance because of their insulating nature. However, the 3D-to-2D transition is inhibited in C8treated films because of its unique anti-gauche isomerization, which elevates the activation energy of this transition. Therefore, the C8 diammonium iodide treatment can successfully passivate perovskite films as evidenced by the SKPM and TRPL measurements. Further investigations on device recombination kinetics also showed reduced charge recombination loss in the derived device, indicating that the C8 salt can also potentially dope PCBM. As a result, the C8-treated PVSC shows a muchimproved PCE of 17.60% compared to that of the control device (PCE of 14.64%). This study highlights the importance of rational molecular design for perovskite surface modification and passivation. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">14.64</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:09:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="19249" length="5"/>
        <text>14.64</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.6</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T13:10:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="19259" length="5"/>
        <text>17.60</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22536</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22561</offset>
      <text> * S Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge on the ACS Publications website at DOI: 10.1021/acsenergylett.6b00327. Experimental section and additional figures and tables (PDF) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22777</offset>
      <text> ■ AUTHOR INFORMATION Corresponding Author *E-mail: ajen@u.washington.edu. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22855</offset>
      <text> Notes The authors declare no competing financial interest. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22916</offset>
      <text> ■ ACKNOWLEDGMENTS This work was supported by the National Science Foundation (DMR-1608279), the Office of Naval Research (N00014-  Figure S1 : S1 Figure S1: a): UV and b)XRD characterization for clear and yellow C8-PbI 4 thin films. The clear film is obtained right after the annealing process as illustrated in 2D hybrid perovskite thin film fabrication and the yellow film here is obtained by exposing the same clear film to air under dark for overnight. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23377</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 : S2 Figure S2: Steady-state current measured and stabilized power output for a): control film at a maximum power point (0.91 V) and b): C8 treated film at a maximum power point (0.93 V). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23577</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Summary scheme for (left panel) possible defects existing in MAPbI 3 thin films with PCBM on top as electron transport layer and (right panel) defects passivation mechanism after introducing diammonium iodide through post treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23835</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. (a) Three kinds of diammonium iodide salts (abbreviated C4, C8, and EDBE) selected for perovskite passivation and the processing details. (b) SEM images where the scale bar corresponds to 1 μm. (c) XRD and (d) UV-absorption of control film (MAPbI 3 ) and C8-, C4-, and EDBE-treated films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24150</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. (a) Photos of C4-, C8-, and EDBE-PbI 4 thin films after the spin-coating and annealing process as illustrated in the Supporting Information. (b) Photo of C8-PbI 4 thin film transferring from clear state to yellow state after being put in air overnight. (c) Schematic demonstration of why EDBE and C4 treatment can induce respective 2D hybrid perovskite formation, while C8 stays only at the surface or grain boundaries without affecting bulk properties. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24629</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (A) 2D topology (a, c) and surface potential maps (b, d) for control and C8-treated perovskite films. (B) PL decay for control and C8-treated films on glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24812</offset>
      <text> Figure 5 . 5 Figure 5. (a) Device architecture used in this study. (b) J-V characteristics of control and C8-treated devices. Dependence of (c) J SC and (d) V OC on light intensity. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24996</offset>
      <text> Table S1 : S1 Fitted lifetime results of control and C8 treated films, where t1 and t2 refer to fast and slow decay lifetime respectively, and t average is intensity weighted. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25174</offset>
      <text> Table S2 : S2 Photovoltaic performance values of the control, C8, C4 and EDBE treated devices. The results include average values with deviation are calculated from 8 representative devices. The values shown in parenthesis in control and C8 treated devices correspond to the J-V characteristics in Figure 5b. t1(ns) t2(ns) t average (ns) Control 7 29 24 C8 treated 9 50 40 Voc (V) Jsc (mA/cm 2 ) FF PCE (%) Control 1.09±0.01 (1.08) 17.89±0.40 (18.18) 0.75±0.02 (0.74) 14.70±0.22 (14.64) C8 treated 1.11±0.01 (1.10) 19.37±0.55 (20.01) 0.79±0.01 (0.80) 17.02±0.33 (17.60) C4 treated 1.10±0.01 12.10±2.38 0.72±0.04 9.75±2.22 EDBE treated 1.12±0.04 3.69±0.64 0.69±0.02 2.84±0.60 (1) Kim, H.-S.; Lee, C.-R.; Im, J.-H.; Lee, K.-B.; Moehl, T.; Marchioro, A.; Moon, S.-J.; Humphry-Baker, R.; Yum, J.-H.; Moser, J. E.; et al. Lead Iodide Perovskite Sensitized All-Solid-State Submicron Thin Film Mesoscopic Solar Cell with Efficiency Exceeding 9%. Sci. Rep. 2012, 2, 591. (2) Kim, J. H.; Liang, P. W.; Williams, S. T.; Cho, N.; Chueh, C. C.; Glaz, M. S.; Ginger, D. S.; Jen, A. K. Y. High-Performance and Environmentally Stable Planar Heterojunction Perovskite Solar Cells Based on a Solution-Processed Copper-Doped Nickel Oxide Hole- Transporting Layer. Adv. Mater. 2015, 27, 695-701. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26469</offset>
      <text> 14-1-0246), the Asian Office of Aerospace R&amp;D (FA2386-15-1-4106), and the Department of Energy SunShot (DE-EE 0006710). Q.C. acknowledges Collaborative Academic Training Program for Postdoctoral Fellows support from Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology. A.K.-Y.J. thanks the Boeing-Johnson Foundation for financial support. This work was made possible by the Molecular Analysis Facility at the University of Washington. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26924</offset>
      <text>			 http://pubs.acs.org/journal/aelccp © 2016 American Chemical Society &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26998</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN on November 8, 2024 at 06:36:26 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27183</offset>
      <text>			 DOI: 10.1021/acsenergylett.6b00327 ACS Energy Lett. 2016, 1, 757-763</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
