<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025031259DEHHHB</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 47&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication Patterned ITO glass substrates were first cleaned by ultrasonication with soap, acetone and isopropanol. The hole transport layer poly(bis(4-phenyl)(2,4,6trimethylphenyl)amine) (PTAA) with a concentration of 2 mg ml -1 dissolved in toluene was spin-coated at the speed of 4,000 rpm for 35 s and then annealed at 100 o C for 10 min. Before depositing perovskite films, the PTAA film was pre-wetted by spinning 80 µl DMF at 4,000 rpm for 15 s to improve the wetting property of the perovskite precursor solution. The perovskite precursor solution composed of mixed cations (lead (Pb), cesium(Cs), formamidinium (FA) and methylammonium (MA)) and halides (I, Br) was dissolved in mixed solvent (DMF/DMSO = 4:1) with a chemical formula of Cs0.05FA0.81MA0.14PbI2.55Br0.45. Then 80 µl precursor solution was spun onto PTAA at 2,000 rpm for 2 s and 4,000 rpm for 20 s, and the film was quickly washed with 130 µl toluene at 18 s during spin-coating. Subsequently, the sample was annealed at 65 o C for 10 min and 100 o C for 10 min. The ammonium sulfate solution was prepared by dissolving methylamine (Sigma-Aldrich, 33 wt. % in ethanol) or octylamine ((Sigma-Aldrich, 99 %) and sulfuric solution (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.999%) in mixed solvents (toluene/isopropanol = 5:1) with the concentration of 4 mM. The sulfate precursor solutions at different concentrations were prepared by serial dilution method. Specifically, the amines and sulfuric solution were firstly diluted twice to a low concentration by the mixed solvents. Then, the diluted amine and sulfuric solution were mixed with certain amount of solvents to a desired concertation. To treat the surface of perovskite films, 100 µl of precursor solution was loaded on the film for 20 s and was then spun at 6,000 rpm for 30 s. During spin-coating process, extra 130 µl of toluene was dropped to wash the unreacted precursors. The devices were finished by thermally evaporating C60 (30 nm), BCP (8 nm) and copper (140 nm) in sequential order. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PTAA</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:03:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="185" length="46"/>
        <text>poly(bis(4-phenyl)(2,4,6trimethylphenyl)amine)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PTAA</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:02:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="233" length="4"/>
        <text>PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs0.05FA0.81MA0.14PbI2.55Br0.45</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:48:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="789" length="31"/>
        <text>Cs0.05FA0.81MA0.14PbI2.55Br0.45</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2050</offset>
      <text> Encapsulation A thin layer of CYTOP was firstly coated onto the back surface of device by blade coating, followed by annealing at 75 o C for 45 min on a hot plate. Then, a cover glass was attached onto the back surface for further protection by epoxy resin. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2310</offset>
      <text> Surface treatment of single crystals MAPbI3 single crystals were treated by dipping in 4 mM octylammonium sulfate solution, followed by washing with toluene. The dipping time is 5 min and 20 s for the water resistant and temperature-dependent conductivity tests, respectively. The sample was then thermal annealed for 10 min in an oven at 100 °C. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:22:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="2348" length="6"/>
        <text>MAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2660</offset>
      <text> Structure characterization Crystallographic information for the as-synthesized crystals was obtained by a Rigaku D/Max-B X-ray diffractometer with Bragg-Brentano parafocusing geometry, a diffracted beam monochromator, and a conventional cobalt target X-ray tube set to 40 kV and 30 mA. Cross-section FIB sample lamellae was prepared on a FEI Quanta 3D FEG instrument, and a low beam current was applied to minimize ion beam damage to the devices. The FIB lamellae were targeted with a final thickness of about 100 nm but this&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3187</offset>
      <text>may vary locally. Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and scanning TEM were performed on a FEI Talos F200X analytical scanning transmission electron microscope operating at 200 kV, and a low electron dose was applied to minimize the electron beam damage. The X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) was measured (SPECS XR-MF) by using a monochromatized Al source (hv=1486.6 eV). The Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR) spectra of perovskite powder were collected in the transmittance mode on the PerkinElmer IR spectrometer instrument in the 400 -4,000 cm -1 region. The morphology and structure of the samples were characterized by Quanta 200 FEG environmental scanning electron microscope. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3881</offset>
      <text> Optical characterization Optical absorption spectra were measured by means of an Evolution 201/220 UV/visible Spectrophotometer. Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) was performed on the perovskite films grown on varied substrates by a Horiba DeltaPro fluorescence lifetime system, which equipped with a DeltaDiode (DD-405) pulse laser diode with wavelength of 404 nm. The laser excitation energy in the measurement was 20 pJ pulse -1 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4322</offset>
      <text> Ion migration studies Activation energy for ion migration was tested using lateral devices by a Keithley 2400 source meter at different temperatures. The electric field of the lateral device was 0.4 V/μm. The device was set in a Lakeshore Probe Station to obtain desired temperature. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4609</offset>
      <text> Device characterizations The J-V analysis of solar cells was performed using a solar light simulator (Oriel 67005, 150 W Solar Simulator) and the power of the simulated light was calibrated to 100 mW cm -2 by a silicon (Si) diode (Hamamatsu S1133) equipped with a Schott visiblecolor glass filter (KG5 color-filter). All cells were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter with scan rate of 0.1 V s -1 . The steady-state PCE was measured by monitoring current with the largest power output bias voltage and recording the value of the photocurrent. External quantum efficiency curves were characterized with a Newport QE measurement kit by focusing a monochromatic beam of light onto the devices. The tDOS of solar cells were derived from the frequency-dependent capacitance (C-f) and voltagedependent capacitance (C-V), which were obtained from the thermal admittance spectroscopy (TAS) measurement performed by an LCR meter (Agilent E4980A). The transient photovoltage was measured under 1 sun illumination. An attenuated UV laser pulse (SRS NL 100 Nitrogen Laser) was used as a small perturbation to the background illumination on the device. The laser-pulse-induced photovoltage variation and the VOC is produced by the background illumination. The wavelength of the N2 laser was 337 nm, the repeating frequency was about 10 Hz, and the pulse width was less than 3.5 ns. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5988</offset>
      <text> Device operational stability tests Long-term stability measurements of encapsulated perovskite devices were operated under a plasma lamp with light intensity equivalent to AM 1.5G (Fig.  S9 ), without ultraviolet filter in air (relative humidity ∼60±10 %). The temperature of the devices under illumination was measured to be ~65 °C. All devices were loaded with a resistance so that they worked at maximum power point (MPP) at the beginning of the tests. Since the sulfate-treated device is rather stable during the whole test, the voltage shift of MPP is expected to be small. The J-V curves were automatically recorded with reverse scan rate of 0.1 V s -1 every six hours. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:19:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="6114" length="54"/>
        <text>plasma lamp with light intensity equivalent to AM 1.5G</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">60+-10</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:48:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="6236" length="8"/>
        <text>60±10 %)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:20:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="6315" length="6"/>
        <text>~65 °C</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6670</offset>
      <text> CPMD computational details To simulate the perovskite surfaces, we have properly cut 2 × 2 × 3 slabs from the bulk tetragonal MAPbI3 crystal structure, which expose MAI-terminated surface. The employed periodic cell dimension are a = b = 17.71 Å, corresponding to twice the tetragonal experimental a = b cell parameters. A layer of 8 PbSO4 units was deposit on the MAI-terminated perovskite slab and a Car-Parrinello molecular dynamics (32) (CPMD) simulations have been carried out. The 2 × 2 × 1 (a = 13.918, b = 16.964 Å) PbSO4 layer was generated by cutting the Anglesite experimental bulk structure (a = 6.959, b = 8.482, c = 5.398 Å). We use this slab dimension to have 8 PbSO4 units corresponding to the 8 iodide undercoordinated atoms of the surface. By doing so we have a lattice matching of 127% a and 104%, calculated as a percentage ratio between the perovskite slab and the PbSO4 slab employed. Along the c direction, a 10.0 Å of vacuum has been added for the slab calculation. Quantum Espresso package  (33)  along with the GGA-PBE functional was used. Electronion interactions were described by scalar relativistic ultrasoft pseudopotentials with electrons from O, N and C 2s, 2p; H 1s; S 3s, 3p; I 5s, 5p; Pb 6s, 6p, 5d shells explicitly included in the calculations. Plane-wave basis set cutoffs for the smooth part of the wave functions and the augmented density were 25 and 200 Ry, respectively. CPMD simulations have been performed with an integration time step of 10 au, for a total simulation time of ca. 10 ps. The fictitious mass used for the electronic degrees of freedom is 1000 au, and we set the atomic masses to an identical value of 5 amu to enhance the dynamical sampling. Initial ions position randomization has been used to reach temperature in the range of 350-400K, without further applying any thermostat. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8521</offset>
      <text> Geometry optimizations of slabs We also simulate the MAI-and PbI2-terminated interface for a full coverage of PbSO4 layers (12 units). The MAI-terminated perovskite surface is the same adopted for the CPMD simulation as specified above while the PbI2-terminate is a 2 × 2 × 5 slab. On these slabs, we deposited a single layer of 12 PbSO4 units. The 3 × 2 × 1 PbSO4 layer was generated by cutting the Anglesite experimental bulk structure. In this case, we adopt the full coverage to evaluate the energetics of the interface formation with a lattice matching of 85 % along a and 104 % along b. On these systems, we performed geometry optimization using GGA-PBE functional. Electron-ion interactions were described by scalar relativistic ultrasoft pseudopotentials with electrons from O, N and C 2s, 2p; H 1s; S 3s, 3p; I 5s, 5p; Pb 6s, 6p, 5d shells explicitly included in the calculations. Plane-wave basis set cutoffs for the smooth part of the wave functions and the augmented density were 25 and 200 Ry, respectively. Formation energy (ΔEform) has been calculated as follows, see Table  S1 : ΔEform = E(MAPbI3-nPbSO4) -E(MAPbI3) -E(nPbSO4) Where E(MAPbI3-nPbSO4) is the energy of the interface with n PbSO4 units, E(MAPbI3) is the energy of the isolated perovskite slab and E(nPbSO4) is the energy of the optimized 1 × 1 × 1 PbSO4 bulk calculated at the same level of theory starting from the experimental structure and using a k-point sampling grid of 2 × 2 × 2; n represents the number of PbSO4 units involved. In Table  S1  we reported also the ΔEform per molec calculated as ΔEform/n and the ΔEform per molec referred to energy of the isolated PbSO4 molecules. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10204</offset>
      <text> Model for Radial Distribution Function (RDF) analysis To evaluate the RDF of the PbSO4 when interacting with perovskite surface we set up a bulk model involving 2 × 2 × 5 PbI2-terminated perovskite bulk interacting with a 3 × 2 × 7 PbSO4 bulk, see Fig.  S6 . The 3 × 2 × 7 PbSO4 layer was generated from the Anglesite experimental bulk structure. In this case, we adopt the full coverage to evaluate the energetics of the interface formation with a lattice matching of 85% along a and 104% along b. The a and b cell parameters are 17.7112 Å while the c dimension was set as sum of the encumbrance of the separated parts (51 Å). The interface has been optimized using CP2K program, using PBE functional, DZVP basis set, DFT-D3 dispersion interactions and a cutoff of 300 Ry.               S4 . Photovoltaic parameters of the phosphate-treated device with different sweeping rates and directions. All the J-V curves were at a simulated AM 1.5 G solar irradiation with a scan rate of 0.  We show that converting the surfaces of lead halide perovskite to water-insoluble lead (II) oxysalt through reaction with sulfate or phosphate ions can effectively stabilize the perovskite surface and bulk material. These capping lead oxysalt thin layers enhance the water resistance of the perovskite films by forming strong chemical bonds. The wide-bandgap lead oxysalt layers also reduce the defect density on the perovskite surfaces by passivating undercoordinated surface lead centers, which are defect-nucleating sites. Formation of the lead oxysalt layer increases the carrier recombination lifetime and boosts the efficiency of the solar cells to 21.1%. Encapsulated devices stabilized by the lead oxysalt layers maintain 96.8% of their initial efficiency after operation at maximum power point under simulated air mass (AM) 1.5 G irradiation for 1200 hours at 65°C. T he power conversion efficiency (PCE) of laboratory-scale metal halide organic perovskite solar cells (PSCs) has reached a certified value of 24.2%, exceeding those of cells that are based on cadmium telluride (CdTe) and copper indium gallium selenide (CIGS) (1). However, PSCs face long-term instability issues under realistic operation conditions, which remains a critical hurdle to be overcome before their commercialization  (2) (3) (4) . Lead halide perovskites generally suffer from instability under stimuli of heat, oxygen, moisture, light irradiation, and electric field (4-6). Tailoring the composition, crystallinity, and internal material strain have been shown to substantially improve the materials' intrinsic stability under different stimuli, but their instability from moisture and oxygen is still an outstanding issue to be solved  (7) (8) (9) (10) . (3-J) Sharp (3-J) Sharp (3-J) NREL Spectrolab (3-J) 39.5% NREL (6-J) Boeing- Spectrolab (5-J) NREL/ Spectrolab (3-J) Spectrolab (3-J) Spectrolab (3-J) Boeing- Spectrolab (3-J) Boeing- Spectrolab (3-J) Boeing- Spectrolab (3-J) Boeing-Spectrolab (3-J, 240x) Boeing-Spectrolab (3-J,179x) NREL (3-J) NREL (3-J) NREL (3-J, 325.7x) FhG-ISE (3-J, 454x) SpireSemicon (3-J, 406x) SolarJunc (3-J, 418x) SolarJunc (3-J, 942x) Sharp (3-J, 302x) Spectrolab (3-J, 299x) Boeing- Spectrolab (3-J, 364x) 47.6% Varian (2-J) No. Carolina State U. (2-J) Spire (2-J) NREL (2-J) NREL (4-J) FhG-ISE (4-J, 665x) NREL (6-J,143x) FhG-ISE/ Soitec (4-J) &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:22:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="11412" length="32"/>
        <text>capping lead oxysalt thin layers</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:23:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="11733" length="12"/>
        <text>lead oxysalt</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">96.8</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:48:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="11920" length="5"/>
        <text>96.8%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:24:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="11973" length="67"/>
        <text>maximum power point under simulated air mass (AM) 1.5 G irradiation</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1200</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:24:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="12045" length="4"/>
        <text>1200</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:24:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="12059" length="4"/>
        <text>65°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:24:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="12208" length="5"/>
        <text>24.2%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13571</offset>
      <text> III-V Multijunction Cells Perovskite degradation is generally initialized from the defect sites at surfaces and grain boundaries, which are more reactive toward water and oxygen  (11) (12) (13) . Many organic molecules and poly-mers have been applied to chemically passivate the perovskite surface defects, and physical covering of some structural defects with hydrophobic organic materials can also enhance the stability of the perovskites  (14) (15) (16) (17) . For example, C 60 and its derivatives have been reported as passivation layers, enhancing device efficiency and reducing current hysteresis in PSCs  (14) . The surface under-coordinated Pb sites can be passivated by Lewis base electron donors, such as thiophene and pyridine, which saturate the lead coordination sphere  (15) . Zwitterions, bearing both negative and positive components, are shown to have a superior dual-passivation effect, leading to enhanced stability of unencapsulated perovskite films under ambient conditions  (16) . Despite these initial successes, limitations exist in using these passivation agents as postsynthesis perovskite treatment for efficiency and stability enhancement. The secondary bonding between these passivation molecules and the perovskite surface is generally too weak to protect the material from attack from moisture and oxygen. Not all structural defects are electronic defects, so some structural defects that may initialize the film degradation might not be covered by passivation molecules. The passivation strategies reported for halide perovskites are fundamentally different from those effectively used in silicon solar cells, in which passivation mainly involves primary chemical bonding. For silicon technology, surface structural defects are generally passivated by silicon oxide, silicon nitride, or aluminum oxide, which form strong covalent bonds to silicon. Oxides and nitrides are mechanically strong, compact, and chem-ically stable, which protect the underlying silicon from degradation. Wide-bandgap oxides and nitrides passivate the surface defects by eliminating silicon dangling bonds and thus enhance device efficiency. We demonstrate a general passivation strategy for lead halide perovskites by forming a thin, compact inorganic lead oxysalt layer on the perovskite surface through in situ reaction with selected inorganic anions. The surface lead oxysalt layer formed strong chemical bonds with the perovskite and afforded much better resistance to many detrimental stimuli under ambient atmosphere and light irradiation. Its passivation effect enhanced the PSC efficiency. The concept of metal halide perovskite surface passivation by using compact inorganic layers is illustrated in Fig.  1A . Inorganic layers for surface passivation of metal halide perovskite should have a large bandgap to reduce surface recombination velocity and be chemically stable in ambient air, especially under humid conditions. The lead salts that are insoluble in water are ideal candidates for perovskite surface stabilization. For example, the solubility of PbSO 4 , Pb 3 (PO 4 ) 2 , and PbCO 3 in water is merely 0.0443, 0.00014, and 0.0011 g liter -1 at 20°C, respectively  (18) . By contrast, PbI 2 has a much higher solubility of 0.756 g liter -1 in water. Another requirement for the surface inorganic layers is that they must bond strongly to the perovskite surface so that the coating is mechanically strong. We formed PbSO 4 and Pb 3 (PO 4 ) 2 as surface inorganic layers through the facile chemical reaction of perovskite with SO 4 2--and PO 4 3-containing salts dissolved in solvents that do not dissolve halide perovskites, such as isopropanol or toluene-in this case, (C 8 H 17 NH 3 ) 2 SO 4 and (C 8 H 17 NH 3 ) 3 PO 4 . Triple-cation perovskite was used in our study with a chemical composition of Cs 0.05 FA 0.81 MA 0.14 PbI 2.55 Br 0.45 (CsFAMA perovskite, where MA is methylammonium and FA is formamidinium). The oxyacid ions reacted with halide perovskite when perovskite films were dipped into (C 8 H 17 NH 3 ) 2 SO 4 and (C 8 H 17 NH 3 ) 3 PO 4 solutions for 30 to ~60 min followed by thermal annealing, according to the following chemical equations APbX 3 þ SO 2À 4 → A þ þ 3X À þ PbSO 4 ð1Þ 3APbX 3 þ 2PO 3À 4 → 3A þ þ 9X À þ Pb 3 ðPO 4 Þ 2 ð2Þ where A = MA, FA, Cs, or a mixture thereof, and X = Br, I, or mixed halide ions. This reaction yielded stable white-colored PbSO 4 and Pb 3 (PO 4 ) 2 films, as shown in the photographs and verified with x-ray diffraction patterns in figs. S1 and S2. Using the same method, a thin lead sulfate layer can be generated on the surface of the CsFAMA perovskite films by reducing the reaction time. Because PbSO 4 is electrically insulating, the reaction time and precursor concentration were carefully optimized to be 20 s and 4 mM, RESEARCH respectively, which yields a layer thickness of &lt;5 nm that can maintain efficient charge transport (fig.  S3 ). Perovskite films or devices with lead sulfate layers, hereafter referred to as lead sulfate samples, were obtained through octylammonium sulfate treatment if not specified otherwise. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and atomic force microscopy (AFM) images in figs. S4 and S5, A and B, show that the topography of the perovskite films was well maintained after the surface reaction, indicating a conformal coating of lead sulfate on the perovskites. Cross-sectional high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) (Fig.  1B ) further revealed a uniform and compact lead sulfate layer that was closely stacked between the fullerene (C 60 ) and perovskite films. The lead sulfate layer had a thickness of 3 to 4 nm, whereas the C 60 layer was crystalline. We used scanning TEM characterization to verify the homogeneity of the sulfate layer on the top of perovskite films. We tested various perovskite/ C 60 interface regions (fig.  S5C ) and observed a thin but continuous lead sulfate layer both on the surface and at grain boundaries of the perovskite film, suggesting complete coverage of lead sulfate on the top surface of perovskite films. Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR) transmission spectra of CsFAMA perovskite powders before and after surface treatment were collected to probe the interactions of sulfate ions with the perovskite. The tetrahedral symmetric sulfate ions typically present one broad peak at ~1100 cm -1 of the triply degenerate v3 band  (19) . The occurrence of v1 band (945 cm -1 ) and split v3 bands (950 to ~1200 cm -1 ) (Fig.  1C ) suggests a distortion of the tetrahedral structure of sulfate ions and formation of strong ionic bonds between Pb 2+ and SO 4 2ions  (20) . The characteristic vibration peaks of the sulfate-treated sample were at the identical frequency (950 to ~1200 cm -1 ) to those of pure PbSO 4 powder (fig.  S6 ), which implies the similar IR vibration behavior of the surface layer on the perovskite surface. We performed x-ray photoemission spectroscopy (XPS) measurements to further characterize the perovskite surface composition after surface treatment. The Pb 4f spectrum exhibited two contributions, 4f 7/2 and 4f 5/2 (Fig.  1D ), located at 138.6 and 143.5 eV for the film without any treatment (control), respectively  (21) . The shift of the Pb peaks toward higher binding energies is evidence for the formation of stronger ionic bonding between Pb 2+ and SO 4 2-ions  (22) . The S/Pb atom ratio was estimated to be 1.03 by the integrated area of corresponding peaks (Fig.  1E ). We performed first-principles density functional theory (DFT) computational analyses of the interaction between MAPbI 3 and PbSO 4 using a slab model of both materials and investigated the nature of their interface by means of ab initio Car-Parrinello Molecular Dynamics (CPMD). We initially considered a (001) MAI-terminated MAPbI 3 surface covered by eight PbSO 4 units arranged in a network similar to that of the perfect PbSO 4 crystal but matching the lattice of MAPbI 3 . We evolved the system dynamics at 350 K for several picoseconds and observed the structural inter-face rearrangement. Starting from the ordered interface (Fig.  2A ), we observed the progressive replacement of a surface MAI unit with a PbSO 4 unit within a few picoseconds (Fig.  2 , B to D), suggesting a stronger interaction between surface Pb atoms of MAPbI 3 and SO 4 -units to form PbSO 4 . We further monitored whether a stronger interaction could exist between the PbI 2terminated surface and PbSO 4 . We thus compared the energetics of interface interaction between PbSO 4 and the two MAPbI 3 surface terminations considering a more closely packed PbSO 4 slab composed by 12 PbSO 4 units (Fig.  2, E  and F , and table  S1 ). These simulations also suggest that interaction between the PbI 2 -terminated surface and PbSO 4 is significantly favored compared with MAI-terminated surface, and the theoretical studies are consistent with the experimental results that show a strong preferential interaction of sulfate anions with perovskite lead atoms. In all cases, bulk PbSO 4 is more stable compared with the formation of a MAPbI 3 -surface PbSO 4 thin film (table  S1 ), which is consistent with the complete perovskite conversion to PbSO 4 observed upon prolonged exposure to sulfate anions. To further investigate the structure of the PbSO 4 phase at the interface with MAPbI 3 , we built a larger model in which the PbI 2 -terminated MAPbI 3 slab was interfaced with several layers of PbSO 4 (fig.  S7A ). The O-S and O-Pb radial distribution functions showed no substantial changes from pure PbSO 4 to the interface with MAPbI 3 (fig.  S7, B  and C ), which suggests the possibility for retention of a crystalline PbSO 4 phase with good lattice matching. The experimental conditions may not favor the crystalline PbSO 4 formation because of the speed of the reaction, but the amorphous PbSO 4 layer was still effective in protecting perovskite surfaces. Solar cells were fabricated with a p-i-n planar heterojunction configuration structured as indium tin oxide (ITO) glass substrate/poly(triaryl amine) (PTAA)/CsFAMA perovskite/C 60 /2,9-dimethyl-4, 7-diphenyl-1,10-phenanthroline (BCP)/Cu. The solar cell device with a lead sulfate surface layer delivered a short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 22.63 mA cm -2 , an open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.16 V, and a fill factor (FF) of 0.804, yielding a PCE of 21.1% under a reverse scan rate of 0.1 V s -1 (Fig.  3A  and table  S2 ). No notable photocurrent hysteresis was observed under forward and reverse sweeps, which suggests good passivation by the lead sulfate layer. The J SC value obtained from the current density-voltage (J-V) characteristics was also verified by measuring the external quantum efficiency (EQE) obtained through integration of the spectral response (fig.  S8 ). Additionally, the best device was further held at maximum power point (MPP) with a voltage of 0.99 V to track the stabilized power output. The photocurrent stabilized at ~21.2 mA cm -2 (Fig.  3B ), corresponding to a stabilized PCE of 21.0%. We measured J-V characteristics of champion devices with different surface treatment under simulated sunlight of air mass (AM) 1.5 G (Fig.  3C ). The control device had a J SC of 22.51 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.07 V, and a FF of 0.796, yielding a PCE of 19.16%. The photovoltaic parameters of the devices with and without octylammonium sulfate treatment were analyzed, and the statistical distribution is shown in fig.  S9 . The To quantify how much cation passivates the perovskite surface, we fabricated solar cells with different cations and anions, and detailed statistical analysis on the device parameters are summarized in table  S3 . Octylammonium iodide treatment increased the mean V OC of the cells from 1.06 to 1.08 V, implying that there is a small but distinct contribution from alkylammonium cations to the passivation of perovskite surface. However, when anions were changed by replacing octylammonium iodide with octylammonium sulfate, the mean V OC of the cells increased from 1.08 to 1.14 V. Moreover, a high mean V OC of 1.13 V could be maintained if methylammonium sulfate was used instead of long-chain alkylammonium cations, implying that sulfate anions dominated in surface passivation. We infer that the perovskite films are mostly covered by the lead sulfate layer after treatment because of the preferential reaction between Pb cations and sulfate anions, as indicated by the results of DFT simulations, so octylammonium cations have less interaction with the perovskite surface. We further demonstrated the universality of this synthetic strategy of using phosphate ions to form a Pb 3 (PO 4 ) 2 surface layer and examined the device performance. One solar cell device based on phosphated CsFAMA perovskite exhibited a J SC of 22.54 mA cm -2 , V OC of 1.14 V, and FF of 0.813, yielding a PCE of 20.87% without hysteresis (fig.  S10  and table S4 ). Trap density of states (tDOS) of the control and sulfate-treated devices was measured with thermal admittance spectroscopy. A device with sulfate top layers had a lower tDOS almost over the whole trap depth region (Fig.  3D ). The density of shallower trap states (0.35 to 0.42 eV) of the sulfate-treated device was only about 10% that of the control device. Our previous characterizations have revealed that the shallow traps mainly locate at the grain boundaries  (23) . Thus, sulfate ions can effectively reach the grain boundaries during the treatment and passivate them, subsequently increasing the device V OC . The time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra of the control CsFAMA perovskite film show a biexponential decay with a fast and a slow component (Fig.  3E ). The surface layer mainly affected the fast PL decay process. The fast-component of the recombination process from the control and sulfate-treated films were fitted to be 3.2 and 24.7 ns, respectively, which is consistent with the enhanced steady-state PL results (Fig.  3F ). The enhanced PL intensity and PL decay lifetime illustrate that the nonradiative recombination of photo-generated carriers in perovskite films is reduced by the formation of lead sulfate surface layers  (24, 25) . Devices were then irradiated under AM 1.5 G simulated illumination, and weak laser pulses (337 nm, 4 ns) were used to modulate V OC to measure the decay of transient photovoltage signals. As seen in Fig.  3G  and fig.  S11 , the chargerecombination lifetime under 1 Sun illumination was increased from 0.27 ms for the control device to 0.58 and 0.47 ms for sulfate-and phosphatetreated devices, respectively. The lower charge trap density and longer carrier recombination lifetime of samples with lead sulfate top layers indicate that the reaction of sulfate and phosphate ions with defective perovskite surface reduces the surface defect density, in addition to the charge compensation effect of these ions. The widebandgap lead oxysalt layer should also contribute to the reduced surface charge recombination rate, similar to the passivation of silicon by oxides  (26) . We performed long-term stability tests of encapsulated CsFAMA perovskite devices under a plasma lamp with light intensity equivalent to AM 1.5 G (fig.  S12 ), without ultraviolet filter in air (relative humidity ~60 ± 10%). All devices were loaded with a resistance so that they worked at MPP at the beginning of the tests. The J-V curves were automatically recorded with a reverse scan rate of 0.1 V s -1 every 6 hours. We frequently checked the stabilized efficiency during the test and did not find obvious differences between the stabilized efficiency and that from J-V scanning. Most importantly, instead of monitoring device stability at a reduced temperature of 20 to 25°C that may cause the overestimation of solar cell stability, we conducted the stability testing at real operation temperature and used a light source with a substantial ultraviolet component. The temperature of the devices under illumination was measured to be ~65°C, which is typical of the thermal heating effect of light. The PCE of the encapsulated control device degraded rapidly from 18.2 to 8.54% after testing for 474 hours (Fig.  3H ). For the devices with the lead sulfate layer, the PCE slightly improved during the first 120 hours of testing and then degraded linearly with both reduced J SC and FF over time. After 1200 hours of testing, the efficiency slightly dropped to 96.8% of the initial value. This CsFAMA perovskite device is one of the most stable reported when tested at MPP conditions (table  S5 ). In ambient conditions, hydration and oxidization of perovskites are among main paths for the degradation of perovskite films  (13, 27) . We studied the water resistance of perovskites with lead sulfate surface layers on MAPbI 3 single crystals. MAPbI 3 crystals were treated with the sulfate precursor solution followed by thermal annealing at 100°C for 10 min (supplementary materials). When dipped in water, the control MAPbI 3 crystal without any treatment quickly turned yellow within 10 s because of fast decomposition of MAPbI 3 with water, forming PbI 2 or other hydrates, whereas the sample with a sulfate layer remained black after dipping in water for &gt;60 s (Fig.  4A  and movie S1). The much later appearance of yellow PbI 2 from perovskite single crystals showed that the lead sulfate top layer was compact enough to slow down the permeation of water into perovskite. We tested the water resistivity of the lead sulfate layer by dripping water on top of the devices with and without sulfate treatment. A device with the lead sulfate layer remained black for 3 min after dripping water, whereas the control device quickly decomposed to yellow-colored PbI 2 (fig.  S13 ). We also tested the protection effect of lead sulfate layer on polycrystalline films that had the same stacking structure of the devices but without metal electrodes. The perovskite film with lead sulfate layer was sandwiched between PTAA and phenyl C61 butyric acid methyl ester (PCBM) layers. We recorded the  absorbance changes at 740 nm during the stability test to quantify the material degradation. The control sample lost 84.2% of its absorbance after illumination for 504 hours, whereas the sample with a lead sulfate layer only lost 16.8% (Fig.  4B  and fig.  S14 ). Ammonium cations have also been reported to enhance the stability of perovskites  (28) . We tested another set of perovskite thin films in air under illumination without any charge transport layers to study which species-specifically, ammonium or sulfate ions-play the dominating role in stabilizing perovskite films. The CsFAMA perovskite film treated with octylammonium iodide fully bleached after testing for 4 days, only slightly preventing the decomposition of the perovskite film as compared with the control sample without any treatment (fig.  S15 ), but perovskite films with sulfate treatment remained black after 4 days. About 56 and 64% of the films' absorbance at 740 nm remained for films treated with methylammonium sulfate and octylammonium sulfate, respectively. The result verified that the stabilization was mainly derived from sulfate rather than ammonium ions. Mass transport of ions is another critical issue that limits the stability of the encapsulated perovskite devices. Ion migration is significantly enhanced under illumination  (29) , which may change the composition and morphology of perovskite films by forming pinholes in addition to causing the degradation of charge transport layers and electrodes  (30) . We also showed that ion migration is much easier at extended defects such as film surface and grain boundaries  (31) . We expect that the formation of a layer of lead oxysalt with strong ionic chemical bonding should stabilize the perovskite surface and suppress the ion migration through it. We measured with temperature-dependent electrical conductivity the activation energy (E a ) for ion migration of perovskite films. Lateral structure devices were fabricated by means of thermal evaporation of two Au electrodes on PTAA/ perovskite/PCBM films. The activation energy can be extracted from the Nernst-Einstein relation: s(T) = (s 0 /T)exp(-E a /k B T), where k B is the Boltzmann constant, s 0 is a constant, and T is temperature. The applied electric field was fixed at 0.4 V/mm, which was near the operational electric field in solar cell devices. For the CsFAMA perovskite films, ionic conductivity began to dominate the total conductivity, with an E a of 0.288 eV when the temperature was increased to 314 K in the dark (Fig.  4C ). When illuminated at 0.1 sunlight intensity, the transition temperature was reduced to 273 K, accompanied with a lower E a of 0.104 eV. This observation agrees well with our previous results that light would facilitate the ion migration  (29) . For the sulfate-treated perovskite film, we did not observe such a transition from electronic to ionic conductivity when the temperature was increased to 330 K both in the dark and under illumination (Fig.  4D ). A constant slope was obtained with an E a of 0.036 eV, which we ascribed to electronic conduction. We also measured E a of individual MAPbI 3 single crystals to isolate the influence of untreated grain boundaries in polycrystalline films, which act as the main channel for ion migration  (31) . Similar phenomena were observed for the single crystals (Fig.  4 , E to F). We thus conclude that ion migration is efficiently suppressed by the lead sulfate top layer on the surface of perovskite, possibly because surface defects such as vacancies were immobilized by the strongly bonded lead sulfate layer, which also explains the restrained morphological variation of perovskite films with the presence of the lead sulfate layer (fig.  S16 ). Generally, ion migration through grain boundaries is much slower than at the surface, so the exclusion of ion migration at a film surface should also indicate the absence of ion migration through sulfated grain boundaries.  Fig. S1 . S1 Fig. S1. XRD patterns of perovskite films reacted with octylammonium sulfate precursor solution for 30 min, followed by 10 min annealing at 100 o C. Diffraction peaks of the products could be ascribed to the formation of anglesite PbSO4. Inset is the photography of the as-resulted PbSO4 film. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">18.2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:28:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="29718" length="4"/>
        <text>18.2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-11T15:27:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="30047" length="6"/>
        <text>CsFAMA</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35947</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. XRD patterns of films treated with octylammonium phosphate precursor solution for 60 min, followed by 10 min annealing at 100 o C. Diffraction peaks of the products can be ascribed to Pb3(PO4)2. Inset is the photography of the as-resulted Pb3(PO4)2 film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36226</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Influence of reaction time (a) and precursor concentration (b) of surface treatment on the J-V characteristics of perovskite solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36388</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images of the control (a) and sulfatetreated (b) perovskite films deposited on ITO glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36537</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. AFM images of (a) control and (b) sulfate-treated perovskite films and root mean squared (RMS) roughness were calculated to be 14.5 and 15.2 nm for control and treated films, respectively. (c) Scanning TEM images of sulfate-treated perovskite solar cell captured at various interface regions. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36854</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. FT-IR spectrum of PbSO4 powder. The FT-IR peaks at 964, 1040 and 1145 cm -2 represent the symmetric stretching (v1) and asymmetric stretching (v3) of sulfate ions, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37056</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . 2 )Fig. S8 .Fig. S9 . S72S8S9 Fig. S7. (a) Optimized bulk MAPbI3-PbSO4 interface. RDF analysis of (b) O-S and (c) O-Pb. Blue and red lines are the RDF calculated per the perfect PbSO4 crystal and MAPbI3-PbSO4 interface, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37302</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 .Fig. S12 . S10S12 Fig. S10. J-V curves of the champion phosphate-treated device measured in reverse (blue) and forward (red) scanning directions &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37459</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. Images of the devices without (left) and with (right) a sulfate layer after exposure to water droplet for 3 min. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37599</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. UV-vis absorption spectra of perovskite films sandwiched between PTAA and PCBM layers under simulated AM 1.5G light illumination (~100 mW cm -2 ) in ambient air recorded at different time intervals. Curves from top to bottom corresponds to that from 0 to 21 days. Insets are the photographs of corresponding films before (left) and after (right) light irradiation for 21 days. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38003</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. UV-vis absorption spectra of perovskite films under light illumination (~70 mW cm -2 ) and dry air recorded at different time intervals. Insets are the photographs of corresponding perovskite films before (left) and after (right) light irradiation for 4 days. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38290</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. Surface SEM image of perovskite films without (a) and with a lead sulfate layer (b) aged under 70 mW cm -2 irradiation for 24 hours in air. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38457</offset>
      <text> (2-terminal, monolithic) LM = lattice matched MM = metamorphic IMM = inverted, metamorphic Two-, three-, and four-junction (concentrator) Three-junction or more (non-concentrator) Two-junction (non-concentrator) REPORT ◥ SOLAR CELLS Stabilizing halide perovskite surfaces for solar cell operation with wide-bandgap lead oxysalts Shuang Yang 1,2 *, Shangshang Chen 1 *, Edoardo Mosconi 3 , Yanjun Fang 1,2 , Xun Xiao 1 , Congcong Wang 4 , Yu Zhou 1 , Zhenhua Yu 1 , Jingjing Zhao 1,2 , Yongli Gao 4 , Filippo De Angelis 3,5,6 , Jinsong Huang 1,2 † &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39010</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Organohalide lead perovskite stabilized by a lead sulfate surface layer. (A) Schematic illustration of protection of perovskites through in situ formation of a lead sulfate top layer on the perovskite surface. (B) Cross-sectional HR-TEM image of the perovskite/lead sulfate/C 60 interface. (C) FT-IR measurement of perovskite powder with or without the lead sulfate layer. (D and E) The XPS spectra of (D) Pb 4f and (E) S 2p for the perovskite films deposited on ITO glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39505</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Theoretical simulation. (A to F) Optimized geometries from the selected snapshots of the MAI-terminated + 8PbSO 4 CPMD simulation. The (A) initial geometry and the [(B) and (C)] optimized geometry after (B) 1.2 and (C) 3.6 ps are also shown. (D) The structure in which a MAI was exchanged with a PbSO 4 from geometry (C). (E) and (F) show optimized geometries of (E) MAIterminated and (F) PbI 2 -terminated interface with a PbSO 4 layer. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39964</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Photovoltaic performance, passivation effects, and long-term stability studies of sulfate-treated devices. (A) J-V curves of the champion sulfate-treated device measured in both reverse (blue) and forward (red) scanning directions. (B) Steady-state measurement of the photocurrent (orange) and PCE (blue) of the champion device with a lead sulfate layer held at MPP voltage of 0.99 V. (C) J-V curves of perovskite solar cells based on perovskite films treated with different precursor solution. (D) tDOS obtained through thermal admittance spectroscopy for the devices with (blue) or without (orange) lead sulfate top layers. The vertical dashed lines define trap bands with different trap energy depths: shallow trap states (band 1, 0.35 to 0.40 eV) and deep trap states (band 2 and band 3, &gt;0.4 eV). (E) Steady-state PL and (F) time-resolved PL of the perovskite films with and without lead sulfate layers. (G) TPV decay curves of the photovoltaic devices with and without lead sulfate surface layers. (H) Stability test of encapsulated solar cell devices based on control (blue) and sulfate-treated (red) CsFAMA perovskite active layers. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41126</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Enhanced water resistance and suppressed ion migration by lead sulfate surface layer. (A) MAPbI 3 single crystals without and with lead sulfate top layers dipped into water at different time intervals. (B) Normalized absorbance decay at 740 nm for perovskite films sandwiched between PTAA and PCBM layers under simulated AM 1.5 G &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41477</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 Energy associated to the interface formation reaction (ΔEform, eV) starting from the corresponding bulk structures. Values in parenthesis are evaluated as single point calculation including D3 dispersion interaction on the optimized geometries. MAPbI3 Termination ΔEform ΔEform per molec. ΔEform per molec. (Ref. Isolated PbSO4) MAI-terminated 9.475 (16.763) 0.395 (0.698) -2.104 PbI2-terminated 6.473 (12.641) 0.270 (0.527) -2.229 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41929</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 hotovoltaic parameters of the best sulfate-treated device with different sweeping rates and directions. All the J-V curves were at a simulated AM 1.5 G solar irradiation with a scan rate of 0.1 V s -1 . Jsc/mA cm -2 Voc/V FF PCE/% Forward 22.65 1.16 0.803 21.09 Reverse 22.63 1.16 0.804 21.11 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42238</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 ummary of the best device performance of solar cells treated with different precursor solutions. All the J-V curves were measured under 100 mW cm -2 simulated AM 1.5G sunlight by reverse voltage scan (scan rate: 0.1 V s -1 ). (Data in brackets are the average values of each parameter. Jsc/mA cm -2 Voc/V FF PCE/% Control 22.51 (22.30±0.34) 1.07 (1.06±0.01) 0.796 (0.783±0.013) 19.16 (18.57±0.34) Octylammonium 22.49 1.08 0.794 19.28 iodide (22.44±0.22) (1.08±0.01) (0.776±00.017) (18.85±0.31) Methylammonium 22.62 1.14 0.799 20.60 sulfate (22.53±0.24) (1.13±0.01) (0.787±0.014) (19.97±0.46) Octylammonium 22.63 1.16 0.804 21.11 sulfate (22.44±0.36) (1.14±0.01) (0.791±0.013) (20.18±0.56) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42959</offset>
      <text> Table &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42967</offset>
      <text> Table S5 . S5 1 V s -1 . Comparison of the stability of the solar cells in our work with some recent reports. PCE0 and PCEt are the efficiency of devices before and after stability tests. MAPbI3 single crystal with a thick lead sulfate layer in water. 52 Best Research-Cell Efficiencies Thin-Film Technologies Hybrid Tandems (2-terminal) Jsc/mA cm -2 22.60 22.54 Temperature Light source Voc/V 1.13 1.14 65 °C plasma lamp with strong UV component, equivalent to 1 sun 25 °C white LED, equivalent to 1 sun 20 °C white LED, equivalent to 1 sun Not specified not specified, equivalent to 1 sun 20-30 °C plasma lamp, equivalent to 0.77 sun ~60 °C white LED, equivalent to 1 sun 55-60 °C white LED, equivalent to 1 sun CIGS (concentrator) Testing duration FF 0.814 0.813 1200 h 1370 h 1000 h 1500 h 1000 h 1000 h 1000 h CIGS CdTe Emerging PV Dye-sensitized cells Perovskite cells Amorphous Si:H (stabilized) Movie of dipping a 8 Forward Reverse Environment Encapsulation Air, RH ~60±10% Yes Air, RH ~30% Yes N2 No Not specified Not specified Air, RH ~10-20% No N2 No Ar No Movie S1 44 48 4 0 16 20 24 28 32 36 40 RCA RCA RCA RCA RCA RCA Organic cells Single-Junction GaAs Organic tandem cells Single crystal CZTSSe cells Concentrator Quantum dot cells Thin-film crystal Perovskite tandem cells Crystalline Si Cells EPFL PCE0 19.44% N.A. 19.54% 19.17±0.4 2% 12.2±0.1% N.A. ~20.6% Perovskite/Si PCE/% 20.80 20.87 PCEt/PCE0 96.8% 95% 78.4% 92% 94% &gt;95% 98.1% Perovskite/organic Perovskite/CIGS III-V/Si EPFL EPFL RCA U.of Maine Boeing Solarex UniSolar U.of Maine Monosolar ARCO Matsushita Kodak Kodak Kodak Kodak Boeing Boeing AMETEK Photon Energy U. So. Florida Boeing Boeing Boeing ARCO ARCO Euro-CIS NREL EPFL Reference This work Nature, 2019, 567, 511. Science 2018, 362, 449. Science 2019, 363, 265. Nat. Energy, 2018, 3, 68. Science, 2017, 358, 768. Nat. Common. 2018, 9, 4482. UniSolar Matsushita NREL Mobil Solar Solarex Solarex SunPower (96x) (140x) UNSW NREL NREL U. Linz UniSolar Groningen U. Linz NREL NREL NREL NREL NREL (14x) U. Stuttgart Sanyo Sanyo Sanyo Siemens Sharp NREL / Konarka Plextronics U. Dresden Heliatek Sumi-NREL (ZnO/PbS-QD) EPFL NIMS Sharp UCLA-Sumitomo KRICT FhG-ISE KRICT UCLA Heliatek tomo U. Linz U.Toronto (PbS-QD) U.Toronto Konarka Mitsubishi HKUST FhG-ISE EPFL FhG-ISE FhG-ISE FhG-ISE FhG-ISE/AMOLF Wuppertal HZB UCLA Oxford PV HZB Oxford PV HZB EPFL/CSEM HZB LONGi LONGi KAUST Oxford PV Stanford/ASU NUS/ SERIS KRICT/MIT &amp; Korea U (tie) EPFL KRICT/UNIST ISCAS KRICT/MIT UNIST ISCAS USTC NU/UT USTC Nanjing Univ Nanjing Univ/ Renshine NJUPT IoP/CAS EPFL EPFL UCLA SCUT/eFlexPV ICCAS Phillips 66 UCLA Raynergy Tek of Taiwan SCUT-CSU SJTU-UMass City U HK/UW SJTU/BUAA SJTU ICCAS Konarka Solarmer IBM IBM IBM MIT U.Toronto NREL Univ.of Queensland UNIST UNIST UniSolar (aSi/ncSi/ncSi) AIST AIST LG First Solar First Solar First Solar First Solar First Solar First Solar GE GE EMPA (Flex poly) NREL NREL ZSW ZSW SolarFron NREL NREL Solibro ZSW ZSW SolarFrontier Evolar/UU NREL (15.4x) NREL (14.7x) Solexel Solexel U. Stuttgart FhG-ISE ISFH Sanyo Sanyo Panasonic Panasonic Panasonic LONGi LONGi Kaneka Kaneka UNSW ISFH UNSW UNSW UNSW UNSW ARCO RCA Sandia UNSW UNSW Spire Stanford Westing-Trina house UNSW / Eurosolare UNSW Georgia Tech Georgia Tech Georgia Tech FhG-ISE Canadian Solar Trina Solar JinkoSolar Research Center) (T.J. Watson IBM FhG-ISE UNSW Radboud U. Alta Kopin Varian FhG-ISE Stanford Amonix (92x) SunPower (lrg-area) FhG-ISE Thin-film crystal Single crystal (concentrator) Multicrystalline Silicon heterostructures (HIT) Single crystal (non-concentrator) Alta Alta Alta Devices Varian (216x) Varian (205x) FhG-ISE (117x) LG NREL (258x) NREL FhG-ISE (232x) Radboud Univ. NREL LG Varian Japan Energy Alta NREL (2-J) Alta LG NREL NREL (MM) NREL NREL (Rev. 10-11-2024) 36.1% 24.2% 23.4% 34.6% 26.7% 30.1% 14.9% 13.0% 14.2% 19.2% 19.1% 14.0% 23.1% 23.6% 23.3% 21.2% 27.3% 27.6% 23.3% 26.1% 29.1% 27.8% 30.8% 32.9% 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995 2000 2005 2010 2015 2020 2025 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46983</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 RESEARCH | REPORT Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:50:02Z</infon>
      <node refid="11" role=""/>
      <node refid="12" role=""/>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
      <node refid="16" role=""/>
      <node refid="15" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
