<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025028761CHHDFD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_review">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 34&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Some Thermodynamics of Photochemical Systems*&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58</offset>
      <text>transitions are indicated with an arbitrarily lower intensity. The codes used in Fig.  7  are the same given in Table  VIII  for the higher state.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>205</offset>
      <text>I. INTRODUCTION T HE purpose of this paper is to discuss the inter- action of a radiation field with a photochemical system which absorbs radiation over a broad band of frequencies. Of primary concern are the evaluation of the chemical potential difference which is developed within the system, and the amount of work-or, equivalently, free energy-which may appear as a result of light absorption by such a system. The thermodynamics of the interaction of a narrowband absorber with a radiation field,! and limitations on the amount of work which may be extracted by such an absorber from a radiation field,2 are fairly well understood. In this paper we extend discussions of the narrow-band situation to apply them to broadband systems. The thermodynamics of broad-bandabsorbing photochemical systems has been considered in a more restricted context by Shockley and Queisser,8 and we use a Planck blackbody-law relationship between the absorption and emission properties of a " This work was supported, in part, by the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission. 1 P. T. Landsberg, Thermodynamics (Interscience Publishers, Inc., New York, 1961). 2 R. T. Ross, J. Chem. Phys. 45, 1 (1966). 3 W. Shockley and H. J. Queisser, J. App!. Phys. 32,510  (1961) . broad-band absorber which has been derived by a number of authors (see Discussion). We consider a two-level photochemical system which consists of a collection of ground electronic states G and excited electronic states E. Ordinarily these consist of the ground singlet states and the first excited singlet states of the light-absorbing molecules. In systems where excitations can migrate easily, these collections of states are often referred to as the valence band and the conduction band, respectively. Each electronic band usually contains a number of vibrational substates. When the rate of absorption of light quanta causing excitations from G to E is rapid with respect to the thermal equilibration of populations between the two bands, then a transition from E to G gives up some free energy which may be stored or used for chemical synthesis. The amount of work which can be done as a result of the absorption of each photon is limited by the product of this free-energy change and the quantum yield for the de-excitation pathway which is coupled to work production. If the sub states within each electronic band remain in thermal equilibrium regardless of the incident radiation field, then the potential difference between any substate of G and any substate of E will be independent of the identity of either substate. In other words, there will be a single well-defined free-energy change for any transition between the bands. There are two ways of viewing the excitations caused by the absorption of light: Excitations may be considered as producing an increase in the population of electrons in a set of states of fixed number, with a corresponding decrease in the population of electrons in another set of states of fixed number. Alternatively, the identical process may be viewed as an increase in the number of an excited state molecular species and a concomitant decrease in the number of a ground state molecular species. These two points of view may be called the photoelectric and the molecular photochemical views, respectively, and the distinction between the two becomes meaningful when one considers the coupling between the light-absorbing molecules, and the larger system of which they are a part. If this system operates thiough electron migration, then the photoelectric view is the more natural, while if the result of light absorption is molecular rearrangement, then the molecular photochemical view may prevail. It is important to remember that the distinction is one of point of view only, as influenced by the fate of the excitation, and makes no difference in the thermodynamics of the light absorption. The formalism for the photoelectric case has been extensively developed for use in semiconductor systems. 4 ,5  In the presence of complete thermal equilibrium, the chemical potential of all of the electrons is equal to the Fermi level, which usually lies midway in energy between the ground band and the excited state band. The electrons within the E band and within the G band each have a chemical potential which is similarly defined, and which is called a quasi-Fermi level. As electrons are transferred from G to E under the influence of light, the quasi-Fermi level of G drops below the equilibrium Fermi level, and the quasi-Fermi level of E increases correspondingly. The alternative point of view is to consider changes in the partial molar free energy of the light-absorbing molecules in their ground state and in their excited state. The action of light usually depletes the population of the ground-state molecules only very slightly, altering the chemical activity of these species to a negligible extent; in this case the potential difference arising between the bands is due almost entirely to the greatly increased population of molecules in the excited state. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5266</offset>
      <text> II. THEORY In order to evaluate the band-to-band potential difference p. caused by a radiation field in any given situatranslated by M. Lauer (Pergamon Press Ltd.,  Oxford, England, 1962)  . tion, we first consider the conditions for equilibrium between the band-to-band transitions and a radiation field. Reversible reaction implies that there is no change in entropy accompanying the emission or absorption of radiation by the photochemical system at any frequency. The entropy change corresponding to the loss of a photon of frequency 1J from a radiation field may be evaluated by considering an equilibrium at 1J between the field and a blackbody: A blackbody is in equilibrium with a radiation field at 1J when foot_1   I(1J) = (87rn 2 1J2jc2) [exp(hp/kTB) -IJ-1, ( 1 ) where TB is the temperature of the blackbody, n is the refractive index of the medium, and I is the intensity of the radiation field in units of photons per 411' solid angle, per unit bandwidth, per unit area, per unit time. The entropy gained by a blackbody upon absorption of a photon at " is h1J/TB • By rearranging (1) to find the temperature of a blackbody in equilibrium with a radiation field of intensity I, we find the entropy change upon loss of a photon from a radiation field to be -as/aN =k In (1 + 87rn 2 1J2jc2I) . (2) From the assumed potential difference f.L and knowledge that the energy change per photon absorbed is h1J, we know that the change in the entropy of the photochemical system per photon absorbed is as/aN = (h1J-p.)/T, ( 3 ) where T is the temperature of the surroundings. If we assume that the photochemical absorber is isotropic in its interaction with a radiation field, then by integrating over solid angle, and equating the entropies, we find that the rate of photon absorption and emission per unit bandwidth and unit cross section IS The figure one in (4) corresponds to stimulated emission, and may usually be neglected, simplifying (4) to I(1J, p., T) = 811' (n1J/ c) 2 exp[ (p.-h1J) /kT]' (4') If the absorption cross section for band-to-band excitation is u(1J, p., T), then the total rate of excitation and emission per unit bandwidth is equal to U(1J, p., T)I(1J, p., T) (5) for a photochemical system which has thermal equilibrium at temperature T within its electronic bands, and a potential difference J.L between the bands, and which is in equilibrium with an isotropic radiation field at all frequencies. Now consider that the same potential difference is established between the bands of the same system by any manner whatsoever. This might be done by causing the same rate of excitations with an arbitrary radiation field, or by pumping the system electrically or chemically. Since we are assuming rapid thermal equilibration among the vibrational substates within each band, the equilibrium radiation field may be replaced with anything else which will cause the same net rate of G-to-E transitions without affecting either the potential between the bands, or the quantity and frequency distribution of radiation spontaneously emitted by the system. This means that, given thermal equilibrium within each band, knowledge of the electronic absorption spectrum of any system permits direct calculation of the luminescence spectrum, and vice versa. This relation has been derived in general and for specific cases by a number of independent authors. We discuss its history and applications in Sec. III. For simplicity we assume that the absorption spectrum is independent of f.L, although this may not be true. Changes with temperature can be ignored since T is assumed to be fixed. Then, by substituting the frequency dependent factors of (4') into (5), we find that the emission spectrum as a function of v is given by u(v )n 2 (v )v 2 exp( -hv/kT), (6) where the emission is defined in units of quanta per unit frequency interval. The Planck-law relationship between absorption and emission may be used to calculate the potential developed in a photochemical system whenever its absorption spectrum and the incident light flux are known. The rate of band-to-band excitations resulting from an arbitrary radiative field is equal to Rin= f u(v)Is(v)dv, (7) where Is(v) is the photon flux provided by the light source. From (5), with (4') substituted in, the rate of radiative decay from a photochemical system having a potential difference f.L is We abbreviate the integral with L, so that Rlum = exp (f.L/ kT) L. (8') By equating (7) and (8'), we can find the maximum possible potential of a photochemical system having an absorption spectrum u(v), and illuminated by a radiation field of intensity and distribution Is (v) : f.Lmax=kT In(Rin/L). ( ) 9 Nonradiative band-to-band transitions are frequently a significant source of E-to-G relaxation. We assume that the rate of induced G-to-E transitions given by (  7 ) is large with respect to all spontaneous excitations. Then we specify that the total rate of decay from E to G is K times the rate of radiative decay alone:  (10)  By equating Rin and Rout we determine the potential developed in the presence of nonradiative relaxation: f.L=kT In[Rin/K(f.L)LJ=f.Lmax-kT In[K(f.L)]. ( 11 ) As K is the reciprocal of the luminescence quantum yield, it may frequently be determined experimentally. For the remainder of this section we assume that K is independent of f.L, although it appears that this is generally true only for noninteracting excitations obeying Boltzmann statistics. Work is one of the more popular commodities which can result from the photochemical absorption of light, so that frequently one desires to maximize the amount of power stored by such a system. The amount of power stored is  (12)  where Rlos s is the rate of E-to-G transitions which are not coupled to the work-storage process. From  (11)  we know that  (13)  is the potential difference in the absence of the workstorage process. We define the quantum yield for the loss processes CPloss = RloBs/ Rout, (14) so that f.L=f.Lo+kT Incploss. (15) The amount of power stored, which may be rewritten as P=Rinf.L(1-CPloss),  (16)  may be maximized by appropriate choice of f.L and CPloss-The power storage is approximately maximal when CPloss = kT / f.Lo, so that the optimal potential is roughly  ( 17)  This more general derivation is strictly parallel to the narrow-band treatment which was given previously.2 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11638</offset>
      <text> III. DISCUSSION The Planck-law relationship between absorption and emission was derived several decades ago by Kennard,7,8 but this work has only recently been rediscovered. 9 The relationship was discovered independently by Stepanov,lO and his derivation has been extended somewhat by Neporent ll and by Ketskemety, Dombi, and Horvai. 12 The relationship was also derived, again independently, for a more restricted situation by van Roosbroeck and Shockley,13 and their work has recently been generalized by McCumber.I 4 Until these several papers revived application of the relationship to all kinds of spectra, it appears that the direct connection between the relative strengths of absorption and emission as a function of frequency was used only in systems where individual vibrational or rotational lines could be resolved.I 5  The experimental validity of the relationship was first shown by Kennard 7 and MerrittS for several species of dye molecule in solution, and following rediscovery of the relationship by Stepanov it has been used fairly extensively by Russian and Hungarian physical chemists. Work with a variety of molecules in solution has shown very good agreement between calculated and observed luminescence spectra 12 ; indeed, the agreement is so good that discrepancies between theory and experiment have been used to determine the presence of impuritiesP Some comparisons between predicted and observed luminescence spectra have also been made in semiconductors,18.19 and the agreement is within the accuracy of the measurements. The relationship has even been used successfully in the vapor phase,20.21 demonstrating that in many complex molecules vibra-tional equilibrium can be attained through intramolecular processes within the lifetime of the excited state. The Planck-law relation itself has a number of applications, some of which are suggested by the work which has already been done. One of the important applications is the use of an absorption spectrum to calculate a luminescence spectrum for systems in which luminescence has not been observed experimentally. Prediction of the luminescence spectrum may be useful in calculating energy-transfer probabilities, and may assist in locating the luminescence experimentally. Examination of differences between predicted and observed luminescence spectra may provide a check on the experimental methods used, and represents a tool for examining deviations from the usual assumption of complete vibrational equilibrium in a two-level system. Knowledge that the Planck-law relationship is applicable permits a ready calculation of the maximum lightinduced chemical potential difference which can be developed by a system, providing only that the incidentlight intensity and the absorption spectrum are known. Given knowledge of the quantum yield for luminescence, it is possible to calculate the actual potential developed. Knowledge of this potential may be useful in examining any photochemical system which uses light to generate any sort of thermodynamic potential gradient. We have found these calculations to be particularly useful in analyzing the energetics of photosynthesis. 22 This process can also be reversed: From knowledge of a luminescence spectrum it is possible to infer the absorption spectrum of the species responsible. Then, given order-of-magnitude estimates for the luminescence yield and for the absolute absorption cross section (i.e., the extinction coefficient) of the luminescing species, it is possible to calculate the chemical potential difference required to generate the luminescence. This should be of use in examining mechanisms in electroluminescence, chemiluminescence, and bioluminescence. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15351</offset>
      <text> The Content Platform Our new content platform brings users and administrators optimized service and a streamlined, modern experience.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15488</offset>
      <text> Searching the Platform From the homepage you can conduct a basic, advanced, or citation search across our content platform. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15614</offset>
      <text> Search Results When Browse: Viewing the Latest Issue After clicking on "Browse" you are directed to the current issue and can navigate to previously published issues. Here you can view an article's abstract or the article in full. In the left-hand column, you can view the cover image, jump to a specific type of article, or view articles by topic. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15965</offset>
      <text> Accessing an Article Institutional customers access content via registered IP ranges. If you try to view content from an unauthorized IP address, you will be asked to select your method of access as shown here. If you do not have access through your institution, you have the option to log in as an individual subscriber, purchase standard PPV, or view the article via Open Athens or Shibboleth. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16363</offset>
      <text> Sign In &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16373</offset>
      <text> Viewing an Article IP authenticated users can access articles without creating a profile. However to benefit from all tools available we encourage users to create a profile. From an article, users can: • Save searches  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16596</offset>
      <text> Article Icons The blue circle icons next to certain article titles indicate if it is a: • Featured Article • Editor's Pick • Scilight A Scilight, a science highlight, is a professional summary of significant developments in a particular field of research. The articles that are chosen for Scilight are recommended by the research-active editors of AIP Publishing's journals. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16979</offset>
      <text> Sign In &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16989</offset>
      <text> Article Figures &amp; Split Screen Option Select "views" to toggle between "figures &amp; tables" and "article contents". Article "figures &amp; tables" can be downloaded directly as a PowerPoint presentation with citations or as a High-res image. The newly added split screen feature offers readers a way to read an article and view the figures, references, and related content alongside each other. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17380</offset>
      <text> Article Metrics &amp; Citations When available, article metrics can be viewed by selecting "View Metrics" in the upper right-corner of the page. As articles receive "views" and "citations" they will be calculated and updated daily. (Note: article metrics are cumulative from 12/13/2016 onwards). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17674</offset>
      <text> Sign In Sign In &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17692</offset>
      <text> Sign In Article citations can be viewed by selecting "Web of Science" or "Crossref" &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17778</offset>
      <text> Related Content A list of related content is found to the right of the article under "Related Content". &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17884</offset>
      <text> Sharing an Article Click on the share button to share an article via Twitter, Facebook, Reddit, or LinkedIn. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17995</offset>
      <text> Sign In Sign In 10 Navigating Books Our books are fully integrated with our journals and are designed to help researchers at every stage of their career to discover new developments, investigate new techniques, and explore key concepts in emerging areas of science. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18263</offset>
      <text> the book type to view titles within each category Accessing the Books Homepage &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18344</offset>
      <text> pubs.aip.org/books Browse: Access our books by publication date, type, or author &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18427</offset>
      <text> Book Title Page The title page offers an easy to navigate overview with a description, short links to the book information, access options, and metrics. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18582</offset>
      <text> Buy this Book: purchase a PDF version of this book Abstract: read the book abstract &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18668</offset>
      <text> PDF: download individual book chapters Share, Tools, Cite: share via social media or Reddit, and download citation information. Buy Print: offers individual an option to purchase a personal softcover copy of this book myBook: offers readers at institutions with an active license an exclusive option to purchase a discounted B&amp;W copy Features•Explore 3 • 3 Enhanced site navigation and discoverability • NEW split screen view option • Greater accessibility for users with disabilities • Figure viewer to explore visual content • Improved video player delivery • Improved site performance Create a profile to optimize your experience by visiting: https://pubs.aip.org/my-account/register AIP Publishing and our portfolio by logging into your account profile. Access published articles, information about our partnerships, individual publications, and submit your next manuscript. Publishers: Learn about AIP Publishing and our publishing partners • Publications: View our journals, Physics Today magazine, conference proceedings and our books • Special Topics: Access the latest special topics across our publications • Authors: View author resources and learn about publishing • Librarians: View librarian resources and learn about access options • About: Learn our mission Most Recent: View some of the most recently published articles across our journal portfolio Submit your article: Find the right journal to share your latest discovery worldwide Sign up for Alerts: register for journal and topic alerts to be delivered right to your inbox • Search box: Search the platform by keyword, phrase, DOI, ISBN, author name, etc. • Magnifying glass: Click to run your search • Advanced search: simultaneously search by several parameters to tailor your results • Citation search: Search by journal, volume and page number Sign In Basic Search: search the platform by a specific phrase or term Advanced Search: the search options below will appear, allowing you to utilize more than one search term or phrase, and apply filters to your search. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20743</offset>
      <text> search results appear, you can: • Filter by format, topic, subject, or journal • Sort by relevance or publication date Sign In Sign In Citation Search: select the journal name and include the volume and page number. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20965</offset>
      <text>			 W, Shockley, Electrons and Holes in Semiconductors (D. Van Nostrand Co., Inc., Princeton, N.J., 1950). 6 J. Tauc, Photo and Thermoelectric Effects in Semiconductors, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21136</offset>
      <text>			 M. Planck, Theory oj Heat Radiation, translated by M. Masius (Dover Publications, Inc., New York, 1959).13 November 2024 17:45:37 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21271</offset>
      <text>			 E. H. Kennard, Phys. Rev. 11, 29 (1918). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21317</offset>
      <text>			 E. H. Kennard, Phys. Rev. 28, 672 (1926). • Yu. T. Mazurenko and B. S. Neporent, Opt. i Spektroskopiya 12,571 (1962) [English trans!.: Opt. Spectry. 12,317 (1962)]. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21489</offset>
      <text>			 R. T. Ross, thesis, University of California, Berkeley, 1966.</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
