<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025046159EAHCED</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 120&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Organometallic-functionalized interfaces for highly efficient inverted perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>107</offset>
      <text>Further enhancing the performance and stability of inverted perovskite solar cells (PSCs) is crucial for their commercialization. We report that the functionalization of multication and halide perovskite interfaces with an organometallic compound, ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate (FcTc 2 ), simultaneously enhanced the efficiency and stability of inverted PSCs. The resultant devices achieved a power conversion efficiency of 25.0% and maintained &gt;98% of their initial efficiency after continuously operating at the maximum power point for 1500 hours under simulated AM1.5 illumination. Moreover, the FcTc 2 -functionalized devices passed the international standards for mature photovoltaics (IEC61215:2016) and have exhibited high stability under the damp heat test (85Â°C and 85% relative humidity). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:06:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="355" length="38"/>
        <text>ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:06:40Z</infon>
        <location offset="395" length="6"/>
        <text>FcTc 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:06:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="540" length="5"/>
        <text>25.0%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">98</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:51:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="562" length="3"/>
        <text>98%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:07:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="654" length="10"/>
        <text>1500 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:07:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="671" length="28"/>
        <text>simulated AM1.5 illumination</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>917</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>927</offset>
      <text>P ower conversion efficiencies (PCEs) as high as 25.7% have been realized for single-junction conventional n-i-p perovskite solar cells (PSCs), approaching the PCEs of state-of-the-art crystalline-silicon solar cells (1-3). Inverted (p-i-n structure) devices, with a deposition sequence of holetransport (p), intrinsic (i), and electron-transport (n) layers, have exhibited greater stabilities and lifetimes because of their undoped holetransporting layers (HTLs) and the formation of highly crystalline perovskite films  (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) . Recently, strategies for managing defects and ion migration in inverted PSCs have further contributed to device stability. For example, Chen et al. have used solid-state carbohydrazide to modulate the crystallization of perovskites and fabricate a minimodule that maintained 85% of its initial PCE under 1-sun illumination (where 1 sun is defined as the standard illumination at AM1.5, or 1 kW m -2 ) for 1000 hours  (11) , and Bai et al. have applied ionic liquids within perovskite films by suppressing ion migration and have fabricated PSCs that exhibited only ~5% degradation of device performance under continuous simulated AM1.5 irradiation for &gt;1800 hours  (12) . However, the currently reported operational lifetime of inverted PSCs under international standards still lags far behind the 25-year lifetime guarantee for commercialized silicon solar cells  (2, 13) . Moreover, although synergistic tailoring of grains, defects, and interfaces can boost efficiencies to 23.3%, there is still a lack of strategy that could result in efficiencies of up to 25% to rival n-i-p PSCs and silicon solar cells  (14) (15) (16) . Here, we report highly efficient and stable inverted PSCs through interface functionalization with an organometallic compound, ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate (FcTc 2 ), that not only provided strong chemical Pb-O binding to reduce surface trap states but also accelerated interfacial electron transfer through the electron-rich and electron-delocalizable ferrocene units. The improved interface binding and carrier transport properties of FcTc 2 contribute to superior device stability. The resulting devices achieved a PCE of 25.0% (with certified 24.3%) and maintained &gt;98% of their initial efficiency in long-term operational stability tests with continuous 1-sun illumination for &gt;1500 hours. Moreover, the FcTc 2 -treated devices exhibited excellent stability under damp heat tests [85Â°C and 85% relative humidity (RH)], which have passed the international standards for silicon solar cells. Interfaces were functionalized with FcTc 2 by using the inherent carboxylate and thiophene groups around the central ferrocene motif (see Fig.  1A  for chemical structure). The ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectra of FcTc 2 in solution and as a thin film are shown in figs. S1 and S2, respectively. The device configuration is depicted in Fig.  1A , in which poly(triaryl amine) (PTAA) was the HTL and C 60 was the electron transfer layer (ETL). Figure  S3  shows the cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) image of a typical device with a perovskite composition of Cs 0.05 (FA 0.98 MA 0.02 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.98 Br 0.02 ) 3 (where MA and FA denote methylammonium and formamidinium, respectively) and FcTc 2 surface treatment. Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) in Fig.  1B  demonstrates that most of the FcTc 2 was located on the surface of the perovskite film. We used x-ray diffraction (XRD), top-view SEM, and UV-vis absorption spectroscopy measurements to study the crystallinity, morphology, and optical absorption of perovskite films with and without FcTc 2 treatment (figs. S4 to S6). All of the samples showed no obvious changes, which indicates that FcTc 2 does not affect the crystallization and lightharvesting properties of perovskite films. The interaction of FcTc 2 with the perovskite was studied by comparing the x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements on the pristine and FcTc 2 -treated perovskite films (Fig.  1 , C to E). The binding energies corresponding to the Pb 4f, I 3d, and N 1s core levels of the FcTc 2 -treated perovskite films all shifted marginally to higher values compared with the control sample, suggesting enhanced binding of both anions and cations on the perovskite surface, which could be caused by strong binding between surface ions and FcTc 2  (17) . Density functional theory (DFT) simulation analyses were performed to study the interaction between the perovskite surface and FcTc 2 molecules. We chose the (001) PbI 2 -terminated perovskite surface as a model because it has been proven to be stable and to have the lowest energy configuration. Starting from the ordered interface, we observed enhanced bonding of O from FcTc 2 with Pb from the perovskite surface within a few picoseconds (Fig.  1,  F  and G ). With the interfacial rearrangement, the molecular dynamics reach a stable equilibrium state in which the bond length of Pb-O was simulated to be 2.65 Ã… (Fig.  1H ). The electrostatic potential (ESP) analysis (fig.  S7 ) indicated a high electronegativity (-29.79 kcal mol -1 ) of O in FcTc 2 , driving the formation of stable Pb-O bonds and substantially enhancing the electrostatic attraction between the perovskite and FcTc 2 interface. XPS analysis combined with DFT simulation proves that there is a strong interaction between perovskite and FcTc 2 , which is beneficial for both passivation of surface defects and stabilization of surface components in perovskite  (7, 18) . To study the effect of FcTc 2 on the electrical properties of perovskite films, we conducted kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) measurements to examine the surface potential of the films (Fig.  2, A  and B ). The perovskite film functionalized by FcTc 2 exhibited a decreased contact potential (~50 mV) relative to that of the control sample, which suggests direct interaction and surface charge transfer between FcTc 2 and perovskite  (18) . Moreover, FcTc 2functionalized perovskite displayed a smaller potential distribution and surface potential difference (~150 mV) compared with that of the control sample (~250 mV). A uniform distribution of surface contact potential was beneficial for effective charge carrier extraction to prevent nonradiative recombination  (19, 20) . The carrier kinetics characterization (figs. S8 and S9) on the perovskite-ETL interface further verifies the accelerated electron extraction with FcTc 2 modification, which can be attributed to the ferrocene and thiophene units  (21, 22) . Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra were measured to evaluate the nonradiative recombination of perovskite films (Fig.  2C ). The carrier lifetime nearly doubled from 1166.74 to 2159.22 ns after incorporating FcTc 2 (the fitted carrier lifetime is summarized in table  S1 ), which is consistent with enhanced steady-state photoluminescence intensity (fig.  S10 ), indicating reduced numbers of nonradiative recombination centers from the surface defects. Additionally, the space charge-limited current (SCLC) measurements (fig.  S12 ) further confirm the decreased defect density through FcTc 2 modification. In triple-cation mixed-halide perovskite, the chemically reactive components, such as MA + and I -at the perovskite surface, can easily volatilize and migrate through photo-and thermal effects. The surface trap states generate decreased photovoltaic performance degradation  (23, 24) . To estimate the effect of FcTc 2 on perovskite stability, the MA + cations of the control and FcTc 2 -functionalized perovskite films were probed by peak force infrared (PFIR) microscopy under illumination and heat conditions  (20) . The Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy spectra of the perovskite films confirmed that the signal of the MA ions in perovskite is distinct and readily resolved (fig.  S13 ). PFIR mapping showed that the intensity and distribution of MA + cations in the FcTc 2 -treated sample were well maintained after aging for 1000 hours (Fig.  2 , D and F), whereas the control sample exhibited substantial reduction of intensity and broadening of distribution of the MA signal (Fig.  2, E  and G ). These results indicate that FcTc 2 can prevent surface ions from migration to produce a more uniform and stable surface component distribution (Fig.  2H )  (25) . By contrast, ion migration and volatilization were more prone to occur in the control films, resulting in increased surface defects and affecting the operational stability of perovskite devices (fig.  S14 ). Measuring the perovskite films after &gt;1000 hours separately under con-tinuous 1-sun illumination or heating at 85Â°C also confirmed the stabilization effects of FcTc 2 on perovskite (figs. S15 and S16). Figure  3A  shows the current density-voltage (J-V) curves for control and FcTc 2 -functionalized devices under AM1.5G simulated solar illumination, in which the concentration of FcTc 2 was optimized to be 1.0 mg ml -1 to obtain the best performance (figs. S17 and S18 and table  S2 ). The control device exhibited a maximum PCE of 23.0%, with an open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.13 V, a short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 25.25 mA cm -2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 80.45%. Compared with the control device, the FcTc 2 -functionalized device exhibited an enhanced PCE of 25.0%, with an increased V OC of 1.184 V, a J SC of 25.68 mA cm -2 , and an FF of 82.32% with a low hysteresis (fig.  S19 ). Corresponding external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra (Fig.  3B ) yielded integrated J SC values with a small variation from the values obtained from J-V measurements.  devices were also measured at the maximum power point (MPP) to obtain a stabilized photocurrent of 23.68 mA cm -2 and a stabilized PCE of 24.2% (Fig.  3C ). One of the best-performing devices was validated by an independent solar cell-accredited laboratory (National Institute of Metrology, China) for certification, where a PCE of 24.3% (with V OC = 1.179 V, J SC = 25.59 mA cm -2 , and FF = 80.60%) was confirmed (fig.  S20 ), which is the highest certified efficiency among all inverted PSCs to date (table  S3 ). The PCEs also exhibited a satisfying reproducibility, with an average PCE of 22.5% for the control device and 24.5% for the FcTc 2based device (Fig.  3D ). The particular effectiveness of FcTc 2 is further verified in figs. S21 to S24 and table  S4 . Additionally, we conducted quantitative analysis of the photovoltage loss (V OC loss) for the control and FcTc 2 -treated devices accord-ing to detailed balance theory  (26) . The EQE EL values of 1.5 and 7.0% for the control device and the device with FcTc 2 , respectively, could be obtained from electroluminescence (EL) spectra (Fig.  3, E  and F ), leading to 108.57 and 68.75 mV of DV 3 (V OC loss from the nonradiative recombination), respectively. The relative lower DV 3 suggests that FcTc 2 suppresses nonradiative recombination as an interfacial modifier. The values of the three components of V OC loss (DV 1 , DV 2 , and DV 3 ) are calculated in the supplementary text and summarized in table  S5 . A V OC loss of 363 mV is one of the lowest values reported among inverted PSCs  (16, 26) . To investigate the effect of FcTc 2 functionalization on device stability, the efficiency evolution under various conditions was monitored. We first examined the long-term operational stability of unencapsulated devices by loading at MPP voltage under continuous 1-sun illumination in an N 2 atmosphere (Fig.  4A ). The FcTc 2 -functionalized device retained its initial PCE in the first 200 hours and only exhibited a decay of &lt;2% after &gt;1500 hours. In comparison, the control device decreased to 72% of its initial PCE. We further measured the stability of unencapsulated devices under heat and ambient conditions. As shown in figs. S27 and S28, the performance of the control devices dropped to &lt;80% of the initial efficiency after &gt;800 hours. By contrast, the    &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T09:38:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="1161" length="5"/>
        <text>p-i-n</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triaryl amine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:08:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="3881" length="19"/>
        <text>poly(triaryl amine)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triaryl amine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:08:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="3902" length="4"/>
        <text>PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:53:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="3924" length="4"/>
        <text>C 60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Pb(I0.98Br0.02)3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:08:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="4100" length="53"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 (FA 0.98 MA 0.02 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.98 Br 0.02 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:11:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="10068" length="5"/>
        <text>23.0%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.13</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:11:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="10115" length="6"/>
        <text>1.13 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:11:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="10314" length="5"/>
        <text>25.0%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.184</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:11:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="10347" length="7"/>
        <text>1.184 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">72</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T09:40:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="12679" length="3"/>
        <text>72%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12952</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12976</offset>
      <text> Materials Cesium iodide (CsI), formamidinium iodide (FAI) and methylammonium bromide (MABr) were purchased from Dysol (Australia). Lead iodide (PbI2), and lead bromide (PbBr2) were purchased from TCI (Japan). C60, poly[bis(4-phenyl)(2,4,6trimethylphenyl) amine] (PTAA) (Mn 6,000-15,000), methylammonium chloride (MACl) and bathocuproine (BCP, purity of 99.9%) were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corporation (China). Copper(I) thiophene-2-carboxylate (CuTC) was purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. The solvents, including dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), isopropanol (IPA) and chlorobenzene (CB) were purchased from J&amp;K (China) and used as received. Acetonitrile (MeCN), dichloromethane (DCM), and hexane were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich and used as received. High purity silver was purchased from commercial sources. Glass substrates patterned with indium tin oxide (ITO) (15 â„¦ sq -1 ) were received from Mishi Tech. Co., &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13932</offset>
      <text> Ltd. (China). Ferrocenyl-bis-thiophene-2-carboxylate (FcTc2) synthesis A solution of 1,1â€²-diiodoferrocene (FcI2) (synthesized according to previous report (  29 )) (0.70 g, 1.60 mmol), CuTC (1.2 g, 6.32 mmol) and 9,10-dihydroanthracene (synthesized according to previous report (  30 )) (0.60 g, 3.33 mmol) in MeCN (30 ml) was stirred at 80 o C for 2 days. After cooling to room temperature, DCM (50 ml) was added and the green-blue reaction mixture was filtered over Celite. The solvent was then removed, and the crude mixture was dissolved in hexane and passed through a pad of silica (ca. 5 cm), with the desired product eluting in 50% DCM in hexane. After solvent removal, FcTc2 was obtained as a yellow solid (0.17 g, 0.38 mmol, 24%).  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14677</offset>
      <text> Diphenylferrocene (FcPh2) synthesis FcPh2 was synthesized following the literature procedure  (31) . (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication Glass/ITO substrates (15 â„¦ sq -1 ) were sequentially cleaned by sonication with detergent, deionized water, acetone and isopropyl alcohol for 20 min, respectively. Then, the glass/ITO substrates were dried at 100 Â°C in an oven, and then were treated with oxygen plasma for 10 min and finally transferred into a N2-filled glovebox before use. The PTAA solution was prepared with a concentration of 2.2 mg ml -1 in CB. The 35 Î¼L as-prepared PTAA solution was spin-coated onto the ITO substrates at 6000 rpm for 30 s and the substrates were subsequently annealed at 100 Â°C for 10 min. The 1.73 M perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing CsI, FAI, MABr, PbI2 and PbBr2 in 1 ml DMF:DMSO (5:1/v:v) mixed solvent with a chemical formula of (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3, 5 mol% of excess PbI2 was needed to improve the device performance. Then 15.5 mol% MACl was added to the perovskite precursor solution and stirred for 2h. 60 Î¼L perovskite solutions were spin-coated onto glass/ITO/hole transporting layer (HTL) at 1000 rpm for 10 s, subsequently at 5000 rpm for 40 s. 250 Î¼L CB was slowly dripped onto the center of film at 12 s before the end of spin-coating. The as-prepared perovskite films were subsequently annealed on a hotplate at 110 â„ƒ for 20 min. For the FcTc2-based devices, FcTc2 powder was prepared and dissolved in CB at a concentration of 1 mg ml -1 . The as-prepared yellowish solution was stirred at room temperature (20-25 â„ƒ) until the solution became clear. The solution was then transferred to a N2-filled glovebox before use. 100 Î¼L of FcTc2 solution was spin-coated on top of the as-prepared perovskite at 5000 rpm for 20 s, and then transferred to the hotplate and annealed at 100 â„ƒ for 2 min. The spin-coating processes were all conducted at room temperature (20-25 â„ƒ) in a N2-filled glovebox with the contents of O2 and H2O &lt; 10 ppm. Finally, 20 nm C60 at a rate of 0.5 Ã… s -1 , 6 nm BCP a rate of 0.5 Ã… s -1 and 100 nm silver electrode a rate of 1.0 Ã… s -1 were thermally evaporated, respectively, under high vacuum (&lt; 4 Ã— 10 -6 Torr). The device area was defined and characterized as 0.08 cm 2 by metal shadow mask. The procedures of ITO/Glass substrate cleaning, and HTL deposit are consistent with (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. The 1.5 M perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing CsI, FAI, MABr, PbI2 and PbBr2 in 1 ml DMF:DMSO (5:1/v:v) mixed solvent with a chemical formula of (FA0.85MA0.15)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3, 10 mol% of excess PbI2 was needed to improve the device performance. 60 Î¼L perovskite solutions were spin-coated onto glass/ITO/HTL at 5000 rpm for 30 s. 250 Î¼L CB was slowly dripped onto the center of the film at 7 s before the end of spin-coating. The as-prepared perovskite films were subsequently annealed on a hotplate at 100 â„ƒ for 30 min. The procedures of FcTc2 interlayer deposition and metal electrode evaporation follow the description of (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T02:15:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="14779" length="40"/>
        <text>(FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17903</offset>
      <text> Stability tests The long-term operational stability was conducted by applying the perovskite solar cells (PSCs) under 1 sun equivalent LED lamp in a N2-filled glovebox (with the contents of O2 and H2O &lt;10 ppm) at room temperature (25 â„ƒ). The PSCs were biased at maximum-power-point (MPP) voltage and the power output was tracked by using a multi-potentiostat (CHI1040C, CH Instruments, Inc.). During the MPP test, the current density-voltage (J-V) curves of the devices were obtained every 12 h to get the proper loads for the MPP. Heat stability was assessed by applying the PSCs on the hotplate (HS 7, IKA) maintained at 85 â„ƒ in a N2-filled glovebox (with the contents of O2 and H2O &lt;10 ppm), the power conversion efficiency (PCE) evolutions of the devices were obtained through the periodical J-V measurement. The water and oxygen stability tests were carried out by applying the PSCs in ambient air (40-50% RH) without any light illumination, and the PCE evolutions of the devices were obtained through the periodical J-V measurement. For the stability tests following the IEC61215:2016 standard, the PSCs were encapsulated by polyisobutylene (PIB) based polymer (PVS 101Â®) and covered with 1.1-mm glass sheets on both sides of the devices. The damp heat test was conducted by keeping the encapsulated devices at 85 â„ƒ/85% RH in the environment test chamber (EL-10KA, ESPEC, Japan) for 1000 h. For the temperature cycling tests, the PSCs were placed in the environment test chamber (EL-04KA, ESPEC, Japan), with the temperature cycling between -40Â±2 â„ƒ to 85Â±2 â„ƒ. The temperature change rate between the -40 â„ƒ and 85 â„ƒ was set to not exceed 100 Â°C/h, and the temperature was stable for at least 15 min at the temperature point of -40 â„ƒ and 85 â„ƒ, respectively. The encapsulated devices were measured periodically in an N2-filled glove box after the devices cooling down. Characterizations X-ray diffraction (XRD) data were collected in the reflection mode at room temperature on a Philips X'Pert diffractometer equipped with a CPS 180 detector using monochromated Cu-KÎ± (Î» = 1.5418 A) radiation. The surface and cross-section morphology of the perovskite films were acquired by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) (QUATTROS, Thermal Fisher Scientific). X-ray photo-electron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements were conducted by AXIS Supra XPS system. Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) data were acquired via Bruker Dimension Kelvin probe force microscopy in Potential Channel equipped with PFQNE-AL probe. Peak force infrared (PFIR) measurements were carried out by a commercial Bruker NanoIR2-FS setup (testing range from 900 to 1800 cm -1 ) consisting of an atomic force microscopy (AFM) microscope operating in contact mode. Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy was conducted by Fourier transform infrared spectrometer (Tensor 27, Germany Bruker). The steady-state and time-resolved photoluminescence (PL) spectra were obtained by Edinburgh FLS980 applied with an excitation wavelength of 485 nm. The film thickness of perovskite obtained by DektakXT stylus profiler. Ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorptions were measured by a UV-vis spectrometer (PerkinElmermodel Lambda 2S). Time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectrometry (Tof-SIMS) measurements were performed using a TOF-SIMS V instrument (IONTOF GmbH, Cameca IMS 4F). The J-V characteristics of photovoltaic devices were conducted in a N2-filled glovebox at room temperature by using a Xenon lamp solar simulator (Enlitech, SS-F5, Taiwan). The power of the light was calibrated to 100 mW cm -2 by a silicon reference cell (with a KG2 filter). Before J-V measurements, a 120-nm thick magnesium fluoride layer was deposited on the back of ITO substrate for transmittance enhancement. All the devices were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under a sweep mode of reverse scan (from 1.20 V to -0.01 V) and forward scan (from -0.01 V to 1.20 V) with the scan rate of 0.01 V s -1 , and the delay time was 10 ms. No pre-conditioning was needed before measurement. The stabilized power output was conducted by monitoring the stabilized current density output at the MPP bias (extracted from the reverse scan J-V curves). External quantum efficiency (EQE) measurements were carried out using a QE-R EQE system (Enlitech, Taiwan). Highly sensitive EQE was measured by an integrated system (PECT-600, Enlitech, Taiwan), where the photocurrent was amplified and modulated by a lock-in instrument. Electroluminescence (EL) quantum efficiency (EQEEL) was conducted by applying external voltage/current sources through the instrument (ELCT-3010, Enlitech, Taiwan).  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22557</offset>
      <text> Density functional theory (DFT) calculations DFT calculations based on ab initio molecular dynamics were performed to evaluate the interaction between FcTc2 and the (001) PbI2-terminated perovskite surface using the Vienna Ab initio Simulation Package (version 5.4.4) with projectoraugmented-wave (PAW) pseudopotentials and PBE functional  (32, 33) . The energy cutoff for plane waves of the Kohn-Sham states was set at 400 eV. Molecular dynamic (MD) simulation was performed within the canonical ensemble NVT under a constant temperature of 300 K. The time step was 2 fs and the gamma point was applied to sample the Brillouin zone. Each trajectory was extracted every 50 fs until 100 ps after thermal equilibrium. The optimization of the ground-state geometry for the FcTc2 molecule was performed with B3LYP functional and 6-31g(d,p) basis set using Gaussian16 package  (34) . The analysis of electrostatic potential (ESP) was performed within Multiwfn program  (35, 36) . The isosurface of van der Waals (vdW) surface was set as 0.001 e/bohr 3 . be calculated to 1.71Ã—10 15 and 7.14Ã—10 14 cm -3 for the control device and device with FcTc2, respectively. Carrier mobility calculation: The electron-only devices with the configurations of ITO/TiO2/perovskite/FcTc2/C60/BCP/Ag and ITO/TiO2/perovskite/C60/BCP/Ag were fabricated to calculate the electron mobilities. As shown in Fig.  S8 , the J-V curve can be defined as three regions, which are Ohmic region (n=1), trap-filled region and the Child region (n=2). n represents the slope of linear region. The carrier mobility can be calculated by fitting the child region to the Mott-Gurney law: ğ½ = 9ğœ€ğœ€ 0 ğœ‡ğ‘‰ 2 8ğ¿ 3 (S2), where Îµ and Îµ0 are the relative dielectric constant and vacuum permittivity, respectively. ğœ‡ is the carrier mobility, V is the onset voltage of TFL region, L represents perovskite thin film thickness. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24457</offset>
      <text> Photovoltage loss (VOC,loss) calculation The detailed VOC,loss can be described by the equation listed below: ğ‘âˆ†ğ‘‰ = ğ¸ ğ‘” -ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ = (ğ¸ ğ‘” -ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) + (ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ -ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ ) + (ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ -ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ) = (ğ¸ ğ‘” -ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ + ğ‘âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) + âˆ†ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ + âˆ†ğ‘ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘›ğ‘œğ‘›-ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ = ğ‘(âˆ†ğ‘‰ 1 + âˆ†ğ‘‰ 2 + âˆ†ğ‘‰ 3 ) (S3) where q, âˆ†V, Eg is the elementary charge, the total voltage loss, and the bandgap of perovskite, respectively. VOC SQ is the Shockley-Queisser limit of open circuit voltage, VOC rad is the VOC without non-radiative recombination occurring in PSCs, âˆ†VOC SQ is the VOC loss due to the non-ideal EQE above the bandgap, âˆ†VOC rad is the VOC loss due to the sub-bandgap radiative recombination, and âˆ† V OC non-rad is the VOC loss of nonradiative recombination. As a consequence, the energy loss can be divided into three parts, Î”V1, Î”V2 and Î”V3, which represent radiative recombination above Eg, energy loss from blackbody radiation and voltage loss induced by the nonradiative recombination, respectively. The photovoltaic bandgap (Eg, PV) of 1.548 eV can be obtained from the inflection point of the EQE spectra by locating the maximum point (ğœ† ğ‘” ) of the Gaussian-like derivate ğœ•ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸/ğœ•ğœ† (37) (Fig.  S25 ). Eg, PV was defined as the mean peak energy at the absorption edge of the distribution, and it should be considered as a convention for the determination of bandgap energy to any solar cells. Since it represents an external property of a photovoltaic device and not an internal property of a photovoltaic material (e.g. extracted from the Tauc plot), it is more precise to estimate a bandgap for a solar cell device  (38) . According to a previous report  (39) , the VOC of a solar cell can be calculated by the equation: ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ½ 0 ) (S5) where ğ‘ , ğ‘˜ ğµ , ğ‘‡ , JSC, J0, represents the element charge, Boltzmann constant, temperature, short-circuit current, and dark saturation current, respectively. The JSC and J0 can be described as: ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ = ğ‘ âˆ« ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ (ğ¸)ğœ™ ğ´ğ‘€1.5 (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ 0 (S6) ğ½ 0 = ğ‘ ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ¸ğ¿ âˆ« ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ (ğ¸)ğœ™ ğµğµ (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ 0 (S7) ğœ™ ğµğµ (ğ¸) = 2ğœ‹ğ¸ 2 â„ 3 ğ‘ 2 1 exp( ğ¸ ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ )-1 (S8) where ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ , ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ¸ğ¿ is photovoltaic external quantum efficiency and electroluminescence external quantum efficiency, respectively. ğœ™ ğ´ğ‘€1.5 , ğœ™ ğµğµ is solar cell radiative spectrum and black-body radiative spectrum, respectively. ğ‘ is light speed in vacuum. According to the Schokley-Queisser limit (S-Q limit): (1) The ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ is described with Heaviside step function, where ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ (ğ¸) = { 1, ğ¸ â‰¥ ğ¸ ğ‘” 0, ğ¸ &lt; ğ¸ ğ‘” ; (2) only the photons with energy larger than bandgap (ğ¸ ğ‘” ) are absorbed; (3) all recombination is radiative (ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ¸ğ¿ = 1). Therefore, JSC and J0 in S-Q limit can be written as: ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ = ğ‘ âˆ« ğœ™ ğ´ğ‘€1.5 (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ ğ¸ ğ‘” (S9) ğ½ 0 ğ‘†ğ‘„ = ğ‘ âˆ« ğœ™ ğµğµ (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ ğ¸ ğ‘” (S10) Therefore, VOC in S-Q limit is: ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ ğ½ 0 ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) (S11) Considering the theory of S-Q limit, ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ can be degraded to VOC with three components of loss. The first VOC loss component is due to the non-ideal ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ , which is less than 100%. In this situation, short-circuit current is expressed as: ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ = ğ‘ âˆ« ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ (ğ¸)ğœ™ ğ´ğ‘€1.5 (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ 0 (S12) The âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ was calculated as below: The PSCs with and without FcTc2 show similar Î”V1 of ~274 mV. As the EQE of the device protrudes into the area below Eg and brings about more black-body radiation, we characterized the highly-sensitive EQE below bandgap to calculate âˆ†V2 (Fig.  S26 ). âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ = The calculated âˆ†V2 is 20.67 mV and 31.50 mV for the FcTc2-based and control devices, respectively. Î”V3 is the VOC loss from the non-radiative recombination, which can be deduced using the equation S22, where EQEEL is the EQE of electroluminescence (EL). The Î”V3 of control PSC and PSC incorporated with FcTc2 can be calculated to 108.57 and 68.75 mV, respectively.                  S2 .   S2 .           &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29131</offset>
      <text> Note: The parameters listed in parentheses are the best performing devices (refer to Fig.  S17 ). The plus-minus sign (Â±) represents the standard deviation. Note: the "p-i-n" structure device was defined as the hole collected at the bottom transparent conducting oxide electrode.  FcTc 2 -treated Li et al., Science 376, 416-420 (2022 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29469</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Metal halide perovskite surface functionalized by FcTc 2 . (A) Schematic illustration of inverted PSC based on FcTc 2 as the interface functionalization material. BCP, bathocuproine; ITO, indium tin oxide. (B) TOF-SIMS characterization of the PSC. (C to E) XPS characterization of Pb element (C), I element (D), and N element (E) on the perovskite film with and without FcTc 2 . a.u., arbitrary units. (F to H) Molecular dynamics simulations of the interaction between perovskite and FcTc 2 . L, bond length. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29999</offset>
      <text> 5 Fig. 2 . 52 Fig. 2. Characterization of film surface properties. (A and B) Surface potential images were obtained by scanning KPFM of the control and FcTc 2treated perovskite films. The statistical potential distributions of film surfaces are shown at the bottom. CPD, contact potential difference. (C) TRPL characterization of control and FcTc 2 -treated perovskite films. PL, photo- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30388</offset>
      <text> FcTc 2 5 Fig. 4 . 254 Fig. 4. Stability measurements of PSCs. (A) Normalized PCE of the unencapsulated PSCs with or without FcTc 2 measured at MPP under continuous 1-sun illumination in an N 2 atmosphere and at room temperature. (B and C) Normalized PCE of the PSCs with or without FcTc 2 measured following the IEC61215:2016 standards. (B) Encapsulated devices stored in 85% RH and 85Â°C in the dark. (C) Encapsulated devices stored in -40Â°C (15-min dwell) to 85Â°C (15-min dwell), ramp rate of 100Â°C hour -1 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30904</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Photovoltaic performance of PSCs. (A) J-V curves of the bestperforming devices with and without FcTc 2 . (B) EQE spectra and integrated current densities of the best-performing devices with and without FcTc 2 . (C) Stabilized power output at the MPP for the best-performing PSCs treated &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31212</offset>
      <text> 1 H nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) (400 MHz, CDCl3, 298 K): Î´ (ppm) 7.78 (dd, J = 3.7, 1.3 Hz, 2H, Thio-H), 7.56 (dd, J = 5.0, 1.3 Hz, 2H, Thio-H), 7.06 (dt, J = 5.0, 3.7 Hz, 2H, Thio-H), 4.68 (t, J = 2.0 Hz, 4H, (CpTc)m-H), 4.10 (t, J = 2.0 Hz, 4H, (CpTc)o-H). 13 C{ 1 H} NMR (100 MHz, CDCl3, 298 K): Î´ (ppm) 160.3 (2C, C=O), 134.2 (2C, ThioC-H), 133.3 (2C, ThioC-CO2Fc), 133.2 (2C, ThioC-H), 128.0 (2C, ThioC-H), 116.6 (2C, CpC-O), 64.8 (4C, (CpTc)o-C-H), 62.2 (4C, (CpTc)m-C-H). MS ES+: m/z 437.9677 ([M]+ Calc.: 437.9683). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31745</offset>
      <text> MAPbI3-based device fabricationThe procedures of ITO/Glass substrate cleaning, and HTL deposit are consistent with (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. The MAPbI3 precursor solution was prepared by mixing 1.55 M MAI, and 1.63 M PbI2 in 1 ml DMF:DMSO (5:1/v:v) mixed solvent, and stirring for 2h before use. 60 Î¼L perovskite solutions were spin-coated onto glass/ITO/HTL at 2000 rpm for 10 s, subsequently at 6000 rpm for 30 s. 250 Î¼L CB was slowly dripped onto the center of the film at 7 s before the end of spin-coating. The as-prepared perovskite films were subsequently annealed on a hotplate at 100 â„ƒ for 30 min. The procedures of FcTc2 interlayer deposition and metal electrode evaporation follow the description of (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. FAPbI3-based device fabrication The procedures of ITO/Glass substrate cleaning, and HTL deposit are consistent with (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. The FAPbI3 precursor solution was prepared by mixing 2 M FAI, and 2.06 M PbI2 in 1 ml DMF:DMSO (8:1/v:v) mixed solvent. Then 35 mol% of MACl was added to the perovskite precursor solution and stirred for 2h. 60 Î¼L perovskite solutions were spincoated onto glass/ITO/HTL at 6000 rpm for 40 s. 250 Î¼L CB was slowly dripped onto the center of the film at 25 s before the end of spin-coating. The as-prepared perovskite films were subsequently annealed on a hotplate at 135 â„ƒ for 1 h. The procedures of FcTc2 interlayer deposition and metal electrode evaporation follow the description of (FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.95Br0.02)3-based device fabrication. (FA0.85MA0.15)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3-based device fabrication &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33475</offset>
      <text> 1 H 1 and 13 C{ 1 H} NMR spectra were recorded on a Bruker Avance 400 MHz spectrometer and referenced to the residual solvent peaks of either CDCl3 at 7.26 and 77.2 ppm or CD2Cl2 at 5.32 or 54.0 ppm, respectively. 1 H-NMR spectra were fully assigned using 2D correlation spectroscopy. Coupling constants are measured in Hz. Mass spectrometry analyses were conducted by Dr. Lisa Haigh of the Mass Spectrometry Service, Imperial College London. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33920</offset>
      <text> Fig. S1 . S1 Fig. S1. UV-vis absorption spectrum of FcTc2 dissolved in chlorobenzene. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34008</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. UV-vis absorption spectrum of FcTc2 thin film spin-coated on glass substrate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34110</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Cross-section SEM image of fabricated inverted PSC with a structure of ITO/PTAA/perovskite/FcTc2/C60/BCP/Ag. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34243</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. XRD patterns of FcTc2, pristine perovskite film, and perovskite thin films modified with different concentrations of FcTc2 (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34420</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. SEM images of pristine perovskite film and perovskite films modified with different concentrations of FcTc2 (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34582</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. UV-vis absorption spectra of pristine perovskite film, and perovskite films with different concentrations of FcTc2 incorporation (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34765</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Electrostatic potential (ESP) analysis of FcTc2, in which the electronegativity of O, S and H atoms is -29.79 kcal mol -1 , -8.12 kcal mol -1 and 15.16 kcal mol -1 , respectively. The high electronegativity of O drives the formation of stable Pb-O bonds and significantly enhances the electrostatic attraction between the perovskite and FcTc2 interface. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35143</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. SCLC plots of perovskite films (A) with and (B) without FcTc2 based on an electron-only device (ITO/TiO2/perovskite/C60/BCP/Ag). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35296</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. TRPL spectra of perovskite/FcTc2/C60 and perovskite/C60. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35377</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Steady-state PL spectra of pristine perovskite film and perovskite films with different concentrations of FcTc2 (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ) excited via a laser with the wavelength of 485 nm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35596</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. SCLC plots of perovskite films (A) with and (B) without FcTc2 based on a hole-only device (ITO/PTAA/perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/MoO3/Ag). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35757</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. FTIR characterization of FAPbI3, MAPbI3, and FcTc2-modified CsFAMA perovskite films before and after heating. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35894</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. XRD pattern of the pristine perovskite film and perovskite film treated by FcTc2 before and after 200 h heat/light aging, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36057</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. PFIR microscopy at an IR frequency of 1480 cm -1 (which is resonant with the C-N stretching absorption of MA + ion) of FcTc2-modified perovskite films (A) and control (B) after heating (continues 85 â„ƒ) treatment for 1000 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36314</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. PFIR microscopy at an IR frequency of 1480 cm -1 (which is resonant with the C-N stretching absorption of MA + ion) of FcTc2-modified perovskite films (A) and control (B) after 1-sun illumination treatment for 1000 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36563</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. Photovoltaic performance of the best performing control devices and devices with different concentrations of FcTc2 (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ). The photovoltaic parameters are summarized in TableS2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36790</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. Statistics of key photovoltaic parameters (open-circuit voltage (VOC), fill factor (FF), short-circuit current density (JSC), PCE) obtained from the J-V characteristic of 20 control devices, and devices modified with different concentrations of FcTc2 (0.5, 1.0 and 2.0 mg ml -1 ). The average value and standard deviation of each parameter is summarized in TableS2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37183</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. J-V curve of the best performing FcTc2-based device under reverse and forward scans. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37295</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. Independent efficiency certification of perovskite solar cells by an accredited institute of National Institute of Metrology (NIM, China), giving a PCE of 24.3% (short-circuit current (ISC) of 2.077 mA, VOC of 1.179 V and FF of 80.6%, reverse scan), which is among the highest values of the certified efficiency for inverted perovskite solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37671</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. (A) J-V curves of the best performing MAPbI3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. The photovoltaic parameters are summarized in Table S4. (B) Histograms of the PCE values among 20 devices of MAPbI3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37957</offset>
      <text> Fig. S22 . S22 Fig. S22. (A) J-V curves of the best performing PSCs of (FA0.85MA0.15)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. The photovoltaic parameters are summarized in Table S4. (B) Histograms of the PCE values among 20 devices of (FA0.85MA0.15)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38319</offset>
      <text> Fig. S23 . S23 Fig. S23. (A) J-V curves of the best performing PSCs of FAPbI3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. The photovoltaic parameters are summarized in Table S4. (B) Histograms of the PCE values among 20 devices of FAPbI3-based PSCs with and without FcTc2, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38613</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. J-V curve and photovoltaic performance of the PSCs treated with ferrocenebased control diphenylferrocene (FcPh2), inset is the molecular structure of FcPh2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38797</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. Eg, PV estimation obtained from the inflection point of the EQE spectra by locating the maximum point (ğœ† ğ‘” ) of the Gaussian-like derivate ğœ•ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸/ğœ•ğœ†. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38996</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 .Fig. S27 . S26S27 Fig. S26. Highly sensitive EQE of control PSCs and FcTc2-based PSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39094</offset>
      <text> Fig. S28 . S28 Fig. S28. Stability test based on unencapsulated devices with and without FcTc2 stored in ambient air (40-50% RH, 25 â„ƒ) in the dark. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39246</offset>
      <text> The second VOC loss component originates from the energy loss related with extra thermal radiation of solar cell in dark. The ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ extends into the sub-bandgap region, where the black-body radiation increases with the photo energy lowering. Thus, this sub-bandgap ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ increased the dark saturation current. The short-circuit current ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ is equal to ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ , and dark saturation current in this condition are written as: ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ - ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ 0 ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ‘†ğ‘„ ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ) (S13) ğ½ 0 ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ = ğ‘ âˆ« ğ¸ğ‘„ğ¸ ğ‘ƒğ‘‰ (ğ¸)ğœ™ ğµğµ (ğ¸) ğ‘‘ğ¸ âˆ 0 (S14) therefore, the radiative VOC loss, âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ , is: âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ 0 ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) - ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ½ 0 ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ ) = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ 0 ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ ğ½ 0 ğ‘†ğ‘„ ) (S15) The third VOC loss component, âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘›ğ‘œğ‘›ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ , which is attributed to the non-radiative recombination in the device, can be calculated as: âˆ†ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ ğ‘›ğ‘œğ‘›ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ = ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ 0 ğ½ ğ‘†ğ¶ ğ‘Ÿğ‘ğ‘‘ ) -ğ‘‰ ğ‘‚ğ¶ (S16) According to Equation S6 and S13, ğ½ 0 rad = EQE EL â‹… ğ½ 0 , so combining Equation S4, Equation S17 can be rewritten as: âˆ†ğ‘‰ OC nonrad = ğ‘˜ B ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( EQE EL â‹… ğ½ 0 ğ½ SC ) - ğ‘˜ B ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln ( ğ½ SC ğ½ 0 ) = - ğ‘˜ B ğ‘‡ ğ‘ ln(EQE EL ) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40845</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 The fitted carrier lifetime of perovskite films obtained from the TRPL measurements (refer to Fig.2C). The average lifetime can be calculated with the equation of:ğœ ğ‘ğ‘£ğ‘” = (ğ´ 1 ğœ 1 2 + ğ´ 2 ğœ 2 2 )/(ğ´ 1 ğœ 1 + ğ´ 2 ğœ 2 ), where parameters A1 and A2 are the amplitude fraction for each decay component, and ğœ 1 and ğœ 2 represent the time constant of the two types of decay. Ï„1 (ns) Ï„2 (ns) Ï„ave (ns) Control 98.11 1173.63 1166.74 FcTc2 440.22 2187.88 2159.22 Note: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41366</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Summary of key photovoltaic parameters of PSCs and PSCs incorporated with different concentrations of FcTc2 (extracted from Figs. S17 and S18). VOC (V) JSC (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Control 1.130Â±0.011 (1.133) 24.95Â±0.40 (25.25) 79.89Â±0.81 (80.45) 22.5Â±0.4 (23.0) 0.5 mg ml -1 1.138Â±0.011 (1.143) 24.93Â±0.50 (25.33) 79.72Â±1.24 (80.48) 22.6Â±0.5 (23.3) 1.0 mg ml -1 1.178Â±0.007 (1.184) 25.40Â±0.20 (25.68) 81.80Â±1.09 (82.32) 24.5Â±0.4 (25.0) 2.0 mg ml -1 1.150Â±0.013 (1.146) 25.62Â±0.28 (24.82) 77.03Â±1.14 (78.84) 21.8Â±0.4 (22.4) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41924</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 Summary of high-performance p-i-n structure perovskite solar cells. 479 Year Strategy Certified Efficiency Reference Novel inorganic 2015 charge extraction 15.0% (40) layer Perovskite-fullerene 2016 graded heterojunction 18.2% (41) engineering Quaternary 2017 ammonium halides for defects 20.6% (42) passivation Solution-processed 2018 secondary growth 20.9% (14) technique 2020 Novel electron-extraction layer 21.3% (9) Managing grains and 2020 interfaces via ligand 22.3% (8) anchoring Novel molecule 2020 designed for defects 22.8% (16) passivation 2021 Perovskite precursor engineering 22.6% (43) 2022 Perovskite surface modification 23.5% (44) Interfacial modulation 2022 by organometallic-functionalized 24.3% This work interfaces &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42677</offset>
      <text> Table S5 . S5 Results of calculated VOC loss in the control PSCs and FcTc2-based PSCs.VOC is the value extracted from J-V curve VOC * is the value based on the Eg,PV and VOC,loss Device Eg,PV VOC,SQ VOC Î”V1 Î”V2 Î”V3 VOC,loss VOC * (eV) (V) (V) (mV) (mV) (mV) (mV) (V) Control 1.548 1.276 1.133 274.07 31.50 108.57 414.14 1.134 FcTc2 1.548 1.276 1.184 273.63 20.67 68.75 363.05 1.185 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43064</offset>
      <text>			 of 5 RESEARCH | REPORT Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T09:41:23Z</infon>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="5" role=""/>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
      <node refid="15" role=""/>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="11" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
