<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025033337BHBBHE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 57&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Large-Grain Double Cation Perovskites with 18 μs Lifetime and High Luminescence Yield for Efficient Inverted Perovskite Solar Cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>145</offset>
      <text>Recent advancements in perovskite solar cell performance were achieved by stabilizing the α-phase of FAPbI 3 in nip-type architectures. However, these advancements could not be directly translated to pin-type devices. Here, we fabricated a high-quality double cation perovskite (MA 0.07 FA 0.93 PbI 3 ) with low bandgap energy (1.54 eV) using a two-step approach on a standard polymer (PTAA). The perovskite films exhibit large grains (∼1 μm), high external photoluminescence quantum yields of 20%, and outstanding Shockley-Read-Hall carrier lifetimes of 18.2 μs without further passivation. The exceptional optoelectronic quality of the neat material was translated into efficient pin-type cells (up to 22.5%) with improved stability under illumination. The low-gap cells stand out by their high fill factor (∼83%) due to reduced charge transport losses and short-circuit currents &gt;24 mA cm -2 . Using intensity-dependent quasi-Fermi level splitting measurements, we quantify an implied efficiency of 28.4% in the neat material, which can be realized by minimizing interfacial recombination and optical losses.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T11:51:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="345" length="3"/>
        <text>pin</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MA0.07FA0.93PbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T11:51:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="424" length="21"/>
        <text>MA 0.07 FA 0.93 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triarylamine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:08:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="531" length="4"/>
        <text>PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1264</offset>
      <text>H alide perovskites offer exciting opportunities to efficiently harvest the energy from the sun either in single junction solar cells or in combination with well-established photovoltaic (PV) technologies as tandem devices.  1  The materials family with chemical structure ABX 3 is intrinsically low-cost, can be easily processed from either solution or low-temperature evaporation, and thus shows significant potential for commercial-scale applications.  2  Halideperovskite-based solar cells are fabricated typically by sandwiching a roughly 500 nm thick perovskite absorber layer between two charge transport layers (TLs), either in the nip-or pin-structure, depending on the arrangement of the pand n-type TL. While perovskite solar cells were first demonstrated in a nip-configuration in a dye-sensitized solar cell,  3  solid-state perovskite cells were established soon afterward in both nip-and pin-structures.  4, 5  Both architectures have been intensively investigated over the last 10 years with nip-cells yielding a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of over 20% in 2015,  6  which was achieved with the pin-type in 2017.  7, 8  This achievement was attributed mainly to the introduction of various cations and halides into the perovskite lattice. For example, formamidinium (FA), Cs, and Rb have been proposed as alternative or additional cations.  9, 10  At the same time, Br was used in addition to I to tune the band gap energy  10, 11  and to increase the tolerance to oxidation,  12  among other reasons. After passing the 20% PCE landmark, efforts to lower the bandgap of the mixed perovskite compositions have been ramped up to optimize the trade-off between photon absorption and thermalization losses.  13  For lead halide perovskites, this was achieved by increasing the molar concentration of formamindium lead iodide (FAPI).  [13] [14] [15] [16]  We note that incorporation of tin, in particular, mixed Pb/Snbased perovskites, enables much lower bandgaps (∼1.2 eV);  17, 18  however, here, we focus on Pb-based perovskites. Notably, pure FAPbI 3 suffers from the presence of a photoinactive, hexagonal "yellow" δ-phase, which is more stable at room temperature compared to the trigonal black αphase.  19  However, these problems were mitigated through various approaches. For example, small amounts of Cs, 20 methylammonium (MA),  15, 21  or MAPbBr 3  13, 16, 22  were used to stabilize the α-phase of FAPbI 3 . In other works, Cl was added to improve the nucleation and crystallization processes, which improved the performance and reproducibility.  [22] [23] [24]  Altogether, these efforts allowed impressive PCE improvements (e.g., 23% in 2018,  16  above 24% in 2019,  25  and 25.5%  26  today) and also led to improved device stabilities, likely due to a decrease of the molar concentration of Br and MA. Compared to one of the best cells in 2016 (ref 9) with a short-circuit current-density (J SC ) of 22.8 mA cm -2 , the performance improvement in the above publications was largely due to a significant J SC increase, e.g., 26.7 mA cm -2 was achieved in ref 25. Most of the top-performing nip-type cells employed perovskites with a molar FAPI concentration of 95% or even more,  13, 16, 22, 23, 25  delivering short-circuit currents of ≥25 mA cm -2 , underlining the importance of lowering the bandgap toward the optimum regime in the Shockley-Queisser (S.-Q.) limit (1.1-1.4 eV). Interestingly, however, these improvements were all achieved in nip-type cells. Similar efforts to lower the bandgap in pin-type cells were not quite as successful. This resulted in a slower increase of the PCE (e.g., 20.4% in 2017  8  to 20.9%  27  in 2018), with only two recent examples with a certified PCE above 22%.  28, 29  In the latter publication, Zheng et al.  29  showed that addition of long surface-anchoring alkylamine ligands promotes favorable grain orientation, which improved the p e r f o r m a n c e o f t r i p l e c a t i o n p e r o v s k i t e s Cs 0.05 (FA 0.92 MA 0.08 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.92 Br 0.08 ) 3 with a bandgap of 1.56 eV as obtained from a Tauc plot. Nevertheless, the J SC (24.1 mA cm -2 ) was slightly lower than in the above-mentioned record nip-type cells (≥25 mA cm -2 ). Similarly, in ref 30, the fabricated low-gap (1.55 eV) double cation/double halide MA 5 FA 95 Pb(I 95 Br 5 ) 3 pin-type cell had a comparatively low J SC (23.5 mA cm -2 ). This raises the important question as to why the formation of low-gap (∼1.53 eV) perovskites with a FAPI concentration of roughly 95% did not yield similar performance improvements in pin-type cells. Clearly, the lower J SC could be related to an imperfect film formation on standard ptype transport layers, such as PTAA or polyTPD, resulting in an inferior perovskite morphology. However, it may also be conceivable that the overall lower performance is related to a higher concentration of interfacial defects and/or due to a more unfavorable energetic alignment between the FA-rich perovskites and the transport layers typically employed in pintype cells, causing more open-circuit voltage (V OC ) losses.  31, 32  Being able to exploit the full potential of almost pure FAPI perovskites in a pin-architecture would greatly increase the possibilities to fabricate efficient and stable perovskite cells as recently demonstrated.  29, 33  Moreover, pin-cells typically require only very thin TLs, e.g., 8 nm of PTAA as a hole TL and 20-30 nm of C 60 as an electron TL  8  or ultrathin (∼1 nm) self-assembled monolayers (ref 30), without the need for chemical-doping or high-temperature treatments during fabrication (100-150 °C). In the present work, we fabricated FA-rich (93%) low-gap double cation pin-type perovskite cells with short-circuit currents of up to 25 mA cm -2 , which are significantly larger than in comparable triple cation perovskite cells. The double cation perovskite is thereby fabricated via a two-step process on a conventional PTAA p-type layer, which resulted in large grains with an average diameter of nearly 1 μm. The resulting perovskite cells enabled not only significant short-circuit current-density (J SC ) improvements but also exceptional fill factors (FFs) of up to 83%. To investigate the reason behind these high fill factors, we measured the FF in the absence of transport limitations via light-intensity-dependent open-circuit voltage measurements. The results demonstrated that the better FF in the double cation perovskite cells is a direct consequence of the optimized charge transport compared to the triple cation cell. Despite these promising results, compared with the radiative V OC limit, the open-circuit voltage losses in the double cation cells were quite significant (∼170 mV). To analyze the recombination losses, we quantified the quasi-Fermi level splitting in various stack layers of the cells following a previously reported approach. We find that both transport layers induce large recombination losses at the p-and the n-interfaces, which exceed the bulk recombination by a factor of 150 in the case of the perovskite/electron TLinterface. Nevertheless, the neat material exhibits an outstanding external photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) of 20% with an unprecedented charge carrier lifetime of 18 μs. Using intensity-dependent quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) measurements, we quantify a large efficiency potential (implied PCE) of 28.4% in the neat material, and we discuss the necessary steps to realize this potential. Following our recent work on triple cation (TC) perovskite solar cells in a pin-structure, with PTAA and C 60 as hole and electron transport layer, respectively, we first aimed to lower the bandgap to optimize the trade-off between photocurrent collection and thermalization losses. Our reference triple cation p e r o v s k i t e h a s a n o m i n a l c o m p o s i t i o n o f Cs 0.05 (FA 0.83 MA 0.17 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 with a bandgap of 1.63 eV, which we call here 83:17 triple cation.  10  We note that in the literature, different approaches exist to estimate the bandgap of a semiconductor.  34  Here, we follow the method proposed by Kirchartz et al.  35  by taking the peak of the derivative of the EQE. However, we note bandgaps obtained from the Tauc plot result in nearly identical values. Using experimentally measured input parameters, such as the recombination rate constants in the perovskite, interface recombination velocities (S = 100 and 2000 cm/s at the PTAA-and C 60 -interfaces, respectively) and bulk lifetime (τ bulk = 500 ns), energy levels, mobilities, and the perovskite density of states, we were recently able to model these solar cells.  36  In particular, we could reproduce the ideality factor  37  and previously determined interfacial and bulk recombination currents in the 83:17 triple cation cell.  31  Based on this set of simulation parameters, we varied the bandgap of the absorber layer by keeping the energy levels of the transport layers aligned with the perovskite. The results are shown in Figure  1a . Interestingly, for all simulations with realistic recombination properties and as well for optimized recombination parameters (S = 10 cm/s at both interfaces, τ bulk = 10 μs), we found that the optimum bandgap (∼1.36-1.53 eV) is considerably different than expected from the S.-Q. model (1.12-1.4 eV), as indicated by the dashed circles in Figure  1a . Therefore, a slight decrease of the bandgap with respect to methylammonium lead iodide (MAPI, 1.6 eV) would put the bandgap of the cell into an optimal regime for perovskites with finite and realistic recombination parameters. In order to lower the bandgap experimentally, we first increased the ratio of FAPbI 3 vs MAPbBr 3 to 95 and even 100% in triple cation cells Cs 0.05 (FA x MA y ) 0.95 Pb(I x Br y ) 3 by keeping the CsPbI 3 molar concentration at 5%. Doing so lowers the bandgap from 1.63 eV for the 83:17 triple cation to 1.57 eV for the 95:5 triple cation and 1.53 eV for the Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 PbI 3 (100:0 CsFA) perovskite as shown by the Tauc plots in the Supporting Information (Supplementary Figure  S1 ). Figure  1b  shows the obtained photovoltaic performance parameters. Unfortunately, we observe that the short-circuit current does not significantly increase with increasing FA content. In combination with the expected drop in open-circuit voltage with decreasing bandgap, the PCE continuously drops with increasing FAPI content. This rather unsuccessful attempt illustrates the above-mentioned challenges to achieve significant performance improvements in triple cation pin-type perovskite cells by lowering the bandgap &lt;1.6 eV, although this does not mean that it is generally not possible.  28, 29  In order to overcome these limitations, we fabricated lowgap, FA-rich perovskite cells using a two-step fabrication process following the description in ref 22. In particular, Brfree MA 0.07 FA 0.93 PbI 3 double cation (DC) perovskites were prepared with a nominal molar FA concentration of 93%, without considering the MACl. Briefly, in this two-step process, the solution consisting of MA and FA cations is spin-coated on top of the PbI 2 layer, which forms the perovskite layer after the cations diffuse through the PbI 2 (all fabrication details are presented in the Supplementary Methods and a Supplementary Video). The sample is then annealed in air at a relative humidity of roughly 25%, which is critical for obtaining the high PLQY of the neat material, which will be discussed further below in detail (Supplementary Figure  S2 ). It is interesting to note that for this particular perovskite composition, cells based on the two-step interdiffusion method outperformed cells fabricated from identical precursors using a one-step solvent assisted process (Supplementary Figure  S3  and Supplementary Table  S1 ). We also found that adding Br to the double cation perovskite by replacing the MAI precursor with MABr, using otherwise the exact same recipe, did not improve the performance. Nevertheless, in this work, we do not aim to make general conclusions as to whether a double cation perovskite composition is better than a triple cation composition nor that a two-step process is generally better than a one-step process. To analyze the optoelectronic properties of the (two-step) DC system, we first characterized the optical properties of the perovskite absorber layer. Supplementary Figure  S1  shows the Tauc plot of the neat perovskite film, which demonstrates a bandgap of 1.54 eV, which is in agreement with the literature.  15  Notably, the bandgap is close to the Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 PI 3 perovskite (1.53 eV). As shown in Supplementary Figure  S4 , this is also consistent with the peak of the first derivative of the EQE (1.54 eV), which reflects the peak of bandgap distribution and confirms the comparatively low bandgap in the final cell. Moreover, the Urbach tail as estimated by an exponential fit to the EQE tails exhibits a value of 15 meV. The sharp absorption onset corresponds to low radiative recombination losses  38, 39  and underlines the high optoelectronic semiconductor quality suitable for solar cell applications. In the following and throughout the rest of the manuscript, we compare the fabricated double cation cells to 95:5 triple cation cells, as similar compositions [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 :(MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 ] (often without the CsI) have been recently employed in highperformance nip-type cells with PCEs above 23%.  13, 16, 22  As shown in Figure  2a ,b, the two-step process results in much larger apparent grains with an average circular grid diameter of 890 nm as compared to the 95:5 triple cation perovskite with an average disk diameter of 140 nm, which has been prepared by a one-step process. The corresponding photovoltaic performance parameters of the cells are shown in Figure  2c . Compared to the 95:5 triple cation cells, the short-circuit current is significantly higher (up to 25 mA/cm 2 ). Figure  2d  depicts the JV-characteristics of the current record device with a reverse-scan PCE of 22.5% and a forward-scan PCE of 21.8%. In reverse, the device demonstrates a comparatively high FF (82.9%), a high J SC (24.7 mA cm -2 ), and a V OC of (1.098 V). This PCE is slightly lower than the highest reported values for a pin-type structure (22.75% certified).  28  The corresponding external quantum efficiency measurement in the inset demonstrates that the integrated EQE-sun spectrum product (24.5 mA/cm 2 ) matches the J SC within a small error. Supplementary Figure  S5  demonstrates that the stabilized PCE of another high-efficiency cell matches closely the initial PCE. Despite these promising features, the V OC of the DC cell is similar to the TC cell, which however also implies that there is significant room for improvements. This point will be explored further below. Moreover, Figure  2e  shows the maximum power point tracking of a high-performance DC device under constant illumination at 27 °C in a nitrogen controlled atmosphere. The MPP exhibits a PCE above 95% of its initial value for ∼350 h. We note that the DC cell was not encapsulated with SnO 2 on top of C 60 , which can further improve the stability of pin-type cells.  29, [40] [41] [42]  In comparison to the triple cation cells, we found a quite similar stability under MPP conditions in the 95:5 triple cation cell; however, the 83:17 triple cation cells degraded significantly faster (Supplementary Figure  S6 ). Therefore, reducing the amount of MA and Brthereby decreasing the bandgap energyimproved the stability under continuous illumination, which is crucial for further perovskite solar cell development. However, this does not mean that Cs is detrimental for the stability. In order to assess the performance difference between the DC and TC systems, we first performed a comparative analysis of the factors determining the FF of the cell. Not counting the shunt resistance, there are three primary considerations affecting the fill factor.  43  These are (1) the series resistance limitation, which is quite small in our configuration (∼0.25 Ω cm -2 ), (2) the transport limitations due to insufficient mobilities, and (3) the nonradiative recombination losses that govern the dark current, hence also causing FF losses, beyond the fill factor in the radiative limit. To assess these parameters in the two systems, we measured the open-circuit voltage as a function of the illumination intensity (Figure  3a ), which resulted in an ideality factor of ∼1.4 for both cells. Note, the intensity-dependent V OC is equivalent to a seriesresistance-free dark JV-curve.  43  Adding the voltage-independent generation current-density to this dark curve creates a pseudo-JV curve that is only impacted by the nonradiative recombination processes in the cell, hence allowing the impact to be assessed independent of transport losses. This result, shown in Figure  3b  by the dashed lines and summarized in Table  1 , demonstrates that the obtained resistance-free pseudo fill factor (pFF) is around ∼86% in both systems. Notably, the device FF of the DC cell was above 83%, meaning the transport losses in the device are quite small. Interestingly, and as a comparison, the pFF of the 95:5 triple cation cell is also 86% with a device FF of 79%. This highlights similar nonradiative (or ideality factor related) FF losses in these two systems but more transport losses in the triple cation cells. Considering that the transport layers are the same in both cells suggests that the enhanced charge extraction in the double cation cells is related to a higher effective mobility in the DC absorber layer and/or to less charge carrier scattering at the grain boundaries. In order to investigate this, we first characterized the intragrain carrier mobilities in the double cation perovskite layer using time-resolved terahertz spectroscopy (TRTS). We note that charges move only very few nm in response to the THz pulse, and therefore, grain boundaries are not expected to affect the obtained TRTS mobility. These measurements reveal an intragrain mobility sum of ∼35 cm 2 / (V s) (Supplementary Figure  S7a ), which is typical for perovskites (e.g., a mobility sum of ∑μ ≈ 30 cm 2 /(V s) was recently obtained on a 77:23 triple cation perovskite with higher Br content 44 ). These observations indicate that it is likely transport barriers (probably grain boundaries) on larger length scales that are decisive for charge collection, FF, and J SC . Consistent with this, cross-section SEM images reveal larger grains along the vertical (z)-direction in the case of the double cation film, while the grains appears to be broken in the zdirection in the case of the 95:5 triple cation film (Supplementary Figure  S8 ). In addition, using numerical simulations, we demonstrate that the THz mobility would be sufficient to avoid charge transport losses in the case of the double cation perovskite. In this case, the charge extraction is then limited by the low mobility in the PTAA layer (Supplementary Figure  S7b ).  8  Finally, we also note that the improved J SC in the double cation cell is likely also a result of the improved collection considering that EQE of the double cation cell is significantly higher than in the 95:5 cell across the whole spectrum (Supplementary Figure  S9 ). Moreover, the double cation has a lower bandgap as compared to our 95:5 cell and has a larger active layer thickness, both of which contribute to the enhanced J SC . Knowing that the V OC is lowered by a nonradiative recombination loss of ∼170 mV in the DC perovskite, we further investigated the devices by measuring the photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) of the individual components of the cell following a previous reported approach.  45  To this end, we prepared different stacks composed of the neat material on glass ("neat"), the perovskite with the electron transport layer (ETL) or the hole transport layer (HTL) attached and the perovskite sandwiched between both TLs (optical pin-stack), and finally a complete cell (with contacts). All samples were illuminated with a 520 nm wavelength laser through the glass or glass/PTAA (PTAA is the less absorbing compared to the ETL). As shown in Figure  4a , in both DC and TC systems, the highest PLQY was obtained in the neat material (2.6% in TC and 20.2% in DC). Notably, as shown in Figure  4b , the high PLQY in the double cation perovskite correlates with a Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) decay time of 18.2 μs in the monoexponential regime, which is superimposed by bimolecular (second-order) recombination at higher excitation fluences and carrier densities up to ∼10 16 cm -3 . We note that the monoexponential TRPL decay time is the minority carrier SRH lifetime in the low-level injection regime, while it is the average electron hole ). We note that a higher shunt resistance is observed in the double cation cell at intensities &lt;10 -3 suns. (b) V OC (I) allows a seriesresistance-free pseudo-JV curve (dashed lines) to be created to estimate the contribution of nonradiative and transport losses to the total fill factor (FF) loss. In comparison to the TC cell, the DC cell has a lower transport loss (i.e., better charge extraction) as visible from the difference of the actual JV curve (solid lines) and the pseudo-JV curve from V OC (I); see also Table  1 . We note that the contribution of nonradiative FF losses is similar in both systems, which is given by the difference between the JV curve in the radiative S.-Q. limit (dotted lines) and the pseudo-JV curves. SRH lifetime in the high-injection regime.  46, 47  Supplementary Figure  S10  shows the initial TRPL amplitude versus the generated carrier density and excitation fluence (nJ cm -2 ), which reveals a switch from low-to high-level injection at a carrier density of around 4 × 10 13 cm -3 . Hence, the background (doping) carrier density is expected to be similar to this value.  47  To our knowledge, this is the longest reported lifetime in the literature with an optical transient measurement. We note a decay time of 8.8 μs have been previously demonstrated for trioctylphosphine oxide (TOPO) passivated MAPI films. 48 However, to our knowledge, such wellpassivated MAPI/TOPO samples with such long lifetimes have not yet been successfully implemented in devices as TOPO likely impedes charge carrier transfer and/or extraction. Therefore, the double cation absorber layers fabricated here stand out, as they do not require further passivation with (d) Current-density vs voltage (JV) and pseudo-JV (pJV) characteristics obtained from intensity-dependent V OC (I) and QFLS measurements of double cation cells (black line) and partial solar cell stacks (neat material, PTAA/perovskite, perovskite/C 60 , pin-stack). The implied PCE of the neat material is marked (28.4%). (e) Loss mechanism in the double and 95:5 triple cation perovskite cells due to short-circuit current losses (difference between the measured J SC and the J SC with an average EQE of 95%), insufficient charge transport and mobility (as discussed in Figure  3b  or Table  1 ), interface recombination (the difference between the implied efficiency of the neat material and the pinstack), and efficiency potential losses in the neat material with respect to the 95% of the S.-Q. limit. The graph demonstrates that the challenge to realize the PCE potential of the neat double cation material relies largely on the ability to suppress the nonradiative recombination at the interfaces. additional chemicals and can be directly employed in highperformance pin-type cells. In comparison, the lifetime in the neat 95:5 triple cation film is "only" 1 μs (Supplementary Figure  S11 ). A further comparison to lifetimes obtained in literature can be found in Supplementary Figure  S12  and Supplementary Table  S2 . In order to better under the reason for the improved carrier lifetime in the double cation perovskite, we performed additional cathodoluminescence measurements, which allow the emission to be resolved with high spatial resolution (∼10-50 nm) yet require a high equivalent carrier generation rate (∼10 5 suns). As shown in Supplementary Figure  S13 , these measurements reveal nonradiative recombination primarily at the grain boundaries in the neat double cation perovskite. Therefore, the differences in the apparent grain size between both perovskites (∼890 vs 140 nm, Figure  2a ) might be related to the difference in the lifetimes of the two systems. Calculating the surface recombination velocity at the grain boundaries (S) via the apparent grain size (d grain ) and the obtained lifetime (τ SRH ) in both systems S = d grain /2τ SRH 49 yields a value of S of ∼2.5 cm/s in the case of the DC perovskite and S ∼ 4.5 cm/s in the 95:5 triple cation perovskite. This analysis would suggest that the recombination speed at the grain boundaries is quite similar in both systems and that the different grain size in these two systems contributes to the difference in the lifetime. Nevertheless, this does not exclude the importance of the perovskite surface in determining the lifetime or the PL yield of the neat material. Despite the high quality of both neat films, the PLQY of the perovskite/C 60 junctions was significantly lower. In the case of TC, the PLQY of the neat material dropped from 2.6 to 0.22% upon the addition of C 60 , i.e., ∼12 times. In the case of DC, the PLQY dropped from 20 to 0.13%, i.e., approximately 150 times. This means that the nonradiative recombination at the C 60 -interface is much more pronounced in the large-grain DC system and exceeds the recombination in the neat DC material by more than 2 orders of magnitude. Notably, in the DC system, the losses at the p-interface are also significant (∼22× reduction of the PLQY compared to the neat), but in the case of the TC perovskite, these losses are minimal. Overall, for both the double and triple cation perovskite, the limiting interlayer is the C 60 -interface. To directly compare the opencircuit voltage potential in the individual stack layers to the V OC of the device, we quantified the QFLS of the stacks from the PLQY using = * k T J J QFLS ln(PLQY / ) B G 0,rad (1) where k B T is the thermal energy, J G is the generation currentdensity, and J 0,rad is the radiative recombination current-density in the dark (see Supplementary Note 1 for more details). As shown in Figure  4c , the highest values were obtained for the DC neat material with a theoretical V OC of 1.23 V that could be obtained in the absence of recombination losses at the interfaces or electrodes. However, the QFLS of the perovskite/ C 60 stack is only 1.1 V, meaning that the voltage loss at the ninterface of the DC cell is as high as 130 mV. Nevertheless, the QFLS of the cell is similar to the corresponding V OC , indicating small energetic offsets between the perovskite and the transport layers and little recombination losses at the electrodes.  31  Having analyzed the primary V OC limitations in the neat perovskite film and at the interfaces, we further investigated the efficiency limiting mechanism across the power-generating JV regime. By using the same approach as shown above to create a pseudo-JV curve from the intensity-dependent V OC of the complete cell, we utilized the intensity dependence of the QFLS to measure the implied PCE of perovskite films on glass as shown in ref 43. To quantify the PCE potential of the neat film, we assume a certain short-circuit current-density that could be potentially reached in complete cells. To this end, we consider that an average EQE above the bandgap of 95% to be the short-circuit current limit of current state-of-the-art perovskite solar cells. Notably, this was already achieved in recent record nip-type cells, with certified PCEs and shortcircuit currents.  23  Figure  4d  depicts these different pseudo-JV curves on partial DC solar cell stacks (neat perovskite, perovskite/TL bilayers, the pin-stack), as well as the JV curve in the S.-Q. limit in comparison to the actually measured JV curve under AM1.5G illumination. Table  2  and Figure  4e  show the calculated pseudo-PCE of each stack in comparison to the measured JV in both studied systems and the losses associated with interfacial charge transport and "avoidable" current losses below 95% of the J SC in the S.-Q. limit. We note that the internal quantum efficiency of the DC cell is near unity (Supplementary Figure  S14 ), which implies that the remaining J SC losses are of optical nature. For the neat material, we obtained an efficiency potential of 28.4%, which is the highest reported value for a perovskite material, slightly outperforming the previously reported PCE potential of a potassium passivated triple cation perovskite.  43  However, the perovskite in this study is significantly simpler, with a low amount of MA and without Br, which is beneficial in terms of stability (as also demonstrated above). Overall, the studied double cation composition combines multiple advantages in terms of stability and allows the fabrication of near-ideal solar cells close to the thermodynamic limit. Clearly, engineering of the interfaces and TLs is the most promising pathway to improve the opencircuit voltage and to realize the PCE potential of the neat material. In summary, in this work, we fabricated low-gap (1.54 eV), MA 0.07 FA 0.93 PbI 3 double cation perovskite solar cells in a pintype architecture via a two-step process. With an external PLQY of 20% under a 1 sun equivalent illumination condition and a record lifetime of 18.2 μs, the neat material exhibits an exceptional optoelectronic quality without the need for further passivation. The high PLQY and lifetime can be at least partially attributed to the large average grain size of nearly 1 μm. Compared with FA-rich triple cation perovskites (95:5), the fabricated cells stand out by their short-circuit current density of up to 25 mA cm -2 , their high fill factors reaching values above 83%, as well as significantly improved stability under continuous illumination and maximum power point tracking. A maximum PCE of 22.5% was reached, which is among the highest efficiencies for pin-type solar cells. Using intensity-dependent open-circuit measurements, we were able to pinpoint the FF enhancement in the DC system to an improvement of the charge transport efficiency. The rather large open-circuit voltage losses in the system can be traced back to a 150-fold reduction of the PLQY upon addition of the ETL on top of the perovskite, although the losses at the pinterface were also significant. Interestingly, the losses at the ninterface were significantly larger in the large-grain (∼1 μm) DC system as compared to the TC system with smaller grains (∼100 nm). Using intensity-dependent QFLS measurements, we quantified the implied PCE of the neat double cation layer to be 28.4%, therefore enabling the possibility to create nearideal single junction solar cells in terms of performance. This efficiency can be reached under the following conditions: (1) interfacial recombination losses are minimized with respect to bulk recombination losses, (2) an average EQE of 95% above the bandgap can be achieved through a reduction of optical losses, and (3) the hole transport layer mobility can be improved by roughly a factor of 10 to minimize the remaining charge transport losses. Therefore, these results rationalize the huge improvements that were recently achieved in nip-type cells and lay out a clear path for further advancements of pintype cells toward the radiative limit. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triarylamine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:08:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="8846" length="4"/>
        <text>PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:54:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="8855" length="4"/>
        <text>C 60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 (FA0.83MA0.17)0.95Pb(I0.83Br0.17)3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:09:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="9129" length="53"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 (FA 0.83 MA 0.17 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">22.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:26:11Z</infon>
        <location offset="15328" length="4"/>
        <text>22.5</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.098</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:26:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="15481" length="5"/>
        <text>1.098</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:28:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="16149" length="88"/>
        <text>maximum power point tracking of a high-performance DC device under constant illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">27</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:28:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="16241" length="5"/>
        <text>27 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">95</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:02:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="16313" length="3"/>
        <text>95%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">350</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:29:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="16343" length="3"/>
        <text>350</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32956</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT * sı Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33097</offset>
      <text> Large-grain double cation perovskites with 18 µs lifetime and high luminescence yield for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells Emilio Gutierrez-Partida 1 , Hannes Hempel 2 , Sebastian Caicedo-Davila 2 , Meysam Raoufi 1 , Francisco Peña-Camargo 1 , Max Grischek 1,3 , René Gunder 2 , Jonas Diekmann 1 , Pietro Caprioglio 1,3 , Kai O. Brinkmann 4 , Hans Kobler 5 , Steve Albrecht 3 , Thomas Riedl 4 , Antonio Abate 5 , Daniel Abou-Ras 2 , Thomas Unold 2 , Dieter Neher 1 , Martin Stolterfoht  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33598</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Methods Absolute Photoluminescence Measurements: Excitation for the PL imaging measurements was performed with a 520 nm CW laser (Insaneware) through an optical fibre into an integrating sphere. The intensity of the laser was adjusted to a 1 sun equivalent intensity by illuminating a 1 cm 2 -size perovskite solar cell under short-circuit and matching the current density to the under the sun 𝐽 SC simulator (e.g. 22.0 mA/cm 2 at 100 mWcm -2 , or 1.375x10 21 photons m -2 s -1 for a 83-17 triple cation perovskite cell). A second optical fiber was used from the output of the integrating sphere to an Andor SR393i-B spectrometer equipped with a silicon CCD camera (DU420A-BR-DD, iDus). The system was calibrated by using a halogen lamp with known spectral irradiance, which was shone into to integrating sphere. A spectral correction factor was established to match the spectral output of the detector to the calibrated spectral irradiance of the lamp. The spectral photon density was obtained from the corrected detector signal (spectral irradiance) by division through the photon energy ( ), and the ℎ𝑓 photon numbers of the excitation and emission were obtained from numerical integration using Matlab. In a last step, three fluorescent test samples with high specified PLQY ( 70%) supplied from Hamamatsu Photonics where measured where the specified value could be accurately reproduced within a small relative error of less than 5%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35061</offset>
      <text> Intensity-dependent PL Measurements: The samples were illuminated in the integrating sphere as described above. A continuously variable neutral density filter wheel (ThorLabs) was used to attenuate the laser power in order to measure at different intensities which was monitored using an additional Si photodetector. The samples were illuminated at a given intensity for a variable illumination time using an electrical shutter. The illumination time was set to 1 second for the measurements shown in the main text, however different illumination times were tested which did not significantly impact the obtained ideality factor and pseudo fill factor values. After the specified illumination the PL spectra were recorded by averaging 30 spectra taken using a detector exposure time of 30 µs. Then the electrical shutter was closed, the filter wheel was moved to the next position and the steps were repeated. A custom-built Labview code was written to automate the measurement, and a Matlab code to automate the data evaluation. Device Fabrication of pin-type Cells: Substrates and HTL: Pre-patterned 2.5x2.5 cm 2 15 Ω/sq. ITO substrates (Automatic Research, Germany) were cleaned with acetone, 3% Hellmanex solution, DIwater and iso-propanol, by sonication for 10 min in each solution. After a microwave plasma treatment (3 min, 200 W), the samples were transferred to a N 2 -filled glovebox. The first layer was a PTAA (Sigma-Aldrich) layer with thickness of 8 nm was spin coated from a 2 mg mL -1 PTAA/toluene solution at 6000 rpm for 30 seconds. After 10 min annealing on a hotplate at 100 °C, the films were cooled down to room temperature and a 60 µL solution of PFN-Br (1-Material, 0.5 mg/mL in methanol) was deposited onto PTAA while the substrate was being spun (dynamic) at 4000 rpm for 30 s resulting in a film with thickness below the detection limit of our AFM (&lt; 5 nm). No further annealing occurred. Perovskite solutions: For the double cation perovskite, 2 different solutions were prepared. The first solution was prepared by dissolving 1.5 M PbI 2 (TCI, 691.55 mg) in 1 mL DMF:DMSO (9:1 volume ratio, v:v). Then a solution containing the cations was prepared by dissolving FAI (Dyenamo, 90 mg), MAI (Lumtec, 6.4 mg) and MACl (Sigma-Aldrich, 9mg) in 1 mL Isopropanol (IPA). Both solutions were left under stirring overnight (14h) to completely dissolve the materials. We note that the addition of MACl improves the crystallization of the perovskite film but evaporates in the final annealing step.  1  The triple cation perovskite solution was prepared by mixing two 1.2 M FAPbI 3 and MAPbBr 3 perovskite solutions in DMF:DMSO (4:1 volume ratio, v:v) in a particular ratio (e.g. 95:5). The 1.2 M FAPbI 3 solution was thereby prepared by dissolving FAI (GreatCellSolar, 722 mg) and PbI 2 (TCI, 2130 mg) in 2.8 mL DMF and 0.7 mL DMSO which contains a 10 molar% excess of PbI 2 . The 1.2 M MAPbBr 3 solution was made by dissolving MABr (Dysol, 470 mg) and PbBr 2 (TCI, 1696 mg) in 2.8 mL DMF and 0.7 mL DMSO which contains a 10 molar% excess of PbBr 2 . Lastly, 40 of a 1.5 CsI (Sigma-Aldrich) solution in DMSO (389 µL mg CsI in 1 mL DMSO) was mixed with 960 of the above described mixture of FAPbI 3 and MAPbBr 3 µL resulting in a nominal perovskite stoichiometry of Cs 0.05 (FA 0.95 MA 0.05 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 , respectively. Perovskite film fabrication: For the double cation perovskite, a 2-step interdiffusion method was employed. The first step was the deposition of the PbI 2 layer. This was achieved by dropping 150 µL of the lead iodide solution in a N 2 -filled glovebox and spin-coating at 1500 rpm for 30 s, the films were then annealed at 70 °C for 1 min resulting in a yellow-transparent layer. We note that if the PbI 2 layers are left for too long before proceeding to the next step, the lead iodides appearance would change to a rougher yellow color and the performance of the complete devices would be substantially lower. Afterwards the formation of the perovskite was achieved by dropping 150 µL of the cation solution on top of the lead iodide layer which turned the film into a brown-transparent layer, then rapidly starting the spin-coating at 2500 rpm for 30 s, which resulted in a red film. This was followed by an annealing step at 150 °C for 15 min outside of the glovebox under ambient conditions (at a relative humidity of 25%) which resulted in a dark brown or black perovskite film. For the second-annealing step, a transport-box was used to transfer the samples out of the glovebox and in order to keep the layers in a nitrogen atmosphere right before the annealing on a preheated plate (150 °C). We note that as soon as the perovskite layers gets into contact with air, the crystallization and a phase-change process starts and we noticed that a rapid transfer to the hotplate directly after opening the transport-box was beneficial for the cell performance. A Supplementary Video is available on the publishers webpage that shows the critical fabrication steps. All triple cation perovskite films were deposited by spin-coating at 4000 rpm for 40 s and 10 s after the start of the spinning process, the spinning substrate was washed with 300 µL ethylacetate for approximately 1 s (the anti-solvent was placed in the centre of the film). We note, that by the end of the spinning process the perovskite film turned dark brown. The perovskite film was then annealed at 100 °C for 1 h on a preheated hotplate where the film turned slightly more dark. ETL and Top Contact: After annealing, the samples were transferred to an evaporation chamber where fullerene-C 60 (Sigma-Aldrich, 30 nm), 2,9-Dimethyl-4,7-diphenyl-1,10-phenanthroline BCP (Sigma-Aldrich, 8 nm) and copper (Sigma-Aldrich, 100 nm) were deposited under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). The overlap of the copper and the ITO electrodes defined the active area of the pixel (6 mm 2 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40971</offset>
      <text> Intensity-dependent Measurements: Steady-state intensity dependent measurements were 𝑽 𝐎𝐂 𝑉 OC obtained with a 445 nm continuous wave laser (Insaneware) providing a power of 1 W. A continuously variable neutral density filterwheel (ThorLabs) was used to attenuate the laser power (up to OD 6). The light intensity was thereby simultaneously measured with a silicon photodetector and a Keithley 485 to improve the accuracy of the measurement. The measurement was performed by measuring alternating the at a given intensity and a variable exposure time and then the for 1 second 𝑉 OC 𝐽 SC before the filterwheel rotated to the next position. A custom-built Labview code was written to automate the measurement. To check whether the reached steady-state conditions, the temporal 𝑉 OC evolution of the open-circuit voltage and the was recorded with a resolution of 200 ms. Moreover, 𝐽 SC the exposure time was varied after the value was taken at each intensity step. This did not lead to 𝑉 OC significant changes in the open-circuit voltage or the ideality factor in the relevant intensity regime from the maximum power point to the at 1 sun as shown previously. 2 𝑉 OC &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42169</offset>
      <text> Current Density-Voltage Characteristics: -curves were obtained in a 2-wire source-sense 𝐽𝑉 configuration with a Keithley 2400. An Oriel class AAA Xenon lamp-based sun simulator was used for illumination providing approximately 100 mW cm -2 of AM1.5G irradiation and the intensity was monitored simultaneously with a Si photodiode. The exact illumination intensity was used for efficiency calculations, and the simulator was calibrated with a KG5 filtered silicon solar cell (certified by Fraunhofer ISE). The obtained short-circuit current density ( ) is checked by integrating the 𝐽 SC product of the External Quantum Efficiency and the solar spectrum which matches the obtained 𝐽 SC within less than 3%. The temperature of the cell was fixed to 25 °C and a voltage ramp (scan rate) of 67 mV/s was used. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42989</offset>
      <text> Maximum Power Point Tracking: The MPP was measured in a glovebox, using a white LED without UV set to a 1 sun equivalent power by matching the current density of the cell to the under the sun 𝐽 SC simulator. Every 20 seconds, the maximum power output of the cell was checked by varying the applied voltage by ±1 mV. The voltage corresponding to the higher power output was then applied to the cell until the voltage was checked again. The temperature was not controlled during the measurement, however the temperature of the cell did not significantly increase during the measurement ( 27 °C), which was measured with an infrared laser. Cathodoluminescence intensity maps were acquired by means of a Zeiss MERLIN SEM equipped with a SPARC system from Delmic. An aluminum parabolic mirror positioned above the sample focused the light into a photomultiplier tube (Thorlabs, PMT1001) outside the SEM chamber. We minimized the effect of beam damage by measuring under mild beam conditions (50 pA and 3.5 kV) and reduced electron dose (10 nm pixel size and 15 µs dwelling time per pixel). Yet the equivalent carrier generation rate is very high, on the order of 10 26 cm -3 s -1 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44174</offset>
      <text> Numerical Drift-Diffusion Simulations: The simulations were performed using SCAPS, an open-source code that can be obtained from  https://users.elis.ugent.be/ELISgroups/solar/projects/scaps  upon the conditions requested by the developers Marc Burgelman et al.  3  Simulation parameters are shown in a previous work.  4  Transient PL: TrPL measurements shown in the main text were carried out in a home-built setup using 660 nm excitation laser light from a supercontinuum light source (SuperK). We chose the longer wavelength excitation to avoid effects of charge diffusion from a high to low carrier density region. The excitation pulse had a repetition rate of 32 kHz and the PL emission was collected panchromatically through a photomultiplier and time-correlated single photon counting technique. The fluence was controlled with a tuneable neutral density filter and monitored with a power meter and increased from low to high injection conditions. The measured samples were never exposed to air and encapsulated around the corners of the of the 2.5 x 2.5 cm 2 large substrates using a commercial glue (Bluefixx) so that the glue was not in direct contact with the sample in the center. To minimize the impact of lateral diffusion on the results which may cause an early decay in the transient signal, we have defocused the laser spot to a circular shape with a diameter of 150 µm (where the boundaries are defined by an intensity drop to 1/e 2 as measured with a beam profilometer). Scanning Electron Spectroscopy: SEM images were acquired with a Zeiss Ultra Plus SEM. The grain size was estimated by using a circular test grid where the average diameter was taken as proxy of the grain size. Time-Resolved Terahertz Spectroscopy (TRTS): TRTS spectroscopy allows to measure the transient photo-excited sheet conductivity Δσ S and mobility sum µ ∑ = µ e +µ h of the electron mobility µ e and hole mobility µ h . The terahertz pulses are generated by optical rectification of 800 nm pulses in a ZnTe crystal and guided through the perovskite sample. The transmitted terahertz field T is then measured by electro-optical sampling in a second ZnTe crystal. Additionally, the perovskite samples are photoexcited by pump pulses with a wavelength of 400 nm and a pulse length of ≈150 fs. The photogenerated charge carriers alter the transmission of the terahertz probe pulse by ΔT, which is also detected. The derived pump-induced change in THz transmission ΔT/T is analyzed by the thin-film approximation in equation (  1 ) to obtain the photo-excited sheet conductivity Δσ S , which is the integral of the induced photoconductivity Δσ over the sample thickness d. The other parameters are the speed of light c, the permittivity of the vacuum ε 0 , and the terahertz refractive index of the substrates n sub , which is 1.95 for the used quartz glass substrate. (eq. 1) The transient of the photo-excited sheet conductivity is measured by scanning the delay of the pump pulse by an optical delay line. In this case, the terahertz pulse is sampled at its maximum. Additionally, the full terahertz pulse was scanned by a second delay line at a pump delay time of 10 ps. After both ΔT and T are Fourier-transformed, the photo-excited sheet conductivity spectrum is derived by Equation (1). The sum mobility spectrum is obtained by equation (2) from the photo-excited sheet conductivity, the flux of the pump beam of 7x10 11 photons/pulse/cm 2 , and the reflectance of the pump beam at 400 nm of 25%. The quantum yield of exciton dissociation in such mixed halide perovskites is approximately 1 at room temperature. , Σ𝜇 = 𝜇 e (𝑓,𝑡) + 𝜇 h (𝑓,𝑡) = The gained sum mobility is a spectrum at the frequencies from 0.5 to 2.5 THz, which constitute the terahertz probe pulse. The observed flat frequency-dependence in Figure  S5  indicates no significant difference between the measured terahertz mobilities and the DC-value, which is relevant for the device operation or carrier diffusion. Further details on the TRTS measurement can be found in ref.  5  8.8x10  -6  MAPI/TOPO DeQuilettes D. et al.    S2 . Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. (a) Numerically simulated power conversion efficiency (PCE) versus band gap energy (E gap ) of the halide-perovskite absorber, assuming aligned electronic energy levels at the perovskite/transport layer-interface for cells with different recombination parameters in the bulk or interfaces (see main text). The dashed circles highlight the bandgap at the peak efficiency. The parameters of the simulation were optimized to describe 83:17 triple cation perovskites including several experimental findings. The trace corresponding to "bimolecular-only" considers only radiative recombination but imperfect light absorption and charge transport. (b) Photovoltaic performance parameters of triple cation perovskite solar cells with an increasing molar concentration of FAPbI 3 (FAPI) with respect to MAPbBr 3 , demonstrating a continuous drop in performance due to open-circuit voltage losses and a stagnating short-circuit current-density when decreasing the band gap energy from 1.63 to 1.57 eV. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49330</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. (a,b) Scanning electron micrographs of double (DC) and triple cation (TC) perovskite films demonstrate a significantly larger apparent grain size in the case of DC (890 nm ±70 nm) as compared to the 95:5 triple cation perovskite (140 ± 14 nm). (c) The average photovoltaic performance parameters of the double cation perovskites highlight a comparatively high FF (81.5%), a high J SC (23.9 mA cm -2 ), and a similar V OC (1.079 V) compared to 95:5 TC perovskite cells. (d) The current-density vs voltage (JV) characteristics of the bestperforming DC perovskite cell demonstrates an efficiency of 22.5% (FF = 82.9%, J SC = 24.7 mA cm -2 , V OC = 1.098 V) in the reverse-scan direction and 21.8% in the forward-scan direction, while the inset shows the external quantum efficiency spectra with an integrated current of 24.5 mA cm -2 . (e) Maximum power point tracking under continuous light illumination (white LED, no UV) shows a relative PCE loss of around 5% after 350 h of operation, which highlights the substantial stability of the DC perovskite under continuous illumination. The initial PCE of the cell was around 21%. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:30:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="50474" length="3"/>
        <text>21%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50482</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. (a) Intensity-dependent V OC (I) demonstrates a similar ideality factor in the double cation (DC) and triple cation (TC) cells (∼1.4). We note that a higher shunt resistance is observed in the double cation cell at intensities &lt;10 -3 suns. (b) V OC (I) allows a seriesresistance-free pseudo-JV curve (dashed lines) to be created to estimate the contribution of nonradiative and transport losses to the total fill factor (FF) loss. In comparison to the TC cell, the DC cell has a lower transport loss (i.e., better charge extraction) as visible from the difference of the actual JV curve (solid lines) and the pseudo-JV curve from V OC (I); see also Table1. We note that the contribution of nonradiative FF losses is similar in both systems, which is given by the difference between the JV curve in the radiative S.-Q. limit (dotted lines) and the pseudo-JV curves. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51374</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (a) Comparison between the PLQY of different perovskite/transport layers combinations in the double cation and 95:5 triple cation perovskite systems. (b) Intensity-dependent transient PL decay measured on a neat double cation film demonstrating a Shockley-Read-Hall lifetime (decay time) of 18.2 μs at all fluences. (c) QFLS corresponding to the PLQY of the different stacks shown in panel (a).(d) Current-density vs voltage (JV) and pseudo-JV (pJV) characteristics obtained from intensity-dependent V OC (I) and QFLS measurements of double cation cells (black line) and partial solar cell stacks (neat material, PTAA/perovskite, perovskite/C 60 , pin-stack). The implied PCE of the neat material is marked (28.4%). (e) Loss mechanism in the double and 95:5 triple cation perovskite cells due to short-circuit current losses (difference between the measured J SC and the J SC with an average EQE of 95%), insufficient charge transport and mobility (as discussed in Figure3bor Table1), interface recombination (the difference between the implied efficiency of the neat material and the pinstack), and efficiency potential losses in the neat material with respect to the 95% of the S.-Q. limit. The graph demonstrates that the challenge to realize the PCE potential of the neat double cation material relies largely on the ability to suppress the nonradiative recombination at the interfaces. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52791</offset>
      <text> 1 ,* 1 11 Institute of Physics and Astronomy, University of Potsdam, Karl-Liebknecht-Str. 24-25, D-14476 Potsdam-Golm, Germany. 2 Department of Structure and Dynamics of Energy Materials, Helmholtz-Zentrum-Berlin, Hahn-Meitner-Platz 1, D-14109 Berlin, Germany 3 Young Investigator Group Perovskite Tandem Solar Cells, Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin fur Materialien und Energie GmbH, Kekulestrase 5, Berlin 12489, Germany 4 Institute of Electronic Devices and Wuppertal Center for Smart Materials &amp; Systems, University of Wuppertal, 42119 Wuppertal, Germany 5 Young Investigator Group Active Materials and interfaces for stable perovskite solar cells, Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin für Materialien und Energie GmbH, Kekulestrase 5, 12489 Berlin, Germany email: stolterf@uni-potsdam.de &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53567</offset>
      <text> , ∆𝜎 𝑠 = ∫ 𝑑 𝑥 = 0 ∆𝜎𝑑𝑥 = -𝜀 0 𝑐(1 + 𝑛 sub ) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53650</offset>
      <text> 27 8 . 3 * 18 . 8318 0x10 -7 CsI 0.05 [FA 0.85 MA 0.15 Pb(I 0.85 Br 0.15 ) 3 ] 0.95 Wolff C. et al. 28 1.0x10 -6 Cs 0.05 (FA 0.92 MA 0.05 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.92 Br 0.05 ) 2x10 -6 FA 0.93 MA 0.07 PbI 3 Gutierrez-Partida et al. * Supplementary Figure S12. A comparison of reported transient PL decay times of various mono-and mixed cation/halide perovskites from the literature shown in Supplementary Table &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54051</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 Fill Factor in the Radiative Limit Obtained from JV and Intensity-Dependent V OC Measurements double cation triple cation &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54187</offset>
      <text> Table 2 . 2 Pseudo-PCEs for Different Stack Layers for Both Double Cation and 95:5 Triple Cation Perovskites as Obtained from the Intensity-Dependent V OC and QFLS sample method double cation triple cation cell JV 21.1% 19.5% cell V OC (I) 21.8% 21.1% HTL/pero/ETL QFLS(I) 24.9% 24.4% pero/ETL QFLS(I) 24.9% 24.5% HTL/pero QFLS(I) 24.8% 25.5% neat pero QFLS(I) 28.4% 26.0% S.-Q. QFLS(I) 31.6% (1.54 eV) 31.1% (1.57 eV) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54608</offset>
      <text> Cs 0.06 FA 0.79 MA 0.15 Pb(I 0.85 Br 0.15 ) 3 + K Abdi-Jalebi M. et al. Cs 0.05 (MA 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 Al-Ashouri A. et al. Cs 0.05 (MA 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 on 2PACz Al-Ashouri A. et al. Cs 0.06 FA 0.79 MA 0.15 Pb(I 0.85 Br 0.15 ) 3 Rb-passivated Abdi-Jalebi M. et al. Cs 0.05 (FA 0.92 MA 0.08 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.92 Br 0.08 ) 3 Zheng X. et al. Cs 0.05 (FA 0.92 MA 0.08 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.92 Br 0.08 ) 3 (OA, 0.1 wt%) Zheng X. et al. Cs 0.05 (FA 0.92 MA 0.08 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.92 Br 0.08 ) 3 (OAm, 0.1 wt%) Zheng X. et al. Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 Pb(I 2.25 Br 0.75 ) Hou Y. et al. 1.6x10 -6 FAPbI 3 :(3.8%)MDACl 2 Min H. et al. 21 1.1x10 -7 22 7.9x10 -7 22 1.1x10 -6 22 5.7x10 -7 23 4.7x10 -7 FA 0.85 MA 0.15 Pb(I 2.55 Br 0.45 ) Tan H. et al. 24 2.3x10 -7 (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 Yang W. et al. 25 1.1x10 -6 (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 + 3mmol I 3 - Yang W. et al. 3.3x10 -7 FAPbI 3 + PEIE Kim M. et al. 27 1.4x10 -6 FAPbI 3 with 40 mol% MACl additive + PEIE Kim M. et al. 12 5.5x10 -6 MAPI/TOPO Braly I. L. et al. 13 3.5x10 -7 MAPI Braly I. L. et al. 13 4.5x10 -7 14 7.1x10 -7 15 2.0x10 -6 15 4.0x10 -7 16 1.6x10 -7 MAPI Abdi-Jalebi M. et al. 17 2.0x10 -7 Ag-and Na-doped MAPI Abdi-Jalebi M. et al. 17 1.4x10 -7 (FASnI 3 ) 0.6 (MAPbI 3 ) 0.4 Tong et al. 18 1.2x10 -6 (FASnI 3 ) 0.6 (MAPbI 3 ) 0.4 + 7% GuaSCN Tong et al. 18 9.7x10 -7 FAMAPbI 3 Jiang Q. et al. 19 4.9x10 -6 FAMAPbI 3 + 60 mmol PEAI Jiang Q. et al. 19 4.1x10 -7 (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 Jeon N. J. et al. 20 7.2x10 -7 (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 Min H. et al. 21 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56194</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:42:08 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56385</offset>
      <text>			 http://pubs.acs.org/journal/aelccp Letter https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.0c02642 ACS Energy Lett. 2021, 6, 1045-1054 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56517</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.0c02642 ACS Energy Lett. 2021, 6, 1045-1054 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56607</offset>
      <text>			 8.5x10-7   CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3-x Cl x Richter et al. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56661</offset>
      <text>			 5.0x10-7   Cs 0.05 (FA 0.83 MA 0.17 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 Stolterfoht M. et al. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56753</offset>
      <text>			 1.5x10-7   (Rb 0.05 (Cs 0.05 (MA 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.95 ) 0.95 )Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 Capriolgio et al. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56859</offset>
      <text>			 9.3x10-7   (Rb 0.05 (Cs 0.05 (MA 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.95 ) 0.95 )Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 +2% Sr Capriolgio et al.26</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:50:03Z</infon>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
      <node refid="11" role=""/>
      <node refid="12" role=""/>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
