<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025042788DBEDFG</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 103&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36</offset>
      <text> Synthesis Formamidinium iodide (FAI) white powder was synthesized by reacting 20 mg of formamidine acetate salt (99%, Alfa Aesar) with 30 mL of hydroiodic acid (HI, 57 wt% in water, Aldrich) in a 250-mL round-bottom flask at 60℃ and 1-mbar pressure for 1 h with rotation. The products were dissolved in ethanol, recrystallized from diethyl ether, and finally dried at RT in a vacuum oven for 24 h. Formamidinium lead triiodide (FAPbI3) powder was synthesized using synthesized FAI and lead iodide (99.99% PbI2, TCI) mixture (1:1 molar ratio) in 11 mL of 2methoxyethanol (anhydrous 99.8%, Aldrich) in a 70-mL vial with stirring. The mixed solution was heated up to 120℃ and then precipitated by retrograde method. Filtered FAPbI3 black powder was baked at 150℃ for 30 min. Methlammonium lead tri-bromide (MAPbBr3) powder, as an additive for fabricating the control [(FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05] device, was synthesized using MABr and lead bromide (98% PbBr2, Alfa) mixture in a 1:1 molar ratio in DMF by capturing single crystal with toluene. Here, methylammonium bromide (MABr) was synthesized by reacting methylamine solution (40 wt% in water, Aldrich) with hydrobromic acid (HBr, 48 wt% in water, Aldrich) (1:1.1 molar ratio) in a round bottomed flask at 0℃ for 3 hours under stirring. The product, was dissolved in ethanol, recrystallized from diethyl ether and dried at room temperature in a vacuum oven overnight. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1463</offset>
      <text> Solar cell fabrication Hole blocking layer titanium oxide (bl-TiO2) was coated onto a fluorine doped tin oxide (FTO) glass (Asahi FTO glass, 12~13 Ω/cm 2 ) substrate by spray pyrolysis deposition of a 20 mM titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) (Aldrich) solution at 450 ℃. Mesoporous TiO2 (mp-TiO2) was spin-coated at 1500 r.p.m. for 40s on the blocking layer (bl)-TiO2/FTO substrate using a TiO2 paste in 2-methoxyethanol (2ME) and terpinol (3.5:1 w/w). The films were calcined at 500℃ for an hour. Perovskite layers were spin-coated on mp-TiO2/bl-TiO2/FTO using the synthesized FAPbI3 with x mol% methylenediammonium chloride (MDACl2: x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, 5.7 mol%) or with 5 mol% of MAPbBr3 (synthesized) in a mixed solvent of dimethylformamide (DMF) and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) (8:1 v/v). The all perovskite precursor solution contained 35 mol% of methylammonium hydrochloride (MACl, 98% Aldrich). The all perovskite layer was first heat-treated at 150 ℃ for 10 minutes and annealed again at 100℃ for 10 minutes. For the surface passivation of perovskite film, octylammonium iodide, dodecylammonium iodide or phenethylammonium iodide (98%, Greatcell Solar) dissolved in isopropyl alcohol (IPA) (15 mM) was spin coated at 5000 rpm. The surface-treated film was dried at RT in a vacuum oven for 24 h or annealed at 100℃ for 5 min according to the passivation condition, and then spin-coated by hole transporting layer (HTL)/chlorobenzene (90 mg/1 mL) in a mixture of 39.5 µL of 4-tert-butylpyridine (TBP), 23 µL of Li-bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl) imide (Li-TFSI)/acetonitrile (520mg/mL), and 10 µL of cobalt-TFSI dissolved in acetonitrile (375mg/mL) at 3000 r.p.m. for 30 seconds. Finally, a gold counter electrode was deposited by thermal evaporation (about 65-75 nm of thickness). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3272</offset>
      <text> Characterization J-V characteristics of the devices were measured using a Keithley 2420 source meter under illumination by a solar simulator (Newport, Oriel Sol3A class AAA) with an AM 1.5 filter and an irradiation intensity of 100 mW/cm 2 . The active area was determined by the metal mask placed in front of the solar cell to avoid overestimation of the photocurrent density. Spectral mismatch factor of 1.05 was used for all J-V measurements. For the measurement of highefficiency devices, an antireflective coating was applied to the surface. The stability test at continuous maximum power point (MPP) operation under 1 Sun, AM 1.5G illumination was carried out in an ambient condition by fixing the voltage at VMPP and then tracking the current output. The morphology of the films was measured using a scanning electron microscope (Cold FE-SEM, SU-8220). Space-charge-limited current (SCLC) characteristics of electron-and hole-only devices are measured by a Keithley 2636B. Grazing-incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) measurements were conducted at the PLS-Ⅱ 6D UNIST-PAL beamline of Pohang Accelerator Laboratory. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) analysis were measured by 400 MHz FT-NMR (Bruker, AVANCE Ⅲ HD). IR measurements were conducted by Frontier FT-IR 6800 (Perkin Eimer). The crystal structure was analyzed using an X-ray diffractometer (D/MAX2500V/PC). X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis was measured by using Thermo Fisher Scientific (ESCALAB 250XI) equipment with Al Kα as the X-ray source. The optical properties of the films were measured using UV-Vis spectroscopy (Shimadzu UV-2600). Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectra were measured using a commercial time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) setup (FluoTime 300, PicoQuant GmbH) equipped with PMA-C-192-M detector, high-resolution excitation monochromators. The composition of the films was analyzed with secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS5, UNIST Central Research Facilities) with Bi 3+ primary beam (25 keV, 1pA) and Cs + sputter beam (1 KeV, 72 nA). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5351</offset>
      <text> Computational method We carried out the first-principles pseudopotential total energy calculations based on the density functional theory (DFT) within the generalized gradient density approximation (GGA) as implemented in the Vienna ab initio simulation package (VASP) (45-48). The electron-ion interactions are described employing the projector-augmented-wave (PAW) method (49) and Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) functional is used for GGA exchange correlation potential (50). To simulate stoichiometric and MDA-and Cl-doped FAPbI3 in α-phase (33), we used a 3x3x3 supercell for all the calculations. A kinetic energy cutoff of 400 eV and only Γ k-point for Brillouin zone integration is employed. All the atomic positions and lattice parameters are fully relaxed until the total energy is converged within 10 -4 eV. Fig. S1. Comparison of ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) spectra of FAPbI3 deposited with and without MACl additive.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6282</offset>
      <text>Table  S1 . Photovoltaic parameters of control and target, measured in reverse and forward mode, as extracted from Figure  2B .      &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6416</offset>
      <text> Solar cell fabrication Hole blocking layer titanium oxide (bl-TiO2) was coated onto a fluorine doped tin oxide (FTO) glass (Asahi FTO glass, 12~13 Ω/cm 2 ) substrate by spray pyrolysis deposition of a 20 mM titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) (Aldrich) solution at 450 ℃. Mesoporous TiO2 (mp-TiO2) was spin-coated at 1500 r.p.m. for 40s on the blocking layer (bl)-TiO2/FTO substrate using a TiO2 paste in 2-methoxyethanol (2ME) and terpinol (3.5:1 w/w). The films were calcined at 500℃ for an hour. Perovskite layers were spin-coated on mp-TiO2/bl-TiO2/FTO using the synthesized FAPbI3 with x mol% methylenediammonium chloride (MDACl2: x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, 5.7 mol%) or with 5 mol% of MAPbBr3 (synthesized) in a mixed solvent of dimethylformamide (DMF) and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) (8:1 v/v). The all perovskite precursor solution contained 35 mol% of methylammonium hydrochloride (MACl, 98% Aldrich). The all perovskite layer was first heat-treated at 150 ℃ for 10 minutes and annealed again at 100℃ for 10 minutes. For the surface passivation of perovskite film, octylammonium iodide, dodecylammonium iodide or phenethylammonium iodide (98%, Greatcell Solar) dissolved in isopropyl alcohol (IPA) (15 mM) was spin coated at 5000 rpm. The surface-treated film was dried at RT in a vacuum oven for 24 h or annealed at 100℃ for 5 min according to the passivation condition, and then spin-coated by hole transporting layer (HTL)/chlorobenzene (90 mg/1 mL) in a mixture of 39.5 µL of 4-tert-butylpyridine (TBP), 23 µL of Li-bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl) imide (Li-TFSI)/acetonitrile (520mg/mL), and 10 µL of cobalt-TFSI dissolved in acetonitrile (375mg/mL) at 3000 r.p.m. for 30 seconds. Finally, a gold counter electrode was deposited by thermal evaporation (about 65-75 nm of thickness). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8225</offset>
      <text> Characterization J-V characteristics of the devices were measured using a Keithley 2420 source meter under illumination by a solar simulator (Newport, Oriel Sol3A class AAA) with an AM 1.5 filter and an irradiation intensity of 100 mW/cm 2 . The active area was determined by the metal mask placed in front of the solar cell to avoid overestimation of the photocurrent density. Spectral mismatch factor of 1.05 was used for all J-V measurements. For the measurement of highefficiency devices, an antireflective coating was applied to the surface. The stability test at continuous maximum power point (MPP) operation under 1 Sun, AM 1.5G illumination was carried out in an ambient condition by fixing the voltage at VMPP and then tracking the current output. The morphology of the films was measured using a scanning electron microscope (Cold FE-SEM, SU-8220). Space-charge-limited current (SCLC) characteristics of electron-and hole-only devices are measured by a Keithley 2636B. Grazing-incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) measurements were conducted at the PLS-Ⅱ 6D UNIST-PAL beamline of Pohang Accelerator Laboratory. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) analysis were measured by 400 MHz FT-NMR (Bruker, AVANCE Ⅲ HD). IR measurements were conducted by Frontier FT-IR 6800 (Perkin Eimer). The crystal structure was analyzed using an X-ray diffractometer (D/MAX2500V/PC). X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis was measured by using Thermo Fisher Scientific (ESCALAB 250XI) equipment with Al Kα as the X-ray source. The optical properties of the films were measured using UV-Vis spectroscopy (Shimadzu UV-2600). Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectra were measured using a commercial time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) setup (FluoTime 300, PicoQuant GmbH) equipped with PMA-C-192-M detector, high-resolution excitation monochromators. The composition of the films was analyzed with secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS5, UNIST Central Research Facilities) with Bi 3+ primary beam (25 keV, 1pA) and Cs + sputter beam (1 KeV, 72 nA). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10304</offset>
      <text> Computational method We carried out the first-principles pseudopotential total energy calculations based on the density functional theory (DFT) within the generalized gradient density approximation (GGA) as implemented in the Vienna ab initio simulation package (VASP)  (45) (46) (47) (48) . The electron-ion interactions are described employing the projector-augmented-wave (PAW) method (  49 ) and Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) functional is used for GGA exchange correlation potential  (50) . To simulate stoichiometric and MDA-and Cl-doped FAPbI3 in α-phase  (33) , we used a 3x3x3 supercell for all the calculations. A kinetic energy cutoff of 400 eV and only Γ k-point for Brillouin zone integration is employed. All the atomic positions and lattice parameters are fully relaxed until the total energy is converged within 10 -4 eV.       Table  S1 . Photovoltaic parameters of control and target, measured in reverse and forward mode, as extracted from Figure  2B .     In general, mixed cations and anions containing formamidinium (FA), methylammonium (MA), caesium, iodine, and bromine ions are used to stabilize the black a-phase of the FA-based lead triiodide (FAPbI 3 ) in perovskite solar cells. However, additives such as MA, caesium, and bromine widen its bandgap and reduce the thermal stability. We stabilized the a-FAPbI 3 phase by doping with methylenediammonium dichloride (MDACl 2 ) and achieved a certified short-circuit current density of between 26.1 and 26.7 milliamperes per square centimeter. With certified power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) of 23.7%, more than 90% of the initial efficiency was maintained after 600 hours of operation with maximum power point tracking under full sunlight illumination in ambient conditions including ultraviolet light. Unencapsulated devices retained more than 90% of their initial PCE even after annealing for 20 hours at 150°C in air and exhibited superior thermal and humidity stability over a control device in which FAPbI 3 was stabilized by MAPbBr 3 . P erovskite solar cells (PSCs) have increased power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) with broader solar-light absorption through narrower bandgaps. Among lead halide perovskites (LHPs), the narrowest bandgap is afforded by the formamidinium (FA)-based lead triiodide (FAPbI 3 ) [1.45 to 1.51 eV (1-3) in thin films], which also affords improved thermal stability (4) relative to MAPbI 3 (where MA is methylammonium) because of its elevated decomposition temperature. However, FAPbI 3 readily transforms from the desired trigonal black a-phase into the undesired wide-bandgap d-phase with hexagonal symmetry under ambient conditions at room temperature  (5) . We have shown that modification of FAPbI 3 with MAPbBr 3 stabilized the a-FAPbI 3 phase and subsequently improved the device efficiency to &gt;18% in (FAPbI 3 ) 0.85 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.15  (6) . Efforts to improve the stability of FAPbI 3 have focused on mixed cation-anion hybrid LHPs that incorporate several cations, anions, or both, such as the FA x MA 1-x double cation or the FA 1-x-y MA x Cs y triple cation. This incorporation is achieved by the partial replacement of FA + , MA + , Rb + , Cs + , Br -, and I -(7-11). Nevertheless, when MA and Br are alloyed in FAPbI 3 , various problems such as low thermal stability (4) caused by the addition of MA, phase separation  (12)  caused by the presence of mixed halides, and reduced photon absorption arise, thereby resulting in low current density owing to an undesirable increase in the bandgap. Although the a-FAPbI 3 phase without MA can be stabilized by incorporating phenylethylammonium lead iodide  (13)  through surface functionalization  (14)  or by using both Rb and Cs  (15) , the resulting PCE is still low when compared with that obtained with the use of the FA x MA 1-x double cation. To further increase the PCE by enhancing the photocurrent density resulting from increased light harvesting, a new composition is needed that stabilizes the a-phase while maintaining the inherent bandgap of FAPbI 3 . The ionic radii and molecular configuration of methylenediammonium [ + H 3 N-CH 2 -NH 3 + (MDA), 262 picometers (pm), calculated] and FA ( + H 2 N=CH-NH 2 , 256 pm) are comparable except for the valence-state difference. However, MDA has more hydrogen atoms than FA and even MA, which means that it can form a greater number of H bonds with I -. Thus, MDA could structurally stabilize the a-FAPbI 3 in even smaller amounts than does MA. Some studies have reported the incorporation of divalent cations into monovalent A-site cations  (16) (17) (18) (19) (20) (21) , but most of the divalent diammonium cations reported have been used to realize twodimensional (2D) or 2D/3D LHPs. Safdari et al. ) that used complementary solidstate grinding and solution methods as a 2D/ 3D mixture has also been reported  (21) . The use of 2D or 2D/3D mixed-perovskite-containing diammonium cations increased the stability of perovskite materials by strengthening electrostatic interactions between the layers that rigidify the structure. However, larger organic cations in 2D structures can inhibit charge transport by creating insulating spacing layers between conductive inorganic slabs, so it would be desirable to fabricate 3D LHPs without the 2D perovskite layer. We report highly efficient and stable PSCs fabricated with MA-, Cs-, and Br-free a-FAPbI 3 by incorporating a small amount of MDACl 2 . The resulting FAPbI 3 :3.8 mole % (mol %) MDACl 2 structure stabilized the a-phase with only a slight change in the bandgap. We achieved a short-circuit current density (J sc ) of between 26.1 and 26.7 mA cm -2 (certified), which is the highest reported for PSCs fabricated from FA-based LHPs. The device exhibited a PCE of &gt;24% (certified stabilized 23.7%) and long-term stability compared with the control [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 ], which itself shows the highest efficiency among mesoporous (mp)-TiO 2 -based PSCs. We deposited a thin film of FAPbI 3 incorporating MDACl 2 with a process similar to that reported previously for state-of-art mixed perovskites (9-11) but adding MDACl 2 instead of MAPbBr 3 (see the experimental section in the supplementary materials). The ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectra of FAPbI 3 :xMDACl 2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol %) slightly blue-shifted with increasing amounts of MDACl 2 (Fig.  1A ) and were nearly identical to that of a thin film without the addition of MACl (fig.  S1 ) as a mediator  (22) (23) (24) (25) (26)  for high-crystallinity perovskite. This result is consistent with the corresponding shifts of photoluminescence (PL) emission peaks (Fig.  1A  and fig.  S2 ) from 826 nm to 824, 822, and 820 nm, and 816 nm for the control. This result suggests that MACl almost completely disappeared during the annealing process, as previously reported  (27, 28) . The presence of MDA in the perovskite was confirmed by Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (fig.  S3 ) and nuclear magnetic resonance imaging (fig.  S4 ). Thus, MDACl 2 may have been incorporated into the perovskite lattice within the experimental x-value range. The bandgap changes in FAPbI 3 caused by the introduction of MDACl 2 were calculated using density functional theory and compared for two cases as per Eqs. 1 and 2: FA vacancy :ðFA þ1 1À2x MDA þ2 x ÞPb 2þ I À1 3 Cl À1 2x → ½ðFA þ1 1À2x MDA þ2 x ÞPb 2þ I À1 3 þ V xFA þ 2xFACl ð1Þ Cl i insertion :ðFA þ1 1Àx MDA þ2 x ÞPb 2þ I À1 3 Cl À1 2x → ½ðFA þ1 1Àx MDA þ2 x ÞPb 2þ I À1 3 Cl À1 x þ Cl xi þ xFACl ð2Þ Equations 1 and 2 represent compositions that assume the FA cation vacancies and the insertion of Cl -with a small ionic radius, respectively, upon the addition of MDACl 2 . The bandgap (1.47 eV) with the FA vacancy (V FA ) composition as per Eq. 1 is slightly greater than that of pristine FAPbI 3 (1.45 eV) and the Cl interstitial composition (Cl i ) based on Eq. 2 yielded an increased bandgap of 1.69 eV (Fig.  1B ). We expected that the addition of MDACl 2 to FAPbI 3 would mainly result in FA defects and the possible induction of PL quenching. However, adding 3.8 mol % MDACl 2 to FAPbI 3 enhanced the PL quantum yield as measured with an integrated sphere, but was greatly reduced with further MDACl 2 addition. This result implies that the FA defects did not act as deep electron traps. As reported previously (4, 29), pristine FAPbI 3 thin films annealed at high temperatures exhibited a black a-phase that absorbed long-wavelength light. However, the a-phase transitions to the yellow d-phase within 10 days at room temperature and within 1 day under high-humidity conditions (5, 30) because the metastable polymorphs stabilized at high temperature are preferably converted back to the thermodynamically stable phase below 120°C. The structural stabilization of the a-phase in FAPbI 3 with added cations can be explained by several factors. First, the a-phase stabilization by smaller cations such as Cs + can be understood from the Goldschmidt tolerance factor t approaching 0.9, which is similar to that of MAPbI 3 , by mixing FAPbI 3 (t ~1) and CsPbI 3 (t ~0.8)  (31) . Second, cation mixing in the FA sites affords entropic stabilization through the resulting entropic gain and small internal energy input to form their solid solution  (32) . Third, the stabilization of a-FAPbI 3 with MA cations can be explained by the presence of strong H bonds between the I -and H-N groups  (33) (34) (35) . The a-FAPbI 3 phase can be more easily stabilized when MA, Cs, or both is used with Br -of small ionic radii, and highefficiency PSCs are normally fabricated using a-FAPbI 3 stabilized by mixed cations and anions. We expected that MDA could stabilize a-FAPbI 3 through the partial replacement of FA sites because MDA has more H groups with an ionic radius similar to that of FA and a stronger ionic interaction of its divalent state. The x-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of FAPbI 3 :xMDACl 2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol %) and the control layers exposed to 80% humidity for 24 hours after annealing of the coatings of precursor solution at 150°C for 10 min (Fig.  1C ) show two peaks characteristic of the a-FAPbI 3 phase at 14.3°and 28.6°assigned to the (001) and (002) crystal planes, respectively, and one peak at 11.6°corresponding to the d-phase. The as-annealed films (fig.  S5 ) exhibited a pure a-phase for all compositions, but after exposure to high humidity for 24 hours, pure FAPbI 3 completely converted to the d-phase and FAPbI 3 with 1.9 mol % MDACl 2 exhibited a strong phase transition, with the control also exhibiting a certain amount of the d-phase. By contrast, FAPbI 3 incorporating 3.8 and 5.7 mol % of MDACl 2 retained the a-phase. Furthermore, as shown in fig.  S5 , the overall signal intensity increased for MDACl 2 addition up to 3.8 mol % without any impurity peaks. The incorporation of &gt;3.8 mol % MDACl 2 may result in increased crystallinity because of the reduced lattice strain at FA defects (fig.  S6 ). As can be inferred from Eqs. 1 and 2, the perovskite structure may contain defective FA + or interstitial Cl -to satisfy the electrical neutrality rule with the release of FACl as a by-product when MDA 2+ ions are substituted into the FA sites in FAPbI 3 . The addition of MDACl 2 likely formed FACl or substituted residual MDACl 2 . However, the final annealed perovskite films did not exhibit any impurity peaks such as those of FACl and MDACl 2 . This result implies that MDACl 2 was successfully incorporated into the FAPbI 3 perovskite lattices, and the resulting FACl was eliminated by annealing at 150°C for 10 min, because FACl easily volatilized during heat treatment. The structural phase of FAPbI 3 with and without the substitution of the representative 3.8 mol % MDA and the presence of other phases such as FACl or MDACl 2 was further characterized using grazing-incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS). In The PbI 2 components remaining in both perovskite layers showed similar out-of-plane orientations. The GIWAXS ring patterns of a-FAPbI 3 :xMDACl 2 (x = 0 and 3.8 mol %) did not exhibit appreciable differences, and the fitted azimuthal circular average GIWAXS 1D full spectra were also nearly identical, without showing any peaks related to FACl or MDACl 2 . This result indicated that MDA is substituted into the FAPbI 3 lattice, as estimated from the conventional XRD analysis. Point defects corresponding to V FA or Cl i expressed by Eqs. 1 or 2, respectively, could decrease the open-circuit voltage (V OC ) and the fill factor (FF) rather than the current density J SC , although V FA defects form shallow traps near the conduction band  (37) . Fig.  4 . We used copper phthalocyanine (CuPC) as the hole-transporting material (HTM) to prevent degradation by hygroscopic dopants and spiro-OMeTAD itself at 150°C. The initial device parameters and J-V curves are presented in table S2 and fig.  S12 , respectively. The target device exhibited higher humidity stability, retaining &gt;90% of the initial PCE after 70 hours under high humidity [85% relative humidity (RH), 25°C], than the control PCE, which reduced to 40% of the initial value (Fig.  4A ). The thermal stability monitored at 150°C and ~25% RH (Fig.  4B ) indicates that the control device PCE degraded gradually, reaching &lt;20% of the initial PCE after 17 hours due to MA evaporation. The target device maintained &gt;90% of its initial PCE and exhibited greatly improved thermal stability. In addition, the long-term photostability (encapsulation and ambient condition) of the PSC, including spiro-OMeTAD as HTM, was tested with maximum power point tracking under full solar illumination without a UV filter (Fig.  4C ). Despite the use of a TiO 2 photoelectrode with high photocatalytic effect, the target device exhibits very high photostability, maintaining ~90% of its initial PCE (&gt;23.0%) over 600 hours of irradiation. This result can be attributed to both the high centration of Cl ions in the interface between photoelectrode and perovskite  (42)  and the stabilization of the a-phase on FAPbI 3 by MDACl 2 . Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. Photoluminescence spectra for different x values of FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">alpha phase formamidinium lead iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:53:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="11634" length="9"/>
        <text>a-FAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylenediammonium dichloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:53:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="11665" length="30"/>
        <text>methylenediammonium dichloride</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylenediammonium dichloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:56:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="11697" length="7"/>
        <text>MDACl 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.7</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:54:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="11878" length="4"/>
        <text>23.7</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:26:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="11895" length="3"/>
        <text>90%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">600</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:54:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="11946" length="9"/>
        <text>600 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSO</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:55:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="11974" length="111"/>
        <text>maximum power point tracking under full sunlight illumination in ambient conditions including ultraviolet light</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylenediammonium dichloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:17:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="15726" length="7"/>
        <text>MDACl 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.7</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:17:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="16087" length="5"/>
        <text>23.7%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:18:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="16144" length="35"/>
        <text>[(FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 ]</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:26:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="23275" length="18"/>
        <text>humidity stability</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:28:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="23306" length="3"/>
        <text>90%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:26:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="23365" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:27:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="23393" length="5"/>
        <text>25°C]</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:27:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="23439" length="3"/>
        <text>40%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOST</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:28:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="23481" length="17"/>
        <text>thermal stability</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">150</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:28:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="23512" length="5"/>
        <text>150°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:28:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="23523" length="3"/>
        <text>25%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:29:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="23610" length="3"/>
        <text>20%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:29:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="23701" length="3"/>
        <text>90%</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:28:18Z</infon>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R3">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T11:29:55Z</infon>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T10:56:09Z</infon>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="5" role=""/>
        <node refid="4" role=""/>
        <node refid="3" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24593</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Comparison of Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy results of MDACl2, target, and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24711</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of as-prepared FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24843</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. Structure relaxation for the control Electronic band structures of FAPbI3, FA0.926(VFA)0.037MDA0.037PbI3, and (c) FA0.963MDA0.037PbI3(Cli)0.037. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25012</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Variation in JSC, VOC, and FF for different x values of FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25152</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. Power conversion efficiency (PCE) change in FTO/bl-TiO2/mp-TiO2/Perovskite:MDACl2 (0, 3.7 mol%)/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au (unencapsulated) measured over time stored under ambient conditions (RH 20-30%, 25 °C) in a dark and X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of resulting layers after 2500 h of operation time. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25475</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. Certified results from accredited photovoltaic certification laboratory (Newport, USA) for device shown in Figure 2B. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25617</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Certified results from accredited photovoltaic certification laboratory (Newport, USA) for a second device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25752</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. Comparison of dark current-voltage curves of electron-only devices among representative control, target, and pure FAPbI3 devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25909</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. J-V curves of control and target fabricated with CuPC as hole-transporting material instead of Spiro-OMeTAD. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26045</offset>
      <text> Fig. S1 . S1 Fig. S1. Comparison of ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) spectra of FAPbI3 deposited with and without MACl additive. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26172</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. Photoluminescence spectra for different x values of FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26308</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Comparison of Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy results of MDACl2, target, and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26426</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of as-prepared FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26558</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. Structure relaxation for the control Electronic band structures of FAPbI3, FA0.926(VFA)0.037MDA0.037PbI3, and (c) FA0.963MDA0.037PbI3(Cli)0.037. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26727</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Variation in JSC, VOC, and FF for different x values of FAPbI3:xMDACl2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol%) and control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26867</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. Power conversion efficiency (PCE) change in FTO/bl-TiO2/mp-TiO2/Perovskite:MDACl2 (0, 3.7 mol%)/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au (unencapsulated) measured over time stored under ambient conditions (RH 20-30%, 25 °C) in a dark and X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of resulting layers after 2500 h of operation time. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27190</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. Certified results from accredited photovoltaic certification laboratory (Newport, USA) for device shown in Figure 2B. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27332</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Certified results from accredited photovoltaic certification laboratory (Newport, USA) for a second device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27467</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. Comparison of dark current-voltage curves of electron-only devices among representative control, target, and pure FAPbI3 devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27624</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. J-V curves of control and target fabricated with CuPC as hole-transporting material instead of Spiro-OMeTAD. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27760</offset>
      <text> ( 16 ) 16 reported on the 2D diammonium perovskites [NH 3 (CH 2 ) 4 NH 3 ]PbI 4 , [NH 3 (CH 2 ) 6 NH 3 ] PbI 4 , and [NH 3 (CH 2 ) 8 NH 3 ]PbI 4 , which demonstrated PCEs of ~1%. The recent synthesis of (NH 3 C m H 2m NH 3 )(CH 3 NH 3 ) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (m = 4-9/n = 1-4 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28032</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1D, we observed diffraction rings assigned to a-FAPbI 3 -(100) c , a-FAPbI 3 -(200) c , a-FAPbI 3 -(210) c , d-FAPbI 3 -(100) h , and PbI 2 -(001) t for the two representative samples (36). In addition, different crystal orientations of a-FAPbI 3 , [100] c and [200] c , were observed as preferential GIWAXS peaks for both samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28371</offset>
      <text> November 2019 2 of 5 Fig. 1 . 51 Fig. 1. Preparation of FAPbI 3 :xMDACl 2 (x = 0, 1.9, 3.8, and 5.7 mol %). (A) UV-vis absorption and PL spectra of perovskite layers with different x values. The perovskite layer based on 0.95FAPbI 3 / 0.05MAPbBr 3 as a control was also investigated. (B) Electronic band structures of (a) FAPbI 3 , (b) representative FA 0.926 (V FA ) 0.037 MDA 0.037 PbI 3 , and (c) representative FA 0.963 MDA 0.037 PbI 3 (Cl i ) 0.037 . The doping amount of 0.037 in the calculation was given by 1/27 (= 0.03704) based on the 3 × 3 × 3 supercell for the composition close to the actual experiment. (C) XRD patterns of perovskite prepared with different x values and the control layer exposed to 80% humidity for 24 hours after annealing of the coatings of the precursor solution at 150°C for 10 min. (D) GIWAXS 2D images at full depth of x-ray incident angle for perovskite layers for (a) x = 3.8 mol % and (b) control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29315</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Photovoltaic parameters of control and target, fabricated with CuPC as holetransporting material, as extracted from FigureS12. Synthesis Formamidinium iodide (FAI) white powder was synthesized by reacting 20 mg of formamidine As-fabricated acetate salt (99%, Alfa Aesar) with 30 mL of hydroiodic acid (HI, 57 wt% in water, Aldrich) in J sc FF PCE V oc [mA/cm 2 ] [V] [%] [%] a 250-mL round-bottom flask at 60℃ and 1-mbar pressure for 1 h with rotation. The products Control were dissolved in ethanol, recrystallized from diethyl ether, and finally dried at RT in a vacuum 22.57 0.926 69.02 14.44 Target oven for 24 h. Formamidinium lead triiodide (FAPbI3) powder was synthesized using 22.97 0.886 69.89 14.23 synthesized FAI and lead iodide (99.99% PbI2, TCI) mixture (1:1 molar ratio) in 11 mL of 2methoxyethanol (anhydrous 99.8%, Aldrich) in a 70-mL vial with stirring. The mixed solution was heated up to 120℃ and then precipitated by retrograde method. Filtered FAPbI3 black powder was baked at 150℃ for 30 min. Methlammonium lead tri-bromide (MAPbBr3) powder, as an additive for fabricating the control [(FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbI3)0.05] device, was synthesized using MABr and lead bromide (98% PbBr2, Alfa) mixture in a 1:1 molar ratio in DMF by capturing single crystal with toluene. Here, methylammonium bromide (MABr) was synthesized by reacting methylamine solution (40 wt% in water, Aldrich) with hydrobromic acid (HBr, 48 wt% in water, Aldrich) (1:1.1 molar ratio) in a round bottomed flask at 0℃ for 3 hours under stirring. The product, was dissolved in ethanol, recrystallized from diethyl ether and dried at room temperature in a vacuum oven overnight. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30999</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Photovoltaic parameters of control and target, fabricated with CuPC as holetransporting material, as extracted from FigureS12. As-fabricated J sc [mA/cm 2 ] V oc [V] FF [%] PCE [%] Control 22.57 0.926 69.02 14.44 Target 22.97 0.886 69.89 14.23 SOLAR CELLS Efficient, stable solar cells by using inherent bandgap of a-phase formamidinium lead iodide Hanul Min, Maengsuk Kim, Seung-Un Lee, Hyeonwoo Kim, Gwisu Kim, Keunsu Choi, Jun Hee Lee, Sang Il Seok* &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31468</offset>
      <text>			 of 5 RESEARCH | REPORT Corrected 13 November 2019. See full text. Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
