<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025034375HGABDH</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 62&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Stable and scalable 3D-2D planar heterojunction perovskite solar cells via vapor deposition&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>104</offset>
      <text>The device stability and toxic-solvent-free processing are indispensable development to industrialize organometal halide perovskite solar cells. In this work, the conventional top surface of vapor prepared 3D-MAPbI 3 was replaced by 2D-(BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 perovskite platelet via molecular substitution from MA (CH 3 NH) to BA (C 4 H 9 NH 2 ). Our fully vapor process fabricated a 3D-2D perovskite heterojunction for solar cell application, realizing the power conversion efficiency as high as 16.50% and the average one as 15.40%. Furthermore, unencapsulated devices can sustain their 81% efficiency after 30 days under 55% RH, and also 74% efficiency after 30 days under 80 °C heat stress. Stability of humidity resistance arises from the reduced n value of 2D perovskite caused by the surface reaction of moisture, and the improvement of thermal stability comes from the buffering of MA molecules release. Meanwhile, the fabrication of large scale device with high efficiency is also demonstrated in our experiment.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:32:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="313" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">16.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:40:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="606" length="5"/>
        <text>16.50</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:34:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="657" length="22"/>
        <text>unencapsulated devices</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">81</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:24:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="698" length="2"/>
        <text>81</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">720</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:49:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="719" length="7"/>
        <text>30 days</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">55</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:32:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="733" length="3"/>
        <text>55%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">74</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:24:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="750" length="3"/>
        <text>74%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">720</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:49:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="771" length="7"/>
        <text>30 days</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">80</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:35:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="785" length="5"/>
        <text>80 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOST</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:35:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="791" length="11"/>
        <text>heat stress</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1132</offset>
      <text>Introduction Organic-inorganic metal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have gained intense attention since 2009  [1] . The power conversion efficiency (PCE) of PSCs has rapidly increased from 3.8% to 23.7%, due to its unique features such as the excellent light absorption, suitable band gap, small exciton binding energy, and long carrier diffusion length  [2] [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9] [10] [11] . Despite three-dimensional (3D) MAPbI 3 perovskite shows impressively high efficiencies, it still undergoes a fast degradation upon exposure to moisture because of its low structural formation energy and the pronounced hygroscopic nature  [12] . The volatile MA cations also leads to poor thermal stability as well  [13] . Compared with 3D perovskite structures, two-dimensional (2D) perovskite materials obtain much attention recently due to their superior moisture resistance and photothermal stability. By using "Hot-Casting" technology to fix out-ofplane crystal orientation, Hsinhan Tsai et al. get 12.52% PCE of the 2D perovskite solar cell with n = 4. The devices can sustain 60% initial PCE after 2250 h under continuous standard (AM1.5G) illumination  [14] . However, the further enhancement of PCE of 2D layered perovskite solar cells is highly challenging because of its large exciton binding energy, increased band gap and low conductivity across adjacent inorganic layers  [15] [16] [17] . When investigating the impact of structure dimension on stability and performance of PEA 2 (CH 3 NH 3 ) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 , Li et al. showed that device performance improved as the increase of n value, while sacrificed the stability  [18] . This provides the good strategy to design the experiments under the balance between efficiency and stability based on hybrid 3D-2D structure. Direct mixture of 2D and 3D perovskite is one feasible attempt. In 2017, Wang et al. added the n-butylammonium cations into a mixed-cation lead mixed-halide FA 0.83 Cs 0.17 Pb(I y Br 1-y ) 3 3D perovskite. The formation of 2D perovskite was then found to suppress non-radiative charge recombination. The optimized solar cells exhibited the best stabilized power conversion efficiency of 19.5% and  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2019.03.014  Received 4 October 2018; Received in revised form 18 December 2018; Accepted 3 March 2019 sustain 80% efficiency after 1000 h in air  [19] .  Hu et al. combined  the Bi-based 2D perovskites solution and 3D MAPbI 3 solution to form 2D/ 3D structure and they found that the 2D perovskite located at the grain boundary and reduced the recombination centers inside the grains and the grain boundary  [20] . Another effective fabrication is to build the hybrid structure through forming a 2D capping layer on the 3D thin film. Chen et al. shows that a capping layer of 2D perovskite was formed via cation exchange by spin-coating a phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) solution upon the 3D perovskite film,  [21] . Similar experiment was also carried out by Chen et al., who dropped 5-ammoniumvaleric acid (5-AVA) solution on the surface with excess PbI 2 and formed an ultrathin 2D perovskite (5-AVA) 2 PbI 4 to improve the device stability and performance  [22] . Currently, the solution processed 2D/3D hybrid structure has shown the breakthrough point to enhance the stability, however, there are still some problems remains to be explored. First of all, the distribution of 2D in 3D phases cannot be easily controlled in the solution  [19, 23] . Band alignment mismatch and thus unfavorable charge recombination are likely to appear  [24] . Secondly, the reaction mechanism is still not well resolved. In 3D CsPbI 3 perovskite system, the PEA treatment was found not to react with the underlying 3D structure. So surface defect passivation is suggested instead of forming of 2D capping layer  [25] . Finally, traditional solution process is also hindered by the widely use of toxic solvent, such as N, N-dimethylformamide (DMF) and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO)  [26] . It is hazardous to handle these toxic solutions during the industrialized production process. Green fabrication with solvent free is imperative for commercialization purpose  [27] . Vapor deposition of perovskite solar cell is one of the promising methods for mass production and green solvent-free device fabrication. Since the first research work used vapor deposition of perovskite was reported by Snaith's group  [28] , the PCE of the device fabricated by vapor phase preparation now reaches 20.13%  [29] . In this work, we provide a fully vapor fabrication of 3D-2D planar perovskite heterojunction for solar cells, via surface vaporized molecular exchange between BAI and the MAPbI 3 thin films. The optimized PSCs show champion PCE of 16.50%, and maintained their 83% output for 30 days under 55% RH, and 71% for 30 days at 80 °C heat stress, without encapsulation. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:38:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="5795" length="3"/>
        <text>BAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:32:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="5807" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">16.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:40:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="5867" length="5"/>
        <text>16.50</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6000</offset>
      <text> Experimental &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6015</offset>
      <text> Devices fabrication The electron transporting TiO 2 layer was spin coated (SETCAS Electronics Co., Ltd KW-4B) onto the FTO substrate at 5000 r.p.m. for 30 s, using precursor with 369 μl titanium isopropoxide (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.999%) and 0.15 ml 37 wt% HCl solution dissolved in 5 ml ethanol (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.5%). It was annealed in air at 500 °C for 30 min. 5 nm-thick C 60 (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.9%) and 150 nm-thick PbI 2 (Sigma-Aldrich, 99%) were deposited onto the TiO 2 surface using thermal evaporation under vacuum of 5 × 10 -4 Pa and the deposition rate of 1 Å/s was measured using quartz crystal oscillation method with sensor near the sample. The as-prepared PbI 2 films were then placed facedown on a 2 cm height corundum boat with 100 mg MAI (TCI, 98%) powder uniformly dispersed at the bottom. The corundum boat was then placed into a vacuum oven preheated to 180 °C, and then pump down to 10 kPa in no more than 10 min (Fig.  S1 ). The whole reaction process lasts for 30 min for the fully formation of 3D-MAPbI 3 perovskite film. To fabricate the 3D-2D perovskite structure, the as-prepared 3D-MAPbI 3 perovskite film was treated by 50 mg BAI (TCI, 97%) with the procedure the same as the above, but with oven temperature set at 120 °C for 5 min, 10 min, 20 min, 40 min and 60 min. After the reaction, the 3D-2D perovskite film was transferred immediately into a nitrogenfilled glove box and naturally cooled down to room temperature. 25 ml of 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis-(N,N-di-4-methoxyphenylamino)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (Spiro-OMeTAD) solution was spin-coated onto the as-prepared perovskite film at 5000 rpm for 30 s. The spiro-OMeTAD solution was synthesized according to our previous work  [30] . The sample was then oxidized for 21 h in a cabinet with controlled humidity under 10% RH. Finally, 80 nm-thick Au was deposited onto the spiro-OMeTAD layer through thermal evaporation method under a vacuum better than 5 × 10 -4 Pa and a deposition rate of 0.6 Å/s. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:55:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="7168" length="3"/>
        <text>BAI</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8003</offset>
      <text> Characterization The current density-voltage (J-V) characteristic was measured with a Keithley 2400 source-meter together with a sunlight simulator (Zolix Sirius-SS150A, AM 1.5G) in a glovebox. KPFM images were obtained using NT-MDT NDTGRE with tip bias. Surface potential on difference devices is calibrated using Au as reference. The XRD patterns of the prepared films were measured using Rigaku miniflex 600. Ultraviolet-visible absorption spectra were measured using SHIMADZU UV-2600. Steady-state PL spectra measurements were taken with 532 nm laser source at room temperature (Horiba, LabRAM HR Evolution Inc.). The valance band maximum (VBM) was measured using ultraviolet photoelectron emission spectroscopy (UPS) (Thermo Fisher Scientific, ESCALAB 250), using the He I (21.2 eV) as excitation source. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8815</offset>
      <text> Results and discussion The 3D CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite was prepared by a two-step vapor fabrication. A PbI 2 thin film of 150 nm was first evaporated on FTO/ TiO 2 substrate, and then exposed in a MAI vapor environment for 30 min under 180 °C (Fig.  1a ). Reaction according to equation (1) take places, which drive the formation of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . PbI 2 +CH 3 NH 3 I = CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 (1) nCH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 +2BAI = (BA) 2 (CH 3 NH 3 ) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 +CH 3 NH 3 I (2) The SEM image in Fig.  1b  shows that the as-prepared MAPbI 3 thin film is composed of compact crystals with sizes of around 800 nm. Formation of the 2D capping layer was accomplished by exposing the as-prepared MAPbI 3 thin film in the BAI vapor (equation (  2 )). Fig.  1c  shows that surface layered structure developed from the 3D grains in 5 min, indicating the partial transformation of 3D to 2D structure. The conversion of morphology proceeds with time and a surface with smaller layer structure was observed after 60 min reaction (Fig.  1d ). The crystal structure of the thin film was investigated by X-ray diffraction (XRD) in Fig.  2a . On the as-prepared MAPbI 3 thin film, typical diffraction peaks at 14.13°, 20.00°, 24.56°, 28.47°, 31.92°, were observed. They correspond to the (110), (  112 ), (  202 ), (  220 ), (310) crystal plane of tetragonal MAPbI 3 . It's found that after BAI vapor treatment, the diffraction peaks did not change until treatment time increase to 20 min. New diffraction peaks of 2D perovskite at 6.38°and 4.73°, corresponding to (002) plane of (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 for n = 1 and n = 2 appeared. The appearance of new excitonic absorption peaks at 517 nm (n = 1), 570 nm (n = 2), 608 nm (n = 3) in the UV-Vis spectra (Fig.  2b ) also confirm the existence of 2D perovskite species in the 3D MAPbI 3 perovskites. This result shows that large alkyl ammonium BA has inserted into the 3D-MAPbI 3 structure and enlarged the distance between inorganic [PbI 6 ] layers by replacing MA to form a 2D perovskite in the thin film. If the 2D and 3D perovskite is in the mixing form, a decrease of n value of the whole perovskite can be expected, and thus broaden the band gap of the thin film. The absorption onset of the thin film in Fig.  2b  keeps constant at 780 nm, corresponding to an optical band gap of 1.59 eV of 3D structure. It suggests that the 2D perovskite does not mixed into the bulk. To locate the existence of 2D perovskite, the photoluminescence (PL) spectra of the perovskite surface and the interface between the perovskite and TiO 2 were measured (Fig.  2c  &amp; Fig.  S2 ). It's found that once the 3D perovskite was exposed to BAI vapor, BA 2 MA 2 Pb 3 I 10 (n = 3) peak at 615 nm and BA 2 MA 1 Pb 2 I 7 (n = 2) peak at 577 nm were observed and increase with prolonging treatment time on the surface side. At the same time, the emission peak at 780 nm shift to 762 nm. It indicates the formation of surface 2D perovskite with higher n values, which has a higher band gap than the original 3D perovskite  [31] . In contrast, PL spectra at the interface detects no signal of 2D perovskite. It confirms that transformation of 3D to 2D structure only appears on the surface, showing the formation of a 3D-2D heterojunction structure. AFM images in Fig.  S3  show that the surface of the 3D perovskite thin film is compact and uniform. After treating with BAI vapor for 5 min, the grains turn to platelet crystals with layered structure, and the root square roughness slightly increase from 24.5 nm to 25.0 nm because of the formation of 2D structure. As the 2D structure shows different energy levels, which will alter the energy level alignment at the interface, we continue to measure the surface potential change on the surface using KPFM. Fig.  2d  &amp; Fig.  S4  shows that as more and more 2D perovskite with smaller n value formed, the surface potential decreases from 530 mV to 96 mV. As the tip is biased in our measurement set-up, the decrease of surface  The inset shows the enlarge section between 550 nm and 650 nm. (d) CPD evolution for different BAI treatment time. The AFM tip is bias so as the decrease of CPD means an increase of vacuum level. (We performs the KPFM in Air, the work function may affected by absorbing H 2 O or O 2 . So the absolute value of work function cannot be taken exactly.) potential means that the upward band bending of vacuum level. This result indicates there is a building potential between 3D and 2D structure, which facilitates the separation of electron-hole. The results indicate that exposing the 3D perovskite thin film using BAI vapor allow slow formation of surface 2D layer and control of the energy structure. We fabricated solar cells with the above 3D-2D hybrid structure using device architecture consists of glass/FTO/TiO 2 /C 60 /3D-2D perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au in Fig.  3a . The effect of treatment time on the performance of the devices was shown in Fig.  3b  and Table  1 . As prepared 3D perovskite device has V oc of 1.01 V, J sc of 23.66 mA cm -2 , and FF of 72.40%, giving a PCE of 17.30% in reverse scan. The device shows a hysteresis index of 7.07%, which is calculate by (J Re- verse (0.8V oc )-J Forward (0.8V oc ))/J Reverse (0.8V oc ) (Fig.  S5a )  [32] . Although the above KPFM results shown that more 2D structure leads to stronger internal field for more efficient electron-hole separation, however, with increased treatment time, the PCE decrease was observed. To investigate the origin, we first investigate the dark current of the devices in Fig.  S5c . Rapid decrease of dark current with increasing treatment time was observed, which leads to a decrease of FF as shown in Table After long time treatment, the S-shape J-V curves was observed (Fig.  S5d ). This shows that transport of carrier is not only affected by the increasing resistance of 2D structures, but also by charging at the interface. To further reveal the mechanism, we analyzed the surface valance band structure evolution during the vapor treatment process in quantify. UPS measurement on samples with increasing treatment time in Fig.  4a  gives the SE cutoff edge at 17.26 eV, 17.19 eV, 17.18 eV, 17.17 eV, 17.16 eV, 17.15 eV, respectively, and the VB onset at 1.59 eV, 1.52 eV, 1.54 eV, 1.55 eV, 1.57 eV, 1.58 eV, respectively using logarithmic extraction method due to its low DOS at valance band  [33] . The   VBM position can be calculated by: E VBM = 21.22-(E SE-cutoff-edge -E VB-onset ) (3) The change of VBM is shown in Fig.  4c . It shows that the VBM becomes deeper as treatment time increases. It means that hole flowing to the Au back contact will encounter an increasing barrier. This VBM offset will induced hole accumulation at the interface, and thus cause reduction of J SC or even the S-shape. It's shown that when the treatment time was restricted at 5 min, the position of VBM lies at -5.55 eV, which is nearly the same as that of 3D counterpart. This energy level  alignment facilitates the extraction of holes and blocking of electrons. Therefore, the J SC and V OC are as high as that of the 3D devices in Fig.  3c . The 3D-2D device after 5 min treatment showed V OC of 1.02 V, J SC of 23.37 mA cm -2 , FF of 68.70% and thus the PCE reaches 16.50%. The hysteresis index of the device is reduced to 4.54%. Moreover, our device structure and fabrication process are proved to be suitable for large area fabrication. Fig.  3d  and e  shows typical devices with active area of 1.00 cm 2 fabricated using the same procedure. The 3D-2D device showed a PCE of 14.10% with J SC of 21.04 mA/ cm 2 , a V OC of 1.07 V, and an FF of 62.55% under reverse scanning measurement. It is similar to the 3D device, which shows PCE of 14.01% with a J SC of 21.91 mA/cm 2 , a V OC of 1.05 V, and an FF of 60.44%. The PCE difference is negligible in large area devices. We suggest that it comes from the reduction of leakage in the film because of more compact surface, where BAI insertion leads to lattice expansion. The stability of the devices is investigated in Fig.  5 . Both the asprepared 3D perovskite and hybrid structure after 5 min treatment shows good illumination stability, giving the stabilized power output (SPO) of 16.75% and 16.12% at maximum power point, as shown in Fig.  5a  and b . Both devices can reach a stable PCE rapidly. The 3D device only shows 95.78% SPO ratio, while the 3D-2D device shows better SPO ratio of 97.69%. The higher SPO ratio means that hysteresis of 3D-2D device is alleviated as compared to the 3D device  [20] . More importantly, the long-term thermal and humidity stability was greatly improved in 3D-2D heterostructure devices as shown in Fig.  5c  and d . Under 55% RH at room temperature without encapsulation, the PCE of as-prepared 3D-MAPbI 3 device decreases to 44% of its original PCE after 30 days, while the 3D-2D hetero-structure keeps 83% after 30 days. Under 80 °C ± 2 thermal aging, the PCE of the 3D device decrease to 27% in 14 days, while the 3D-2D hetero-structure keeps 73% after 30 days. To understand the mechanism of stability improvement, we first trace the change of XRD patterns under difference storage environment. It's found that the under 55% RH environment, strong PbI 2 peaks at 12.67°can be observed in 3D MAPbI 3 after 4 days. For the 3D-2D structure, although significant decrease of the (110) peaks intensity was observed, the PbI 2 peak is not observed at 9 days. At 14 days, a small PbI 2 peak appeared. Moreover, we can observe a strong peak at 10.50°a nd a small peak at 8.52°These peaks coincided with the (-101) and (100) reflections of monoclinic MAPbI 3 •H 2 O  [34] , indicating the formation of monohydrate. Reaction between 2D perovskite and H 2 O has been proposed as  [35] : → + ⋅ - + -- - -+ MA Pb I x H O MA Pb I x MAPbI H O BA ( ) BA ( ) n n n n x n x n x 2 1 3 1 2 2 ( ) 1 ( )3 ( ) 1 3 2 (4) This reaction shows that on the surface, the amount of 2D perovskite with high n value will be reduced, giving a surface layer with MAPbI 3 •H 2 O and 2D inside layer with smaller n value (Fig.  6c ). This process will increase the amount of 2D perovskite with smaller n. It's found from the XRD that a small peak at 9.54°also appears after 14 days storage. This peak consists with the n = 2 peak of BA 2 MAPb 2 I 7  [16] . It supports the above analysis and shows that n = 2 is the most stable form in the system. The generation of 2D perovskite with smaller n value at surface can protect the inner species and is helpful for the stabilization of devices. The thermal degradation of the 3D perovskite shows the similar quick degradation process as compared with humidity degradation of 3D perovskite film. However, the evolution of 3D-2D structure under heat stress shows difference with that of humidity degradation. From XRD monitoring, PbI 2 peak cannot be observed after 4 days storage. After 9 days, only the peak of PbI 2 was observed, no additional peaks appear (Fig.  S6b ). It means that the thermal degradation of 3D-2D system is different from the humidity degradation. To further investigate the change, we map the surface potential evolution using insitu KPFM under 80 °C. The surface of as-prepared 3D-MAPbI 3 perovskite thin film in Fig.  S7  shows uniform and smooth grains. After heating at 80 °C for 20 min, some nanoscale particles first appeared on the grain boundary (marked by the black arrow), and then dispersed to overall surface after 57 min. The surface roughness increases from initially 18.05 nm-20.76 nm after 57 min. KPFM shows that the surface potential decreased from 480 mV to 220 mV, this process can be understood by the formation of lower surface potential PbI 2 owning to release of MA molecules  [36] . The AFM topography evolution of the 3D-2D perovskite films shown in Fig.  7a -d is different. The 2D-(BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 platelet structure keeps robust under 80 °C heat stress for 56 min. It reflects that the 2D surface is more resistive to heat stress. Meanwhile, the change of surface potential of the 2D layer shows opposite tendency to that of thermal degradation of 3D-MAPbI 3 , with value increases from 350 mV to 660 mV. It indicates that the perovskite does not experience the thermal decomposition to PbI 2 . If revisit the surface potential change of 2D perovskite in Fig.  2d , where the surface potential decreases as n value decreases, it can be found that the surface potential evolution during decomposition of the 2D layer has inverse tendency to the formation process, and thus an increase of n value can be expected. As a result, we suggest that the thermal decomposition is an inverse process to the 2D perovskite growth (Fig.  7f ). At high temperature, the MA species inside the MAPbI 3 counterpart is released to the top 2D layer, while the BA species slightly diffuses inside. This interdiffusion behavior leads to the formation BA 2 (MA) n Pb n+1 I 3n+4 from a (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 grain. Improvement of the thermal stability comes from generation of 2D perovskite with high n value, which buffers the release of MA species inside the film. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:32:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="8846" length="15"/>
        <text>CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:55:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="10677" length="14"/>
        <text>alkyl ammonium</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:55:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="10692" length="2"/>
        <text>BA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:32:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="10720" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:55:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="13417" length="3"/>
        <text>BAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:45:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="13607" length="55"/>
        <text>glass/FTO/TiO 2 /C 60 /3D-2D perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:45:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="13890" length="5"/>
        <text>17.30</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">55</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:48:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="17506" length="3"/>
        <text>55%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:32:31Z</infon>
        <location offset="17579" length="10"/>
        <text>3D-MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">44</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:24:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="17610" length="3"/>
        <text>44%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">720</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:49:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="17640" length="7"/>
        <text>30 days</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">83</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:24:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="17688" length="3"/>
        <text>83%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">80</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T15:50:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="17713" length="5"/>
        <text>80 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">27</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:24:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="17775" length="3"/>
        <text>27%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21936</offset>
      <text> Conclusion In summary, we have successfully fabricated 3D-2D planar heterojunction perovskite solar cells by BAI vapor treatment of 3D-MAPbI 3 perovskite films. Compared with the 3D-MAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells, the mixed 3D-2D planar heterojunction perovskite solar cells show better stability in humidity by forming 2D perovskite with smaller n value to prevent direct reaction between H 2 O and MAPbI 3 , and also demonstrate better thermal stability by buffering the release of MA molecules in the film. The non-encapsulation device shows a champion PCE of 16.50% and can maintain their 84% efficiency after 30 days under 55% RH, and 72% efficiency after 30 days under 80 °C heating stress. Moreover, the device with 1 cm 2 active area fabricated with the same processes gives PCE as high as 14.10%, showing the potential of scale-up fabrication. Additionally, this fully vapor fabrication of 3D-2D perovskite heterojunction solar cell avoids the use of toxic solvent entirely. It finally provides a potential green way of mass production of large-area perovskite solar cell with high stability solar cells in the future. Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. (a) Schematic diagram of the growth of MAPbI 3 -(BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 hybrid structure. The n value describes the perovskite layer numbers between two layers of BA molecules. (b)-(d) SEM images of the perovskite thin films without (b) and with 5 min (c) and 60 min (d) BAI vapor treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23382</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. (a) XRD patterns and (b) UV-Vis spectra of perovskite films with different time for BAI vapor treatment. (c) Typical PL spectra of perovskite films after 5 min BAI treatment. The PL spectra are collected when the excitation laser illuminated from the top surface and the FTO side (interface) respectively. The inset shows the enlarge section between 550 nm and 650 nm. (d) CPD evolution for different BAI treatment time. The AFM tip is bias so as the decrease of CPD means an increase of vacuum level. (We performs the KPFM in Air, the work function may affected by absorbing H 2 O or O 2 . So the absolute value of work function cannot be taken exactly.) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24059</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. (a) Schematic structure of 3D-2D device, (b) J-V curve after different BAI vapor treatment time. The active area is 0.045 cm 2 . (c) Statistical graph of device parameters after different BAI vapor treatment time. J-V curves of large area devices (1 cm 2 ) (d) without and (e) with 5 min BAI treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24383</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. UPS (a) secondary electron (SE) cutoff and (b) valance band onset of perovskite films without and with different BAI treatment time. (c) Calculated VBM. As charging effect cannot be fully excluded from the current data, absolute values cannot be taken seriously. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24667</offset>
      <text> Fig. 5 . 5 Fig. 5. Stabilized power output of devices (a) without and (b) with 5 min BAI treatment. (c) Humidity stability and (d) thermal stability of control without and with 5 min BAI treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24867</offset>
      <text> Fig. 6 . 6 Fig. 6. XRD patterns degradation during 55% RH of (a) without and (b) with 5 min BAI treatment (■: MAPbI 3 , □:PbI 2 , ▽: 2D perovskite, ○: MAPbI 3 •H 2 O). (c) Schematic diagram of humidity degradation in 3D-2D structure. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25113</offset>
      <text> Fig. 7 . 7 Fig. 7. (a)-(d) In-suit 80 °C heat stress degradation and (a 1 ) -(d 1 ) corresponding KPFM images (the size of picture is 1.5 μm × 1.5 μm) of 5 min BAI treatment with tip as reference. (e) Surface potential evolution under 80 °C heat stress of 5 min BAI treatment. (f) Schematic diagram under 80 °C heat stress of 5 min BAI treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25468</offset>
      <text> Table 1 1 Photovoltaic parameters of PSCs after different BAI treatment time. treatment time Jsc (mA/ Voc (V) FF (%) Champion PCE Average PCE (min) cm 2 ) (%) (%) 0 23.66 1.01 72.40 17.30 16.07 5 23.37 1.02 68.70 16.50 15.40 10 22.32 1.00 66.50 14.78 13.88 20 22.09 0.95 58.24 12.28 11.05 40 20.33 0.94 56.79 10.88 9.37 60 19.62 0.69 45.55 6.14 4.75</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:59Z</infon>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
      <node refid="8" role=""/>
      <node refid="7" role=""/>
      <node refid="28" role=""/>
      <node refid="23" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:59Z</infon>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="5" role=""/>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
      <node refid="23" role=""/>
      <node refid="24" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
