<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250129224507861FGGIIA</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">3</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">3</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #:29&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text> Title: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20</offset>
      <text>Amine additive reactions induced by the soft Lewis acidity of Pb 2+ in halide perovskites. Part I: evidence for Pb-alkylamide formation †&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>160</offset>
      <text> Abstract: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>172</offset>
      <text>Metal halide perovskite materials (ABX 3 ) employed in optoelectronic devices have rapidly achieved high efficiencies. Their performance can be partially attributed to intrinsic defects being electronically benign. Despite the inertness of defects within the bulk, such as ion vacancies, solution processing additives and surface passivation have been shown to enhance material properties. Thus, detailed knowledge of additive chemistry is desirous to elucidate passivation mechanisms and facilitate further improvements. In particular, the soft Lewis acid nature of Pb 2+ has been overlooked heretofore as a key feature of amine-lead chemistry in perovskite preparations. In Part I of this study, we demonstrate that acid-base reactions between PbI 2 and aliphatic amines yield alkylammonium and Pb-alkylamide species. The alkylammonium and alkylamide products are capable of occupying A-site cation and anion vacancies, respectively. Subsequent incorporation of these impurities at perovskite crystal surfaces or formation of non-perovskite phase inclusions likely influence the perovskite layer morphology and properties which are investigated in Part II. These results reveal a new mechanism by which optoelectronic properties of perovskites can be chemically modified. Additionally, the general concept of acidification of organic molecules solvated to Pb 2+ promoting unexpected reactions is applied to explain amine reactions with other additives, such as formic acid. Understanding acid-base reactions induced by PbI 2 complexing to protic molecules is useful to comprehend and predict defect/impurity chemistry in a wide variety of perovskite precursor formulations.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1848</offset>
      <text> Body: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1856</offset>
      <text>Introduction Rapid increase of metal, mainly Pb, halide perovskite (formula ABX 3 , X = halide) based optoelectronic device performance owes largely to empirical improvements in electron/hole transport layers, ink additive engineering, and various post processing treatments.  [1] [2] [3]  Despite achieving high performance, short shelf lifetimes of perovskite inks and low operational stability of devices are paramount challenges to be overcome for commercialization of this technology.  2, 4, 5  Additives are most often included in perovskite solutions with the intention of influencing perovskite crystallization during thin film deposition.  2, [6] [7] [8] [9]  Alternatively, the surface of as-deposited thin films can be exposed to gaseous or liquid additives to alter the properties of the film and improve performance of the finished devices.  [10] [11] [12]  Many different types of solvent mixtures and additives are now widely used without consideration of the full extent of chemical reactions that can occur with perovskite constituents. Among myriad additives reported, amines are becoming increasingly common and perovskite thin films can be intentionally or unintentionally exposed to amines during various stages of fabrication and characterization. It was discovered that gaseous methylamine treatment dissolves solid methylammonium lead triiodide (MAPbI 3 ) into a liquid which can be useful for healing poor film morphologies.  13  The solubilizing benefits of amines led to their use as an additive in N,N dimethylformamide (DMF) and acetonitrile (ACN) based perovskite inks resulting in improved solar cell efficiencies.  9, 14, 15  These studies revealed that crystallization and morphology are directly influenced by amines, but there is speculation that chemical passivation occurs simultaneously.  15, 16  Additionally, post-deposition exposure of films to butylamine, poly-ethylenimine, or ethylendiamine were very effective at improving photoluminescence quantum yield resulting in enhanced device performance and/or stability.  12, 16, 17  As molecular additive engineering with amines becomes an area of focus for advancing perovskite technology, the detailed chemistry with Pb halides and other additives will become of greater importance. In this study, we identify underappreciated acid-base reactions between Pb halide salts and aliphatic amines. Counterintuitively, mixing PbI 2 with amines results in the generation of an acidic alkylammonium molecule. The chemical reaction is driven by the Lewis/soft acidity of the Pb 2+ cation in which the N-H protons are acidified by Pb 2+ upon formation of the PbX 2 Áamine coordination complex. A proton is then abstracted by a Brønsted base; in this case, a second amine molecule which generates an alkylammonium halide molecule and a Pb-alkylamide bond (generally referred to as ammonium and amide hereafter). It is known from studies on amino acid/Pb reactions that the soft acid characteristics of Pb 2+ lead to the formation of Pb-amide bonds preferentially over Pb-carboxylate bonds.  18, 19  The Pb-amide represents a dative bond that is more covalent in nature than a coordination complex bond and can potentially fulfill the role of a halide anion on the surface of the perovskite crystal. Thus, the reaction products in small amounts are capable of occupying both A-site cation and anion surface vacancies while precipitating new phases at larger concentrations. Furthermore, this concept is applied to acidification of formic acid in the presence of PbI 2 promoting deprotonation by amines which would otherwise be unfavorable in DMF. Elucidating this chemical mechanism is important for understanding the effects that additives and additive combinations have on the composition, morphology, and optoelectronic properties of metal halide perovskite thin films.  20   &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Lead II Iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-03T00:06:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="4267" length="5"/>
        <text>PbI 2</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5717</offset>
      <text> Results and discussion &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5742</offset>
      <text> Acidification of protic additive molecules Based on established transition metal halide chemistry, we propose Scheme 1 outlining the reaction mechanism between PbI 2 and various additives.  21  The general mechanism for anhydrous conditions is depicted in Scheme 1a, although one could easily envision H 2 O as either reactants HA or B. In this scheme, a protic molecule (denoted by HA) acting as a weak Brønsted acid, (1), is not deprotonated by a weak base, B, under normal conditions. However, in the presence of PbI 2 , the pK a of (  1 ) is lowered by the formation of a coordination complex (2) with PbI 2 . It then becomes favorable for a weak Brønsted base (3) to deprotonate the acidified complex (2) forming the conjugate base (4) and conjugate acid salt with iodide (5). Scheme 1b shows a plausible reaction for the case of a single additive, butylamine, which can act as both the acid and the base (i.e. HA = B) producing a Pb-butylamide bond (  6 ) and a butylammonium iodide molecule. While this reaction is well known to occur for many transition metals, reports of the formation of simple Pb-alkylamides by this mechanism are limited.  21  Scheme 1c illustrates a heterogenous reaction in which HA a B exemplified by formic acid and butylamine, respectively. In DMF, carboxylic acids (pK a E 13.5) would not be expected to be deprotonated by amines (alkylammonium pK a E 10.3).  22  However, in the presence of PbI 2 , formic acid can be acidified by coordinating to Pb 2+ and deprotonated by a sufficiently strong base to form insoluble PbI(formate) (7). This work focuses mainly on the reaction in Scheme 1b with butylamine and characterization of the PbI-butylamide product. We then demonstrate Scheme 1c occurs in DMF when HA = formic acid. These results provide important insight into chemical reactions occurring in perovskite solutions that can only be predicted by considering the combined effects of solvent, additives, and precursor properties. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7717</offset>
      <text> Case of HA = B = amines We begin with reactions of amines with PbI 2 in various solvents (reaction in Scheme 1b). Understanding amine reactions with PbI 2 is important for several reasons: (1) perovskite solutions are often prepared non-stoichiometric with excess PbI 2 ,  23, 24  (2) PbI 2 inclusions are present or form easily upon the release of MAI,  24, 25  (3) defects in MAPbI 3 , such as undercoordinated Pb surface sites and MAI deficiencies, are likely similar in reactivity to PbI 2 , 3 and (4) reacting with bulk PbI 2 produces enough material to be able to easily characterize the products. High solubility of PbI 2 in amines was easily demonstrated by dissolving concentrated PbI 2 in butylamine (B500 mg mL À1 ) at refrigeration temperatures, approximately 5-10 1C (Fig.  S1 , ESI †). When the PbI 2 /butylamine solution temperature was elevated, a large amount of pale-yellow precipitate formed which did not redissolve upon cooling. In DMF (200 mg mL À1 PbI 2 in DMF with 2 molar equivalents butylamine), the solution became turbid within 12 hours. We infer that the precipitate is the result of a chemical reaction, as Pb halides are extremely soluble in both DMF and aliphatic amines. We hypothesize that the precipitate is a Pb-iodo-butylamide, compound (6) in Scheme 1b which will be verified below. Amine/amide reactions as revealed qualitatively by precipitate formation and/or color changes were observed for a variety of primary and secondary amines as well as different PbX 2 salts (see Fig.  S2  and S3 , ESI †). Tertiary amines lacking an acidic proton, such as triethylamine, were not reactive with PbI 2 . No precipitate was observed for a reaction between PbI 2 and methylamine in DMF but, as will be shown later, a reaction still took place. In general, the length/ structure of the alkyl groups of an aliphatic amine is not expected to strongly affect the reaction in Scheme 1b other than influencing kinetics through steric hindrance. As DMF is the most-employed solvent for perovskite processing, we use it to study amine/amide reactions of PbI 2 with butylamine in similar conditions. In anhydrous DMF at 55 1C, PbI 2 reacts with butylamine on a time scale of several hours to days as shown in Fig.  1 . Including one molar equivalent of tetrabutylammonium iodide (TBAI) as an additive, a soluble iodide source lacking acidic protons, slows the precipitate formation. Days passed before the TBAI : PbI 2 solution showed signs of Pb-amide formation. Given extended reaction time (B1 month at RT), the final product of the TBAI : PbI 2 sample is very similar in appearance to the control (Fig.  S4 , ESI †). In contrast, the precipitation is nearly fully inhibited when equimolar butylammonium iodide (BAI) is dissolved with the PbI 2 . The effect of BAI was anticipated since relatively stable inks and quality films of MAPbI 3 have been processed by ACN/ methylamine solvent mixtures.  14  Furthermore, the precipitate in the control and TBAI containing solutions were fully redissolved by addition of BAI demonstrating equilibrium chemistry and good reversibility. Thus, to take advantage of the solubilizing properties of amines for perovskites, both solution ''pH'' and temperature must be kept low. While we intentionally used a large excess of amines to guarantee enough product to characterize, small amounts of precipitates were observed via the Tyndall effect for butylamine concentrations as low as 0.2 molar equivalents with respect to PbI 2 (Fig.  S5 , ESI †). Methylammonium iodide was also effective at inhibiting reactions with butylamine while formamidinium iodide, a much weaker acid, was not (Fig.  S6 , ESI †). Finally, simulating a sub-stoichiometric formulation, a solution of butylamine/MAI/PbI 2 in a 0.5 : 0.5 : 1 molar ratio in DMF developed a precipitate (Fig.  S6 , ESI †) as well indicating this reaction is especially pertinent to typical PbI 2 rich precursor ink formulations. The effect of TBAI can be understood in the context of soft acid/base interactions. Iodide is a soft base with very high affinity for soft acids and can significantly slow the kinetics by competing with amines for coordination with Pb 2+ to make [PbI 3 ] À .  26  With iodide present, the PbI 2 Áamine complex becomes much more labile. However, excess iodide (TBAI vs. BAI) alone was not able to sufficiently prevent the amide reaction from occurring. The strength of soft basicity and the resulting adduct bond is quantified by the donor number (DN).  7, 26, 27  Relative to DMF (DN = 26.6 kcal mol À1 ), 1,3-dimethyl-3,4,5,6-tetrahydro-2pyrimidinone (DMPU, DN = 33 kcal mol À1 ) slowed the butylamine/PbI 2 reaction supporting the role of competitive soft acid-base interactions.  7, 26, 27  For better or for worse, primary and secondary alkylamines (donor number E 42-50 kcal mol À1 ) Fig.  1  Photographs of PbI 2 , TBAI : PbI 2 (molar ratio 1 : 1), and BAI : PbI 2 (molar ratio 1 : 1) dissolved in DMF reacting with 2 equivalents of butyl amine (ba) additive at 55 1C. After one week, the resulting precipitates were fully reversible by the addition of excess BAI. will ultimately prevail over most other organic molecules.  27  Thus, a convenient organic molecule additive that would inhibit the amide reaction by completely blocking amine solvation yet be volatile enough to leave the perovskite film during deposition are scarce or non-existent. Reversibility of the reaction with BAI supports the acid-base chemistry proposed in Scheme 1b. To further assess the plausibility of Scheme 1b, 1 H-NMR was performed on the PbI 2 Ábutylamine complex which was isolated by reacting PbI 2 with butylamine (no DMF) followed by extraction with deuterated chloroform. Note that BAI is insoluble in chloroform and continually precipitated out as the PbI 2 Ábutylamine complex reacted with excess butylamine. The 1 H-NMR spectra of butylamine, PbI 2 Ábutylamine adduct, and butylammonium are contrasted in Fig.  2 . Relative to free butylamine, the N-H protons (indicated with *) in the PbI 2 Ábutylamine complex are shifted significantly downfield corroborating an increase in acidity. The narrowing of the N-H peak is typical of coordination complexes due to the inhibition of hydrogen bonding/proton exchange. Furthermore, the downfield shift of the N-H protons in the coordination complex is even greater than that of butylammonium. Thus, the relative pK a 's suggested by the 1 H-NMR measurements strongly support the plausibility that proton transfer to a second butylamine molecule would be favorable in solvents like chloroform. However, the pK a of acids can change considerably due to counter ion (e.g. Cl vs. I) and, more importantly, solvent choice so the reaction products in DMF require further characterization.  22  As the reaction progressed, aliquots of the reaction mixture of PbI 2 /butylamine in DMF were drop casted and characterized by XRD as shown in Fig.  3a . The sample prepared immediately after butylamine addition contains peaks solely from PbI 2 (main peak at 2y = 12.71). However, after only 2 h at 55 1C, a new phase with a peak at approximately 7.71 begins to emerge. The ratio of this unidentified phase to PbI 2 increases over the course of several days until there is no longer crystalline PbI 2 in the samples. In order to rule out the new phase simply being a result of PbI 2 Ábutylamine coordination/solvation, several measures were taken. First, 1 H-NMR of a fresh solution of PbI 2 /butylamine in deuterated-DMF showed that the butylamine completely complexes to the PbI 2 within 15 min (recall the DN of butylamine is much larger than DMF). Thus, the time scale of the formation of the unidentified phase in Fig.  3a  does not match the rate of amine solvation. Second, PbI 2 Áamine coordination complexes are known to decompose at room temperature  28  and the drop cast samples in Fig.  3  were annealed at 110 1C for 20 min to remove free or solvating butylamine. Third, a film of View Article Online drop cast PbI 2 was solvated by a gaseous butylamine atmosphere at room temperature, quickly encapsulated in PMMA, and characterized by XRD (Fig.  S7 , ESI †). The PbI 2 Ábutylamine solvate displayed a primary peak at roughly 2y E 4.21 which was absent in the films drop cast from the PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF. Unsurprisingly, the peak at 4.21 due to the PbI 2 Ábutylamine solvation complex decreased quite rapidly during the course of the measurement despite PMMA encapsulation. It is worth noting that the PbI 2 exposed to butylamine vapor formed a small amount of the Pb-amide product peak apparent from a peak at 2y = 7.71, comparable to the amount formed after 1 h in solution with DMF, which did not decrease appreciably over time. Finally, addition of methylamine : ethanol mixture (33 wt% methylamine) to a PbI 2 solution in DMF reacted to form a similar phase as the butylamine/butylamide reaction, but with a primary peak at 2y = 8.21 (Fig.  3b ). The larger scattering angle is consistent with the smaller d-spacing due to the smaller size of methylamine. Note that no precipitate was observed with methylamine which means the reaction could easily go unnoticed. X-ray photoemission (XPS) measurements identify significant nitrogen content (nitrogen must be 41 atomic% on the surface to resolve with XPS) after 4-6 hours of reaction time (Fig.  S8, ESI † ). Negligible oxygen content rules out the direct involvement of water impurities in the reaction (Fig.  S9 , ESI †). The XPS spectrum of the N 1s region of the PbI 2 /butylamine product after complete reaction is shown in Fig.  4a . The peak clearly contains two distinct N species. The high binding energy (BE) peak (Z402 eV) is identified as butylammonium by comparison to a drop cast film of BAI:PbI 2 . We attribute the lower BE peak (E401 eV) to the Pb-amide species.  29, 30  To rule out the presence of residual butylamine, a solid-state PbI 2 /linear-polyethylenimine (PEI) thin film heterojunction was also characterized (Fig.  4b ). The free amine peak is located at o400 eV (see also an Au/PEI control in Fig.  S10, ESI † ) which strongly suggests the peak at 401 eV arises from amide N. Note that three distinct N species have been previously measured in MAPbI 3 films via XPS.  31  A peak observed at 401.2 eV was particularly prominent in films processed from an ACN/methylamine solvent system.  32  In addition, the PbI 2 /PEI sample was observed to react in situ during XPS measurements. After 20 minutes of X-ray exposure during consecutive scans, the free amine peak intensity decreased concurrent with an increase in intensity of the high BE features. The photosensitivity of the amine/amide reaction was characterized by irradiating the PbI 2 / PEI heterojunction with AM1.5G simulated solar illumination for 2 hours in an N 2 atmosphere. Consistent with the N 1s peaks observed for butylamine conversion to butylammonium and butylamide in Fig.  4a , peak deconvolution of the 1 sun irradiated PbI 2 /PEI sample revealed a best fit with peaks centered at 399.5 eV, 400.9 eV, and 402 eV. Illumination clearly accelerates the conversion of the PEI amine groups to ammonium and amide species. Furthermore, the absence of solvent molecules in this solid-state reaction prove that the BE features at 402 eV and 401 eV arise solely due to a reaction between aliphatic amines and PbI 2 . Similar N species at BE E 401 eV were observed in a film of PbI 2 /methylamine reacted in DMF (Fig.  4c ). Curiously, methylammonium was absent, possibly suggesting that the amide species segregate to PbI 2 /perovskite surfaces or interfaces. Additionally, a thin film spin coated from an MAI deficient ink (MAI : PbI 2 ratio = 0.8 : 1 in DMF) in which the 20% excess PbI 2 was allowed to react with the methylamine additive for 1 week contained a considerable amount of amide species. This condition of excess PbI 2 is highly relevant for typical perovskite ink formulations.  23, 24  More importantly, Fig.  3a  and 4c  clearly demonstrate the plausibility of amide incorporation in fresher solutions (aged less than 1 day) using amine additives, likely at concentrations below the detection limit of XPS. The amide incorporation in MAPbI 3 films was correlated to photoluminescence improvements (Fig.  S11, ESI † ) which is consistent with reports of amine passivating perovskite surfaces.  9, 15  Finally, the insoluble PbI-butylamide product was isolated by decanting the DMF and repeated ACN washings to solubilize and selectively remove ammonium halides which, in turn, help to dissolve unreacted PbI 2 . The N 1s XPS spectra of the materials soluble and insoluble in ACN indeed indicate that ammonium and amide components were segregated by this method (Fig.  S12, ESI † ). We hypothesize from Scheme 1b that the insoluble material is composed of a Pb-halide-butylamide of the formula: PbI[NH(CH 2 ) 3 CH 3 ]. This material resembles a class of materials referred to as coordination polymers and are commonly synthesized from transition metal halides.  [33] [34] [35]  The precipitate collected after subsequent DMF and ACN washing was characterized by thermal gravimetric analysis (TGA) shown in Fig.  5  (for PbI 2 controls see Fig.  S13, ESI † ). The TGA samples were held at 150 1C for 10 min before starting the scan in order to remove any residual coordinating solvent molecules including DMF.  7  Under N 2 flow (Fig.  S13 , ESI †), the PbI 2 control begins to sublime at 430 1C (5% mass loss). Under air flow the mass loss of PbI 2 at 450 1C corresponds to replacement of the two iodide by oxygen to make PbO 1.6 , the expected stoichiometry for the temperature range 400-500 1C.  36  At higher temperatures, the PbO 1.6 continues to decompose in several more steps (presumably to PbO 1.4 , PbO 1.2 , and PbO).  36  In contrast, the butylamine reaction product begins to decompose at approximately 230 1C, much lower temperature than PbI 2 . Based on Scheme 1b, we hypothesize that the insoluble PbI 2 /butylamine reaction product is likely a PbI-butylamide as opposed to a Pb diamide.  21, 29, 30  Assuming this stoichiometry, the 18% mass loss between 200-400 1C correspond strikingly well to the expected change due to loss of the amide group in N 2 (Fig.  5a ) and 14% mass loss due to replacement by oxygen in air (Fig.  5b ). The expected mass losses for PbI 2 Ábutylamine solvation complexes are listed in Table  S1  (ESI †).  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22178</offset>
      <text> View Article Online As both DMF and butylamine should be expelled from the material below 150 1C, the agreement of TGA in N 2 and air strongly support that the chemical composition of the insoluble PbI 2 /butylamine reaction product is indeed the singly substituted PbI[NH(CH 2 ) 3 CH 3 ].  7  Most of the discussion of the Lewis acidity of Pb 2+ and PbI 2 in perovskite literature has focused on Lewis acid-base coordination complexes or adducts with aprotic Lewis bases like DMF, dimethylsulfoxide, thiourea, and pyridines.  [6] [7] [8] 10, 11  These dative perovskite-organic coordination bonds have been shown to form with molecules such as pyridines, phosphine oxides, sulphur moieties, esters, etc. resulting in passivation of surface traps and non-radiative recombination centers.  7, 8, 10, 11  In contrast, this work indicates another option, demonstrating the plausibility of Pb-amide bond formation in perovskite solutions and subsequent incorporation in thin films. The Pb-amide bond is similar yet distinct from a coordination complex bond (e.g. PbÁamine, PbÁpyridine) in that it is more covalent in nature. The higher energy of the Pb-amide bond is reflected in the thermal decomposition onset 4200 1C whereas PbI 2 Ápyridine complexes are known to decompose at o100 1C.  28  We assert that post-thin-film-deposition amine treatments are susceptible to amide formation at PbI 2 inclusions or undercoordinated Pb surface defects, which are proposed non-radiative recombination sites.  11, 37  Note that an ammonium is simultaneously produced for every amide such that both an A-site and X-site vacancy can be annihilated via the same reaction. Additionally, the density of states at the valence and conduction band extrema are composed mainly of Pb and iodide orbitals while the A-site sublattice does not contribute to band edge electronic states.  38  Thus, a molecule covalently bonded to Pb at a perovskite surface is a potentially ideal passivating agent. The properties or benefits of small amounts of Pb-amide species in perovskite films are as yet unknown but are the subject of a follow up study.  20  However, the demonstration of perovskite solar cells with high power conversion efficiencies from processes utilizing amines motivates obtaining a deeper understanding of amine/amide chemistry with Pb halides. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24517</offset>
      <text> Case of HA a B We demonstrate the generality of the mechanism identified in the amine/amide reaction by applying it to heterogeneous reactions (i.e. the acid and base are dissimilar molecules) induced by PbI 2 that are otherwise unfavorable. The situation is exemplified in Scheme 1c by the reaction between formic acid and amines which have both been employed in perovskite processes independently.  9  Additionally, the presence of formate has recently been identified in perovskite films (before annealing) fabricated from aged perovskite inks in which hydrolysis of DMF released dimethylamine and formic acid.  5  In DMF, formic acid is not acidic enough to be deprotonated by an aliphatic amine.  22  However, the acidity is increased upon complexation with PbI 2 which drives deprotonation. Upon the addition of a small amount of butylamine, a solution of PbI 2 /formic acid in DMF instantaneously forms a precipitate. Indeed, 1 H-NMR spectra of a formic acid/butylamine mixture in deuterated DMF shows that proton exchange does not occur (Fig.  6 ). In fact, the hydrogen bonding between formic acid and butylamine make the acidic proton on formic acid observable as a broad peak at 10.1 ppm. The rapid exchange of the proton between oxygens in a carboxylic acid make them very difficult to detect in the formic acid control. However, the supernatant of a reaction of PbI 2 /formic acid/ butylamine in deuterated-DMF reveals a butylammonium peak at approximately 8.1 ppm which corresponds well to a BAI control. Note that formic acid DN = 19 kcal mol À1 so the PbI 2 Áformic acid complex would be expected to be a very labile species in the presence of DMF and butylamine.  27  Despite the relatively low concentration of the PbI 2 Áformic acid complex in DMF, it is effectively deprotonated by butylamine to produce PbI(formate) The spectra indicate that the presence of PbI 2 induces proton transfer from formic acid to butylamine in d7-DMF whereas no reaction is observed for the formic acid + butylamine control. and BAI. As hydrolysis of DMF releases dimethylamine and formic acid, the importance of understanding impurity reactions, the products induced by the Lewis acidity of PbI 2 , the influence on perovskite film crystallization, and effects on device stability cannot be underestimated. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26829</offset>
      <text> Conclusions In summary protic molecules commonly used as halide perovskite processing additives are acidified when solvated to an acidic Pb 2+ center. This change in pK a induces proton transfer to a suitable base molecule leading to unanticipated chemistry in perovskite precursor solutions. We demonstrate the Lewis acidity of PbI 2 causes proton transfer from carboxylic acids to amines in DMF. More importantly, an acid-base reaction between amines and PbI 2 releases protons to produce Pb-amide and ammonium species in solution which can be incorporated into thin films. Formate and amide impurities may play a significant role in the crystallization, morphology, and properties of perovskite thin films fabricated from different processes and ink formulations as well as the differences in film properties resulting from variable aging time of solutions. The insight provided by this work into different types of dative bonds that can form from additive chemistry in perovskite films elucidates a new approach for covalently bonding amide groups to undercoordinated Pb sites and also raises questions regarding the role of these complexes in resulting devices. As the processing of perovskite films becomes more complex, understanding and predicting the detailed structure/bonding of impurities is paramount for advancing performance and stability of metal halide perovskite based optoelectronic devices. solid was dried under vacuum for 8 h before loading into the TGA where it was dried at 150 o C for 10 min prior to starting a scan. Photoluminescence measurements were performed on an Edinburgh Instruments FLS980 photoluminescence spectrometer with an excitation wavelength of 550 nm. Acid/Base Chemistry of a variety of Pb salts. A variety of primary and secondary amines reacted with PbX 2 salts (X = Cl, Br, I, and NO 3 ). Tertiary amines and salts of PbX (such as X = SO 4 ) were not observed to react. Salient observations include azobenzene formation between aqueous Pb(NO 3 ) 2 and aniline and gelation when PbBr 2 was reacted with butylamine in DMF under certain conditions.      Fig.  S7 . XRD versus time of a drop cast film of PbI 2 solvated in a butylamine atmosphere and subsequently encapsulated in PMMA by spin coating (50 mg/mL in chlorobenzene at 4000 rpm giving roughly 300 nm of PMMA). The peak at low angle decreases over time as the solvate loses butylamine at room temperature which is only slowed by the PMMA. The peaks near 2θ ≈ 6.4 o are very near to that of BA 2 PbI 4 which is expected to form from a PbI 2 •butylamine solvate exposed to atmosphere due to a reaction with water.       Fig. 2 2 Fig. 2 Chemical shifts of the N-H protons measured by 1 H-NMR of butylamine, butylammonium, and PbI 2 Ábutylamine coordination complex in deuterated chloroform. The magnitude of the downfield shifts corroborates the acidification of butylamine complexed to Pb 2+ . Fig. 3 (a) Normalized XRD patterns of drop cast samples of a PbI 2 / butylamine (1 : 2) solution in DMF as a function of reaction time showing a gradual shift from PbI 2 to a new phase potentially containing Pb-butylamide moieties. (b) Comparison of XRD of the PbI 2 /methylamine (ma) reaction product to PbI 2 /butylamine (ba) reaction product. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30080</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 N 4 Fig. 4 N 1s XPS of (a) drop cast samples of BAI : PbI 2 (1 : 1 ratio in DMF) and the supernatant of the PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF, (b) a thin film bilayer of PbI 2 /linear-PEI showing in situ changes in relative intensity of the free amine peak (BE E 399.5 eV) and amide/ammonium peaks (BE 4 400 eV), (c) thin films of an MAPbI 3 control (1 : 1 MAI : PbI 2 ratio) and PbI 2 /methylamine reaction in DMF showing amide formation with methylamine, and (d) amide formation in a non-stoichiometric MAI : PbI 2 solution in DMF after the addition of methylamine. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30657</offset>
      <text> Fig. 5 5 Fig. 5 TGA of the isolated precipitate from the reaction of PbI 2 and butylamine in DMF under (a) N 2 and (b) ambient air. The mass losses indicated for (a) butylamide removal and (b) replacement of butylamide by oxygen confirm the hypothesized starting composition of PbI[CH 3 (CH 2 ) 3 NH]. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30961</offset>
      <text> Fig. 6 6 Fig. 6 1 H-NMR at (a) high and (b) low chemical shifts of combinations of formic acid (fa), butylamine (ba), and PbI 2 in deuterated DMF (d7-DMF).The spectra indicate that the presence of PbI 2 induces proton transfer from formic acid to butylamine in d7-DMF whereas no reaction is observed for the formic acid + butylamine control. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31305</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S2. (vials on the right in each image) Days old mixtures of Pb(NO 3 ) 2 and an excess of (a) butylamine, (b) diethylamine, (c) triethylamine, (d) aniline, (e) N, methylaniline, and (f) N,N dimethylaniline alongside (vials on the left in each image) a control of the neat amine liquid reacted at 50 o C. Days old mixtures of PbI 2 with an excess of (g) butylamine, (h) diethylamine, and (i) triethylamine alongside the control of the neat amine liquid reacted at 50 o C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31791</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S3. A reaction of 4 equivalents of butylamine with (a) PbBr 2 in DMF (~183 mg/mL) and (b) PbI 2 (200 mg/mL) completely gelled after 1 day at 55 o C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31956</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 . S4 Figure S4. Equimolar tetra-BAI:PbI 2 in DMF after adding 2 equivalents of butylamine and storing at room temperature for 2 months. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32104</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S5. (a) Solutions of 200 mg/mL of PbI 2 in DMF with (from left to right) 0, 0.1, 0.2, and 0.5 molar equivalents of butylamine (ba) after reacting for 1 week at 55 o C. Visible precipitates are observed to form even for small additions of butylamine down to 0.2 molar equivalents. (b) Tyndall effect helps to visualize precipitates forming for butylamine ratios down to 0.1 whereas no precipitates are observed in the control solution. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32555</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S6. (a) Solutions of PbI 2 in DMF (200 mg/mL) with additives ratios from left to right: methylammonium iodide (MAI):butylamine (ba):PbI 2 (molar ratio 1:1:1), formamidinium iodide (FAI):ba:PbI 2 (molar ratio 1:1:1), and ba:MAI:PbI 2 (molar ratio 0.5:0.5:1) in DMF at a concentration of 200 mg/mL with respect to PbI 2 . The solutions were reacted for one month at room temperature. The FAI and MAI deficient solutions produced an insoluble product which is clearly illustrated by the Tyndall effect (b). The ba:MAI:PbI 2 0.5:0.5:1 solution illustrates that any excess of PbI 2 w.r.t. MAI in solution is available participate in acid-base reactions with free amines. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33237</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S9. O 1s XPS of PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF versus time showing negligible oxygen content. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33345</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S10. XPS of a thin film of linear-PEI on a glass/Au substrate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33424</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. Photoluminescence of thin films spin coated from stoichiometric and non-stoichiometric (MAI:PbI 2 = 0.8:1) reacted with methylamine in solution showing improved emission and blue-shift compared to the stoichiometric control film. Films were encapsulated in a layer of PMMA (50 mg/mL in chlorobenzene). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33753</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12. N 1s XPS of the products of the neat reaction of PbI 2 with butylamine (4 equivalents, 24 hours at 60 o C) which were soluble or insoluble in ACN. The butylammonium iodide was selectively extracted due to its solubility in ACN whereas the amide product remained in the precipitate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34047</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. TGA under (a) N 2 and (b) ambient air flow of PbI 2 powder. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34134</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8. Evolution of the N 1s XPS of PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF versus time. The lowest measurable N content is approximately 1-2 atomic % via XPS. 70000 0hrs 1hr 2hrs Intensity (cps) 40000 50000 60000 4hrs 6hrs 12hrs 24hrs 48hrs 30000 404 402 400 398 396 Binding Energy (eV) 1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34422</offset>
      <text>			 This journal is © The Royal Society of Chemistry 2019</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
