<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025029594BEDIIG</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_review">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 39&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>2D/3D perovskite engineering eliminates interfacial recombination losses in hybrid perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>118</offset>
      <text>Understanding interface energetics and physics is essential for gaining fundamental knowledge of perovskite solar cells' operation and optimization. 2D/ 3D perovskite interfaces incorporating thiophene-based bulky organic cations are investigated. By fine tuning the halide counterion of the thiophene-based cation, a p-n junction is formed at the interface. The formation of a p-n junction eliminates the interfacial recombination losses by reducing the electron density, resulting in devices with high V OC , which approach the potential internal quasi-Fermi level splitting of the perovskite absorber.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>723</offset>
      <text>2D/3D perovskite engineering eliminates interfacial recombination losses in hybrid perovskite solar cells Albertus A. Sutanto, 1 Pietro Caprioglio,  2, 3  Nikita Drigo,  1  Yvonne J. Hofstetter,  4  Ines Garcia-Benito,  1  Valentin I.E. Queloz,  1  Dieter Neher,  2  Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, 1, * Martin Stolterfoht, 2, * Yana Vaynzof,  4 , * and Giulia Grancini  1, 5, 6 , * INTRODUCTION Understanding and exploiting interfacial physics is key in perovskite solar cell engineering and optimization.  1, 2  That is especially true when interface losses play a dominant role, and complex interface functionalization is essential to minimize them. In the field of hybrid perovskite engineering, much attention has been lately focused on multi-dimensional perovskite interfaces consisting of a wider band gap layered (namely, two dimensional-2D) perovskite deposited between the bulk 3D perovskite and the hole-transporting layer (HTL) in a standard mesoporous configuration.  [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9]  Such configuration is currently among the most effective strategies to enhance both the efficiency and stability of perovskite solar cells.  3, [10] [11] [12] [13] [14]  In general, it is considered that the 2D perovskite acts as both an efficient means to passivate the surface traps (leading to reduced defect recombination) and also as an electron-blocking layer owing to its wider band gap.  [15] [16] [17] [18] [19] [20]  However, despite these empirical observations, the energetic alignment at the interface and the relative function of the 2D/3D interface are only qualitatively depicted with a partial understanding of these aspects. This lack of knowledge prevents the advancement of device efficiencies toward the theoretical Shockley-Queisser predictions beyond the common trial and error approach.  21  More specifically, the exact role of the interface &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2597</offset>
      <text> The bigger picture Understanding interface energetics and physics is paramount to obtain exact knowledge about the function and operation of a device. This stands true for solar cells and for devices where interfaces are crucial. In this work, for the first time, we determine the exact knowledge on the interface energetics across 2D/3D perovskite interfaces showing that it forms a p-n junction that is capable of suppressing the interfacial recombination losses. This leads to the photovoltaic devices with high open-circuit voltage, which approach the potential internal quasi-Fermi level splitting of the perovskite absorber, nullifying the losses. This is a breakthrough in this field. Chem 7, 1903-1916, July 8, 2021 ª 2021 Elsevier Inc. 1903 ll band structure and energetics and their effect on the processes and loss mechanisms remain largely unexplored, mainly due to the lack of a direct experimental evidence. In this study, we target the interface energetics of optimized 2D/3D perovskite systems by measuring the vertical energy level landscape by an innovative ultraviolet photoemission spectroscopy (UPS) depth profiling technique. The analysis reveals intriguing variations of the interfacial energetics, which depend on the chemical nature of the 2D overlayer. Specifically, we explore a series of thiophene-based cations that form the 2D perovskite layer, which differ slightly in their chemical structure. When integrated in a 2D/3D-based perovskite solar cell, they deliver approximately 21% power conversion efficiency and open-circuit voltage (V OC ) approaching 1.2 V. The photovoltaic performance is intimately linked to 2D/3D interfacial band bending and to a natural formation of a p-n junction in optimal devices. By calculating the quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) from photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) for the neat material and the complete device, we identify that the optimal energetic alignment and reduced electron density at the interface serve as the reasons for such a significant reduction in the nonradiative interfacial recombination losses. This allows us to reach radiative efficiencies of 2% in completed devices, which is far above average.  2  Importantly, the recombination mechanisms proposed are corroborated by drift-diffusion simulation. The optimized 2D/3D interface shows zero interfacial voltage losses, reaching the QFLS-potential of the neat perovskite absorber, thus nullifying the energy losses at the interfaces. As such, we rationalized the mechanisms and the effect of 2D/ 3D interfaces on the effective reduction of the interfacial energy losses, providing a clear path for pushing perovskite solar cells performances closer to their theoretical limits.  2  In particular, we elucidate the fundamental principles of how the creation of 3D/2D heterojunctions and the energy alignment at the hole-selective interface allow us to overcome the decisive interfacial recombination losses of minority carriers at the interface to spiro-OMeTAD interface. This is achieved with a 2-TMAI (Br)-based 2D perovskite layer, which forms an apparent p-n junction with the 3D perovskite, thereby blocking the minority carriers from reaching the spiro-OMeTAD layer. Notably, in this system, the main voltage loss is only because of nonradiative recombination in the perovskite absorber layer, whereas interface recombination is essentially absent. This finding bears important implications for further perovskite design as several perovskites now achieve radiative efficiencies that are very close to the radiative limits.  2, [22] [23] [24] [25]  Hence, our approach to effectively suppress the interfacial recombination may hold the key to create near-ideal perovskite cells in the near future if applied to perovskite layers with very high PLQYs. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:44:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="5590" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6401</offset>
      <text> RESULTS AND DISCUSSION The 2D/3D interfaces investigated here are based on a novel set of bulky thiopheneterminated cations, namely, 2-thiophenemethylammonium iodide (2-TMAI), 9,26 2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide (2-TMABr), and 2-thiophenemethylammonium chloride (2-TMACl), that serve as a building block for the formation of the 2D perovskite layer on top of the 3D bulk layer (Figure  1A ). The 3D perovskite layer is based on a triple-cation composition [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.87 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.13 ] 0.92 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.08 with a band gap of 1.610 eV. The chemical structures of the thiophenemethylammonium salts are shown in Figure  1B . The three different 2-thiophenemethylammonium halides (2-TMAX, where X: Cl, Br, I) were prepared from the commercially available amines and the corresponding acids (see experimental procedures). The salts were then diluted in isopropanol (IPA) and dynamically spin-coated on top of the triple-cation-based 3D perovskite film. 2D perovskites were selectively grown by controlling the excess PbI 2 composition (PbI 2 :FAI = 1.05:1) in the 3D perovskite, which reacts with the thiophene ammonium halide cations to form the 2D layer.  4, 9, 26  Figure  1B  shows the X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of the 2D/3D films collected at a low diffraction angle. When the 2-TMAX is used to coat the 3D layer, intense reflexes at 4.3 and 8.6 appeared at the XRD diffractograms, consistent with the key characteristic peaks of 2D perovskites (n = 2).  9, 26  In the case of 2-TMAI, an additional reflection at 6.1 was observed, which corresponds to the n = 1 phase of 2D perovskite.  9  The XRD pattern of the 3D perovskite layer as the control is depicted in Figure  S1 . Cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images shown in Figure  1C  show that the 500 nm thick 3D perovskite layer was continuously coated with a 2D overlayer, with a thickness of approximately 50-60 nm. The top surface images reveal that the formation of the 2D layers results in smoother surfaces, with lessdefined grain boundaries and crystal borders. This was particularly evident in the cases of 2-TMAI and 2-TMABr, whereas in the case of 2-TMACl, a distribution of distinct phases with larger and more elongated grains was visible. The absorption spectra of the 2D/3D thin films are reported in Figure  S2 , while Figure  S3  shows the PL spectra upon excitation from the front side of the film. Notably, in all cases, a clear peak at the lower wavelength region was observed, confirming the formation of a distinct 2D perovskite overlayer. 2-TMAI-based 2D/3D exhibited PL emission peak at 520 and 570 nm, which correspond to n = 1 and n = 2 phases of 2D perovskite, respectively. On the other hand, 2-TMABr and 2-TMACl-based 2D/ 3D only showed an emission peak at the low wavelength region ($545 nm), which is associated with the n = 2 phase. Furthermore, in agreement with what we recently reported, 9 the 2-TMAI-based 2D/3D showed a slightly reduced band gap with respect to the 2-TMABr and 2-TMACl, as revealed by the photoluminescence peak emission shift (of around 0.1 eV) in Figure  S3 . The photovoltaic (PV) response of the 2-TMAX-based 2D/3D perovskite solar cells are shown in Figure  2 , and the PV parameters for champion devices are summarized in Table 1. The hysteresis measurements are reported in Figure  S4  and Table  S2 . With respect to the control, a clear increase in the V OC was observed with the 2D perovskite layer that was higher for 2-TMABr and 2-TMACl. It is important to note that the device V OC reported here is underestimated due to the use of a small mask (0.16 cm 2 ) on a large pixel (0.54 cm 2 ). The reduction in V OC values due to the masking effect could be calculated by the equation DV OC = kT/q ln(A aperture /A device ), where kT/q is the thermal voltage, A aperture is the mask aperture, and A device is the pixel area.  27  Considering that the dark current of the pixel is not affected by the mask, this implies a $3.4-fold overestimation of the dark saturation current (J 0 ), which is equivalent to a voltage loss of 31 mV. When measuring was done without mask, the real maximum device voltage (represented with stars in Figure  2B ) for the reference cell was 1.141 V, while for 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl, the values were 1.153, 1.193, and 1.175 V, respectively (see also Figure  S5 ), which are among the highest values reported so far for n-i-p devices with a mesoporous structure. Importantly, the 2-TMABr shows a remarkable increase in V OC , without compromising the fill factor (FF), which remains comparable to the control device, resulting in an overall increase in the device efficiency. On the other hand, the 2-TMACl shows a reduction in the FF. The highest PV performance is therefore achieved with 2-TMABr-based 2D devices, delivering a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 20.82%. We noticed that in this series of 2D perovskites, a slight decrease in the short-circuit current (J SC ) was observed. The J SC values obtained from the J-V measurements were in agreement with the calculated J SC from the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra (Figure  S6 ). This decrease might be related to the limitation in the charge transport induced by the presence of the bulky organic moieties. The long-term stability of the devices was monitored under continuous illumination of 1-sun intensity for 1,000 h in an argon atmosphere and is shown in Figure  2D . While the performance of the standard 3D device is reduced to 65% of its initial PCE, the 2D-functionalized solar cells showed a reduced loss in the PCE, with the 2-TMABr/ 3D devices displaying the best stability retaining 75% of the initial PCE after 1,000 h. This confirms that the 2D surface functionalization has a crucial impact on the device lifetime with the best performances achieved with the 2-TMABr-based 2D perovskite. 2D/3D perovskite devices are demonstrated to be highly sensitive to the nature of the organic cation that impacts the device V OC and FF. To elucidate the link between material properties and device performances, it is necessary to directly probe the energetic alignment of the 2D/3D interfaces. The traditional methodology based on UPS measurements is only capable of probing the top 1-2 nm of the surface and will not provide an insight regarding the buried 2D/3D interface. Recently, we developed a method termed UPS depth profiling technique, which allows probing the energetic landscape at the bulk of materials and across buried interfaces.  28  The principle of this technique is shown in Figure  3A  and is based on the essentially damage-free etching enabled by argon gas-cluster ion beams-(1) in combination with UPS measurements and (2) after each etching step. While this method has been previously applied solely to organic systems and organic/inorganic systems,  [29] [30] [31]  this is the first example of its application for the study of perovskite materials. Using this method, we could accurately measure the progression of the vacuum level and valence band positions as a function of film depth, as depicted in the illustration in Figure  3B , providing an in situ measurement of the interfacial energy levels alignment in a 2D/3D system for the first time (Figure  3C ). The position of the conduction band was then estimated by adding the corresponding optical gap. The UPS measurements reveal that the ionization potential (IP) of the 2D and 3D perovskites are all very similar (in the range 6.2-6.6 eV). This is in agreement with previous studies on BA 2 PbI 4 (IP = 6.5 eV) and BA 2 PbBr 4 (IP = 5.8 eV),  32  the IP values of which were found to be in good agreement with those of the corresponding 3D perovskites.  33, 34  The similarity of the IPs is also in agreement with the results of the study conducted by Zhang et al., who observed a change in IP of only 0.1 eV between the 3D and the 2D perovskites they investigated.  32  The matching IPs explain why 2D perovskites can serve as capping layers for 3D perovskites in the n-i-p architecture in which they can permit the extraction of holes, while blocking electrons owing to their higher-lying conduction bands. While the ionization potentials of the materials are similar, UPS depth profiling of the three sets of 2D/3D samples revealed significant differences in their interfacial energetic alignment. Examining the band structure, it is clear that exchanging the halide on the bulky cations has important consequences for the evolution of the valence band levels: (1) 2-TMABr and 2-TMAI showed a shift in valence band compared with the 3D perovskite, indicating an effective energy level alignment to promote hole extraction, while 2-TMACl exhibited an opposite trend, with a slight uphill energy barrier (over the entire 2D layer). This resulted in the first two cases in the formation of a p-n junction, which promoted charge extraction. Notably, this is consistent with the low FF observed in the 2-TMACl 2D/3D devices. (2) All the 2D/3D interfaces investigated exhibited excellent electron-blocking properties, with the energetic barrier being enhanced from 0.55 eV for 2-TMAI to 0.63 and 0.68 eV for 2-TMABr and 2-TMACl, respectively. The improvement in electron blocking suggested a more efficient reduction of minority carriers at the HTL interface of the device, which is in good agreement with the corresponding enhancement in the opencircuit voltage observed from the photovoltaic results. Notably, in all cases, the 3D perovskite was n-type, which is in agreement with the PbI 2 excess used in this case (see reference measurement on a 3D film in Figure  S7 ).  34  Surprisingly, while the 2D layer formed by the 2-TMACl cation followed a similar character to that of the 3D perovskite, 2-TMABr and 2-TMAI denoted a clear transition toward a p-type material. Such a transition is responsible for the formation of a p-n junction at the interface, offering the possibility to improve the charge extraction and reduce interface recombination. This is particularly evident in the cases of 2-TMABr and 2-TMAI, while it is less manifested at the 2-TMACl-based interface, possibly due to a less homogeneous 2D surface layer (see SEM top view in Figure  1C ). As such, this proves that band bending happens at an optimized 2D/3D perovskite interface, contributing to improving the device performance, as reported for other PV technologies.  35  A similar formation of a p-n junction also occurs in other cations, such as 2-thiopheneethylammonium iodide (2-TEAI) and 3-methylammonium iodide (3-TMAI) (Figure  S8 ), which also show high photovoltaic performance.  9  These results are also supported by numerical drift-diffusion device simulations, based on a well-established model,  [36] [37] [38] [39] [40] [41]  which compares the effect of the additional 2D layer and the different energetic alignment scenarios based on the experimental results obtained for the reference 3D samples, 2-TMABr and 2-TMACl (Figures  S9A-S9C ). The effect of the enhanced electron blocking at the 2D/3D interface is evident when comparing the carrier densities in the proximity of the HTL interface (Figures S9D-S9F, dashed red circle). In the case of 2D/3D systems, the electron density at that interface is significantly reduced when compared with the reference 3D case. When incorporating the 2-TMABr layer into the device structure, the simulated V OC increases from $1.14 to $1.19 V (Figure  S9G ), which is in excellent agreement with the experimental J-V results. This increase can be attributed to the strong reduction of the electron density in the 2D perovskite closer to the interface with the HTL, which effectively limits the interfacial recombination losses (see Figure  3H ).  42  Overall, in the case of the 2-TMABr cation, the band bending reduces the electron accumulation at the interface with the HTL, thereby reducing charge recombination while effectively driving holes into the HTM without inducing FF losses. Together, these processes provide an effective means to eliminate the severe nonradiative recombination loss at the HTM/perovskite interface. To further corroborate these findings and to understand the physical processes governing these 2D/3D interfaces triggering the improvement in device V OC , we measured the PL spectra, as shown in Figures  S10A  and S10B , and we calculated the photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY, Figure  S10C ). The PLQY values were then used to derive the QFLS in neat materials and complete solar cell devices, as shown in Figure  4 . This analysis allowed us to assess the relative contribution of bulk and interfacial recombination losses and also the impact of the interfacial energy alignment.  2, 39, 43  We noticed that the neat materials exhibited PLQYs over 1% (see Figures S10A and S10C), which is quite typical for mixed perovskites. The results also highlight that the addition of a 2D layer improves the QFLS of the neat perovskite absorber (triangle in Figure  4A ), indicating a trap-passivating behavior and/or a reduction of minority charges at the defect-dense perovskite surface in the presence of the 2D layer.  2  More importantly, however, the PLQY of the 2-TMABr device approached 2%, which is above average (see Figures  S10B  and S10C ).  38  The deviation from the Shockley-Queisser radiative V OC limit is due to mainly two factors. The first one is the nonradiative recombination in the perovskite absorber. As observed from the PLQY of the neat materials, the QFLS is already limited to roughly 1.25 eV, indicating a certain degree of recombination limiting the potential V OC . The second limiting factor is interface recombination between the perovskite and the transport layers. Usually, the latter is strongly limiting the V OC of Pb-based perovskite cells. Notably, in our 2D/3D system, since the QFLS of the neat materials matched with a good degree to the V OC of the complete device, the main voltage loss was only due to nonradiative recombination in the perovskite absorber layer, while interface recombination was essentially absent. Furthermore, Figure  4  shows that the trend in the nonradiative recombination losses in the devices as determined from the PLQY (squares in Figure  4 ) follows the trend observed in the J-V measurements. Interestingly, when the QFLS of the device was compared with the QFLS of the neat material, we found that all devices that employ the 2D layer display smaller energy losses due to less interfacial recombination losses compared with the reference cell. This confirms a key conclusion from the UPS measurements and the numerical simulations, which is that the 2D layer effectively reduces the density of minority carriers at the HTL interface. Importantly, the device based on 2-TMABr as the cation exhibits an equal QFLS in the neat material and in the complete device, which is also approximately equal to the device V OC (stars in Figure  4 ). This highlights the presence of a lossless perovskite/HTL interface and that the 2-TMABr/3D layer enables to reach the QFLS-potential of the neat perovskite layer.  2  These results are in accordance with the UPS depth profiling and simulation data. However, in the case of the reference device and to a lesser extent in the devices with the other 2D layers, the internal QFLS is considerably higher than the external V OC . As recently discussed, this effect can be explained by an internal bending of the hole quasi-Fermi level, which impacts primarily the device V OC rather than the QFLS in the perovskite layer and suggesting an energy misalignment between the perovskite and the transport layer. This represents an additional interfacial recombination loss that is not captured by measuring the PL emission from the cell.  38, 39  Considering that the internal QFLS is significantly higher than the external V OC in the reference device, an energy misalignment between the perovskite and the spiro-OMeTAD is suggested. Hence, the application of 2D layers might further reduce the detrimental effect of an energetic misalignment between the perovskite and the spiro-OMeTAD layer, as it effectively blocks the minority carriers from reaching the spiro-OMeTAD layer. In fact, we found that 2-TMABr and the formation of the p-n junction is most effective at suppressing all interfacial recombination losses, where the V OC is only limited by the radiative efficiency of the neat material. In conclusion, by combining a comprehensive analysis on device performances, device and interface QFLS, and interface energetics, we demonstrate that even subtle changes in the composition of the 2D perovskite can lead to differences in the energetic alignment at the 2D/3D interface, with a direct impact on charge density distribution, interfacial recombination, and ultimately on the device performance. Our work provides the first demonstration of an optimized 2-TMABr-based 2D/3D perovskite solar cells with zero interfacial voltage losses, reaching the QFLS-potential of the neat perovskite absorber, thus nullifying the energy losses at the interfaces. UPS depth profiling is demonstrated to be a valuable method allowing the direct probe of the interfacial alignment and band bending. Overall, this knowledge is essential to drive interfacial chemistry and functionalization to guide a smart device optimization. Combining chemical manipulation of the 2D perovskite and a deep understanding of the 2D/3D interface energetics and recombination processes, our results provide clear evidence that 2D/3D interface engineering with optimal energetics allows nullifying the nonradiative interfacial recombination of electron and holes, demonstrating a breakthrough in the path to further enhance perovskite solar cell performance. gradually and then it was poured into an excess of diethyl ether (Et ) in DMF and DMSO mixture with the volume ratio of 0.78:0.22. An excess of PbI 2 by 5% toward FAI was used in the precursor solution to control the growth of the 2D perovskite layer. The 3D perovskite layer was deposited by spin coating the precursor solution at 2,000 rpm for 12 s and 5,000 rpm for 30 s. Chlorobenzene was poured on top of the spinning substrate 15 s prior to the end of the spin-coating process. The deposited 3D perovskite film was annealed at 100 C for 60 min. Then, the film was allowed to cool down to the room temperature, and the corresponding thiophenemethylammonium halide cations (60 mM in isopropanol) was deposited dynamically under 4,000 rpm for 30 s. The film was then annealed at 100 C for 6 min on a hotplate. Spiro-OMeTAD (Merck) with a concentration of 60 mmol in 1 mL of chlorobenzene as hole-transporting material doped with 31.28 mL of 4-tert-butylpyridine (Sigma-Aldrich), 18.57 mL of Li-bis (trifluoromethanesulphonyl) imide (Aldrich) from the stock solution (196 mg in 379 mL acetonitrile), and 13.69 mL of FK 209 Co(III) TFSI (GreatCellSolar) from the stock solution (99 mg in 263 mL acetonitrile) was deposited by spin coating at 4,000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, a gold counter electrode (70 nm) was deposited by the physical vapor deposition process under high vacuum. Thin-films characterizations Photoluminescence Steady-state photoluminescence spectra were recorded on a Fluorolog3-22 spectrofluorometer upon excitation at 450 nm. The emission was measured from both the top and bottom surfaces of the film. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:48:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="6535" length="32"/>
        <text>2-thiophenemethylammonium iodide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:48:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="6569" length="6"/>
        <text>2-TMAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:44:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="6583" length="33"/>
        <text>2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:44:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="6618" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMABr</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:46:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="6632" length="34"/>
        <text>2-thiophenemethylammonium chloride</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:46:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="6668" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMACl</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(FAPbI 3 ) 0.87(MAPbBr3)0.13]0.92(CsPbI3)0.08</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:44:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="6862" length="55"/>
        <text>(FAPbI 3 ) 0.87 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.13 ] 0.92 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.08</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:48:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="10642" length="6"/>
        <text>2-TMAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:48:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="10650" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMABr</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:46:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="10663" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMACl</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.153</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:46:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="10688" length="5"/>
        <text>1.153</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.193</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:45:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="10695" length="5"/>
        <text>1.193</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.175</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:45:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="10706" length="7"/>
        <text>1.175 V</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20.82</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:47:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="11253" length="5"/>
        <text>20.82</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:49:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="11672" length="97"/>
        <text>long-term stability of the devices was monitored under continuous illumination of 1-sun intensity</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:49:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="11774" length="7"/>
        <text>1,000 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:49:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="11896" length="3"/>
        <text>65%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:49:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="11997" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMABr</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">0.75</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:49:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="12057" length="3"/>
        <text>75%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-thiophenemethylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:44:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="17736" length="7"/>
        <text>2-TMABr</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R4">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:50:10Z</infon>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="22" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25773</offset>
      <text> UV-vis absorption An ultraviolet, visible, near-infrared spectrophotometer (PerkinElmer Lambda 950s) was used to measure the absorption spectra of the perovskite thin films. X-ray diffraction XRD patterns were acquired by measuring the perovskite thin films using Bruker D8 Advance diffractometer and non-monochromated Cu-radiation. For the 2D/3D perovskite thin films, measurements under grazing incident diffraction (GID) geometry were performed using Bruker D8 Discover diffractometer with non-monochromated Cu-radiation at the incident angle of 2 in order to obtain the XRD patterns on the surface of the films. Scanning electron microscopy SEM micrographs (cross-section and surface) were recorded in the FEI Teneo scanning electron microscope using in-lens detector under the accelerating voltage of 3 and 5 kV. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26593</offset>
      <text> Ultraviolet photoemission spectroscopy depth profiling The samples were transferred to an ultrahigh vacuum chamber (ESCALAB 250Xi), with a base pressure of 2 3 10 À10 mbar, for UPS depth profiling (DP) measurements. UPS measurements were performed using a double-differentially pumped He gas discharge lamp emitting He I radiation (hn = 21.22 eV) with a pass energy of 2 eV and a bias of À5 V to ensure secondary electron onset detection. The UPS spectra are shown as a function of the binding energy with respect to the Fermi energy. The energy edge of the valence band features was used to determine the valence band level position with respect to the Fermi level. The onset of the valence band was analyzed using a linear presentation of the UPS spectra. The secondary electron onset was used to determine the vacuum level with respect to the Fermi level. The conduction bands were estimated using the optical gaps of the 2D and 3D materials. Cluster etching was performed using large Ar clusters generated by the MAGCIS dual Beam Ion Source (Thermo Scientific) with an energy of 4,000 eV. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27690</offset>
      <text> Absolute photoluminescence Excitation for the PL measurements was performed with a 445 nm continuous wave laser (Insaneware) through an optical fiber into an integrating sphere. The intensity of the laser was adjusted to a 1 sun equivalent intensity by illuminating a 1 cm 2 size perovskite solar cell under short-circuit and matching the current density to the J SC under the sun simulator (22.0 mA cm À2 at 100 mW cm À2 , or 1.375 3 10 21 photons m À2 s À1 ). A second optical fiber was used from the output of the integrating sphere to an Andor SR393i-B spectrometer equipped with a silicon charge-coupled device camera (DU420A-BR-DD, iDus). The system was calibrated using a calibrated halogen lamp with specified spectral irradiance, which was shone into to integrating sphere. A spectral correction factor was established to match the spectral output of the detector to the calibrated spectral irradiance of the lamp. The spectral photon density was obtained from the corrected detector signal (spectral irradiance) by division through the photon energy (hf) and the photon numbers of the excitation and emission obtained from numerical integration using Matlab. In the last step, three fluorescent test samples with high specified PLQY (z70%) supplied from Hamamatsu Photonics were measured, where the specified value could be accurately reproduced within a small relative error of less than 5%. All PL measurements were performed on complete cells, prepared fresh, and immediately encapsulated in a glovebox under N 2 atmosphere. The PL of the samples was readily recorded after mounting the sample and after an exposure of 1 s at each laser intensity subsequently, the incident laser was blocked by a shutter, and the filter wheel position adjusted, while the sample was kept in dark conditions avoiding any effects induced by constant illumination. The cell was illuminated through the glass/ITO side. It was noted that all absolute PL measurements were performed on films with the same HTL, ETL, and perovskite thicknesses as used in the operational solar cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29770</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic characterization The current density-voltage (J-V) curves were measured under 1 sun illumination (AM 1.5G) in the ambient atmosphere and temperature using xenon lamp solar simulator (450 W, Oriel, AAA class). The light intensity was calibrated to 1 sun using a Si reference equipped with an IR-cutoff (KG5) filter (Oriel 91150V). The current responses were measured using a digital source meter (Keithley 2400) by applying an external voltage bias. A metal mask with an aperture of 0.16 cm 2 was used during the measurement in order to determine the active area. The J-V curves were scanned at the rate of 50 mV/s. No pre-biasing was applied prior to the measurements. EQE measurement was carried out using IQE200B (Oriel). Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Structural and morphological characterization of 2D/3D perovskite films (A) Schematic illustration of the 2D/3D perovskite interface. (B) Molecular structure (left) and XRD pattern at 2 incident angle of the 2D/3D film employing 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl, respectively (&gt; and * denote 2D perovskite phase with n = 1 and n = 2, respectively). (C) Top view (left) and cross-section (right) micrographs of the 3D-only device as control and the 2D/3D perovskite solar cells (PSCs) employing 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl. Insets show the magnified cross-section micrographs on the 2D/3D interface. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31128</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Photovoltaic performances of 2D/3D PSCs (A) Schematic device structure of the 2D/3D PSCs. (B) Statistics (the average values are included in the box) of the photovoltaics parameters of 3D PSCs as a control and 2D/3D PSCs based on 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl on over 70 devices. Note that the star symbols in the V OC subpanel represent the V OC measured without using a mask. (C) J-V curves of the champion cells of 3D and 2D/3D PSCs employing 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl. (D) Stability test under continuous 1 sun illumination for 1,000 h in inert gas (Ar) atmosphere without any encapsulation. The stability data of 2-TMAI 2D/ 3D and control device were collected from the same experimental batch from our previous report 9 for a fair comparison. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31904</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. UPS depth measurement of 2D/3D perovskite interface (A) Schematic representation of the UPS depth profiling technique which combines (1) etching by Ar ion clusters with (2) UPS measurements. (B) Illustration of the evolution of the UPS spectra as a function of depth. (C) The corresponding energy level diagram is extracted from (B). (D-I) Measured UPS spectra and corresponding energetic level diagrams of 2-TMAI (D and G), 2-TMABr (E and H), and 2-TMACl (F and I) with the 3D perovskite layer. Note: dashed line in UPS spectra is a guide to the eye. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32481</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Calculated QFLS and calculated energy losses due to nonradiative recombination (A) QFLS calculated from the PLQY for the neat material and the full device for the different samples investigated in the study. Moreover, the Shockley-Queisser radiative limit and the experimental V OC are plotted for each sample. (B) Different types of energy losses are calculated from (A) in order to compare the contribution of the different recombination processes for each system. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32973</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 Photovoltaic parameters of the champion PSCs based on 3D perovskite and 2D/3D perovskite hybrids employing 2-TMAI, 2-TMABr, and 2-TMACl tested under AM 1.5G illumination (100 mW cm À2 ) V OC (V) J SC (mA cm À2 ) FF PCE (%) 2-TMAI/3D 1.09 24.2 0.76 19.9 2-TMABr/3D 1.15 23.2 0.78 20.8 2-TMACl/3D 1.16 22.8 0.74 19.7 Control 1.09 24.2 0.79 20.7 &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.09</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:51:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="33309" length="4"/>
        <text>1.09</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20.7</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:50:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="33324" length="4"/>
        <text>20.7</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33332</offset>
      <text> 2 O). The precipitate was separated and washed thoroughly with Et 2 O. The salts were recrystallized from ethanol (EtOH) and Et 2 O mixtures, resulting in crystalline solids of the salts. On top of the cleaned substrates, a 30 nm think compact TiO 2 layer as electron transporting layer was spray deposited from the titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution (Sigma-Aldrich) precursor diluted in isopropanol (1:15 by volume fraction) at 450 C, followed by the deposition of a 100 nm thick mesoporous TiO 2 layer by spin coating a diluted TiO 2 paste solution in ethanol (1:8 w/v) at 5,000 rpm for 20 s and sintering at 500 C for 20 min. A 20 nm thick tin oxide layer as a passivation layer was formed from the aqueous tin (IV) chloride solution (12 mL SnCl 4 for 1 mL solution) by depositing the SnCl 4 precursor at 3,000 rpm for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 C for 10 min and at 190 C for 60 min. UV-ozone treatment was carried out for 15 min before both SnO 2 layer deposition and perovskite layer deposition. Perovskite thin-film and solar cells devices fabrication Fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO) substrates (Nippon Sheet Glass) were patterned by a chemical etching process using zinc powder and aqueous HCl solution (3.0 M) and cleaned with the detergent (Hellmanex), water, acetone, and isopropanol subse- quently. A triple-cation-based 3D perovskite precursor solution (1.3 M) with the composi- tion of [(FAPbI 3 ) 0.87 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.13 ] 0.92 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.08 was prepared by mixing the starting materials (FAI [GreatCellSolar], MABr [GreatCellSolar], CsI [ABCR], PbI 2 [TCI], and PbBr 2 [TCI]</text>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Titanium dioxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:50:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="33577" length="5"/>
        <text>TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R3">
      <infon key="type">performance_3</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:51:31Z</infon>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
      <node refid="24" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">performance_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:51:26Z</infon>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="24" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">performance_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T08:51:21Z</infon>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
      <node refid="16" role=""/>
      <node refid="17" role=""/>
      <node refid="24" role=""/>
      <node refid="25" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
