<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025049695ADGAAG</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 137&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Bimolecularly passivated interface enables efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>109</offset>
      <text>Compared with the n-i-p structure, inverted (p-i-n) perovskite solar cells (PSCs) promise increased operating stability, but these photovoltaic cells often exhibit lower power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) because of nonradiative recombination losses, particularly at the perovskite/C 60 interface. We passivated surface defects and enabled reflection of minority carriers from the interface into the bulk using two types of functional molecules. We used sulfur-modified methylthio molecules to passivate surface defects and suppress recombination through strong coordination and hydrogen bonding, along with diammonium molecules to repel minority carriers and reduce contact-induced interface recombination achieved through field-effect passivation. This approach led to a fivefold longer carrier lifetime and one-third the photoluminescence quantum yield loss and enabled a certified quasi-steadystate PCE of 25.1% for inverted PSCs with stable operation at 65°C for &gt;2000 hours in ambient air. We also fabricated monolithic all-perovskite tandem solar cells with 28.1% PCE. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:56:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="153" length="7"/>
        <text>(p-i-n)</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1189</offset>
      <text> C ertified power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) &gt; 25% have been widely reported for perovskite solar cells (PSCs) in the regular (n-i-p) structure  (1) (2) (3) . Although inverted (p-i-n) PSCs have potential advantages because of their stability, lowtemperature processing, and compatibility with integration into tandem solar cells  (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) , their reported PCEs rarely surpass 24% under the stringent quasi-steady-state (QSS) protocol  (9) (10) (11) . This efficiency gap is primarily attributed to higher recombination rates at the interface between the perovskite and the charge transport materials  (12) . The detrimental impact of buried perovskite/hole transport layer interface losses has been addressed through the development of self-assembled monolayers  (13) (14) (15) . However, the top interface between the perovskite and the electron transport layer (ETL), typically made from C 60 and its derivatives, suffers from interfacial recombination that results from minority carriers in the vicinity of the interface as well as the effect of incompletely passivated trap states  (16) . Surface passivation can suppress interface charge recombination and has been accomplished with organohalides  (4, (17) (18) (19) , Lewis bases  (20, 21) , and dipolar compounds  (22, 23) . We noted that reliance on a single species of molecule may fail to address simultaneously both surface and interface recombination processes (Fig.  1A )  (24, 25) . Specifically, the existence of near-interface minority carriers (holes in the perovskite layer) leads to direct interface recombination with majority carriers (electrons in the ETL), a process that can occur even at nondefect sites  (26) . In addition, defects at the perovskite surface induce surface recombination through trapping of carriers. The most common defect, the halide vacancy, has a low formation energy  (27, 28) . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3082</offset>
      <text> Exploring class 1 and 2 molecule combinations We sought to address complex interface carrier recombination issues using a combination of different molecules, each with distinct functionalities. The first class of molecule we incorporated repelled hole carriers to reduce interface recombination through field-effect passivation (Fig.  1B ). The second class of molecule interacted with defect sites to form chemical bonds to reduce surface recombination through chemical passivation. Diammonium ligands, in which one - , with high binding energy with the perovskite surface (fig.  S3 ), enabled a device performance improvement compared with the control devices (without passivation), from PCEs of ~22.8% to ~23.9% with active areas of 0.05 cm 2 (Fig.  1 , C and D). Thus, diammonium ligands work well in normal bandgap PSCs, and the PCE improvement could be explained by field-effect passivation that repels minority carriers  (26) . We then sought a second molecule to add a chemical passivation function. We first examined n-butylammonium iodide (BAI), which is widely used as a chemical passivating agent  (31, 32) , in combination with PDAI 2 . Its addition increased PCE to ~24.3% compared with PDAI 2 alone. Extending the chain length to amylamine hydroiodide (AAI) further improved the average efficiency to ~24.5%, thus providing a baseline roughly at parity with efficient previously reported inverted PSCs  (12, 17) . We then tuned the electrical dipole moment by incorporating sulfur as a donor atom in the alkyl chain by synthesizing methylthio-based ammonium ligands, namely 2-(methylthio) ethylamine hydroiodide (2MTEAI) and 3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide (3MTPAI). The use of both diammonium and methylthio molecules led to improved PCE across several combinations, namely EDAI 2 /2MTEAI, PDAI 2 / 2MTEAI, EDAI 2 /3MTPAI, and PDAI 2 /3MTPAI, in comparison to both the control device and single-molecule passivated devices. The highest average PCE (&gt;25.5%) was achieved with PDAI 2 /3MTPAI (Fig.  1D ). We thus focused on the PDAI 2 /3MTPAI combination for further investigation. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:52:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="4723" length="37"/>
        <text>3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:52:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="4762" length="6"/>
        <text>3MTPAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-diammonium iodide,propane-1 / 3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide bilayer</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:01:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="5131" length="14"/>
        <text>PDAI 2 /3MTPAI</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5186</offset>
      <text> PDAI 2 /3MTPAI characteristics We used density function theory (DFT) to compare 3MTPA + versus AA + by modeling ligand orientations of 3MTPA and AA on the perovskite surface (fig.  S4 ). The binding energy difference (DE clean ) between the parallel (E clean-parallel ) and vertical configurations (E clean-vertical ) was used as a measure of ligand orientation. A larger DE clean value of -0.22 eV for 3MTPA indicated a stronger preference for the parallel orientation compared with -0.13 eV for AA (Fig.  2A ). This difference corresponded to greater occupation on the vacancy defect position. Electrostatic potentials in the ligands (Fig.  2B ) showed that 3MTPA, when compared with AA, had a lower minimum electrostatic potential (ϕ min ) because of its electron-rich center surrounding the S atom that facilitated binding with the positively charged iodide vacancy. The higher maximum electrostatic potential (ϕ max ) at the -NH 3 + side also added increased binding strength between the ligand and the surface cation vacancy site of the perovskite. The passivation effect of the ligands was further evaluated by considering the presence of iodide vacancies, which are the predominant defects on the perovskite surface (fig.  S5 )  (33) . We assessed the binding energy difference (DE relative ) between that of the defective surface (E VI-parallel ) and the clean surface (E clean-parallel ). DE relative of AA with the perovskite remains nearly unchanged, regardless of the presence or absence of iodide vacancy. In contrast, DE relative = -0.38 eV was obtained for 3MTPA, indicating a favorable interaction with the defective sites. 3MTPA induced a notable charge redistribution that accumulated charges at iodide vacancy, assigned to S-Pb coordination bonding (Fig.  2C ). Charge transfer between 3MTPA and formamidinium (FA) was also observed (Fig.  2D ), accompanied by a shorter distance of 2.72 Å between the sulfur atom in 3MTPA and the hydrogen atom in FA that indicated the formation of a hydrogen bond. In contrast, the distance between the carbon atom at the corresponding site in AA and the hydrogen atom in FA was 3.33 Å. Thus, the formation energy of the FA vacancy increased from -0.79 eV to -0.71 eV (fig.  S6 ). Proton nuclear magnetic resonance ( 1 H NMR) spectra showed that the amino proton peak of FAI at d = 8.82 parts per million (ppm) exhibited increased broadening and shifted to a lower field after mixing with 3MTPAI compared with AAI (Fig.  2E ). These changes again indicated stronger hydrogen bonding interactions between 3MTPA and FA than between AA and FA  (34) . Computation work suggested that the methylthio group provided stronger binding-viewed in some studies as a proxy for stronger passivationcompared with ligands that relied on ammonium functional groups alone. We assessed diammonium-methylthio dual passivation (DMDP) using x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). The Pb 4f peaks of the passivated perovskite film shifted toward a lower binding energy of 0.23 eV compared with the control film (Fig.  2F ), which we attributed to an increased electron density at Pb 2+  (35) . Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (ToF-SIMS) was used to analyze the surface ligand distribution. Comparing signal ratios of PDA:3MTPA and PDA:AA under identical conditions on perovskite films with PDAI 2 /3MTPAI and PDAI 2 /AAI bimolecular passivation, we found that the signal ratio of 1:2.7 for PDA: 3MTPA was lower than the ratio of 1:1.1 for PDA:AA (Fig.  2G ). This suggests that 3MTPA has a stronger binding affinity to the perovskite surface and a better passivation effect on defects, consistent with its higher binding energy (fig.  S7 ). Figure  2H  illustrates the centimeter-scale photoluminescence (PL) intensity distribution of a perovskite film with Gaussian-distributed passivators on the surface (fig.  S8 )  (36) . The region surrounding the PDAI 2 /3MTPAI center exhibited higher PL emission than the corresponding region for PDAI 2 /AAI; and the contour region with the lowest PL intensity was skewed toward the PDAI 2 /AAI center. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images revealed dense polygonal grains with sizes of ~500 nm for the control perovskite film; the morphologies were unchanged after DMDP passivation (fig.  S9 ). Grazing-incidence wideangle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) did not reveal any peaks at low scattering vectors q in the DMDP-based film, which indicated that no lowdimensional perovskite formed (Fig.  3A ). We ascribed the peak at ~0.84 Å -1 in the control sample to the presence of d-FAPbI  To examine the chemical passivation effect of the DMDP strategy on film optoelectronic properties, we conducted time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) measurements (Fig.  3B  and table  S1 ). Control perovskite films showed a sharp decrease in emission characteristic of high levels of nonradiative carrier recombination on the bare perovskite surface. Treatment with PDAI 2 showed little improvement in lifetime, reflecting its limited suppression of defect-induced surface recombination. In contrast, the perovskite film treated with 3MTPAI displayed a sustained plateau in the decay curve, reflecting increased carrier lifetime. This might be due to a combined effect of reduced nonradiative traps and enhanced photon recycling  (37) . The reemission of photons from the WBG subcell might serve to augment photon absorption of the adjacent NBG subcell when it is integrated in the tandem configuration. We used ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) to characterize band edge energies (Fig.  3C  and fig.  S11 ). PDAI 2 treatment reduced the energy level difference between the conduction band minimum (E CBM ) and the Fermi level (E F ) of the perovskite surface to 0.10 eV, compared with 0.20 and 0.17 eV for the control and 3MTPAI treatments, respectively. The stronger n-type doping effect of PDAI 2 was attributed to the additional -NH 3 + group extending away from the perovskite matrix that induced a surface dipole that repelled the minority carrier at the interface  (26, 38) . This treatment enabled field-effect passivation and reduced interface recombination (fig.  S12 ). We expect this passivation effect to be retained upon incorporation of 3MTPAI because n-type doping was also observed. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11483</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic performance PDAI 2 did not enhance the PL quantum yield (PLQY) (Fig.  3D ) of the perovskite film before C 60 deposition, and there was little PLQY loss after coating with C 60 , consistent with its fieldeffect passivation role. Increased PDAI 2 concentration led to a decrease in both PLQY and PCE, which we attributed to increased surface recombination. For 3MTPAI, in the absence of C 60 , PLQY increased as 3MTPAI processing solution concentration increased from 3 mM to 15 mM. On contact with C 60 , noticeable PLQY and PCE losses were seen, and these losses became more pronounced at higher concentrations, indicating increased interface recombination. The DMDP strategy improved PLQY of the perovskite/C 60 samples and increased the PCE to &gt;26% even at 12 mM concentration of 3MTPAI. In sum, 3MTPAI and PDAI 2 could increase passivation and decrease carrier recombination without interfering with one another (Fig.  3E ). The photovoltaic parameters of devices with different treatments at the optimized concentration are summarized in fig.  S13 . The DMDP-based devices showed an improved PCE from 22.8 ± 0.4 to 25.5 ± 0.3% compared with the control device, accompanied by enhancements in open-circuit voltage (V OC ) from 1.12 ± 0.01 to 1.16 ± 0.01 V and fill factor (FF) from 78.5 ± 1.3 to 83.8 ± 1.3%. The RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE diode characteristics of the devices in the absence of light showed that the devices in which we used the DMDP strategy presented an average dark saturation current (J 0 ) reduction by two orders of magnitude compared with the control devices, demonstrating effective inhibition of carrier recombination (fig.  S14 )  (39) . Figure  4A  shows the current density-voltage (J-V) curves for the champion DMDP device, which exhibited a PCE of 26.4%, with a short-circuit current (J SC ) of 26.2 mA cm -2 , V OC of 1.17 V, and FF of 85.8%. We focused on QSS measurement in certification. Here, the highest performance based on maximum power point tracking (MPPT) was a PCE of 25.5% for 100 s (fig.  S15 ). A National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) certification that used the asymptotic maximum power scan protocol (Fig.  4B  and fig.  S16 ) reported a QSS PCE of 25.1% for an illuminated area of 0.05 cm 2 along with a fast-scan PCE of 25.9%, compared with other reported certified QSS PCEs that did not exceed 25% (Fig.  4C  and table  S2 )  (9, 10, 40, 41) . We also fabricated 1.5 cm 2 devices using the DMDP treatment that delivered a PCE of 24.0% (fig.  S17 ), consistent with increased film homogeneity and reduced localized nonradiative recombination (fig.  S18 ). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:51:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="11602" length="4"/>
        <text>C 60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">26.4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:57:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="13281" length="8"/>
        <text>26.4%, w</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.17</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:57:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="13352" length="6"/>
        <text>1.17 V</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14121</offset>
      <text> Longevity studies In our studies of the thermal stability of encapsulated devices, we found that after 1600 hours of thermal aging at 85°C in nitrogen (ISOS-D-2 protocol, where ISOS is the International Summit on Organic PV Stability), the DMDP-based devices retained 95% of initial PCE, surpassing the retention of 84% for the control device (Fig.  4D  and fig.  S19 ). We investigated the operating stability under MPPT under 1 sun of an encapsulated device operating in ambient air. After 2000 hours of continuous operation under 1 sun illumination at 65°C (ISOS-L-3 protocol), the DMDP-based device maintained 96% of original PCE, whereas the control device was reduced to 70% of initial PCE (Fig.  4E  and fig.  S20 ). A comparison with other PSCs tested using the ISOS-L-3 protocol is provided in table  S3 . &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1600</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:57:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="14225" length="10"/>
        <text>1600 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:58:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="14256" length="4"/>
        <text>85°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:59:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="14274" length="8"/>
        <text>ISOS-D-2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">95</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:45:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="14390" length="3"/>
        <text>95%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">84</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:45:11Z</infon>
        <location offset="14438" length="3"/>
        <text>84%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:58:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="14614" length="10"/>
        <text>2000 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:58:57Z</infon>
        <location offset="14677" length="4"/>
        <text>65°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:59:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="14683" length="8"/>
        <text>ISOS-L-3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">96</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:45:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="14736" length="3"/>
        <text>96%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">70</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:45:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="14799" length="3"/>
        <text>70%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14940</offset>
      <text> Discussion To investigate the applicability of the DMDP strategy on other perovskite compositions, we fabricated PSCs with both WBG and NBG perovskite materials. Notably, the average PCE was improved by 14 and 13% when the DMDP strategy was used for NBG and WBG PSCs, respectively (Fig.  4F ). We applied the DMDP strategy to monolithic all-perovskite tandem solar cells with the structure of FTO/NiO x / Me-4PACz/WBG perovskite/C 60 /SnO x /Au/ poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate (PEDOT:PSS)/NBG perovskite/C 60 / RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE SnO x /Ag (Fig.  4G ). The J-V characteristics of the champion tandem device (Fig.  4H ) with an illuminated area of 0.05 cm 2 exhibited a PCE of 28.1% with a V OC of 2.14 V, J SC of 15.6 mA cm -2 , and FF of 84.0%, and a stabilized PCE of 27.1% under MPPT. A well-matched current response is seen in the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra (fig.  S21 ). Realizing both chemical and field-effect passivation by the combined use of methylthio and diammonium molecules has mitigated complex carrier recombination issues at the perovskite/ ETL interface. We consider the multimolecule passivation approach, along with diverse functionalities, as a promising direction for exploring next-generation passivation strategies to achieve improved performance and stability in perovskite optoelectronics.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16307</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16337</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16361</offset>
      <text> Materials [4-(3,6-Dimethyl-9H-carbazol-9-yl)butyl]phosphonic Acid (Me-4PACz), PbI2 (99.99%), PbBr2 (99.99%), and PbCl2 (99.99%) were purchased from TCI America™. C60, bathocuproine (BCP), and methylammonium chloride (MACl) were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. CsI (99.99%), SnI2 (99.999%), Sn powder (99.99%), SnF2 (99%), guanidinium thiocyanate (GuaSCN, 99%), ethane-1,2-diammonium iodide (EDAI2, 98%), 2-(methylthio)ethylamine (2MTEA, 97%), amylamine (AA, 99%), n-Butylammonium iodide (BAI, 98%), 1,4-diaminobutane (BDA, 99%), and 3-(methylthio)propylamine (3MTPA, 97%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate (PEDOT:PSS, Al 4083) was purchased from Ossila. 3-(methylthio)propylamine hydroiodide (3MTPAI), 2-(methylthio)ethylamine hydroiodide (2MTEAI), amylamine hydroiodide (AAI), and 1,4-diaminobutane dihydroiodide (BDAI2) were obtained by the reaction of hydroiodic acid and 3MTPA/2MTEA/AA/BDA with molar ratios of 1:1/1:1/1:1/2:1, respectively: hydroiodic acid was slowly added to amines under stirring in the ice water bath. The solution was stirred in the ice water for 2 hours, followed by rotary evaporation at 50℃ until the white solid was obtained which was washed with diethyl ether several times. Finally, the product was dried in a vacuum drying oven to obtain the corresponding ammonium halide salts. Formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium iodide (MAI), and propane-1,3-diammonium iodide (PDAI2) were purchased from Greatcell Solar Materials. N, N-dimethylformamide (DMF, anhydrous, 99.8%), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, anhydrous, 99.9%), isopropanol (anhydrous, 99.5%), ethanol (anhydrous, 99.5%), chlorobenzene (anhydrous, 99.8%), toluene (anhydrous, 99.8%), and anisole (anhydrous, 99.7%) were purchased from the Millipore Sigma. All the materials were used as received without any purification. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-diammonium iodide,propane-1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:52:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="17806" length="29"/>
        <text>propane-1,3-diammonium iodide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-diammonium iodide,propane-1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T08:52:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="17837" length="5"/>
        <text>PDAI2</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18249</offset>
      <text> Perovskite precursor solutions Normal bandgap perovskite. Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.90PbI3 perovskite precursors were dissolved with 5 mol% MAPbCl3 in a mixed DMF and DMSO solvent (4:1 v/v) at a concentration of 1.6 M. Narrow bandgap (NBG) perovskite. 1.8 M Cs0.05MA0.25FA0.7Pb0.5Sn0.5I3 perovskite precursors were dissolved in a mixed DMF and DMSO solvent (3:1 v/v) with the addition of 2 mol% Sn power, 5 mol% SnF2 and 2 mol% GuaSCN. Wide bandgap (WBG) perovskite. 1.1 M Cs0.2FA0.8PbI1.9Br1.1 precursors were prepared in mixed solvents of DMF and DMSO (4:1 v/v). All the perovskite solutions were stirred at room temperature for 30 min. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18880</offset>
      <text> Solar cell fabrication Single-junction normal bandgap PSCs. Fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO) glasses were cleaned using detergent, deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol each for 15 min in an ultrasonic bath, followed by ultraviolet ozone treatment for 30 min. The hole transport layer (HTL) was NiOx/4PACz. NiOx was synthesized by our previously reported method  (17) . The NiOx solution (5 mg/mL in deionized water and isopropanol (3:1 v/v)) was spin-coated on the substrates at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s. Then, a 0.5 mg/mL 4PACz in ethanol solution was spincoated on NiOx at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100℃ for 10 min. The perovskite film with a thickness of ~ 600 nm deposition was done in the N2 glovebox with O2 and H2O content less than 1 ppm. The perovskite solution was filtered by a 0.22 μm polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) membrane and spin-coated at 1000 r.p.m for 10 s (acceleration rate 200 r.p.m./s) and 5000 r.p.m. for 30 s (acceleration rate 2000 r.p.m./s), respectively. At the 20 s of the second step, 300 μL anisole was dropped as the antisolvent. The films were then annealed at 100°C for 15 min. For the mono-molecular post treatment, 100 μL 3 mM PDAI2 or EDAI2 or BDAI2 isopropanol/chlorobenzene (1:1 v/v) solution was deposited on the perovskite films by dynamic spinning-coating at 4500 r.p.m for 25 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. For the bi-molecular passivation, 12 mM 3MTPAI or AAI or 2MTEAI or BAI and 6 mM PDAI2 or EDAI2 was dissolved in the isopropanol/chlorobenzene (1:1 v/v) solvent and then 100 μL mixed solution was filtered and dynamically spin-coated on the perovskite films at 4500 r.p.m for 20 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. For electron transport layer (ETL), 30 nm C60 was thermally evaporated on the perovskite films under a high vacuum of ~10 -7 Torr, followed by 7 nm BCP evaporation as a hole-blocking layer. Finally, 140 nm Ag electrode was evaporated under a high vacuum of ~10 -7 Torr. Single-junction WBG PSCs. The NiOx/4PACz HTL deposition was the same as described above. WBG perovskite solution was filtered by a 0.22 μm PTFE membrane and spin-coated at 4500 r.p.m for 30 s (acceleration rate 2000 r.p.m./s). 300 μL anisole was dropped at the last 10 s. The films were annealed at 100°C for 15 min. For the DMDP devices, 12 mM 3MTPAI and 6 mM PDAI2 was dissolved in isopropanol/chlorobenzene (1:1 v/v) solvent and then 100 μL mixed solution was filtered and dynamically spin-coated on the perovskite films at 4500 r.p.m for 20 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. The C60, BCP, and Ag deposition were the same as normal bandgap devices. Single-junction NBG PSCs. The PEDOT:PSS was diluted to 1/3 of its original concentration using isopropanol and filtered with a 0.45 μm PTFE membrane. The 50 nm PEDOT:PSS layer was deposited by spin-coating method at 5000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 150℃ for 20 min in the ambient. The NBG perovskite solution was filtered by a 0.22 μm PTFE membrane and spin-coated at 1000 r.p.m for 10 s (acceleration rate 500 r.p.m./s) and 3000 r.p.m. for 45 s (acceleration rate 1500 r.p.m./s), respectively. 300 μL chlorobenzene was dropped at the last 18 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 10 min. For the DMDP devices, 3 mM 3MTPAI and 3 mM EDAI2 was dissolved in isopropanol/toluene (1:1 v/v) solvent and then 100 μL mixed solution was filtered and dynamically spin-coated on the perovskite films at 4500 r.p.m for 20 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. The C60, BCP, and Ag deposition were the same as described in the normal bandgap PSCs. Tandem devices. WBG subcell was first fabricated: the NiOx/4PACz HTL deposition was the same as described above. WBG perovskite solution was spin-coated at 4500 r.p.m for 30 s and 300 μL anisole was dropped at the last 10 s. The 500 nm films were obtained after annealing at 100°C for 15 min. 12 mM 3MTPAI and 6 mM PDAI2 was dissolved in isopropanol/chlorobenzene (1:1 v/v) solvent and then 100 μL mixed solution was filtered and dynamically spin-coated on the perovskite films at 4500 r.p.m for 20 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. The C60 deposition was the same as normal bandgap devices. A 20 nm SnO2 was deposited by atomic layer deposition method (17), and 1 nm Au was deposited by thermal evaporation method. The NBG subcell was then fabricated: the diluted PEDOT:PSS solution was spin-coated at 5000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 150℃ for 20 min in the ambient. The NBG perovskite solution was spin-coated at 1000 r.p.m for 10 s (acceleration rate 500 r.p.m./s) and 3000 r.p.m. for 45 s (acceleration rate 1500 r.p.m./s), respectively. 300 μL chlorobenzene was dropped at the last 18 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 10 min, and a 1μm-thick film was obtained. 3 mM 3MTPAI and 3 mM EDAI2 was dissolved in isopropanol/toluene (1:1 v/v) solvent and then 100 μL mixed solution was filtered and dynamically spin-coated on the perovskite films at 4500 r.p.m for 20 s, followed by annealing at 100°C for 5 min. 30 nm C60, 7 nm BCP, and 140 nm Ag electrode was thermally evaporated to complete the tandem devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24054</offset>
      <text> Characterizations Current-density-voltage (J-V) characteristics. The J-V characteristics were measured in a nitrogen glovebox at room temperature using a Keithley 2401 digital source-meter under simulated AM 1.5 G irradiation from a Xe arc lamp (Sciencetech A1 Light Line Class AAA solar simulator). The light intensity was calibrated by a Sciencetech SCI-REF-Q silicon cell from before measurement, and no preconditioning was applied. The scanning step was 20 mV with a scanning rate of 70 mV/s. The active area of the solar cells was defined by an opaque metal mask with an aperture area of 0.049 cm 2 . Stability test. The operational stability tests at elevated temperatures were conducted by putting the encapsulated devices in the air with relative humidity of ~50% under 1-sun illumination (Sunbrick G2V) at 65˚C which was monitored by an infrared thermometer. For thermal stability tests, the encapsulated cells were heated at 85℃ in nitrogen. The device performance was evaluated periodically. Encapsulation was performed using a capping glass slide, with ultraviolet-adhesive (Lumtec LT-U001) as sealant. Crystallographic characterizations. X-Ray diffraction (XRD) was carried out by a Rigaku Miniflex diffractometer (Cu Kα1 radiation). Grazing-incidence wide-angle X-ray Scattering (GIWAXS) was conducted on perovskite films at the Brockhouse X-ray Diffraction and Scattering Sector Low Energy Wiggler (BXDS-WLE) beamline of the Canadian Light Source (CLS) using a photon energy of 15.12 keV (λ = 0.82 Å). A Rayonix MX300 detector 328.04 mm away from the sample was used for collecting patterns. Other characterizations. Time of flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (ToF-SIMS) was collected by IONTOF M6 instrument using a primary 30 keV Bi ion source with an analysis area of 50 × 50 μm 2 . SEM images were collected by JEOL JSM-7900FLV microscope using a 5 keV and 10 keV electron beam for surface and cross-section images, respectively. Photoluminescence (PL) maps were collected using a confocal Raman system (excitation wavelength = 633 nm) integrated with SWIFT and DuoScan technologies. Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) measurement was conducted using an Edinburgh FS5 spectrofluorometer with a 373 nm excitation laser. The luminescence quantum yield was measured by a LuQY Pro System (Quantum Yield Berlin) under the excitation of 532 nm laser (100 mW). X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) were performed on Thermo Scientific ESCALAB 250Xi with an X-ray spot size of 500 μm. Contact potential difference and photocurrent were obtained by a Bruker Photocurrent and Thermal AFM (Pt/Ircoated cantilevers), with a scan rate of 0.25 Hz and scan area of 5 × 5 μm 2 . Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy (NMR) was performed using Bruker Avance HD 500 MHz w/ Prodigy probe (x500) on solutions prepared by dissolving FAI, a 1:1 molar ratio mixture of FAI and 3MTPAI, as well as a 1:1 molar ratio mixture of FAI and 3MTPAI powder, in DMSO-d6 solvent at a concentration of 0.12 M. The transient absorption (TA) spectra were measured with a spectrometer (Acton SP2300, Princeton Instruments). Femtosecond laser pulses of 800 nm were generated by a Ti:Sapphire laser at a 250 kHz repetition rate (Mira, Coherent), which were then amplified by a Ti:Sapphire amplifier (RegA, Coherent). The pulses were passed through an optical parametric amplifier (OPA 9400, Coherent) to select 500 nm light as the pump pulse. The probe pulses were generated by focusing the initial 800nm pulse into a sapphire crystal, which resulted in a white light. EQE measurements were performed without bias voltage in ambient air using a QuantX-300 Quantum Efficiency Measurement System (Newport) and bias illumination from bright LEDs, with emission peaks of 850 and 450 nm used for measurement of the front and back subcells, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27954</offset>
      <text> Computation First-principles calculations based on density functional theory (DFT) were carried out using the Vienna Ab initio Simulation Package (VASP)  (42) . The generalized gradient approximation (GGA) of the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) functional was employed as the exchange-correlation functional  (43) . DFT-D3 method for the van der Waals (vdW) correction was included  (44) . The plane-wave cutoff energy was 400 eV. The energy and force convergence criteria were set to 10 -5 eV and 0.02 eV•Å-1, respectively. The binding energies (Eb) of ligands with the perovskite surface were calculated as E(ligand@perovskite)-E(ligand)-E(perovskite), where E(structure) is the total energy of the corresponding structures. The electrostatic potentials of the ligands were calculated in the Gaussian 09 package at the B3LYP/def2TZVP level with DFT-D3. The plots of the electrostatic potentials were obtained with the help of Multiwfn code  (45) .               (39) . Hence, we extracted J0 from linear fits to semi-log current-voltage plots measured in the dark, following the diode equation J = J0 [exp(qV/nkT)-1], where J is the current density, q is the electronic charge, V is the voltage, n is the ideality factor, k is the Boltzmann constant, and T is the temperature. DMDP devices consistently show a smaller J0 compared to control devices, which is indicative of a smaller recombination current density in DMDP devices.         NH 3 + 3 group anchors to the perovskite surface and the other extends away from it, can induce a surface dipole and n-type doping (29, 30) and provide effective field-effect passivation for both narrow bandgap (NBG) (~1.2 eV) and wide bandgap (WBG) (~1.8 eV) PSCs (26). We explored the passivation effect of different diammonium ligands on normal bandgap (~1.5 eV) PSC devices. The device architecture consisted of fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)/ NiO x /[4-(3,6-dimethyl-9H-carbazol-9-yl)butyl] phosphonic acid (Me-4PACz)/perovskite/ passivation layer/C 60 /bathocuproine (BCP)/ Ag (fig. S1). Optical constants of materials are shown in fig. S2. The current-voltage characteristics showed that ethane-1,2-diammonium (EDAI 2 ) and propane-1,3-diammonium iodide (PDAI 2 ) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30167</offset>
      <text> 3 formed in the ambient humid air during the measurement. The suppression of d-FAPbI 3 in the DMDP-based film indicates improved ambient stability. The unchanged surface dimensionality was further corroborated by transient absorption (TA) spectra where the passivated film displayed a single bleach spectral &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30477</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Passivation at the perovskite/ETL interface. (A and B) Schematic of the perovskite surface without passivation (A) and with both chemical and field-effect passivation (B). (C) Chemical structures of the diammonium and ammonium ligands investigated in this study. (D) PCEs of control versus passivated PSCs using different passivation ligands. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30841</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. The process of passivation through the methylthio group on perovskite surfaces. (A) Binding energies of ammonium ligands with a clean or defective perovskite surface with the typical iodide vacancy. (B) Electrostatic potential (ϕ) of 3MTPA and AA ligands (ϕ max , blue color; ϕ min , red color). (C) Calculated charge density difference (blue, depletion; yellow, accumulation) of anchoring ammonium ligands onto the perovskite surface with I vacancies. The red open circles indicate the positions of I vacancies. The atoms in the structures are differentiated by different colors: S is represented by grass green, C by brown, Pb by gray, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31503</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. DMDP strategy working principle. (A) GIWAXS patterns of the control and DMDP-based perovskite films. (B) TRPL of the perovskite films treated with different ligands. (C) The energy level difference between the conduction band maximum and Fermi level for the perovskite films treated with different ligands. (D) Ligand concentration-dependent PLQY of the perovskite films, PLQY loss of the perovskite films after C 60 deposition, and PCEs of devices. For DMDP, the concentration of 3MTPAI was varied, while the PDAI 2 concentration was optimized and maintained at 6 mM. (E) Schematic diagram showing the inhibition of interface recombination by PDAI 2 and the suppression of defectinduced recombination by 3MTPAI. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32237</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Device performance and stability. (A) J-V characteristics of the bestperforming DMDP-based device. (B) QSS J-V curve of one representative DMDP-based device certified at NREL. (C) Certified QSS and fast-scan PCE statistics of inverted PSCs. (D) Thermal stability of encapsulated PSCs annealed at 85°C in nitrogen. (E) Operational stability of encapsulated PSCs under constant 1-sun illumination at 65°C in air with 50% relative humidity. (F) PCEs of the WBG and NBG PSCs showing the universality of the DMDP strategy. (G) Architecture of the tandem device. (H) J-V characteristics of the best-performing tandem device based on the DMDP strategy. The inset shows the stabilized PCE under MPPT. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:03:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="32672" length="3"/>
        <text>50%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32953</offset>
      <text> Fig. S1 . S1 Fig. S1. Cross-section SEM images the DMDP-based PSCs. Scale bar, 100 nm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33042</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. The refractive index and extinction coefficient of NiOx (A), 4PACz (B), perovskite (C), C60 (D), BCP (E), and Ag (F). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33184</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. Binding energies of diammonium ligands with the perovskite surface. EDA, PDA, BDA, PeDA, and HAD represent ethane-1,2-diammonium, propane-1,3-diammonium, butane-1,4-diammonium, pentane-1,5-diammonium, and hexane-1,6-diammonium, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33450</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. (A-D) Atomic structures of the perovskite surface with 3MTPA in vertical (A) and parallel (B) orientation, and AA in vertical (C) and parallel orientation (D). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33634</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. (A-B) Atomic structures of the I vacancy-contained perovskite surface with 3MTPA (A) and AA (B) adsorption. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33766</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. (A, B) The perovskite structures with 3MTPA (A) and AA (B) passivation used for simulating the FA vacancy formation energy. The red circles indicate the positions of FA vacancies. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33970</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Comparison of the binding energies between the perovskite and the cations of AAI and 3MTPAI. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34087</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. SEM images the perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34144</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. TA spectra of the DMDP-based perovskite film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34217</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. (A-D) UPS spectra the control (A), 3MTPAI-treated (B), PDAI2-treated (C), and the DMDP-based (D) perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34359</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. Spatial band diagram of the perovskite/ETL interface without (A) and with (B) fieldeffect passivation. Blue dots are holes and red dots are electrons. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34537</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. (A-D) Photovoltaic (PV) parameter statistics of the control (A), 3 mM PDAI2-treated (B), 3 mM 3MTPAI-treated (C), and the DMDP-treated (6 mM PDAI2/12 mM 3MTPAI) (D) PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34735</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. The dark diode characteristics of the PSCs. The recombination parameter J0 quantifies the current density under thermal equilibrium(39). Hence, we extracted J0 from linear fits to semi-log current-voltage plots measured in the dark, following the diode equation J = J0 [exp(qV/nkT)-1], where J is the current density, q is the electronic charge, V is the voltage, n is the ideality factor, k is the Boltzmann constant, and T is the temperature. DMDP devices consistently show a smaller J0 compared to control devices, which is indicative of a smaller recombination current density in DMDP devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35360</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. The steady-state output of the best-performance DMDP-based PSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35451</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. Certification of stabilized PV performance of the DMDP-based p-i-n device measured by NREL PV Performance Group. The certification was conducted using the Asymptotic Pmax Scan protocol, where the stabilized asymptotic scans were measured by holding the cell at a set of voltage points in the region of Vmax. The criterion for stabilization was when the current change per minute was less than 0.1%, the cell was biased to next voltage. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35914</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. Device performance of the 1.5 cm 2 DMDP-based PSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35992</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. (A, B) PL intensity maps and statistical distribution of the control (A) and DMDPbased (B) perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36128</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. Thermal stability of six encapsulated PSCs annealed at 85˚C in nitrogen. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36229</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. Operating stability of two additional encapsulated PSCs under constant one sun illumination at 65˚C in air with 50% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36377</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. EQE curves of WBG and NBG subcells within the tandem device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36465</offset>
      <text> Table S1 S1 Time-resolved photoluminescence of the perovskite films with different ligand passivation.Table S2Summary of certified photovoltaic parameters of efficient inverted PSCs with quasisteady-state (QSS) PCE over 22% following asymptotic maximum power (AMP) scan or maximum power point (MPP) tracking protocols. Samples τ1 (ns) A1 (cnts) τ2 (ns) A2 (cnts) τave (ns) Ctrl 24.7 354.3 150.7 539.2 138.5 PDAI2 36.6 167.8 172.6 608.2 165.0 AAI 11.7 80.1 205.9 731.5 204.7 3MTPAI 11.3 130.6 627.5 600.2 625.1 DMDP 43.7 259.7 718.8 470.0 696.9 Protocol (AMP/ MPP) QSS PCE (%) Fast-scan PCE (%) Certification organization References AMP 25.11 25.9 NREL This work AMP 24.09 N.A. NREL S. M. Park, Science, 2023 (46) AMP 24.05 25.4 NREL Q. Jiang, Nature, 2022 (10) AMP 23.91 N.A. NREL H. Chen, Nat. Photonics, 2022 (17) AMP 22.62 N.A. NREL S. Chen, Sci. Adv., 2021 (47) AMP 22.34 N.A. Newport X. Zheng, Nat. Energy, 2020 (48) MPP 24.10 24.5 JET F. Li, Nat. Photonics, 2023 (41) MPP 24.71 24.9 NPVM W. Peng, Science, 2023 (9) MPP 24.25 24.5 NPVM X. Wu, Adv. Mater., 2023 (40) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37541</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37645</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37754</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37863</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37972</offset>
      <text>			 of &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37980</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38084</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:52Z</infon>
      <node refid="8" role=""/>
      <node refid="9" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
      <node refid="11" role=""/>
      <node refid="12" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:03:11Z</infon>
      <node refid="15" role=""/>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
      <node refid="16" role=""/>
      <node refid="17" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="20" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
