<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025025793IBHIFF</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 19&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Engineering ligand reactivity enables high-temperature operation of stable perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>110</offset>
      <text>Perovskite solar cells (PSCs) consisting of interfacial two-and three-dimensional heterostructures that incorporate ammonium ligand intercalation have enabled rapid progress toward the goal of uniting performance with stability. However, as the field continues to seek ever-higher durability, additional tools that avoid progressive ligand intercalation are needed to minimize degradation at high temperatures. We used ammonium ligands that are nonreactive with the bulk of perovskites and investigated a library that varies ligand molecular structure systematically. We found that fluorinated aniliniums offer interfacial passivation and simultaneously minimize reactivity with perovskites. Using this approach, we report a certified quasi-steady-state power-conversion efficiency of 24.09% for inverted-structure PSCs. In an encapsulated device operating at 85°C and 50% relative humidity, we document a 1560-hour T 85 at maximum power point under 1-sun illumination. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">fluorinated aniliniums</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:06Z</infon>
        <location offset="692" length="22"/>
        <text>fluorinated aniliniums</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.09</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="895" length="6"/>
        <text>24.09%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:32:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="970" length="4"/>
        <text>85°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:32:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="979" length="3"/>
        <text>50%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1560</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:32:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="1016" length="9"/>
        <text>1560-hour</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:37:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="1034" length="44"/>
        <text>maximum power point under 1-sun illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:36Z</infon>
        <node refid="1" role=""/>
        <node refid="2" role=""/>
        <node refid="5" role=""/>
        <node refid="3" role=""/>
        <node refid="4" role=""/>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1082</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1092</offset>
      <text>M etal-halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) are emerging photovoltaic (PV) technologies that hold promise in terawattscale deployment  (1) . They unite high power-conversion efficiencies (certified PCEs up to 25.7%)  (2)  with low-cost solution processing that uses abundant materials  (3) (4) (5) . To compete with crystalline silicon (c-Si) solar cells and to be applied with c-Si in tandem cells, PSCs will need improved evidence of bankability  (6) , such as operating stability at elevated temperatures in accelerated aging  (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) . Interfaces, which have high defect densities  (13, 14)  and low barriers to ion transfer  (15, 16)  and are susceptible to moisture-and oxygeninduced degradation  (17, 18) , can provide pathways for energy loss and degradation in PSCs  (19, 20) . In record-efficiency PSCs, interfaces have been passivated by using two-and threedimensional (2D/3D) hybrid structures  (21) (22) (23) , where a thin layer of Ruddlesden-Popper 2D perovskites terminates the 3D-perovskite surface. These 2D/3D structures are constructed by exposing perovskite surfaces to a solution containing ammonium ligands, during which the 3D lattice is fragmented into 2D layers  (24, 25) . This approach is beneficial because the 2D overlayer increases the resistance of perovskites to degradation  (17, 26) . There is a diversity of findings in reports on the stability of 2D overlayers under stress. Some studies have indicated limited stability of the 2D/3D interface under thermal stress  (27) (28) (29) . Progress has been made, with a recent study demonstrating 500-hour operating stability under conditions of 65°C, 50% relative humidity (RH), and maximum power point (MPP) tracking [International Summit on Organic Photovoltaic Stability (ISOS)-L-3-65°C], enhanced by the incorporation of 3-fluorophenethylammonium (3FPEA) intercalation  (23) . Another study  (30)  that used an oleylammonium-intercalated 2D overlayer showed promising results in a 1000-hour damp-heat test, although this study was based on silicon PV module IEC 61215:2016 standards (85°C and 85% RH, dark). Given these promising performance and stability improvements, the field continues to pursue ever-higher durability targets. There is interest in raising the standard to 85°C ISOS-L-3 (MPP tracking at 85°C and 50% RH). However, the reactivity of ammonium ligands with 3D perovskites may lead to further penetration into the bulk perovskite film  (28, 31, 32)  and may contribute to deterioration in device performance under these very demanding stress conditions  (27, 28, (31) (32) (33) . Thus, we explored noninvasive surface-passivating ligands, but we did note that in prior studies, these have yet to achieve the remarkable benefits of the 2D/3D strategy. We sought to understand how molecular structure affects ligand reactivity with 3D perovskites. Previous studies used bulkier ammonium ligands to suppress ligand intercalation, whereas certain small-sized ammonium ligands exhibit low reactivity  (34, 35) . We attribute this difference to the limited availability of characterization techniques that allow one to compare ligand reactivity among different ammonium molecules-a particularly challenging pursuit in view of the ultrathin nature (typically &lt;10 nm) of the passivating overlayer  (23) . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4417</offset>
      <text> Spectroscopy studies of ammonium ligands in perovskites We used angle-resolved x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (AR-XPS) and time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) to investigate the penetration of a library of ammonium ligands into the bulk of perovskites (Fig.  1A ), which include varying tail groups and alkyl chain lengths. A small-sized ammonium ligand, anilinium (An), had the lowest reactivity with 3D perovskites. We then explored derivatives of An with different degrees of fluorination to couple low ligand reactivity with effectual interfacial passivation. These molecules improved operating stability for the encapsulated PSC at 85°C and 50% RH. Ammonium ligands were deposited on Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 perovskite films (materials and methods), and films were annealed at 100°C  (31) . We used AR-XPS to probe the spatial distribution of ammonium ligands in the out-of-plane direction (Fig.  1B ). AR-XPS is a nondestructive depth-profiling technique used to determine the composition of ultrathin layers (&lt;10 nm) at the top surfaces of films  (36, 37) . We varied the probe depth by changing the angle between the normal of the perovskite sample and the analyzer. Three different electron takeoff angles (0°, 45°, and 75°) were selected, with probe depths varying from ~6 to 8 nm at 0°to ~1 to 2 nm at 75°(Fig.  1C ). To obtain the proportion of ammonium ligands at a given probe depth, we compared the ratio of C-N, where N signals originated from methylammonium (MA) and ammonium ligands at a binding energy of ~401.5 eV, with the N signals originating from formamidinium (FA) at a binding energy of ~399.8 eV in the peak area in the N 1s XPS spectrum (figs. S1 and S2). The C-N/FA N ratio plots (Fig.  1D ) revealed that the aryl ammoniums phenethylammonium (PEA) and 3FPEA had relatively uniform depth distributions. By contrast, alkyl ammoniums butylammonium (BA) and octylammonium (OA) tended to accumulate on the top surfaces, as evidenced by the C-N/FA N ratio increasing with larger electron takeoff angles. However, each of the ligands yielded C-N/FA N ratios greater than those of untreated perovskites (control) for all electron takeoff angles (Fig.  1E ), indicating their distinct contributions to C-N signals and their intercalation into the bulk of perovskites. We then examined long-chain alkyl ammonium decylammonium (DA), along with smallsized An  (34, 35, 38) . For DA, the C-N/FA N ratio decreased with a larger electron takeoff angle (Fig.  1D ). The reversed trend, as compared with other alkyl ammoniums, suggested that DA molecules diffused into the bulk of perovskites. By contrast, An exhibited low reactivity and had limited penetration into perovskites. The C-N/FA N ratios for An were a factor of ~2 less than those for PEA at different electron takeoff angles and are similar to control perovskites (Fig.  1E ). At these low C-N/FA N ratios, quantifying the extent of ligand penetration was difficult, given the prominent C-N contribution from MA cations (fig.  S2  and table  S1 ). We thereby performed TOF-SIMS and found that, whereas PEA cations were distributed throughout the thickness of the perovskite film, An cations were detected only at the top surface of the film (fig.  S3 ). The combination of AR-XPS and TOF-SIMS supported An remaining surface localized. Although An exhibited low ligand reactivity, it has also been reported to have limited passivating capacity  (35, 39) . To promote interfacial passivation, we explored fluorinated An, including 4-fluoroanilinium (4FAn), 2,6-difluoroanilinium (26FAn), and 3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium (345FAn), as well as tert-butyl-substituted 3,5-di-tertbutylanilinium (35tbuAn)  (17, 40, 41) . The C-N/ FA N ratios (Fig.  1E ) revealed that, compared with An, the newly synthesized ligands retained similarly low reactivity with perovskites. For fluorinated An, this low reactivity was also seen in the C-F signal in the F 1s XPS spectrum (fig.  S4 ). We identified a distinct C-F peak for 3FPEA, whereas the C-F signals from 4FAn, 26FAn, and 345FAn were all below the detection limit at the different electron takeoff angles. TOF-SIMS further confirmed that 345FAn cations were localized to the surface of the perovskite film (fig.  S5 ). We then characterized the phase transformation of perovskites driven by their interaction with ammonium ligands. Ultrafast transient reflection (TR) spectroscopy was used initially to detect 2D perovskite formation  (42) . For the PEA-treated perovskite films, negative reflectance features associated with n = 1, 2, and 3 layered 2D perovskites were observed in the TR spectra (Fig.  2A ). The relative proportion of 2D phases increased as the solution exposure time was prolonged (fig.  S6 ) and was indicative of progressive phase transformation. For the An-and 345FAn-treated perovskite films, no 2D phases were observed (Fig.  2, B  and C ), which we attributed to their inability to convert 3D perovskites into 2D phases (fig.  S7 ). These results reinforce the model proposing that inhibiting 2D phase conversion would also reduce ligand penetration. We also investigated phase transformation with grazing incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) measurements. Consistent with the TR studies, n = 2 2D perovskites were observed at around q = 0.29 Å -1 along q z for the PEA-treated perovskite film (Fig.  2D ) that blocks vertical carrier transport  (32) . Incidence angle-dependent diffraction patterns of PEA-treated perovskites revealed that the 2D phase formation was more pronounced near the surface (fig.  S8 ). No 2D phase was detected in the An-and 345FAn-treated perovskites (Fig.  2, E  and F ). In addition, we observed the formation of PbI 2 at q = 0.9 Å -1 for An-treated perovskite films, which we attributed to polar solvent-induced decomposition during solution exposure, as seen in x-ray diffraction (XRD) characterization (fig.  S9 ). This is a topic that requires further in-depth investigation. GIWAXS characterization showed that 345FAn protected the underlying perovskites from this solventinduced degradation (Fig.  2F ). We associate the reduction in surface degradation with increased hydrophobicity of this fluorinated ligand (fig.  S10 )  (26) . &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:57:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="5131" length="44"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:55:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="8030" length="24"/>
        <text>3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:56:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="8056" length="6"/>
        <text>345FAn</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:56:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="8500" length="6"/>
        <text>345FAn</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:56:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="10461" length="6"/>
        <text>345FAn</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10693</offset>
      <text> Theoretical calculations The interactions of ammonium ligands and perovskites are depicted in Fig.  3A . We performed density functional theory (DFT) calculations to explore how molecular structure affected these interactions. We first calculated the binding energies (E b ) of two adjacent perovskite fragments at their interface with the insertion of ammonium ligands (Fig.  3B ). A more negative E b implies that it is thermodynamically more favorable to form the 2D/3D heterostructures  (24) . Consistent with the AR-XPS studies, penetrating PEA had a more negative E b value than alkyl ammoniums OA and BA, whereas An and its derivatives showed the least tendency to form 2D/3D structures (Fig.  3C ). It has been suggested that the formation of 2D perovskites is related to the steric hindrance around the NH 3 + group  (43) . We calculated the steric effect index (STEI, defined as the steric environment around the NH 3 + group) of the ammonium ligand  (43)  and found that An had a much larger STEI (2.34) than that of PEA  (1.21) . Furthermore, phase transformation entailed the replacement of A-site cations at 2D/3D interfaces  (24) . DFT calculations indicated that this process demanded more energy for An-intercalated interfaces than for PEAintercalated ones (fig.  S11 ). This evidence further supported our finding that An was less likely to penetrate the bulk of perovskites through ligand intercalation. We proceeded to examine the interactions between ammonium ligands and perovskite surfaces. We calculated the interaction energy (E int ) for the scenario in which an ammonium ligand occupied an MA-vacancy site on the perovskite surface (Fig.  3D ). Electrostatic potential calculations showed that fluorine substitution resulted in a higher positive charge density near the ammonium group (fig.  S12 ) that could enhance its binding with the negatively charged MA vacancy  (13) . Indeed, the E int values were -0.74, -0.89, -0.92, and -1.22 eV for An, 4FAn, 26FAn, 345FAn, respectively (Fig.  3E ), indicating that 345FAn exhibited the strongest interaction with the perovskite surface. Future computational studies could beneficially predict the binding energy of the N 1s XPS peak. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12902</offset>
      <text> Perovskite degradation and solar cell studies We used TR and TOF-SIMS to study perovskite degradation. The TR results indicated that PEAbased 2D perovskites were thermally unstable on the film surface and decomposed into PbI 2 after thermal aging at 85°C for 2 hours (Fig.  4,  A  and B ). This process we associated with the diffusion of PEA cations into bulk perovskites, as was seen with TOF-SIMS (Fig.  4C ) and AR-XPS (fig.  S13 ). The dynamic nature of 2D/3D heterostructures was also confirmed for BA, OA, DA, and 3FPEA (fig.  S14 ). By contrast, neither ligand penetration nor phase degradation was observed for An-and 345FAn-treated films (Fig.  4C  and fig.  S15 ). These results suggested that suppressing ligand intercalation into 3D perovskites improved interface stability under thermal stress. We monitored the photoluminescence (PL) stability of perovskite films after annealing at 85°C (Fig.  4D ). The emission intensity of the untreated control and PEA-treated films degraded to 30% of its initial value within 144 hours (Fig.  4E ), as seen in the previous reports  (31) . By contrast, An-and 345FAn-treated films show improved thermal stability, and 345FAn-treated perovskites retained 85% of their initial brightness after annealing. We fabricated inverted-structure PSCs to investigate how ammonium ligands influenced the efficiency and stability of PSCs. We used both Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 and Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3 perovskites as the absorber, the self-assembled monolayer 2PACz as the hole transport layer, the thermally evaporated C 60 /bathocuproine (BCP) bilayer as the electron transport layer, and indium tin oxide (ITO) as the transparent electrode (materials and methods). Three representative ammonium ligands, including the 2D-forming PEA cation and the noninvasive An and 345FAn cations, were used for interfacial engineering. We sent a 345FAn-treated Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3 device to National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL, USA) for independent characterization. The device delivered a certified PCE of 24.09% by using a quasi-steady-state (QSS) I-V   S19 ). The QSS-certified efficiency reported for inverted PSCs is compared with that of other devices in table  S2 . Seeking a better understanding of the improved performance, we used ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) to characterize the electronic structure of the perovskite films. The secondary electron cutoff spectra (fig.  S20 ) showed that 345FAn decreased the work function of perovskites from 4.64 to 4.17 eV and shifted the valence-band maximum from 1.15 eV below the Fermi level in the control perovskites to 1.50 eV below the Fermi level. These results show that 345FAn induced more n-type character in the perovskite film (fig.  S20 ), which in inverted PSCs leads to favorable band bending for electron extraction and a decrease in nonradiative carrier recombination  (44, 45) . We performed optoelectronic characterization to investigate carrier recombination. From photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) measurements, we identified nonradiative recombination at the perovskite/C 60 interface as the limiting factor for the performance of control devices (fig.  S21 ). This recombination loss corresponded to a reduction of the quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) by ~100 meV (table  S3 )  (46, 47) . We found that PEA and 345FAn passivation could reduce the interfacial nonradiative recombination, as reflected by the improved QFLS relative to the control stack, by ~15 and ~30 meV, respectively. We further analyzed the energy loss of PSCs on the basis of the device diode characteristics (figs. S22 and S23)  (48) . Consistent with the PL studies, nonradiative losses were reduced for PEA and 345FAn devices (12.7 and 12.1% for PEA and 345FAn, respectively) compared with those of the control device (16.5%) (fig.  S24 ). We evaluated the effect of ligand reactivity on the material processing of PSCs. We varied the solution exposure time between 0 s (dynamic spinning) and 120 s and tracked the PV parameters of PSCs accordingly (Fig.  5D  and fig.  S25 ). The average PCE of PEA devices (eight devices for each condition) dropped to 15.8%, with an average fill factor (FF) of merely 67.4% over the course of solution exposure for 30 s, whereas 345FAn devices maintained an average PCE of 23.0% (Fig.  5D ). Wide solution-processing windows were also achieved for other nonpenetrating ligands, such as 35tbuAn, 4FAn, and 26FAn (fig.  S26 ). In pursuit of initial evidence of capacity to scale area, we fabricated perovskite solar modules (PSMs) with an active area of 22 cm 2 and nine interconnected subcells (materials and methods). The champion PCE under reverse voltage scan was improved from 19.9 to 20.8% for the 345FAn-treated PSMs, with an open-circuit voltage (V oc ) of 10.13 V, an FF of 74.2%, and a J sc of 2.77 mA cm -2 (fig.  S27 ). We studied the operating stability of PSCs using ISOS protocols  (49) . Accelerated lifetime testing was performed at the ISOS-L-3-85°C level, constituting light-soaking tests at 50% RH and 85°C with MPP tracking. We used atomic-layer deposition for SnO 2 as the buffer layer and Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 perovskites as the absorber (materials and methods). The initial PCEs of the encapsulated control, PEA, and 345FAn devices were 18.9, 20.1, and 20.2%, respectively (fig.  S28 ). The stability results are shown in Fig.  5E . We recorded a similar T 80 of ~220 hours for the control and PEA devices, in accordance with the limited thermal stability of perovskite films (Fig.  3E ). We found that 2D/3D PSCs based on alkyl ammonium BA and OA were even less stable than the control device (fig.  S29 ). By contrast, the 345FAn device retained &gt;80% of its initial value after the 800-hour test. We estimate the T 80 for the 345FAn device to be ~810 hours (fig.  S30 ), representing a fourfold enhancement over the operating lifetime of the PEA device. To improve the T 80 further, we moved to fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO) as an alternative transparent electrode (fig.  S31 ) because of its chemical stability  (50, 51) . We monitored the MPP of the encapsulated device under 1-sun illumination at 50% RH and 85°C. The initial PCE was 19.0%, which increased progressively to a peak value of 19.9% after ~50 hours of operation (Fig.  5F ). This maximum PCE (PCE max ) corresponds to a temperature coefficient of -0.12% /°C relative to the room temperature device PCE (21.5%), which is con-sistent with reported results for inverted PSCs  (52) . After 1586 hours of continuous operation, the PCE dropped to 16.8% (84% of the PCE max ), primarily because of a reduction in current density (Fig.  5G ). We determined the T 85 to be ~1560 hours (Fig.  5F ). A comparison with other ISOS-L-3-stable PSCs is provided in table S4. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:57:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="14074" length="6"/>
        <text>345FAn</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:57:50Z</infon>
        <location offset="14295" length="44"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:58:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="14344" length="28"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2PACz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:58:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="14431" length="5"/>
        <text>2PACz</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T00:58:40Z</infon>
        <location offset="14821" length="28"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:06:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="19106" length="18"/>
        <text>1-sun illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:07:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="19128" length="3"/>
        <text>50%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:07:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="19139" length="4"/>
        <text>85°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:08:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="19396" length="6"/>
        <text>(21.5%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1586</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:08:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="19480" length="10"/>
        <text>1586 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">84</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="19542" length="3"/>
        <text>84%</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-24T12:48:23Z</infon>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="22" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19760</offset>
      <text> Discussion Two types of 2D/3D heterostructures have been reported for ISOS-L-3-stable PSCs: 3FPEAintercalated 2D/3D perovskites (  23  all-inorganic heterostructures  (12) . For allinorganic PSCs, the T 85 reached an impressive 4000 hours at 85°C, but with further room for progress in PCE (≤17% when measured at 85°C). 3FPEA-based PSCs have achieved PCEs exceeding 23% at room temperature, but stable operation over 500 hours was limited to 65°C. Aided by spectroscopic techniques, including AR-XPS, TOF-SIMS, and TR, we see evidence here that certain 2D/3D heterostructures, such as those employing typical ammonium ligands including PEA, 3FPEA, BA, and OA, may evince thermal degradation, something we assign to the dynamic nature of the interfaces at elevated temperatures. Anilinium and its fluorinated derivatives offer a more robust interface structure correlated with limited penetration into the bulk of perovskites. Fluorinated An contributes interface passivation linked to strong interactions with perovskite surfaces. The resultant optimized 345FAn devices are among the most stable PSCs seen under ISOS-L-3 protocols at 85°C, achieving PCE of 19.9% during MPP tracking at this elevated operating temperature. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20991</offset>
      <text> Materials All materials were used as received without further purification. Organic halide salts, including methylammonium iodide (MAI), formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium bromide (MABr) methylammonium chloride (MACl), were purchased from Great Cell Solar, and cesium iodide (CsI) was purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. [2-(9H-Carbazol-9-yl)ethyl]phosphonic Acid (2PACz), lead iodide (PbI2, 99.99%), and bathocuproine (BCP) were purchased from TCI. Anhydrous solvents including N, N-dimethylformamide (DMF, 99.8%), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, 99.9%), 2-propanol (IPA, 99.5%), chloroform (CF, 99.8%), chlorobenzene (CB, 99.8%), and anisole (99.7%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich and toluene (99.8%) was purchased from Alfa Aesar. 3-fluoro-phenethylammonium iodide (3FPEAI) and C60 were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corp. Non-patterned indium tin oxide (ITO) coated glass substrates (15 Ω/sq) were purchased from Tinwell Technology. Commercial patterned ITO substrates (20 Ω/sq) with 25 mm x 25 mm dimensions were purchased from TFD Inc. Bulky ammonium halide salts, including anilinium iodide (AnI, TCI, 98%), butylammonium iodide (BAI, TCI, 97%), phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI, Great Cell Solar, 99%), were purchased and used as received. 4-fluoroaniline (TCI, 98%), 2,6-difluoroaniline (TCI, 98%), 3,4,5trifluoroaniline (TCI, 98%), octylamine (Alfa Aeser, 99%), decylamine (Sigma-Aldrich, 95%), and 3,5-di-tert-butylaniline (TCI, 98%) were purchased and converted to ammonium salts using the same procedure as reported before  (20) . The abbreviations of the converted ammonium salts are 4-fluoroanilinium iodide (4FAnI), 2,6-difluoroanilinium iodide (26FAnI), 3,4,5trifluoroanilinium iodide (345FAnI), 3,5-di-tert-butylanilinium iodide (35tbuAnI), octylammonium iodide (OAI), and decylammonium iodide (DAI). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2PACz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:09:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="21359" length="5"/>
        <text>2PACz</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:10:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="21772" length="3"/>
        <text>C60</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22827</offset>
      <text> Perovskite film fabrication The precursor solution (1.5 M) was prepared from CsI, MAI, FAI, PbBr2, and PbI2 precursors dissolved in mixed solvents of DMF and DMSO with a volume ratio of 4:1. For the Cs0.05MA0.15FA0.8PbI3 perovskite, the molar ratio for FAI/MAI/CsI was 0.8:0.15:0.05, and 10 mg mL -1 MACl was added in the solution to improve the film morphology; For the Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.9Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 perovskite, the molar ratios for FAI/MABr/CsI and PbI2/PbBr2 were 0.9:0.05:0.05 and 0.95:0.05, respectively. The precursor solution was filtered through a 0.22 μm polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) membrane before use. 60 μL of perovskite solution was deposited on the substrate and spun cast at 1000 rpm for 10 s followed by 6000 rpm for 30 s. 150 μL anisole was dropped onto the substrate during the last 5 s of the spinning, resulting in the formation of dark brown films that were then annealed on a hot plate at 100°C for 20 min. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23769</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication The pre-patterned ITO or FTO glasses were sequentially sonicated in aqueous detergent, deionized water, acetone, and IPA each for 10 min. After drying with nitrogen, the substrates were exposed to UV-ozone treatment for 15 min to remove organic contaminants. 100 μL of 2PACz in anhydrous ethanol (1 mmol/l) solution was spun-cast at 3000 rpm for 30 s inside the nitrogen-filled glovebox (&lt;0.1 ppm of O2 and H2O) and annealed at 100°C for 10 min. Following the 2PACz coating, Cs0.05MA0.15FA0.8PbI3 perovskites were deposited on the substrate as detailed above. 200 μL of ammonium ligand solution (1mg/mL) in CF with an additional 3% of IPA was then drop cast within 2-3 s on the perovskite film spinning at 4000 rpm (i.e., dynamic spinning) and annealed at 100°C for 5 min. For the exposure time-dependent measurements, 200 μL of ammonium ligand solution was left on the perovskite film for a certain period before spinning at 4000 rpm. Both control and treated films were then transferred to the thermal evaporator (Angstrom engineering), and C60 (30 nm) and BCP (7 nm) were deposited sequentially with a rate of 0.3 Å/s and 0.5 Å/s, respectively, at a pressure of ca. 2 x 10 -6 mbar. Finally, Ag contact (120 nm) was deposited on top of BCP through a shadow mask with the desired aperture area. For the stability testing, Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.9Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 perovskites were instead deposited as described above, and C60 (30 nm) and ALD-SnO2 were used as the electron transport layer. The deposition of ALD-SnO2 was carried out in the PICOSUN R-200 Advanced ALD system. H2O and TDMASn were used as oxygen and tin precursors. Precursor and substrate temperature were set to 75°C and 85°C, respectively. 90 SCCM N2 was used as carrier gas. Pulse and purge times for H2O were 1 s and 5 s, and 1.6 s and 5 s for TDMASn. The total deposition cycle is 150, corresponding to 20 nm of SnO2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25681</offset>
      <text> Module Fabrication Perovskite solar modules were fabricated on pre-cleaned FTO glass substrates with a size of 6 x 6 cm 2 , which were patterned by a 1030 nm laser (LPKF ProtoLaser R) with nine sub-cells connected in series. FTO substrates were patterned with a laser power of 5 W (P1). The SnO2 was used as the electron transport layer (ETL) using the chemical bath deposition method. The solution was prepared by adding 2.5 g of urea (Sigma-Aldrich, 99%), 3.5 mL of HCl (Sigma-Aldrich, 37% wt. % in water), 50 μL of thioglycolic acid (Sigma-Aldrich, 98%), and 0.55 g of SnCl2•2H2O (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.99%) into 200 mL of deionized water. The FTO substrates were immerged into the solution at 90°C for 5 hours, followed by annealing at 190°C for 1 hour. Then 1.5 M perovskite precursors with PbI2 (TCI America, 99.99%): FAI (GreatCell Solar, 99.99%): MAI (GreatCell Solar, 99.99%): CsI (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.99%): MACl (GreatCell Solar, 99.99%) = 1: 0.85: 0.05: 0.05: 0.20) were dissolved in the mixed DMF (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.8%): DMSO (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.9%) = 4:1 (volume ratio) solvent. The perovskite films were deposited by spin-coating at 1000 rpm for 10 s and 5000 rpm for 30 s. At the 20 s of the second step, 200 µL of chlorobenzene (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.8%) was dropped onto the perovskite films to facilitate crystallization. The perovskite films were annealed at 100 °C for 10 min and 150 °C for 10 min. The passivation layer was fabricated by spinning 100 μL 345FAn solution (1 mg/mL) in isopropanol (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.5%) and chlorobenzene (1:1 volume ratio) at 5000 rpm 30s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. The hole transport layer was deposited by spin-coating 0.06 M spiro-OMeTAD (Sigma-Aldrich, SHT-263 Solarpur) solution in chlorobenzene at 3000 rpm for 20 s. 0.03 M bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)-imide lithium salt (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.0%) in acetonitrile (Sigma-Aldrich, 99.8%), 0.2 M 4-tert-Butylpyridine (Sigma-Aldrich, 98%) and 0.0035 M FK 209 Co(III) TFSI salt (GreatCell Solar) in acetonitrile were added to the spiro-OMeTAD solution as additives. Then the P2 lines were patterned aligning with P1 using a laser power of 0.5 W. Finally, the electrode was realized by thermal evaporating a 70 nm gold under high vacuum, followed by P3 etching using a laser power of 0.5 W. The geometric fill factor (GFF) of 92% was defined as the active area (22.0 cm 2 ) divided by the aperture area (23.9 cm 2 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28119</offset>
      <text> Solar cell characterization The current-voltage (I-V) characteristics of solar cells were measured using a Keithley 2400 sourcemeter under the illumination of solar simulator (Newport, Class AAA) at the light intensity of 100 mW cm -2 as checked with a calibrated reference solar cell (Newport). Unless otherwise stated, the I-V curves were all measured in a nitrogen atmosphere with a scanning rate of 100 mV s - 1 (voltage steps of 10 mV and a delay time of 100 ms). The active area was determined by the aperture shade mask (0.049 cm 2 ) placed in front of the solar cell to avoid overestimation of the photocurrent density. EQE measurements were performed using Newport system (QuantX-300) with monochromatic light and white bias light (~0.2 Sun). The system was calibrated by a certified silicon solar cell. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28934</offset>
      <text> Stability tests of solar cells Devices were placed in a homemade stability tracking station. The illumination source is a white light LED with intensity calibrated to match 0.8-sun conditions. For the ISOS-L-3 ageing protocol, the device chamber was left open in a room with 50±10% humidity and solar cell was mounted on a metal plate kept at 85°C by a heating element. A thermal couple attached to the metal plate was used to monitor and provide feedback control to the heating element to ensure temperature consistency. MPP was tracked using a home-build MATLAB-based MPP tracking system using a 'perturb and observe' method. The MPP was updated every 1000 minutes. Encapsulation was done by capping the device with a glass slide, using UV-adhesive (Lumtec LT-U001) as a sealant. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29720</offset>
      <text> AR-XPS measurements AR-XPS measurements were performed with a Thermo Scientific K-Alpha system with 180° double-focusing, hemispherical analyzer. The system is equipped with a 128-channel detector and monochromated small spot XPS. An Al Kα source (1486.6 eV) was used for excitation and a pass energy of 147.6 eV was used for XPS acquisition. Three electron take-off angles (α = 0°, 45°, and 75°) were defined as the angle between the normal of the perovskite sample and the analyzer (Fig.  1b ). Samples mounted on a metal specimen holder were rotated along x, y, z directions to match the analyzing spots. All data were analyzed with Thermo Avantage software. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30390</offset>
      <text> TR measurements A regeneratively amplified Yb:KGW laser at a 5 kHz repetition rate (Light Conversion, Pharos) was used to generate femtosecond laser pulses, and a pulse picker was used to lower the frequency to 1 kHz. A portion of the 1,030 nm fundamental was sent into an optical bench (Ultrafast, Helios), where it passed through a retroreflector and was then focused into a calcium fluoride crystal, translated at 1 mm s -1 , to create the white light continuum probe. An optical parametric amplifier (Light Conversion, Orpheus) was used to generate the 450 nm pump pulse by upconversion of the fundamental wavelength. This was then sent to the optical bench and was chopped at 500 Hz. Both the pump and probe were sent to the sample, with the time delay adjusted by changing the path length of the probe (time resolution ~350 fs). The probe pulse was then collected by a CCD after dispersion by a grating spectrograph (Ultrafast). Time zero was allowed to vary with wavelength to account for the chirp of the probe. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31412</offset>
      <text> GIWAXS measurements GIWAXS measurements were performed at CMS beamline, NSLS II. The monochromatic X-ray with the energy of 13.5 keV shone upon the samples at different grazing incident angles of 0.08°, 0.12°, 0.25°, and 0.5° with an exposure time of 10 s. A Pilatus800K detector was placed 259 mm away from the sample to capture the 2D diffraction pattern. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31776</offset>
      <text> PL and time-resolved PL (TRPL) measurements Photoluminescence lifetime (TCSPC) was measured using an Edinburgh Instruments lifespec II fluorescence spectrometer; a picosecond pulse diode laser (EPL-510, excitation wavelength 510 nm, pulse width &lt; 60 ps, fluence &lt; 3 nJ cm -2 ) was used. Absolute intensity photoluminescence spectra were measured using an integrating sphere, and Andor Kymera 193i spectrograph, and a 660 nm continuous-wave laser set at 1-Sun equivalent photon flux (1.1 µm beam full-width halfmaximum, 632 µW); photoluminescence was collected at normal incidence using a 0.1 NA, 110 µm-diameter optical fiber. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32408</offset>
      <text> TOF-SIMS Measurement The time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) measurements were performed on the IONTOF M6 instrument with a Bi 3+ (30 keV) primary ion beam for analysis and an Arcluster gun (5 keV) for sputtering due to its low damage depth. Data was acquired for positive ions in an analysis area of 49 × 49 μm 2 centered inside the cluster raster area of 200 × 200 μm 2 . No distribution gradient was observed for FA cations, indicating that measurement artifacts were successfully minimized  (53) . Other characterizations XRD spectra were collected with a Bruker-AXS D8 advance diffractometer with Cu Kα radiation (λ = 1.5418 Å) operating at 40 kV and 40 mA. Contact angles were measured with a standard goniometer (Ramé-hart) equipped with a camera was used to measure. A 4 μl drop of deionized water was placed onto the target surface and pictures were captured after 2 s of depositing the drop. The images were analyzed using ImageJ software to extract macroscale contact angle data. UPS measurements were taken with an Excitech H Lyman-α photon source (10.2 eV) with an oxygen-filled beam path coupled with the same PHI 5600 UHV and analyzer system. A sample bias of -5 V was applied and a pass energy of 5.85 eV was used for UPS acquisition. Highresolution SEM images were obtained using the Hitachi S5200 microscope with an accelerating voltage of 1.5 kV. A low accelerating voltage and a low beam current were deployed to reduce surface damage of perovskite films under electron beam bombardment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33950</offset>
      <text> DFT calculations First-principles calculations based on density functional theory (DFT) were carried out using the Vienna Ab initio Simulation Package (VASP)  (54) . The generalized gradient approximation (GGA) of Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) functional was employed as the exchange-correlation functional  (55) . We adopt DFT-D3 method for the van der Waals (vdW) correction  (56) . The plane-wave cutoff energy of 400 eV was used. The energy and force convergence criteria were set to 10 -5 eV and 0.02 eV•Å -1 , respectively. In 2D perovskite formation calculations, the binding energies (Eb) of adjacent fragments was defined as  (24) : 𝐸 𝐵 = 𝐸 𝑡𝑜𝑡 -𝐸 𝑓𝑟𝑎𝑔𝑚𝑒𝑛𝑡1 -𝐸 𝑓𝑟𝑎𝑔𝑚𝑒𝑛𝑡2 , where 𝐸 𝑡𝑜𝑡 , 𝐸 𝑓𝑟𝑎𝑔𝑚𝑒𝑛𝑡1 and 𝐸 𝑓𝑟𝑎𝑔𝑚𝑒𝑛𝑡2 are the total energies of the entire system, and two fragments cut from the optimized system. The interaction energies (Eint) of different ammonium cations (L) with tetragonal MAPbI3 perovskite surface were calculated as Emol/pvsk-Epvsk-EL, where Emol/pvsk, Epvsk and EL are the total energies of the adsorption system, the perovskite system and LI, respectively. We used a vacuum of 20 Å to separate two surfaces along the z-direction.                  S3 . Fig.  S22 . Voc-light intensity dependence of PSCs. The values of the ideality factor for control, PEA, An, and 345FAn devices are 1.13, 1.19, 1.12, and 1.07, respectively. It is noted that no direct correlation between ideality factor and device performance is found herein. This can be explained by recent findings: Although non-radiative bulk recombination leads to a higher ideality factor, surface and interface recombination can lead to a lower one  (59, 60) . In addition, the ideality factor in perovskites solar cells can also be critically affected by the ionic nature of the absorber layer  (61) . The details behind the shown J-V curves can be found in supplementary text. Losses due to nonradiative recombination appear in Voc and FF, transport losses apparent between the transport limit J-V curve and the measured J-V curve additionally lower the FF.          Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. AR-XPS characterization of ammonium ligand penetration. (A) Chemical structures of the ammonium ligands investigated in this study. (B) Experimental setup for AR-XPS characterization. The electron takeoff angle a is defined as the angle between the normal of the sample substrate and the analyzer. (C) Schematic indicating the relation between a and the photoelectron probing depth, d. (D and E) C-N to FA N ratios at electron takeoff angles of 0°, 45°, and 75°for the control (untreated) and ammonium ligand-treated perovskite films. The results show reduced bulk and surface existence for An and An derivatives. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36787</offset>
      <text> Park 7 Fig. 2 . 72 Fig. 2. Phase transformation of perovskite films. (A to C) Pseudocolor representation of the transient reflectance spectra, DR/R, for the PEA-(A), An-(B), and 345Fan-treated (C) perovskite films, respectively. n = 1, n = 2, n = 3 2D perovskites (n 1 , n 2 , and n 3 ) appear in the film after PEA passivation. (D to F) GIWAXS image for perovskite films of PEA (D), An (E), and 345FAn (F) passivation, respectively. The color bar shows the diffraction intensity collected from the GIWAXS detector. q xy and q z represent in-plane and near out-of-plane scattering vectors, respectively. n = 2 2D perovskite (n 2 ) and PbI 2 -related diffraction peaks are observed in the PEA-and An-treated films, respectively. (100) refers to the (100) diffraction peak of 3D perovskites. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37579</offset>
      <text> The cross-sectional scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of a complete device is shown in fig.S16.Device performance (Fig.5A) showed that compared with control devices, PEA-treated Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3 PSCs (16 devices) pro-vided improved PV performance with an average PCE of 23.2% (Fig.5Aand fig.S17). The average PCE of An devices decreased to 19.9%, a finding we linked to perovskite decomposition. Because of the improved surface passivation, 345FAn treatment increased average PCEs of Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3 and Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb (I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 PSCs to 23.3 and 22.9%, respectively (Fig.5Aand fig.S18). The external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the champion cells (Fig.5B) for PEA and 345FAn devices exhibited improved charge collection compared with controls, and their integrated short-circuit current density (J sc ) values matched well with those from the current-voltage (I-V) sweep. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:11:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="38083" length="28"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.15 FA 0.8 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-10T01:11:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="38116" length="45"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.9 Pb (I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38514</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. DFT studies. (A) Schematic depiction of the model of ammonium ligand and perovskite interactions. (B) Models used in DFT calculations to calculate the binding energy (E b ) of adjacent 2D perovskite fragments. (C) E b values for seven ammonium ligands substituted into MAPbI 3 perovskite slabs. (D) Models used to calculate the interaction energy (E int ) of ammonium ligands with the MAPbI 3 perovskite surface. (E) E int values of four ammonium ligands with the perovskite surface. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39019</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Thermal stability of perovskite films. (A and B) Pseudocolor representation of the transient reflectance spectra for PEA-treated perovskite films before (A) and after (B) thermal aging at 85°C for 2 hours. 2D perovskites were decomposed into PbI 2 after thermal aging. (C) The distribution of PEA + and An + in fresh and aged (at 85°C for 2 hours) perovskite films observed with TOF-SIMS. (D) PL spectra of perovskite thin films under thermal annealing at 85°C. The films were kept on a hot plate at 85°C in the N 2 -filled glovebox and measured every 24 hours in ambient air. (E) Changes in PL intensity for different annealing times. Data are presented as mean values ± standard deviation. Three films were measured under each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39785</offset>
      <text> of 7 Fig. 5 . 75 Fig. 5. Photovoltaic performance of PSCs with interface engineering. (A) PCE for control (8 devices) versus ammonium ligand-treated (16 devices for each type) PSCs. (B) EQE curves of the control and ammonium ligandtreated devices. (C) QSS current density-voltage (J-V) curve of one representative 345FAn device certified at NREL. (Inset) PV parameters of the device. (D) PCE evolution of PEA and 345FAn devices as a function of solution exposure time (8 devices for each condition). Data are presented as &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40309</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6. a , a Fig. S6. a, Pseudocolour plot of ΔR/R as a function of incident photon wavelength and delay time for the control perovskite film. b-c, TR spectra of the PEA (b), An (c), and 345FAn (d) treatedperovskite films at the pump-probe delay time of 410 fs, as a function of the solution exposure time. n = 1, 2, and 3 2D perovskites were found for the PEA-treated films, and their relative proportion to 3D perovskites is increased when the exposure time is prolonged. For An and 345FAn treated films, no 2D phases were detected, irrespective of the exposure time. It is noted that TR spectroscopy is utilized only for examining the phase distribution of quasi-2D perovskites, while photoinactive δ-FAPbI3 and PbI2 are detected by GIWAXS. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41059</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. XRD patterns of mixed An+PbI2 (top) and 345FAn+PbI2 (bottom) films. The (001) and (101) diffraction peaks of PbI2 are observed. There are no 2D-related diffraction peaks for either film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41270</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. GIWAXS spectra as a function of incidence angle 0.08°, 0.12°, 0.25°, and 0.5°: a-b, Cuts near the qz axis of GIWAXS measurements for PEA (a), An (b), and 345FAn (c) treated perovskite films. n = 2 2D perovskites (n2) were observed in the PEA-treated films only at low incidence angles, indicative of the preferable presence of 2D perovskites on the film surface. PbI2 was observed in the An-treated films due to surface degradation. δ indicates the hexagonal perovskite phase. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41776</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. XRD patterns of perovskite films with varying solution exposure times: a, XRD patterns of control perovskite films. The asterisk symbol (*) indicates PbI2 species. b-d, XRD patterns of 4FAn (b), 26FAn (c), and 345FAn (d) treated perovskite films. The generation of PbI2 during exposure to both pure solvent and An-solution is comparable, which suggests that the decomposition of perovskites is caused by solvents. Films exposed to 26FAn and 345FAn solution exhibited minimal PbI2 generation, indicating these ammonium ligands can protect perovskites from degradation more efficiently than An. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42393</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Contact angle images of control and various ammonium ligand-treated perovskite films: a-f, The images of the water droplet for control (a) and An (b), 4FAn (c), 26FAn (d), 345FAn (e), and 35tbuAn (f) treated perovskite films. All images are recorded 2 s after the DI water drop was placed on the surface. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42725</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. DFT analysis of MA vacancy formation in various intercalated 2D/3D interfaces: a, Computational models used to determine the MA vacancy formation energy in the case of 345FAn intercalation. b, MA vacancy formation energies for PEA, An and 345FAn intercalation. Compared to PEA, the removal of MA cations becomes energetically less favorable for An and 345FAn. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43112</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. Gaussian calculated electrostatic potentials (φ) of An and fluorinated An ligands. The right color bar from red to blue marks the increase of electro positivity. The φmax is the maximum electrostatic potential amplitude of a specific ligand (57). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43388</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. AR-XPS N 1s region of aged perovskite films as a function of the electron take-off angles 0°, 45°, and 75°: a,b, PEA (a), and 3FPEA (b) treated films measured after 85°C annealing for 2 h. The pink peak fits the C-N bond and the blue to the C=N bond. At a 75° electron take-off angle, the C-N signals diminish significantly in comparison to the fresh sample for both films, suggesting decreased surface presence due to ligand penetration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43859</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. Phase stability of penetrating ammonium ligand-treated perovskite films: a-d, Pseudocolor representation of the transient reflectance spectra for 3FPEA (a), BA (b), OA (c), and DA (d) treated perovskite films before (fresh) and after (aged) thermal aging at 85°C for 2 h. All 2D phases disappeared from the film surfaces after thermal aging. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44229</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. Phase stability of 345FAn treated films at elevated temperatures: a,b, Pseudocolor representation of the transient reflectance spectra for the 345FAn treated perovskite film before (a) and after (b) thermal aging at 85°C for 2 h. No apparent phase change was observed after thermal aging. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44546</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. Cross-sectional SEM image of 345FAn treated inverted PSCs. Scale bar = 1 μm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44651</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. Performance of control and treated PSCs: a-d, PV parameters, including PCE (a), Jsc (b), Voc (c), and FF (d), of control devices (8 devices) and treated PSCs (16 devices for each type). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44864</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. PV parameters of treated Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.9Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 devices: a-d, PCE (a), Jsc (b), Voc (c), and FF (d) of 345FAn-treated devices (8 devices). Statistical distribution is represented in box-and-whisker plots (line within the box: median, box limit: 25th and 75th percentiles, whiskers: outliers). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45195</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. Certified results of the inverted PSC with 345FAn passivation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45285</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. UPS spectra and energy level schematic: a,b, Secondary electron cut-off region (a), and valence band onset region (b) plotted on a relative logarithmic scale of control and ammonium ligand treated films. The x-axis energy scale is with respect to the Fermi energy. Gaussian fit (grey solid line) was used to determine the valence band (58). c, Energy diagram comparing the alignment between the control and ammonium ligand treated films. The dashed lines indicate work functions. 345FAn induces the n-type perovskite film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45835</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S21. a-b, Absolute intensity PL spectra of perovskite thin films on glass/ITO/2PACz without (a) or with (b) a 30 nm-thick C60 overlayer. The corresponding PLQY and QFLS values are summarized in TableS3. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46049</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S23. a-d, J-V characteristics of control (a) and PEA (b), An (c), and 345FAn (d) treated PSCs.The details behind the shown J-V curves can be found in supplementary text. Losses due to nonradiative recombination appear in Voc and FF, transport losses apparent between the transport limit J-V curve and the measured J-V curve additionally lower the FF. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46411</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. Breakdown of energy loss in PSCs derived from the J-V fits. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46498</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. PV performance of PEA and 345FAn treated PSCs as a function of solution exposure times: a,b, PV parameters, including Jsc , Voc, and FF, of PEA (a) and 345FAn (b) treated devices with different solution exposure times (8 devices for each condition). Data are presented as mean values ± standard deviation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46832</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 . S26 Fig. S26. Device performance of PSCs with different An-derivative passivation: a, PCE statistics for 35tbuAn, 26FAn, and 4FAn-treated PSCs (8 devices for each type). b, PCE evolution of ligandtreated devices as a function of solution exposure time (8 devices for each condition). Data are presented as mean values ± standard deviation. The grey dash line is the PCE evolution of PEAtreated devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47249</offset>
      <text> Fig. S27 . S27 Fig. S27. Photovoltaic performance of control and 345FAn treated perovskite solar modules: a,b, J-V curves (a) and PCE statistics (b) of control and 345FAn treated perovskite solar module with an active area of 22 cm 2 . Inset: Photograph of a representative perovskite solar module. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47550</offset>
      <text> Fig. S28 . S28 Fig. S28. J-V curves and figures of merit for devices used in stability testing. The device architecture is ITO/2PACz/Perovskite/C60/ALD-SnOx/Ag and the perovskite composition is Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.9Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47781</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 . S29 Fig. S29. MPP tracking of encapsulated BA and OA devices at 85°C with a relative humidity of ~50% under 0.8-sun illumination. PEA and 345FAn results, as presented in Fig. 5E, are included for reference. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48002</offset>
      <text> Fig. S30 . S30 Fig. S30. Linear extrapolation of stability testing. Based on the initial 500 h stability data, we estimate the T80 lifetime to be ~810 h for the 345FAn-treated PSC using linear extrapolation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48212</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S31. a,b, The device architecture (a), J-V curve, and figures of merit (b) for the FTO device used in stability testing. The perovskite composition is Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.9Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3. The J-V curve was measured under 1-sun-equivalent white LED illumination at room temperature. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48503</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 XPS peak position and area for control and ammonium-ligand-treated perovskite films at α = 0°, 45°, and 75° electron take-off angles Films Take-off angle (°) C-N peak position (eV) C-N peak area FA N peak position (eV) FA N peak area C-N to FA N ratio 0 401.3 0.80 400.0 18.0 0.04 Control 45 401.3 0.74 400.0 16.5 0.04 75 401.4 0.91 400.1 14.2 0.06 0 401.4 1.82 399.7 14.0 0.13 PEA 45 401.5 1.31 399.8 13.1 0.10 75 401.6 1.25 399.8 11.4 0.11 0 401.6 2.14 399.9 14.2 0.15 3FPEA 45 401.7 1.72 400.0 13.3 0.13 75 401.7 1.54 400.0 10.9 0.14 0 401.3 1.56 399.6 12.7 0.12 BA 45 401.4 1.78 399.5 10.5 0.17 75 401.5 1.80 399.6 9.06 0.20 0 401.3 2.31 399.6 14.2 0.16 OA 45 401.4 2.67 399.6 12.2 0.22 75 401.4 2.38 399.6 10.5 0.23 0 401.5 2.31 399.7 14.1 0.16 DA 45 401.6 1.58 399.9 15.2 0.10 75 401.6 1.02 399.9 13.6 0.08 0 401.4 0.86 399.7 12.5 0.06 An 45 401.5 0.78 399.8 15.2 0.05 75 401.3 0.81 399.8 13.2 0.06 0 401.5 0.57 399.9 12.7 0.04 4FAn 45 401.6 0.54 399.9 10.9 0.05 75 401.5 0.40 399.9 7.83 0.05 0 401.4 0.66 399.9 15.6 0.04 26FAn 45 401.4 0.64 399.9 12.8 0.05 75 401.5 0.76 399.9 10.1 0.07 0 401.6 0.83 400.0 16.1 0.05 345FAn 45 401.5 0.57 400.0 14.1 0.04 75 401.7 0.77 400.0 11.7 0.06 0 401.4 0.90 399.9 14.7 0.06 35tbuAn 45 401.4 0.68 399.9 12.4 0.05 75 401.4 0.16 399.9 3.2 0.05 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49810</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Summary of quasi-steady-state (QSS) certified PV parameters of &gt; 21% PCE inverted PSCs Voc (V) Jsc (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) PCE Ref. 1.1595 25.02 83.05 24.09% (NREL) This work 1.1607 25.44 81.48 24.05% (NREL) Q. Jiang, Nature (2022) (45) 1.1505 24.90 83.46 23.91% (NREL) H. Chen, Nat. Photonics (2022) (23) 1.1687 22.89 84.55 22.62% (NREL) S. Chen, Sci. Adv (2021) (62) 1.1429 23.84 82.0 22.34% (Newport) X. Zheng, Nat. Energy (2020) (63) &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:20Z</infon>
        <location offset="49890" length="2"/>
        <text>21</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50259</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 Summary of PL peak position, PLQY, Voc,rad, and QFLS for the perovskite thin films with or without the C60 overlayer Films Overlayer PL peak position (nm) PLQY (%) Voc,rad (V) QFLS (eV) Control None C60 799 796 13.4 0.26 1.265 1.269 1.213 1.117 PEA None C60 798 797 13.9 0.47 1.265 1.270 1.214 1.132 An None C60 797 796 7.0 0.28 1.266 1.270 1.198 1.119 345FAn None C60 799 795 15.0 0.73 1.266 1.271 1.217 1.144 &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.269</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="50501" length="5"/>
        <text>1.269</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="29">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.271</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:05:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="50667" length="5"/>
        <text>1.271</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50686</offset>
      <text> Table S4 . S4 Summary of reported device operational stability based on ISOS-L-3 protocols. Light source T Environ ment Surface passivation PCE @high-T Lifetime Ref. White LED 85°C ~50% RH 345FAn 19.9% (85°C) T85 = 1560 h This work White LED 65°C ~50% RH 3FPEA 2D/3D N.A. T92 = 500 h H. Chen, Nat. Photonics (2022) (23) Metal-halide lamp 85°C ~65% RH Cs2PbI2Cl2 ~16.5% (85°C) T85 = 4000 h X. Zhao, Science (2022) (12) Xenon lamp 85°C ~50% RH None ~14.2% (85°C) T95 = 1200 h (Post 15% burn-in) Y-H. Lin, Science (2020) (11) Plasma lamp 65°C ~60% RH PbSO4 ~19.5% (65°C) T96.8 = 1200 h S. Yang, Science (2019) (18) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51309</offset>
      <text>			 of 7 RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
