<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025028347HIFDDD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">3</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">3</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 32&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Unique Properties of Halide Perovskites as Possible Origins of the Superior Solar Cell Performance&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>111</offset>
      <text>Table S1. Calculated effective masses for electrons and holes*. *For heavy elements like Pb with strong relativistic effect, spin orbital coupling (SOC) is also considered. (a) G.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>291</offset>
      <text>Figure S5: The equivalent ionic size of CH 3 NH 3 + can be estimated by the trend of lattice constants of CH 3 NH 3 MI 3 , where M=Si, Ge, Sn, Pb. At the ideal condition of perovskite AMX 3 , the ionic size meet the condition of (r A +r X )/ 2 (r M +r X ) = 1. In this case, the ideal lattice constant is 2×(r M +r X ). The undersized A atom will shrink the ideal lattice constant and oversized A atom will expand ideal lattice constant. To evaluate the extremely high optical absorption of halide perovskites, the optical absorption coeffi cients of two representative halide perovskites, CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 and CsSnI 3 ,  [ 2, 18 ]  are calculated and compared with the optical absorption of GaAs: the absorber of the thin-fi lm solar cell with the highest conversion effi ciency. The optical absorption of a semiconductor at photonic energy ω, according to the Fermi Golden rule, is directly correlated with 2 ˆ2 2 8 3 3 v H c 2 8 3 d k π π δ ( ) c v ω Ec Ev k k k ∫ Ev k ,  [ 19 ]  where v H c is the transition matrix from states in the valence band (VB) to states in the conduction band (CB) and the integration is over the whole reciprocal space. For simplicity, the transition matrix v H c can be considered independent of k and the absorption formula is approximately 2 ˆ2 8 2 3 3 v H c 2 3 d k π π δ ( ) c v ω Ec Ev k k k Ev k ∫ , where the second term is the joint density of states (JDOS) at energy ω. Our calculations show that the transition matrices of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 and GaAs near the optical absorption edges do not have signifi cant differences. Therefore, the JDOSs determines the optical absorption difference between these two materials. Our calculations show a large difference in JDOS, and therefore in optical absorptions, in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 and GaAs. The lower part of the GaAs CB is derived from the dispersive s band (dilute s electron); whereas, the lower part of the CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 CB is mainly composed of Pb p bands (Figure  S1 , Supporting Information). The atomic p states have two more orbitals than the s states and exhibit less dispersion. As a result, the density of states (DOS) in the lower CB of the halide perovskites is signifi cantly higher than that of GaAs as shown in Figure  1  a, leading to higher JDOS (Figure  1 b ), and therefore, stronger optical absorption for halide perovskites. The calculated optical absorption coeffi cients of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , CsSnI 3 and GaAs are shown in Figure  1 c . It is seen that the optical absorption coeffi cient of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 is up to 1 order of magnitude higher than that of GaAs within the visible light range. As the visible light range accounts for the major usable portion of the full solar spectrum, high visible light absorption is critical for achieving high effi ciency cells. Current high efficiency thin-fi lm solar cell absorbers such as CdTe, CIGS and Cu 2 ZnSnSe 4 (CZTSe) have similar chemical characters in their CBs  [20] [21] [22] [23]  as GaAs and thus they have weaker optical absorption above the absorption edge than CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . The strong optical transitions of halide perovskite originate from two key features in halide perovskites: (i) The realization of p-p transition. Sn and Pb are elements that may have n s 2 electron confi gurations, the so called lone-pair s electrons.  [ 24 ]  In halides, these s states will not lose their s electrons and thus the lower parts of the CBs of Sn or Pb halide perovskites are mainly derived from the unoccupied Sn/Pb p orbitals [Figure  S1 ]. The Organic-inorganic hybrid halide perovskites such as CH 3 NH 3 PbX 3 (X = Cl, Br, I), have attracted great attention as absorbers for solar cells.  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9] [10] [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] [16]  Recent reports have shown that these perovskites have very long electron-hole diffusion lengths  [ 15, 16 ]  and a simple planar heterojunction solar cell based on CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3-x Cl x , with the same structure as conventional thin-fi lm solar cells, can have solar-to-electricity conversion efficiencies of over 15 percent.  [ 11 ]  Remarkably, however, the cell has an absorbing perovskite layer as thin as only 330 nm; yet it achieves an open circuit voltage as high as 1.07 V.  [ 11 ]  This performance is comparable to the best single-crystal GaAs and polycrystalline Cu(In,Ga)Se 2 thin-fi lm solar cell and outperforms current polycrystalline thin-fi lm solar cells based on CdTe and Cu 2 ZnSn(Se,S) 4 .  [ 17 ]  In contrast to the rapid increase in effi ciency, the fundamental mechanisms concerning how halide perovskite solar cells can work so well are still unknown. Furthermore, the present effi ciency is still much below the theoretical limit for single-junction solar cell and the guidance to improve solar cell performance is urgently required. Here we show by a systematic theoretical study that halide perovskites exhibit a number of unique properties: (i) Much higher optical absorptions than conventional thin-fi lm solar cell absorber. Ultrahigh optical absorption enables the use of ultrathin absorbers in which photogenerated carriers do not have to travel far before they are collected, and consequently lead to a low non-radiative recombination rate. (ii) Strong s-p anti-bonding coupling, which leads to small effective masses for both electrons and holes. This ensures effi cient solar cells with a p-i-n confi guration. (iii) Dominant shallow point defects. All point defects with low formation energies are found to generate only shallow defect states. (iv) Intrinsically benign grain boundaries (GBs). GBs do not generate any gap states, making polycrystalline halide perovskite thin fi lms single-crystal-like. These superior photovoltaic properties explain the long carrier diffusion length and high effi ciency reported with lead halide perovskites. We further reveal that these unique properties are attributed to the combination of perovskite symmetry and the existence of the lone-pair s orbitals, which enable halide perovskite semiconductors to have direct bandgap p-p transition. The direct bandgap p-p optical transition is generally much stronger than the p-s transition seen in common thin-fi lm solar cell upper VBs are mainly halogen p orbitals mixed with a small component of Pb/Sn s . Therefore, the full occupation of lonepair s orbitals below the valence band maximum (VBM) makes the pp transitions possible. (ii) The direct bandgap. In halide perovskites, the CBM is at the R point due to the p-p coupling in O h symmetry.  [ 25 ]  Meanwhile, the VBM is formed by the antibonding coupling between the lone-pair ns 2 orbitals and the halogen element p orbitals. With a local O h symmetry, such antibonding s-p coupling is particularly strong at the R point and thus results in a direct bandgap at the R point. These two features make halide perovskites direct-gap p-p transition semiconductors. Furthermore, the strong s-p coupling enhances the dispersion of the upper VB [Figure  S1 ] and results in a small effective mass for holes. Our calculated electronic structures are consistent with previous report on halide perovskites.  [ 26, 27 ]  The calculated hole effective masses of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 and CsSnI 3 [Table  S1 ] are much smaller than that of GaAs, CIS, CZTSe, and CdTe whose VBMs have no s-p coupling. The unique small effective masses for both electrons and holes and high absorption coeffi cients make these halide perovskites ideal candidates for solar cells having a p-i-n confi guration. In GaAs, CIS, CZTSe, and CdTe, the effective masses are much larger for holes than for electrons, therefore, solar cells based on these materials rely on the formation of p-n junctions. Our calculated effective mass for CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 is comparable to the previous theoretical results.  [ 28 ]  The optical absorption coeffi cient strongly affects the quantum effi ciency of a solar cell, which is not considered in the well-known Shockley-Queisser limit.  [ 29 ]  For a real solar cell, the theoretical maximum effi ciency depends on the thickness of the absorber layer. After taking the absorption coeffi cient and absorber layer thickness into consideration, we have calculated the maximum effi ciencies of some common light absorbers as a function of the thickness of the absorber layers (shown in Figure  1 d ). The three halide perovskites (CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , CsSnI 3 , and CsPbI 3 ) exhibit much higher conversion effi ciencies than GaAs, CIS and CZTSe for any given thickness. More importantly, the halide perovskites are capable of achieving high effi ciencies with very thin absorber layers. For example, with a 0.3 µm absorber (similar to the thickness of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3-x Cl x in the 15.4% perovskite based cell  [ 11 ]  ), CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 based cells can have a maximum effi ciency up to 21%, while it is only 13% for a GaAs-based solar cell. The results are consistent with many of today's most common thin-fi lm solar cells (GaAs, CdTe, CIGS and CZTSS) -the absorbers must be about 2 µm thick to achieve high effi ciencies.  [ 30 ]  It should be noted that not all p-p optical transitions can result in high optical absorption. For examples, Si has p-p optical transitions, but has an indirect bandgap, and therefore does not have high optical absorption. We fi nd that the perovskite symmetry plays a critical role in establishing strong direct bandgap p-p optical transitions and appropriate bandgaps for solar cell applications. An ideal perovskite structure possesses a local O h symmetry.  [ 31 ]  However, most perovskites exhibit distortions and reduced local symmetries. In order to form a perfect perovskite phase AMX 3 , the bond lengths among the three constituent elements should satisfy a stringent requirement,  [ 32 ]  i.e., the bond length ratio, t = (r A +r X )/ 2(r M +r X ), should be equal to 1. This stringent requirement is often not satisfi edmost cations at A sites are not large enough, leading to buckling and distortion in many perovskite structures. Likewise, the CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite exhibits many distorted phases such as the phases with 3 Pm m, Pbnm , I4/mcm and Pmnb symmetries  [ 31, [33] [34] [35]     S2 ]. The small distortions do not change signifi cantly the electronic properties: such as optical absorption, bandgap, and electron and hole effective masses [Figure  S3 ]. Therefore, these phases still show higher conversion effi ciencies than GaAs. The Pmnb phase, however, has a signifi cant distortion that causes some Pb-I bond breakings. The Pb-I bond breaking weakens the s-p coupling and leads to an increased bandgap (2.31 eV) and heavier hole effective masses. Therefore, our results suggest that to achieve the best effi ciencies, the three-dimensional Pb-I bond framework in AMX 3 perovskites should not been broken. Since it directly affects the performance of solar cells, the structural distortion of halide perovskites deserves further investigation. The distortion in a perovskite can be quantitatively determined by the bond length ratio t . The ratio t for halide perovskites can be tuned in different halide perovskites by choosing the appropriate combination of Sn, Pb, and halogen elements. Figure  2 b  shows clear correlations between perovskite stability and t . Larger t value deviations from 1 have a larger structure distortion. The results suggest that mixing Br and/or Cl with I in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 would help stabilize the perovskite phase, which could partially explain the improvement of cell performance when mixing Cl.  [ 5, 11 ]  Furthermore, proper alloying of Sn and Pb, or/and halogen elements (I, Br, Cl, F) could optimize the bandgaps for solar cell applications. Figure  2  b gives a guideline for engineering the bandgap and phase stability of perovskites to achieve solar cells with improved performance. It is worthy to note that high-concentration alloying may result in the problem of miscibility gap and band gap increase. The actual Cl concentration in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3-x Cl x were reported to be below 4%,  [ 36, 37 ]  even though the ratio in precursor could be 33.3%.  [ 38 ]  The small amount of Cl was believed to dramatically improve the charge transport.  [ 37 ]  The exact effects of small-amount Cl/Br alloying in halide perovskites deserve further investigations. In thin-fi lm solar cells, shallow acceptors (donors) are responsible for p -type ( n -type) doping. However, defects with energy levels deep in the band gaps act as Shockley-Read-Hall non-radiative recombination centers, which are mainly responsible for short minority carrier lifetime, and therefore, low V oc . For The results suggest that the dominant defects in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 are shallow defects. Furthermore, CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 could be grown either n -type or p -type by manipulating the chemical potentials (growth conditions). The detailed point defect properties have been studied in Ref. [ 39 ] . The superior defect properties of halide perovskite are possibly due to the strong sp coupling at VBM. This is similar to the case in CIGS  [ 24 ]  where shallow V Cu dominates the defects and is partially responsible for the higheffi ciency of CIGS-based solar cells. In polycrystalline semiconductor absorbers, GBs also play important roles. In most solar cell absorbers such as GaAs, CIGS, CZTS, and CdTe, intrinsic GBs create deep levels in band gaps and are considered detrimental for solar cell performance.  [ 35, [40] [41] [42]  Surprisingly, however, we fi nd that grain boundaries in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 are intrinsically benign. Figure  4  a shows the atomic structure of a supercell containing two Σ5(310) grain boundaries with the exact same structure in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . We choose Σ5(310) GB because it consists of typical features of GBs in semiconductor, such as wrong bonds, dangling bonds and extra bonds and, therefore, the results are representative. Other GB confi gurations have been explored (e.g., Σ3(111) GB) and have consistently yielded band gaps that are essentially free from defect states.  [ 43 ]  The atomic structure is adopted from the same GB in perovskite SrTiO 3 , whose atomic structure has been determined by atomic-resolution scanning transmission electron microscopy  [ 44 ]  [Figure  S4 ]. The DOS analysis [Figure  4  b] shows that the GBs do not generate any states in the bandgap of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . The benign GB properties could be explained In summary, we have shown that CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 based perovskites exhibit intrinsic properties that are superior for solar cell applications: extremely high optical absorption; small effective masses for electrons and holes; dominant point defects that only generate shallow levels; grain boundaries that are completely benign. These unique properties can be understood from the perovskite symmetry and Pb lonepair 6s orbitals. Our results explain why CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 related materials have long electron-hole diffusion length and their thinfi lm solar cells can achieve high effi ciencies and high open-circuit voltage. These results further point the way towards achieving even higher effi ciencies through metal or/and halogen element alloying. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CsSnI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T03:23:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="901" length="7"/>
        <text>CsSnI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CIS</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T03:23:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="7530" length="3"/>
        <text>CIS</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Methylammonium Lead Iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-26T07:42:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="8623" length="15"/>
        <text>CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CsSnI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T03:23:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="8641" length="7"/>
        <text>CsSnI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CsPbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T03:23:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="8655" length="7"/>
        <text>CsPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15420</offset>
      <text> Experimental Section First-Principles Calculations : The fi rst-principles calculations were carried out by using the VASP code  [ 45 ]  with the standard frozen-core projector augmented-wave (PAW) method. The cut-off energy for basis functions was 400 eV. The general gradient approximation (GGA) method was used. Both spin orbit coupling (SOC)  [ 46 ]  and non-SOC were considered for band structure electron and effective mass calculations. The atomic positions and cell size are fully relaxed for each calculation. The k -points mesh was chosen such that the product of the number of k points and corresponding lattice parameter is at least 30 Å. The bandgaps are corrected to experimental values by the scissor operator. Maximum Solar Cell Effi ciency : The standard AM1.5G solar spectrum at 25 °C is used for simulating the effi ciency.  [ 47 ]  The maximum effi ciency of each absorber material is calculated  [ 48, 49 ]  by considering the optical absorption coeffi cient with improvement on the Shockley-Queisser methods.  [ 29 ]  The short-circuit voltage (J sc ) is calculated by 0 J sc e 0 I sun dE α( ) E ( ) E = ∞ ∫ 0 0 , where α ( E ) is optical absorption coeffi cient at photonic energy E, I sun ( E ) is the sunlight photon fl ux at energy E, and e is the fundamental electron charge. The J-V curve of an ideal p-n junction follows the formula J = J sc -J 0 (1-exp( e V/ k T)).  [ 50, 51 ]  In optimal conditions, the nonradiative electron-hole recombination was  , where I bb ( E , T ) is the black-body spectrum at temperature T. Once we know the optical absorption coeffi cient α ( E ) for a material, its maximum quantum effi ciency could be calculated by numerically maximizing J • V according to J = J sc -J 0 (1exp( e V/ k T)) and dividing the maximized J • V by the total AM1.5G solar power. Ionic Size of CH 3 NH 3 + : The equivalent ionic size of CH 3 NH 3 + can be estimated by using the trend of lattice constants for CH 3 NH 3 MI 3 , where M = Si, Ge, Sn, Pb. Under ideal conditions, the ionic size meets the condition of (r A 1+ + r X 1-)/ 2 (r M 2+ + r X 1-) = 1, and the lattice constant is 2 × (r M 2+ + r X 1-), where r A , r M and r X are the ionic radius for A, M, and X ions. The undersized A atom will decrease the ideal lattice constant and oversized A atom will increase the ideal lattice constant. From Figure  S5 , we can see that the lattice constants of 1+ + r I 1-)/ 2 (r M 2+ + r I 1-) = 1 when 2 ×(r M 2+ + r I 1-) = 6.27 Å and it is calculated that r CH3NH3 1+ is 2.37 Å. The ionic size of other ions are taken from Ref. [ 52 ] . Point Defect Level : For calculating the transition levels of point defect in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , each type of defect is calculated based on a (3 × 3 × 3) supercell based on the 3 Pm m phase with dimension of (19.17 Å × 19.17 Å × 19.17 Å). Only the Γ point is considered in the calculations. The defect formation energy, H f ( ) , a q Δ , can be obtained  [ 53 ]  by: H n qE f i E n F qE ∑ μ , a q ( ) a q , ( ) ΔH ( ) a q , a q + ΔE E ( ) a q a q , + where E E E n E q q i E ∑ ( ) , a q ( ) ( ) a q , ( ) ost ( ) h t ( ) host ( ) i i ΔE ( ) , a q -E (host + E F is referenced to the valence band maximum (VBM) of the host. µ i is the chemical potential of constituent i element as referenced to elemental solid/gas with energy E(i). For CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , we referred the chemical potential of CH 3 NH 3 to CH 3 NH 2 and H 2 gas. n i is the number of elements, and q is the number of electrons transferred from the supercell to the reservoirs. The transition energy for the defect α from the q charge state to the q' charge state, a ε ( ) / q q / , was obtained by / E a ε ( ) / q / ( ) ,q ( ) ( ) , a, ( ) q q ) Δ ( ) ,q ΔE ( , a, ⎡ ⎣ ⎤ ⎦ . Figure S1 :Figure S2 : S1S2 Figure S1: The band structure, total and partial DOS of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . The partial DOS of Pb s has been enlarged by 5 times for clarity. The VBM charge density map clearly shows the antibonding character of VBM through Pb s and I p coupling. The CBM is mainly Pb p. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19487</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 .Figure S4 : S3S4 Figure S3. The band structures of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 at (a) Pm3m, (b) I4/mcm, (c) Pbnm, and (d) Pmnb phases. The band characters of Pm3m phase are kept in distorted I4/mcm and Pbnm phase. In Pmnb phase, some Pb-I bonds are broken and the antibonding between Pb s and I p are weakened. The VBM is lowered and band gap is increased to 2.31 eV. Meanwhile, the hole effective mass increases. The unique features of perovskite phases are destroyed. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19958</offset>
      <text> Figure S5: The equivalent ionic size of CH 3 NH 3+ can be estimated by the trend of lattice constants of CH 3 NH 3 MI 3 , where M=Si, Ge, Sn, Pb. At the ideal condition of perovskite AMX 3 , the ionic size meet the condition of (r A +r X )/ 2 (r M +r X ) = 1. In this case, the ideal lattice constant is 2×(r M +r X ). The undersized A atom will shrink the ideal lattice constant and oversized A atom will expand ideal lattice constant. From this Figure, we can see that the lattice constants of CH 3 NH 3 SiI 3 and CH 3 NH 3 GeI 3 are larger than the ideal lattice constant indicating that (r CH3NH3 + +r I )/ 2 (r Si/Ge +r I ) &gt;1. The lattice constants of CH 3 NH 3 SnI 3 and CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 are smaller than the ideal lattice constants indicating that (r CH3NH3 + +r I )/ 2 (r Sn/Pb +r I ) &lt;1. By linear interpolation methods, we estimate that the equivalent ionic size of CH 3 NH 3 + is 2.37 Å. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20861</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. (a) DOS of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , CsSnI 3 and GaAs. The VBMs are referred to as zero energy and CBMs are marked as dashed lines. (b) The JDOS of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , CsSnI 3 and GaAs. (c) The optical absorptions of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , CsSnI 3 and GaAs. (d) Calculated maximum effi ciencies of halide perovskites, CIS, CZTS, and GaAs as a function of fi lm thickness. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21243</offset>
      <text> [Figure S2], which exhibit diverse optical absorption and carrier effective masses. Their maximum effi ciencies (as a function of fi lm thickness) of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 with different crystal symmetries are shown in Figure 2 a. The effi ciencies for GaAs are included for comparison. We fi nd that the maximum effi ciencies decrease as the symmetry deviates from the perfect perovskite ( 3 Pm m). The I4/mcm and Pbnm phases have relatively small distortions from the perfect 3 Pm m structure and exhibit no bond breaking [Figure &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21771</offset>
      <text> CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 , we have calculated all the possible intrinsic point defects and fi nd that those with low formation energies such as I interstitials (I i ), CH 3 NH 3 molecules on Pb sites (MA Pb ), CH 3 NH 3 vacancies (V MA ), Pb vacancies (V Pb ), CH 3 NH 3 interstitials (MA i ), Pb atoms on CH 3 NH 3 sites (Pb MA ), I vacancies (V I ), and CH 3 NH 3 molecules on I sites (MA I ) have very shallow transition energy levels ( Figure 3 ). The defects with deep transition levels, such as I atoms at CH 3 NH 3 sites (I MA ), I atoms at Pb sites (I Pb ), Pb interstitials (Pb i ), and Pb atoms at I sites (Pb I ) have relatively high formation energies. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22429</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. (a) Calculated maximum effi ciencies of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 at different phases and GaAs as a function of absorber thickness. (b) The correlations between bond length ratio t and the relative stability of I4/mcm CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 with respect to the Pnmb phase (ΔE = E Pnmb -E I4/mcm per formula unit, where E is the total energy. The positive ΔE indicates that the undistorted phase, I4/ mcm, is more stable). The bandgaps for I4/mcm phases are shown in parentheses. MA denotes methylamine ammonia (CH 3 NH 3 ). The ionic sizes from Ref. [ 51 ] are used and listed in TableS2. The ionic size CH 3 NH 3 + was estimated by an interpolation method [FigureS5]. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23108</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (a) The structural model of Σ5(310) GB for CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . Two identical GBs are included the supercell to enable the periodicity. (b) DOS of Σ5(310) GB model shown in (a) with comparison to CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 bulk calculated from the unit cell. (c-f) show the partial DOS of selective atoms in (a). The (partial) DOS are average per atom and (b) and (c) are enlarged twice for clarity. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23521</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Calculated transition energy levels of point defects in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 . The formation energies of neutral defects are shown in parentheses. The acceptors/donors are ordered by the formation energies (from left to right). MA denotes CH 3 NH 3 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23792</offset>
      <text> CH 3 NH 3 SiI 3 and CH 3 NH 3 GeI 3 are larger than the ideal lattice constant indicating that (&gt;1. The lattice constants of CH 3 NH 3 SnI 3 and CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 are smaller than the ideal lattice constants indicating that (r linear interpolation methods, (r CH3NH3 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24059</offset>
      <text>			 15214095, 2014, 27, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/adma.201306281 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24420</offset>
      <text>			 wileyonlinelibrary.com © 2014 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
