<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025051015EIAGFD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_review">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 143&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Supporting Information CuSCN as hole transport material with 3D/2D perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>103</offset>
      <text>We report stable perovskite solar cells having 3D/2D perovskite absorber layers and CuSCN as an inorganic hole transporting material (HTM). (Phenylethyl)ammonium (PEA) and [(4-fluorophenyl)ethyl]ammonium (FPEA) have been chosen as 2D cations, creating thin layers of (PEA) 2 PbI 4 or (FPEA) 2 PbI 4 on top of the 3D perovskite. The 2D perovskite as an interfacial layer, neutralizes defects at the surface of the 3D perovskite absorber, and can protect from moistureinduced degradations. We demonstrate excellent charge extraction through the modified interfaces into the inorganic CuSCN HTM, with device efficiencies above 18%, compared to 19.3% with conventional spiro-OMeTAD. Furthermore, we show significantly enhanced ambient stability.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">copper(I) thiocyanate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:50:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="187" length="5"/>
        <text>CuSCN</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:50:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="768" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>845</offset>
      <text>S5 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>849</offset>
      <text> INTRODUCTION Organic-inorganic metal halide perovskites exhibit fascinating optical and electrical properties and are used in solar cells. Perovskite-based solar cells (PSCs) emerged as promising alternatives toward clean energy production because of their high power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) and low materials and processing cost. Up to now, PCEs as high as 25.2% have been achieved benefiting from morphology and compositional optimization of the perovskite absorber, modification and development of selective contact materials, and the design of innovative device structures and interface engineering.  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5]  The impressive efficiency improvements are, however, overshadowed by the stability issues of hybrid perovskites resulting from thermal impact, oxygen, moisture, and ion migration under illumination.  [6] [7] [8] [9] [10]  This poor stability under standard operation conditions still limits their practical applications and therefore prevents PSCs from entering the solar cell market. State-of-theart 3D perovskite APbX 3 absorbers are usually complicated mixtures including multiple cations (formamidinium (FA), methylammonium (MA), and Cs) and anions (I and Br) for high device performance and stability.  11, 12  To further increase the material stability and prevent ion migration, layered 2D perovskites have recently been developed on top of the pristine 3D perovskite.  13, 14  Recently, Jiang et al.  4  used organic salt PEAI on HC(NH 2 ) 2 -CH 3 NH 3 mixed perovskite film for surface defect passivation which resulted in higher PCE cells (as high as 23.32%) by reducing the defects and suppressing nonradiative recombination. The V OC obtained in this study was 1.18 V, which is 94.4% of the Shockley-Queisser limit V OC (1.25 V). The 2D perovskite will thereby not only act as a passivation layer in the cell structure but also as a protection layer against environmental influences such as moisture. Usually, when in contact with moisture, hybrid perovskites irreversibly decompose into PbI 2 and organic components. Moisture stability can be improved by introducing larger ammonium cations in the perovskite or by surface modification. These large cations consist of a hydrophobic tail that can repel moisture from the perovskite structure. Recent studies have shown that mixing 2D perovskite in bulk may result in higher moisture stability, however at the cost of a lower PCE.  15  This can be explained due to the fact that mixing bigger cations in the perovskite bulk often compromises the tolerance factor, widens the band gap, and lowers charge carrier mobility.  16  On the other hand, placing a hydrophobic 2D perovskite on top of 3D perovskite has shown significant improvement in stability. Furthermore, the passivation of defect states at the perovskite/HTM interface using 2D perovskite cations has even been shown to enhance the device efficiencies further.  14  The 2D perovskite layers are usually chosen to be very thin to not influence the charge extraction in the device. This article is made available for a limited time sponsored by ACS under the ACS Free to Read License, which permits copying and redistribution of the article for non-commercial scholarly purposes. Another source of instability in PSCs is the organic hole transport material; spiro-OMeTAD, which is most commonly used and suffers from low thermal stability. Furthermore, the necessary use of dopants has shown to have negative influence on the device stability.  17  Ideally the organic HTMs are replaced by inorganic materials such as CuSCN, CuI, NiO 2 , or CuO x . CuSCN has the advantage of being an inorganic material that is solution processable and having ideal band alignment with the perovskite. Good power conversion efficiencies have been achieved using CuSCN as a hole extracting layer in PSCs previously.  18, 19  Furthermore, it has been reported that the CuSCN-based PSCs show a better longterm ambient moisture stability than spiro-OMeTAD-based PSC. Chen et al. used an ultrathin 2D perovskite which is (5-AVA) 2 PbI 4 (5-AVA = 5-ammoniumvaleric acid) as a passivation layer between (FAPbI 3 ) 0.88 (CsPbBr 3 ) 0.12 perovskite and CuSCN hole transport layer, which resulted in a PCE of 16.75%.  20  In this work, we have adopted a combinatory approach by employing 2D perovskite materials as passivation layers to enhance the device resistance to moisture and CuSCN as an inorganic HTM to remediate the instability of the solar cells that originates from the usage of spiro-OMeTAD. This approach is able to enhance the device stability while maintaining high power conversion efficiencies of PSCs. We investigated 2D perovskites on the basis of (phenylethyl)ammonium (PEA) and [(4-fluorophenyl)ethyl]ammonium (FPEA) cations. The perovskites were applied as thin layers on top of the Cs-containing triple cation 3D perovskite absorber material. With passivated perovskite layers, we obtained efficiencies up to 19.3% with spiro-OMeTAD and 18% with CuSCN-based devices. Furthermore, we demonstrate significantly enhanced stability of devices having passivated perovskite layers as well as CuSCN. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5996</offset>
      <text> RESULTS AND DISCUSSION Panels a and b of Figure  1  show the schematic device architecture and the corresponding energy level diagram of PSCs investigated in this study. The devices are based on a mesoporous TiO 2 scaffold and triple cation perovskite with a composition of (FAPbI 3 ) 0.77 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.14 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.09 used as absorber material. The perovskite layer is deposited using a one-step spin coating with antisolvent quenching, as reported previously.  11  In this work, we study the efficiency and stability of PSCs when using a thin buffer layer of 2D perovskite at the perovskite/HTM interface, as well as CuSCN as an inorganic hole transport layer. The 2D perovskites were deposited by spin coating PEAI and FPEAI dissolved in isopropanol (15 mg/mL) on top of the perovskite capping layer as described in the Experimental Section. A thin layer of the 2D perovskites (PEA) 2 PbI 4 and (FPEA) 2 PbI 4 respectively is thereby formed on the triple cation perovskite via ion exchange and/or reaction of excess PbI 2 . Figure  1c  shows the cross-sectional SEM micrograph of a device with a thin interlayer of (PEA) 2 PbI 4 . It is evident from the figure that the 2D layer is creating an additional interface between the HTM and the perovskite layer. Devices passivated with FPEA or using CuSCN as an HTM revealed very similar interlayer structures, and their SEM pictures are shown in the Supporting Information (SI; Figure  S1 ). From the SEM images, the thickness of the 2D perovskite is estimated to be less than 50 nm. The CuSCN HTM layer was applied onto the perovskite by spin coating its solution (30 mg/mL) in diethylsulfide. Top-view SEM images of pristine and 2D treated perovskite layers are shown in Figure  2a ,b, respectively. The pristine perovskite reveals the formation of the uniform crystal grains, while for the 2D perovskite treated layers a clear change of the surface morphology can be observed. The 2D perovskite has a platelike morphology and fully covers the underlying 3D absorber layer. The presence of the 2D perovskite could be additionally confirmed by XRD diffraction of thin films (Figure  2c ). PEAI and FPEAI treated samples clearly show the diffraction peaks at low angles corresponding to the respective 2D perovskites as observed for the pure 2D reference sample. Exclusively reflections corresponding to the (00l) crystallographic plane could be observed, suggesting a strong preferred orientation growth of the 2D perovskite, commonly observed in layered structures. Surprisingly we noticed the appearance of an additional set of diffraction peaks (*) corresponding to an enlarged unit cell. We assign these peaks to unreacted PEAI during the isopropanol treatment along with (PEA) 2 PbI 4  4  . The diffraction peaks of the 3D Cs triple cation perovskite, however, remain unchanged before and after the treatment. This strongly suggests that the bulk of the 3D perovskite has not been affected in the multilayer deposition process. Also, the excess lead present in the pristine sample (PbI 2 peak at 12.8°) is no longer present after the treatment, suggesting that it has been reacted with the PEAI and FPEAI respectively to form the 2D perovskites. To further analyze the 3D/2D perovskite interface, we performed photoluminescence (PL) experiments. For this  &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(FAPbI3)0.77(MAPbBr3)0.14(CsPbI3)0.09</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:51:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="6271" length="48"/>
        <text>(FAPbI 3 ) 0.77 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.14 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.09</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenylethylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:52:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="6714" length="4"/>
        <text>PEAI</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">fluorophenylethylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:52:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="6723" length="5"/>
        <text>FPEAI</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>9314</offset>
      <text> ACS Applied Energy Materials Letter purpose; 3D/2D perovskite films with and without HTMs were deposited on plain glass to avoid PL quenching by injection into the conductive substrates. PL measurements from the top surface (Figure  2d ) as well as from the glass side (Figure  S2 ) were measured using an excitation wavelength of 420 nm. The emission of the 2D perovskite could only be observed from the top, confirming that the 2D perovskite is not present in bulk but rather forms on top of the 3D perovskite. Due to the small thickness, the emission of the 2D perovskites around 525 nm (inset in Figure  2d ) is relatively weak compared to the emission of the triple cation perovskite peaking around 790 nm. From the PL emission spectra, the band gap of 3D perovskite is 1.57 eV (∼790 nm), and 2D perovskite is 2.36 eV (∼525 nm). The PL emission of the 3D perovskite is increased approximately by a factor of 2 with the (PEA) 2 PbI 4 2D perovskite present on top. This can be explained by passivation of defects present at the perovskite surface that act as recombination centers. With both spiro-OMeTAD and CuSCN the PL signal at 790 nm is significantly quenched, suggesting an effective injection of holes from the 3D perovskite into the HTM. The purpose of using a thin 2D perovskite buffer layer is 2fold: First, the 2D perovskite layer can passivate the 3D perovskite surface, eliminating defects present at the otherwise perovskite/HTM interface. This is expected to reduce trapassisted charge recombination and thus increase the V OC . On the other hand, the thin 2D perovskite layer is also able to protect the underlying 3D perovskite from external influences such as moisture. The effect of passivation has been described in the literature  14  and could be clearly reproduced in devices having a PEA/spiro-OMeTAD interface with an increase of 63 mV in V OC compared to the reference sample. Surprisingly, using CuSCN along with a 2D perovskite layer seems to have little influence on the V OC . An explanation of this phenomenon could be the wetting on the modified perovskite surface. While small organic molecules such as spiro-OMeTAD are expected to have a good wetting on the organic cations of the 2D perovskites, CuSCN as an inorganic material may experience wettability problems. Such effects may lead to non-uniformity in the HTM layer as well as pinholes. An indication of this effect can be seen from the SEM images (Figure  S1 ), which show a poor interface between the 2D perovskite and CuSCN. Apart from the passivation, the 2D perovskites have been shown to exhibit increased stability compared to their 3D counterparts because the hydrophobic tails of their bulky organic cations act as water repellants. Furthermore, 2D cations can be further tuned by introducing functional groups such as fluorine atoms that increase hydrophobicity. Following this strategy, we investigated both PEA and fluorinated FPEA as 2D perovskite precursors. Our results confirm that two-dimensional layered perovskites such as (PEA) 2 PbI 4 , can be used as a passivation layer, which eventually reduces charge carrier recombination at the interface and, at the same time, facilitates charge transport to the hole transport layer. Defect sites in the region of carrier collection, near the valence and conduction band edges of the 3D perovskite and CuSCN layers interface, are suppressed by passivating 2D layers. One possible explanation is that, due to the thin nature of the 2D film, defects in the 2D layer will recombine with the minority charge carrier, electrons in this case in the 3D film at the interface. Otherwise, these defects act  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12974</offset>
      <text> ACS Applied Energy Materials Letter as active centers for recombination at the 3D perovskite/ CuSCN interface, which reduces the charge transport of holes. This reduces the quenching percentage in the perovskite/ CuSCN interface, as explained in Figure  2 . By introducing the 2D layer between perovskite and HTM, a neutral junction is made for the holes to pass. This process reduces charge carrier recombination at the interface and facilitates transport of selective carriers such as hole majority carriers as substantiated in the higher PL intensity of the 3D/2D perovskite interface. Similarly, SiO 2 acts as a passivation layer in silicon solar cell that reduces the charge carrier recombination.  21  However, in the case of silicon, +ve defects in the SiO 2 layer repel the minority holes and facilitate tunneling of the majority electrons. Effectively, the carriers are tunneled through the passivation layer. To improve the hole transport through 2D perovskite, the defect levels could be slightly below the VBM, and the minority charge carriers are repelled by the defects with the same charge polarity. The JV curves of the 3D/2D perovskite-based champion devices are shown in Figure  3  for both CuSCN and spiro-OMeTAD as HTMs, and their corresponding device parameters are summarized in Table1. Average values are indicated in parentheses. Detailed device statistics are shown in Figure  S6 . The results show that the best 3D reference cell with spiro-OMeTAD delivered a PCE of 18.77%. This value is only slightly higher than the champion cell obtained with CuSCN (18.09%). In general, all CuSCN-based cells show a lower short circuit current (J SC ) and a comparable open circuit voltage (V OC ) with respect to spiro-OMeTAD. With spiro-OMeTAD, PEA passivated devices showed increased efficiencies compared to the reference, while FPEA slightly lowered the solar cell performance. In the case of using CuSCN as HTM, solar cell efficiencies are very similar to and without different 2D perovskite passivation layers. In order to demonstrate the potential of this combinatorial approach of using 3D/2D perovskite absorber layer and CuSCN, we have studied the stability of the devices and the results are shown in Figure  3c . For stability testing, the CuSCN-based devices were kept in the ambient laboratory atmosphere without encapsulation. The relative humidity (RH) varied between 40 and 70% during the period of measurements. The 2D perovskite incorporated devices   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15462</offset>
      <text> ACS Applied Energy Materials Letter showed a remarkable increase in the stability over the reference cell after 400 days, as shown in the graph. The spiro-OMeTAD-based samples show the worst stability and start to drop in efficiency with respect to CuSCN-based devices. Surprisingly, devices with 2D perovskite present at the perovskite/HTM interface initially show a slight increase in efficiency, which is due to an increase in fill factor. An initial increase in efficiency during stability testing of perovskitebased devices has been previously described in the literature.  22.23  All CuSCN-based devices preserve well over 90% of their initial power conversion efficiency after 400 h. The highest stability was found for the sample with the FPEAbased 2D perovskite. This is in agreement with the increased hydrophobicity of FPEA and the therefore increased moisture resistance in ambient conditions. A detailed overview of the device parameters of the 3D/PEA/CuSCN-based cell during the stability measurements can be found in the SI (Figure  S4 ). 2.1. Theoretical Device Analysis for 3D/2D Perovskite Solar Cells with CuSCN. Drift-diffusion simulations for solar cell devices with CuSCN as HTM and 3D/2D perovskites as absorbers are performed to study the efficiency limits of 3D/ 2D solar cell devices. Besides, the impact of 3D/2D interfacial recombination on the device is examined by analyzing the interface defect states and energy barriers. Table  S1  shows the material properties of solar cell device simulation with the FTO/TiO 2 /3D perovskite/2D perovskite/CuSCN/Au architecture. Figure  4a  shows the schematic energy levels, and Figure  4b  shows the J-V curves obtained from the device simulations for the above two cases with 3D perovskite/CuSCN and 3D perovskite/2D perovskite/CuSCN. Under intrinsic radiative recombination limits, 3D perovskite absorber gives about 29.70% PCE. However, by combining both 3D and 2D perovskite absorbers, PCE of 29.43% is realized with J SC and V OC of 28.31 mA/cm 2 and 1.16 V, respectively, as shown by an inset in Figure  4b . This, in principle, shows the potential and practical efficiency limit of 3D/2D perovskite solar cell coupled with CuSCN as an HTM. For complete device fabrication, it is also essential to consider the optimization of thickness for 2D and 3D absorbers. Therefore, to assist experimentalists with thickness management, Figure  4c  shows simulated contours and working space for key electrical parameters as a function of 3D and 2D perovskite absorber geometries. Analysis of the device shows the impact of 3D absorber thickness is more dominant due to the higher absorption in the bulk of 3D absorber primarily because of its near ideal band gap condition, i.e., 1.5 eV, whereas increasing the thickness of 2D perovskite is not found to contribute significantly to the PCE limits due to the large energy band gap of 2.5 eV. In fact, it is desirable to keep the 2D thickness at the realistic minimum because of its low absorption (E g ∼ 2.5 eV) and to decrease any associated transport losses. Certainly, at larger thicknesses, higher PCE is observed due to increased short circuit current and increased light absorption. Since the modeling was performed for radiative limits without considering the extrinsic defects (trap-assisted recombination and impurities in bulk), the difference in V OC , J SC , and fill factor (FF) are not significant. However, in practical experiments, the deposition processes to increase the absorber layer thickness may introduce extrinsic defects, which could reduce the experimental PCE. The simulation results are promising with a potential of 29.41% PCE. While these values may serve as the guideline to approach theoretical limits, it is also imperative to consider the dynamics of the interfacial defects between 3D and 2D perovskite. The extrinsic recombination or trap-assisted Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) defects may deter the quality of the material and eventually the carrier transport. By applying SRH theory, we study the impact of defects on the device performance using energy level of the traps (E T ), capture cross-section area (σ), and interfacial trap density (N T ) as shown in Figure  4d . The contour indicates that even under radiative limits for bulk 2D and 3D, defects at the interface could decrease the PCE from 29.50% to 21.50%. The worst performance is realized under deep level defects around midgap at ΔE T = 0, due to reduced carrier lifetime and associated transport loss. On the contrary, shallow interfacial recombination shows better PCE over a broad range of N T σ product. Therefore, to achieve any improvement in 3D/2D perovskite solar cells, addressing interfacial defects are equally as crucial as the defects in the bulk. More studies are required to understand the electronic properties of layered perovskites concerning their defect energies and band alignment with energy bands of the perovskite and transport layers. Such results can guide us with information about the charge carrier mobilities, transport properties of layered perovskite as interface passivation layers. First-principles atomic-scale calculations of formation energies of different defects, such as vacancies, impurity charge states, and surface dangling bonds defects, in layered perovskite and at interfaces will have to be looked at by keeping an eye on efficient passivation and charge carrier selective possibilities and faster charge transport. Such studies of the layered perovskites and their interface with other layers are critically  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21042</offset>
      <text> ACS Applied Energy Materials Letter important for the enhancement of passivating layer based PSCs with improved performances. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21170</offset>
      <text> SUMMARY In this work, we adopted a combinatory approach of passivating and protecting the perovskite absorber using a thin layer of 2D perovskite as well as using CuSCN as an inorganic HTM. The charge transports along the stacking direction is significantly hindered by the insulating organic layers. We show that using a thin layer of 2D perovskite on top of the 3D perovskite absorber material can improve device stability while maintaining moderately high power conversion efficiency. Efficient charge transfer from the 3D perovskite to the HTM is shown through a thin 2D perovskite layer for both spiro-OMeTAD as well as CuSCN. These findings were confirmed by theoretical calculations using drift-diffusion simulations, which show that a thin layer of a wide band gap has only a minor influence on the device efficiency. On the other hand, theoretical analysis shows that 2D perovskite absorbers themselves are not ideal solar cell materials. An increased open circuit voltage could be observed with a 2D perovskite/spiro interface, indicating the effect of defect passivation. Efficiencies over 18% could be reached using 2D perovskites in combination with CuSCN. We demonstrate that this architecture results in significantly improved device stability. Ambient stability measurements or aging tests show a slowing down of degradation even after 1 year. In conclusion, we present an innovative device architecture combining the use of 2D perovskites as well as CuSCN to improve the stability of PSC significantly. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22692</offset>
      <text> EXPERIMENTAL SECTION 4.1. Materials. The following chemicals were used for preparing the devices and films for characterization: formamidinium iodide (FAI, Greatcell), methylammonium bromide (MABr, Greatcell), lead iodide (PbI 2 , TCI), lead bromide (PbBr 2 , TCI), cesium iodide (CsI, ABCR), (phenylethyl)ammonium iodide (PEAI, Greatcell Solar), [(4-fluorophenyl)ethyl]ammonium iodide (F-PEAI, Greatcell Solar), TiO 2 paste 30 N-RD (Greatcell Solar), copper thiocyanate (CuSCN, 99%, Sigma-Aldrich), and diethyl sulfide (Sigma-Aldrich). 4.2. Perovskite Solar Cell Fabrication. Conductive FTO glass, (NSG-10, Nippon Sheet Glass) was sequentially cleaned with detergent solution, deionized water, and isopropanol. By spray pyrolysis, a compact TiO 2 layer was deposited on the cleaned FTO substrate heated at 450 °C. The precursor solution was prepared by diluting titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) (Sigma-Aldrich) in ethanol (0.2:6 (mL)). After cooling, a mesoporous TiO 2 film was prepared by coating a diluted TiO 2 solution in ethanol (1 mg to 8 mL). Right after spin coating at 4000 rpm for 20 s, the substrates were sintered on a hot plate at 500 °C for 30 min. After the substrates cooled, Li-doping was performed by spin coating a solution of 0.1 M lithium bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimidate (Li-TFSI, Aldrich) in acetonitrile at 3000 rpm for 10 s. The substrates were finally baked at 500 °C for 10 min again and were transferred into a nitrogen-filled glovebox for the perovskite and HTM layer deposition. A triple cation perovskite (FAPbI 3 ) 0.77 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.14 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.09 was prepared by mixing FAI (1.1 mmol), PbI 2 (1.15 mmol), MABr (0.2 mmol), and PbBr 2 (0.2 mmol) in mixed solvent DMF:DMSO = 4:1 (volume ratio) using 5% PbI 2 excess. And a solution of CsPbI 3 (1.15 mmol/ mL) was prepared in DMSO using PbI 2 and CsI as precursors. The two (FAPbI 3 ) 0.85 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.15 and CsPbI 3 solutions were mixed in 10 vol % ratio to get the final solution with a stoichiometry of (FAPbI 3 ) 0.77 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.14 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.09 . The perovskite layers were fabricated by a single-step spin coating procedure based on the antisolvent addition previously reported by Seok et al.  24  In short, the precursor solution is spun at 4000 rpm for 40 s, with an acceleration of 2000 rpm for 30 s, and 10 s prior to the end, 100 μL of chlorobenzene was added onto the spinning film to obtain dense pinhole-free perovskite layers. The finished films were annealed at 100 °C for 1 h. For forming an additional 2D perovskite film on top of this perovskite film, cooled substrates were treated with a PEAI or FPEAI isopropanol solution. For deposition, 100 μL of PEAI (or FPEAI) solution (15 mg/mL) was spin coated according to ref 17 onto the asprepared perovskite films at 4000 rpm, similar to the antisolvent dropping method followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. As HTM, either a thin film of CuSCN or standard spiro-OMeTAD was deposited on top of the perovskite. For the CuSCN deposition, a solution containing 30 mg/mL CuSCN in diethyl sulfide was stirred overnight and spin coated at 2000 rpm for 30 s. For comparison, spiro-OMeTAD was used as a reference HTM material. Spiro-OMeTAD was applied from a 60 mM solution in chlorobenzene using tert-butylpyridine, Li-TFSI, and FK209 co-dopant as additives, as described elsewhere.  25  Finally, the top contact was prepared by thermal evaporation of 80 nm gold using a shadow mask. 4.3. Characterizations. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images were taken with a FEI Teno SEM equipped with an upper inlens detector (T2) operated at 5 keV and 0.4 nA at a working distance of 4 mm. The thickness of the films was measured using a stylus profilometer (Bruker). The X-ray diffraction pattern was recorded on a Bruker D8 Advance diffractometer. The photovoltaic device performance was analyzed using a xenon lamp-based Class AAA solar simulator (Newport) producing 1 sun AM 1.5G (100 mW/cm 2 ) sunlight. Current-voltage curves were measured in air with a potentiostat (Keithley). The light intensity was calibrated with an NREL certified KG5 filtered Si reference diode. The solar cells were masked with a metal aperture of 0.16 cm 2 to define the active area. The current-voltage curves were recorded by scanning at 20 mV s -1 . Absorption spectra were measured on a PerkinElmer UV-vis spectrophotometer Lambda 950s. For measuring the photoluminescence (PL), layers were deposited on glass substrates under the same conditions as those for device preparation, followed by PMMA encapsulation for isolating the films from atmospheric conditions during measurement. PL emission spectra were recorded by exciting the perovskite films at 420 or 550 nm using a Horiba Fluorolog 3 spectrofluorometer. The unencapsulated devices were stored at ambient laboratory conditions and measured stability. 4.4. Simulation Study. Drift-diffusion simulations for solar cells are performed to examine the potential of 3D/2D perovskite with CuSCN as hole transport material. Solar cell capacitance simulator (SCAPS)  26  is used for simulations which are capable of solving Poisson's, transport, and continuity models for solar cells. Two important n-i-p configurations were examined to study the impact on short circuit current, open circuit voltage, fill factor, and power conversion efficiency: 1. FTO/TiO 2 /3D perovskite/CuSCN/Au 2. FTO/TiO 2 /3D perovskite/2D perovskite/CuSCN/Au Incident power is considered as 100 mW/cm 2 from the global AM 1.5 spectrum which is directed from the FTO side. For simulations, 2D perovskite data are extracted from refs 15 and 27, whereas 3D measurements are obtained from refs 28 and 29. The input parameters for CuSCN are obtained from the current experimental measurements. To assess the theoretical efficiency limits of the proposed device architecture, only intrinsic band-to-band radiative recombination is considered for perovskite absorbers. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28642</offset>
      <text> ■ ASSOCIATED CONTENT &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28667</offset>
      <text> * S Supporting Information The Supporting Information is available free of charge at  https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsaem.9b01692 . Additional data in the form of SEM images, PL/UV-vis spectra, XRD patterns, stability plots, device statistics, images, and experimental parameters for the SCAPS simulation (PDF) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28984</offset>
      <text> ACS Applied Energy Materials Letter Figure S1 : S1 Figure S1: SEM Cross-section of 3D/2D perovskite solar cells based on CuSCN and Spiro-OMeTAD HTMs. The solar cell structure is FTO/c-TiO2/mp-TiO2/3D perovskite/2D perovskite/HTM/Au. Solar cells based on (a) 3D/CuSCN (b) 3D/FPEA 2D perovskite /CuSCN (c) 3D/Spiro and (d) 3D perovskite/FPEA 2D perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29354</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 :Figure S4 :Figure S5 : S3S4S5 Figure S3: (a) UV-VIS spectra of the 3D, 2D and 3D/2D perovskite layers on glass substrates. (b) XRD patterns of the FPEA-based 3D/2D perovskite layers on glass substrates. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29570</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 : S6 Fig. S6: Statistical data of devices produced with both spiro-OMeTAD and CUSCN as HTM. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29672</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. (a) Schematic device architecture and (b) a drawing of the energy levels through various layers of the device including 3D perovskite/2D perovskite/CuSCN/gold. (c) Cross-sectional SEM image of the device. Different colors are used to distinguish between the different cell components. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29982</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. (a, b) SEM surface morphology of 3D perovskite and 2D perovskite on top of 3D perovskite. (c) XRD patterns of the 3D/2D and 2D perovskites on glass substrates. (d) PL emission data of the 3D, 3D/2D, 3D/CuSCN, and 3D/2D/CuSCN layers on glass substrates. Spectra are recorded from the top of the film side. The peak at around 525 nm verifies the presence of 2D perovskite (inset of panel d). Also, the PL signal shows increased PL intensity for the 3D/2D layer with respect to the 3D layer, indicating the better quality of material and signatures of passivation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30569</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. J-V measurements of different 2D cation-based perovskite solar cells. (a) J-V data of champion devices from 3D/CuSCN, 3D/PEA/ CuSCN, and 3D/FPEA/CuSCN. (b) J-V data of champion devices from 3D/spiro-, 3D/PEA/spiro-, and 3D/FPEA/spiro-based devices. (c) Ambient laboratory stability data. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30882</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (a) Energy band schematic of 3D and 3D/2D perovskite solar cells with the interface. (b) J-V curves simulated for two cases of 3D and 3D/2D perovskites-based solar cells. The inset table shows the key parameters achievable by the examined device architectures. (c) Absorber thickness optimization for FTO/TiO 2 /3D perovskite/ 2D perovskite/CuSCN/Au under radiative limits. Color contour shows the values of PCE. (d) Impact of 3D/2D interfacial defects on the PCE. Here the x-axis shows the product of interfacial traps, N T (1/cm 2 ), and capture cross-section area, σ (cm 2 ), whereas the y-axis shows the trap level relative to the middle of interface gap, ΔE T . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31576</offset>
      <text> Table S1 : S1 Properties of charge transport layers in 3D/2D perovskite solar cell device used for theroterical Device Layers Device Layer Properties Unit TiO 2 3D Perovskite 2D Perovskite CuSCN Thickness nm 20 1000 100 50 Energy Gap eV 3.26 1.5 2.5 3.4 Electron Affinity Energy eV 4.2 3.9 2.8 1.9 Electron Mobility cm 2 /V.s 100 10 1 100 Hole Mobility cm 2 /V.s 25 10 1 25 Acceptor Concentration 1/cm 3 0 1.0E+09 5.0E+16 1.0E+18 Donor Concentration 1/cm 3 1.0E+17 1.0E+09 1.0E+09 0 CB effective density of states 1/cm 3 2.0E+17 2.7E+18 5.6E+17 2.2E+18 VB effective density of states 1/cm 3 6.0E+17 3.9E+18 1.2E+18 1.8E+18 Dielectric Permittivity 10 10 25 10 performance analysis S6 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32261</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 Summary of Power Conversion Efficiencies of Different 3D and 3D/2D Cations-Based Champion Perovskite Solar Cells CuSCN 3D 18.09 (15.83) 1130 (1059) 21.26 (20.95) 75.3 (70.1) 3D/PEA 18.01 (14.79) 1102 (1064) 21.60 (20.34) 75.6 (68.2) 3D/FPEA 18.03 (16.41) 1085 (1083) 21.91 (20.72) 75.9 (72.5) spiro-OMeTAD 3D 18.77 (17.58) 1088 (1090) 22.37 (21.91) 77.1 (73.6) 3D/PEA 19.30 (16.81) 1151(1135) 22.30 (21.48) 75.2 (68.9) 3D/FPEA 17.66 (17.28) 1099 (1090) 22.39 (22.31) 71.8 (70.1) a device PCE (%) V OC (mV) J SC (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) a Average values are indicated in parentheses. Both CuSCN-and spiro-OMETAD-based devices are fabricated for comparison. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">copper(I) thiocyanate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:54:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="32387" length="5"/>
        <text>CuSCN</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">18.09</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:57:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="32396" length="5"/>
        <text>18.09</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.130</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:57:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="32410" length="4"/>
        <text>1130</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenylethylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:56:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="32451" length="3"/>
        <text>PEA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">18.01</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:58:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="32455" length="5"/>
        <text>18.01</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.102</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:58:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="32469" length="6"/>
        <text>1102 (</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">fluorophenylethylammonium iodide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:55:53Z</infon>
        <location offset="32510" length="4"/>
        <text>FPEA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">18.03</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:00:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="32515" length="5"/>
        <text>18.03</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.085</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:00:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="32529" length="4"/>
        <text>1085</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:54:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="32567" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">18.77</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:57:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="32583" length="5"/>
        <text>18.77</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.088</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:57:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="32597" length="4"/>
        <text>1088</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.30</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:58:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="32642" length="5"/>
        <text>19.30</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.151</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:59:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="32656" length="4"/>
        <text>1151</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.66</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:00:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="32701" length="5"/>
        <text>17.66</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.099</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:00:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="32715" length="4"/>
        <text>1099</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">performance_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:58:10Z</infon>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">performance_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T11:59:27Z</infon>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R3">
        <infon key="type">performance_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:00:32Z</infon>
        <node refid="6" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32925</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:52:26 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33116</offset>
      <text>			 ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2020, 3, 114-121</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
