<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025026123EEEBED</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 21&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Electronic Supplementary Information An Interface Stabilized Perovskite Solar Cell with High Stabilized Efficiency and Low Voltage Loss&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>148</offset>
      <text>Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>157</offset>
      <text> Chemicals Fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO) were purchased from Pilkington (TEC8). Titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution (75 wt. % in isopropanol), DMF, DMSO, diethyl ether, chlorobenzene, chloroform, isopropyl alcohol, Lithium Bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide salt (Li-TFSI), and 4-tert-butylpyridine (tBP) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. TiO 2 paste (SC-HT040) was purchased from ShareChem. 2,2',7,7'-Tetrakis(N,N -di-p -methoxyphenylamino)-9,9'-spirobifluorene (Spiro-OMeTAD, LT-S922) and Tris(2-(1H -pyrazol-1-yl)-4-tertbutylpyridine)-cobalt(III)Tris(bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide)) salt (Co(III) TFSI) were purchased from Lumtec. Methylammonium chloride (MACl) was purchased from Dyenamo. Formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium bromide (MABr), n-butylammonium bromide (C 4 Br), n-hexylammonium bromide (C 6 Br), and n-octylammonium bromide (C 8 Br) were purchased from GreatCell Solar. Lead iodide (PbI 2 ) and lead bromide (PbBr 2 ) were purchased from TCI America. Au pellets were purchased from Kurt J. Lesker. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1204</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication FTO substrates were cleaned by sonicating in deionized water, acetone, and isopropyl alcohol for 10 min each. A blocking TiO 2 layer was deposited via spray pyrolysis using a 20 mM titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution at 450 °C. A mesoporous TiO 2 layer was deposited by spin coating a TiO 2 paste and was sintered at 500 °C for 2 hrs. A Li-TFSI solution (45 mg/mL in acetonitrile) was spin coated onto the TiO 2 layer and heat treated at 500 °C for 2 hrs. The FTO/TiO 2 substrate was plasma treated to make the surface hydrophilic before pumping it into a nitrogen glovebox. The (FAPbI 3 ) 0.92 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.08 perovskite solution (1.53 M PbI 2 , 1.4 M FAI, 0.11 M MAPbBr 3 , 0.5 M MACl in DMF:DMSO=8:1 volume ratio) was spin coated at 1000 rpm for 10 sec and 5000 rpm for 30 sec onto the FTO/TiO 2 substrate. 10 seconds into the 5000 rpm setting, 600 µL of diethyl ether was deposited and the FTO/TiO 2 /perovskite sample was heat treated at 150 °C for 10 min. For in-situ LP synthesis, a solution of LP precursors (10 mM in chloroform or IPA) was deposited and spin coated at 5000 rpm for 30 sec on the FTO/TiO 2 /perovskite sample, followed by heat treatment at 100 °C for 5 min (Note: our additional solubility testing showed that LP precursors are not soluble in chlorobenzene, 1,2dichlorobenzene, and toluene). The hole transporting layer (HTL) was deposited by preparing the HTL solution consisting of 50 mg of Spiro-OMeTAD, 19.5 µL of tBP, 5 µL of Co(III) TFSI solution (0.25 M in acetonitrile), 11.5 µL of Li-TFSI solution (1.8 M in acetonitrile), and 547 µL of chlorobenzene. 70 µL of the HTL solution is loaded onto the perovskite substrate and spin coated at 4000 rpm for 20 sec with the ramp of 2000 rpm/sec. The HTL solution preparation and deposition is performed inside a nitrogen glovebox. The Au electrode (100 nm) was deposited by thermal evaporation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3126</offset>
      <text> Device Characterization Current density-voltage (J-V) curves were recorded using a solar simulator (Newport, Oriel Class A, 91195A) and a source meter (Keithley 2420). The illumination was set to AM 1.5G and calibrated to 100 mW/cm 2 using a calibrated silicon reference cell. The step voltage is 10 mV and the delay time is 50 ms. The active area was controlled by using a dark mask with an aperture of 0.095 cm 2 (used at both Newport and at MIT). For the stability measurement, the devices were encapsulated and tested under AM 1.5G and 100 mW/cm 2 in an ambient condition. The MPP was measured via perturb and observe algorithm implemented onto a custom LabView code. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3800</offset>
      <text> Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM) and X-ray Diffraction (XRD) The SEM images were recorded using a Zeiss Merlin High-resolution SEM and the XRD patterns were collected using a Rigaku SmartLab and a Bruker D8 Discovery Diffractometer with a General Area Detector Diffraction System. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4085</offset>
      <text> AFM and KPFM AFM measurements were performed with a Cypher S (Asylum Research). Topography images were collected using an uncoated silicon tip at a resonant frequency of 300 kHz and a spring constant of 26 N/m in tapping mode. All images are shown with line-wise flattening to remove tilting effects of the substrate plane. Root mean square (RMS) values were determined by 20 x 20 µm 2 images. Kelvin probe force measurements were performed with a MFP-3D AFM (Asylum Research) in air. PtIr and electrilevers were employed at a lift height of 25 nm and with a 3 V AC bias applied to the tip to induce an electrostatic force between the tip and sample. The surface potential difference between the tip and sample is regarded as the DC bias applied to the tip in order to null the tip oscillations. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4884</offset>
      <text> Ultraviolet Photoelectron Spectroscopy (UPS) UPS was conducted in an Omicron ultrahigh vacuum (UHV) system with base pressure of approximately 1e-10 mbar. Perovskite films prepared on un-patterned ITO-coated glass were grounded to steel UPS sample plates via carbon tape and subsequently loaded from air into the UHV system. Measurements were carried out at a pressure of approximately 1e-7 mbar and sample bias of -5.0V, under excitation from the He I line (21.22eV) of a helium discharge lamp. Spectra were collected using a constant analyzer energy of 5eV, step size of 20 meV, and step delay of 20ms and were calibrated to the Fermi edge of a thermally-evaporated Au sample. Cutoff energies were found by intersecting a linear fit of each cutoff region with a linear extrapolation of the corresponding baseline. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5702</offset>
      <text> Time Resolved Photoluminescence (TRPL) Photoluminescence lifetimes were collected using a 532 nm picosecond pulsed diode laser (Picoquant; LDH-P-FA-266) adjusted to a repetition rate of 200kHz using a pulse generator (Stanford Research; DG535). The laser was set to an average power of 0.2μW using neutral density filters and focused to a 150 μm spot on the perovskite film. The emission from the film was collected and collimated using an off-axis parabolic mirror (Thorlabs; MPD269V) and measured with a silicon single-photon avalanche diode (SPAD) detector (Micro Photon Devices; $PD-100-C0C). Scattered laser excitation was suppressed using a 532 nm notch filter (Chroma; ZET532NF) and a 550 nm longpass filter (Thorlabs; FELH0550). The 532 nm laser harmonic was suppressed using a 900 nm shortpass filter (Thorlabs; FESH0900). Photon arrival times were recorded using a time-correlated single photon counting card (Picoquant; PicoHarp 300) and all analysis was performed in Matlab. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6693</offset>
      <text> Electroluminescence (EL) efficiency measurements EL efficiency is measured in a nitrogen filled glovebox under ambient conditions in the dark. The device is voltage driven, and current is measured simultaneously by a Keithley 2636A sourcemeter. Photocurrent is collected using a calibrated Newport 818-UV/DB Silicon photodetector coupled to a Newport 1835-C Multifunction Optical meter. EL spectra are collected using an Ocean Optics USB 2000 spectrometer using a multimode fiber positioned over the center of the active area. As the device area (~0.32cm2) is comparable to the photodetctor active area, the photodetector surface is positioned such that the active area is 17.0 mm from the top surface of the device. To prevent collection of waveguided emission, a black plastic baffle surrounds the edge of the device. We measured the emission profile to be approximately Lambertian (Extended Data Figure  9 ) and applied an appropriate multiplicative geometric factor to the photocurrent value collected. EQE and radiance values are then obtained by scaling the corrected photocurrent values with the photodetector responsivity and EL spectrum. Note that the detector responsivity is relatively flat in the emission region and the observed variation in the EL spectra will account for a negligibly small variation in EQE. Current density and radiance values are calculated assuming the device active area is equal to the gold top contact area. It is found that a sweep rate below 20mV/s is required for the EL to stabilize. The I-V-Photocurrent sweep is run by a custom Labview code.     The band diagrams depicted in Extended Data Figure  8c -f to provide an explanation of the observed kinetics in the TRPL traces and the observed increased device performance. The 3D-control structure (Extended Data Figure  8c ) depicts the band diagram and the observed recombination pathways based on TRPL measurements. The observed radiative rate, k R (3D), is faster than the known intrinsic carrier lifetime in 3D perovskite thin films, likely due to the presence of non-radiative recombination pathways, k NR (3D), associated with the surface. When a LP layer is deposited on the 3D perovskite (Extended Data Figure  8d ), TRPL measurements observed with excitation from the 3D perovskite side show an increase in carrier lifetimes, k R1 (3D/LP), compared to the 3D control perovskite. On the other hand, the lifetime trace shows a relatively fast component, k R2 (3D/LP), when the 3D/LP is excited from the LP side, in addition to the long component (Extended Data Figure  7a ). This behavior of different lifetime profiles depending on the excitation side is not observed in the 3D control perovskite where the lifetime traces are almost identical for both film and substrate excitation. We identify the LP interlayer as a passivating layer that minimizes surface/interface trap states that otherwise would serve as nonradiative recombination centers. The additional passivation results in an increase in carrier lifetimes and the increase in detected photons. Furthermore, we hypothesize that the fast radiative component, k R2 (3D/LP), is due to a carrier buildup at the 3D/LP interface from band bending, which is supported by the UPS results. This carrier accumulation can contribute to the    without a UV-filter. The PSC shows an initial PCE of 22.6% and maintained 85% of its efficiency after 500 hrs. The device is encapsulated and measured in ambient condition. Fig Fig. S1 a, Photograph of vials containing the LP precursor C 6 Br in chlorobenzene (CB), 1,2- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10261</offset>
      <text> Fig S2 a , a Fig S2 a, UVVis of 3D perovskite dipped in IPA (left) and CF (right). The UVVis of perovskite &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10370</offset>
      <text> Fig S4 a , a Fig S4 a, Planar SEM images of 3D, 3D/LP (IPA), and 3D/LP (CF) perovskites where C 6 Br was &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10477</offset>
      <text> Fig S7 a , a Fig S7 a, TRPL traces of 3D and 3D/LPs on quartz substrates. "Film" indicates that the sample &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10586</offset>
      <text> Fig S8 a , a Fig S8 a, UPS spectra of 3D and three different 3D/LP substrates. b, Summary of energy levels &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10695</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig S9 a, J-V curves of 3D and 3D/LP representative PSCs showing reduced hysteresis for LP &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10792</offset>
      <text> Fig S10 a , a Fig S10 a, Plot of current density, EQE, and radiance as a function of voltage from the 3D &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10899</offset>
      <text> Fig S11 a , a Fig S11 a, Normalized PCE as a function of storage time for 3D and 3D/LP PSCs. The devices &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11006</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig S14 a, 3D/LP PSC device results on the same pad on two consecutive days (measurement at</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
