<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025032510IBGCBF</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 53&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Metastable Dion-Jacobson 2D structure enables efficient and stable perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>102</offset>
      <text>The performance of three-dimensional (3D) organic-inorganic halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) can be enhanced through surface treatment with 2D layered perovskites that have efficient charge transport. We maximized hole transport across the layers of a metastable Dion-Jacobson (DJ) 2D perovskite that tuned the orientational arrangements of asymmetric bulky organic molecules. The reduced energy barrier for hole transport increased out-of-plane transport rates by a factor of 4 to 5, and the power conversion efficiency (PCE) for the 2D PSC was 4.9%. With the metastable DJ 2D surface layer, the PCE of three common 3D PSCs was enhanced by approximately 12 to 16% and could reach approximately 24.7%. For a triple-cation-mixed-halide PSC, 90% of the initial PCE was retained after 1000 hours of 1-sun operation at ~40°C in nitrogen. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>942</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>952</offset>
      <text>P erovskite solar cells (PSCs) are a promising photovoltaic (PV) technology, and certified power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) as high as 25.5% have been reported  (1) . Despite this high performance, device stability hinders their commercialization. Efforts to improve device stability include defect passivation, contact layer modification, and encapsulation  (2) (3) (4) (5) . The use of two-dimensional (2D) perovskite as the interfacial modification layer has great potential for addressing surface defects, in particular to improve the stability and efficiency of PSCs  (6) (7) (8) . The Ruddlesden-Popper (RP) 2D layered perovskites that are based on bulky cations, such as phenethylammonium (PEA + ) or butylammonium (BA + ), have been widely applied to the surface of 3D perovskite thin films to decrease defect densities and enhance device stability  (8) (9) (10) (11) . Such bulky organic cations often self-assemble into a barrier layer that protects against surface water adsorption or ingress. However, bulky-cation-based 2D structures often exhibit anisotropic and poor charge transport across the organic layer and are susceptible to charge-extraction barrier formation that inhibits efficient device operation  (12) (13) (14) . We show a rational design strategy to maximize the out-of-plane hole transport based on a metastable Dion-Jacobson (DJ) 2D perovskite surface layer with a reduced transport energy barrier by using asymmetric bulky organic molecules, leading to highly efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Our general design strategy to maximize the out-of-plane charge transport in 2D perovskites is illustrated in Fig.  1 . Because the free electrons and holes are localized in the conduction band minimum (CBM) and valence band maximum (VBM) of the [PbI 6 ] planes, respectively, and because of the long distance between two adjacent [PbI 6 ] planes, the out-of-plane charge transport must traverse the bulky cationic organic layers. Thus, it is mainly limited by two factors: (i) the low carrier mobility within the organic layer and (ii) the energy barrier between the [PbI 6 ] planes and the bulky organic cations. To mitigate the first limit, DJ 2D structures based on a short and single layer of divalent organoammonium cations  (15) (16) (17) (18)  are generally more preferable than the RP 2D structures based on double layers of monovalent organoammonium cations  (19) . To mitigate the second limiting factor, the band offsets between the [PbI 6 ] planes and the bulky cationic organic layers need to be optimized. The coupling (interaction) between [PbI 6 ] planes and the organic cations is through hydrogen bonding, and the change in the bonding strength can affect the band offsets  (20) . For a weaker hydrogen bonding configuration, the bonding states of the bulky organic layers are normally at a higher energy position, which brings them nearer the VBM of the [PbI 6 ] planes (Fig.  1A ). This effect leads to a smaller band offset or barrier for hole transport between the [PbI 6 ] inorganic planes and organic cations. Because of the spinorbital coupling of Pb 6p orbitals, the antibonding states of the organic layers are much higher than the CBM of the [PbI 6 ] planes. Thus, a DJ structure with weaker hydrogen bonding should improve hole transport. Yet, a weaker hydrogen bonding (or H-bonding) configuration generally means a less stable structure. Thus, a metastable DJ 2D structure with short cationic organic layers could in principle facilitate out-of-plane hole transport. A rational strategy to induce the desired metastable H-bonding motifs in DJ 2D structures is to use asymmetric diammonium cations in lieu of symmetric straight chain divalent  cations. For example, both N,N-dimethyl-1,3propane diammonium (DMePDA 2+ ) and 1,4butane diammonium (BDA 2+ ) form DJ 2D structures with short interlayer distances  (19) . Whereas BDA 2+ is symmetric and features two terminal primary ammonium ions on the butyl (C4) chain, DMePDA 2+ is asymmetric, with a primary ammonium on one end and a dimethyl-substituted tertiary ammonium on the other end of the propyl (C3) chain. The "head or tail" H-bonding options for the DMePDA 2+ molecules are asymmetric, giving rise to different possible relative orientations of the adjacent molecules, and the different H-bonding interactions possible within the [PbI 6 ] planes could lead to both stable and metastable energy polymorphs of the 2D structure (Fig.  1B ). The alternating relative head-to-tail alignment of adjacent DMePDA 2+ cations (most stable orientation configuration) provides a larger compensation for overall structural relaxation than those of other orientation arrangements. By contrast, the symmetric BDA 2+ molecule has only one possible orientation configuration (Fig.  1B ) and cannot form metastable polymorphs. We further examined single-crystal 2D DJ structures from BDAI 2 and DMePDAI 2 and conducted first-principle calculations to verify our design strategy. We found that 1,3-propane diammonium diiodine (PDAI 2 )-which is often assumed the shortest diamine  (15, 21)  to form DJ 2D perovskites-templated Pb-I to a non-perovskite structure (empirical formula:  S1  and table  S1 ). Thus, BDA 2+ represents the shortest linearalkyl-chain diamine that forms an iodide-based 2D DJ structure (BDAPbI 4 ) (fig.  S2A  and table  S2 ). C3-based DMePDAI 2 with two methyl groups attached to one side of PDA can form 2D DJ structures with two polymorphs, which we refer to as DMePDAPbI 4 -1 (fig.  S2B  and table  S3 ) and DMePDAPbI 4 -2, respectively (fig.  S2C )  (22) . [PDAPbI 4 ] 15 •[PDAI 2 ]) (fig. We grew the DMePDAPbI 4 -1 single crystal, which was based on the most stable DMePDA 2+ orientation alignment, from a concentrated hydroiodic acid solution using a slow-crystallization process, as adapted from our previous report  (23)  and consistent with a previous theoretical predication  (24) . By contrast, the DMePDAPbI 4 -2 single crystal, which was based on a metastable orientational alignment, was formed from either a fast cooling  (22)  or antisolvent quenching during singlecrystal growth  (25) , both of which represent a fast-crystallization process. In comparison with DMePDAPbI 4 -1, DMePDAPbI 4 -2 had an emission wavelength that was red-shifted ~25 nm, which is consistent with the corresponding absorption data (fig.  S3 ). The average interlayer distances were comparable among these 2D structures (~10.10 to 10.39 Å), with that of BDAPbI 4 being the shortest. The corresponding hydrogen-bonding configurations for these three single-crystal structures (figs. S4, S5, and S6) were consistent with the analysis in Fig.  1B . We confirmed our design strategy by means of density functional theory (DFT) calculation.   We calculated the effect of organic molecules using the screened hybrid functional and van der Waals (vdW) interaction (HSE+vdW)  (26, 27) . The DMePDAPbI 4 -2 structure was indeed less stable than the DMePDAPbI 4 -1 structure. The energy level differences of the organic cations in BDAPbI 4 , DMePDAPbI 4 -1, and DMePDAPbI 4 -2 could be seen in the total density of states (DOSs) of the organic cations (the sum of states of C, N, and H atoms) (Fig.  1C ). The total DOS of BDA 2+ cations in BDAPbI 4 was lower in energy (farther from VBM) than that of DMePDA 2+ cations in DMePDAPbI 4 -1, which in turn was lower in energy compared with the total DOS of DMePDA 2+ cations in DMePDAPbI 4 -2. Thus, we expected the outof-plane hole transport to improve from BDAPbI 4 to DMePDAPbI 4 -2. Rapid perovskite film growth conditions from standard solution deposition also led to the formation of the metastable DMeP-DAPbI 4 -2 structure. The XRD patterns of the DMePDAPbI 4 thin film prepared by means of spin coating are shown in Fig.  2A . The powder XRD pattern measured from DMePDAPbI 4 -1 and DMePDAPbI 4 -2 single-crystal samples, along with the calculated powder XRD patterns shown in Fig.  2A  for comparison, revealed the differences of XRD patterns between these two single crystals. The XRD pattern of the thin-film sample matched that of the DMePDAPbI 4 -2 structure. A metastable polymorph does not mean it is unstable under synthetic or ambient conditions. The phase transformation between polymorphs requires 180°rotation of the alkyl chain, which is highly energetically unfavorable (Fig.  2B ) (figs. S7 and S8). A wide range of thin-film growth conditions from solution all formed DMePDAPbI 4 -2 thin films (fig.  S9 ). To test our hypothesis that the reduced energy barrier from the asymmetric bulky organic cation layer could facilitate charge transport between inorganic [PbI 6 ] sheets, we conducted time-resolved microwave conductivity (TRMC) measurements along the out-of-plane direction  (28) . In Fig.  2C , we compare the normalized TRMC results between several n = 1 2D perovskite thin films calibrated by their corresponding internal quantum yield of charges measured in devices. The out-of-plane transport for DMePDAPbI 4 (or more specifically, DMePDAPbI 4 -2) is about a factor of 4 to 5 faster than that of BDAPbI 4 , despite the slightly longer interlayer distance. Space-charge-limited current (SCLC) measurements further verified that the DMeP-DAPbI 4 -2 structure had faster out-of-plane hole transport than that of the DMePDAPbI 4 -1 structure (fig.  S10 ). These results confirmed the role of reducing the energy barrier for improving out-of-plane charge transport. The out-of-plane transport for the two 2D DJ structures (DMePDAPbI 4 and BDAPbI 4 ) was faster than those of the two 2D RP structures (BA 2 PbI 4 and PEA 2 PbI 4 ). These TRMC results were consistent with the current density-voltage (J-V) results of PSCs on the basis of the corresponding n = 1 2D structures (Fig.  2D  and table  S4 ). The DMePDAPbI 4 -based PSC reached a PCE of 4.90% (forward scan) and 4.33% (reverse scan), which is among the highest obtained thus far for any n = 1 2D lead iodide-based PSCs (6); the corresponding external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum is shown in fig.  S11 . The use of 2D systems to passivate defects and enhance performance has recently been used in many polycrystalline PV technologies  (29) . We validated the impact of this metastable design motif with the use of DMePDAPbI 4 as a surface layer to improve the quality of 3D perovskite absorbers. We spin-coated the corresponding bulky organic halide salt in isopropanol (IPA) solution on top of a 3D perovskite absorber layer  (6) . Specifically, the DMePDAI 2 /IPA solution was coated atop (FAPbI 3 ) 0.85 (MAPbI 2 Br) 0.1 (CsPbI 3 ) 0.05 (or FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 ) followed by annealing, where FA is formamidinium and MA is methylammonium. The thin-film XRD  results suggested that the DMePDAPbI 4 -2 structure formed, as evidenced by the characteristic low-angle diffraction peak, at ~8.5°f or DMePDAPbI 4 -2, rather than ~8.7°for DMePDAPbI 4 -1 (Fig.  3A ). We also checked the 2D structures on top of three other common perovskite compositions of Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 PbI 3 , (FAPbI 3 ) 0.95 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.05 , and FAPbI 3 (fig.  S12 ). For these compositions, the characteristics peaks at (002), (004), and (006) matched well to DMePDAPbI 4 -2, which were absent in the DMePDAPbI 4 -1 spectrum. Last, the low-angle diffraction peak associated with the 2D structure from the thin-film XRD results were further confirmed with grazingincidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS) measurements (fig.  S13 ). In terms of 2D surfacelayer topology and coverage, the scanning electron microscopy (SEM) measurements indicated that the treatment induced formation of a thin surface layer with small apparent grain sizes (figs. S14 and S15). The conductive-atomic force microscopy (C-AFM) measurements show that the current of the treated film is much more uniform and lower than that of the control film, which is consistent with the formation of a capping layer over the 3D perovskite layer (fig.  S16 ). To gain more insight into how the DMeP-DAI 2 modification affects the optoelectronic properties in perovskite films, we conducted steady-state photoluminescence (PL), timeresolved photoluminescence (TRPL), and TRMC studies on these samples. The DMePDAI 2 treatment led to enhanced PL intensity (fig.  S17 ), longer TRPL lifetime (fig.  S18  and table  S5 ), and improved TRMC mobility and lifetime (fig.  S19 ) that were consistent with the improved surface properties  (8, 30) . In addition, the ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) measurements showed that the 2D surface treatment improved the energetics for hole transport from the 3D perovskite to the 2D surface layer (fig.  S20 ). The impact of the DMePDAI 2 treatment on the perovskite surface chemistry was investigated with x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Normalized core levels from key elements identified on the sample surface are included in figs. S21 and S22. The spectral shapes of most core levels showed minimal change between the two samples, indicating similar bonding environments, but surface treatment caused change in the C 1s and N 1s core levels. We fit the core levels (Fig.  3 , B to E) using constrained fitting procedures (summarized in tables S6 and S7). The control sample had a N 1s region whose relative peak areas were dominated by a C=NH 2 + (FA) peak (~401 eV) with a small shoulder to higher binding energy (~403 eV) that corresponded to C-NH 3 (MA). The DMePDAI 2 treatment increased the area of the C-NH 3 peak and also led to two additional peaks at a lower binding energy consistent with that of C-NH 2 (~400 eV) and the tertiary amine in DMePDAI 2 (~398 eV). Concomitant with these changes, redistribution occurred in the features in the C 1s spectra comprising four main peaks that are consistent with primarily C-C or C-H (~285 eV), N-CH 3 (~287 eV), HC(NH 2 ) 2 (~289 eV), and C-O or C=O bonds (~290 eV). The surface treatment decreased the concentration of HC(NH 2 ) 2 bonds from FA on the surface while simultaneously increasing the amount of N-CH 3 and C-C or C-H bonds. In addition, XPS revealed that surface treatment increased the amount of halide on the surface, from about 2.6 halide-to-lead ratio for the control to 3.1 for the DMePDAI 2 -treated film. Collectively, these results suggest that both organic and halide components of the additive incorporated into the top surface of the treated films. Undercoordinated lead can cause donor defects on the surface, resulting in downward band bending and increased recombination centers  (31) , so the increase in the halideto-lead ratio associated with the formation of 2D interfacial component upon surface treatment was consistent with a less defective surface. We investigated the impact of DMePDAI 2 surface treatment on the PV performance by fabricating PSCs using the standard n-i-p device architecture, glass/FTO/electron transport layer (ETL)/perovskite/hole transport layer (HTL)/ Au, where ETL is TiO 2 or SnO 2 and HTL is spiro-OMeTAD, with more details in the supplementary materials  (23) . Typical cross-section SEM images of devices are shown in fig.  S23 . In Fig.  4A , we compare the J-V curves of the PSCs on the basis of triple-cation-mixedhalide FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 without and with DMePDAI 2 treatment under simulated 100-mW/cm 2 air mass coefficient (AM) 1.5 G 4 of 6 illumination (Table  1 ). With the surface treatment, the device PCE increased from about 20.9 to 24.0% from forward scan and from 20.4 to 23.7% from reverse scan. The PCE improvement is also consistent with a better perovskite-HTL junction on the basis of the cross-sectional Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) measurements (fig.  S24 )  (32) . The optimum concentration for DMePDAI 2 -surface treatment was found at 0.5 mg/mL (fig.  S25 ). In addition to the FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 perovskite composition, we also examined the impact of DMePDAI 2 surface treatment on PSCs on the basis of double-cation-mixedhalide (FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09 ) and singlecation-single-halide (MAPbI 3 ) using ETL of SnO 2 and TiO 2 , respectively, and found PCE improvements for both compositions (Fig.  4,  B  and C ). Noteworthy for PSCs based on FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09 , the PCE was improved from 22.0 to 24.7% from forward scan and from 21.8 to 24.5% from reverse scan, with shortcircuit current density (J sc ) &gt; 25 mA/cm 2 , which is in agreement with the EQE spectrum (fig.  S26 ). For all three perovskite compositions, the stabilized power outputs (SPOs) for PSCs based on the control and DMePDAI 2 -modified perovskite thin films matched well with the J-V mea-surements (Fig.  4 , A to C, insets, and Table  1 ). The PCE improvement for all three perovskite compositions was reproducible on the basis of the statistical comparison (fig.  S27 ). The devices with this treatment also exhibited higher PCE than that of devices based on other surface treatments with similar length of bulky organic salts for either RP or DJ 2D perovskites (fig.  S28 ). Last, we checked the operation stability of unencapsulated FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 -based PSCs using maximum power point (MPP) tracking at ~40°C in N 2 , following the ISOS-L-1 stability protocol  (33) . The DMePDAI 2 -modified PSC (Fig.  4D ) showed only 10% relative efficiency drop after 1000 hours of continuous operation, whereas the PCE of the control device decreased by ~43%. The stability improvement with DMePDAI 2 surface treatment was also observed when the devices were tested at high-moisture (&gt;85% relative humidity) or high-temperature (85°C) conditions (figs. S29 and S30). These results suggest that the DMePDAI 2 -modification to form a 2D DJ phase surface layer is a general way to improve PSC performance. Our use of the metastable 2D DJ structure through hydrogen bonding tuning based on asymmetric bulky organic molecules represents a promising chemical design element for perovskite interfacial engineering to enhance PSC efficiency and stability.    &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">DMePDAI 2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:07:40Z</infon>
        <location offset="15697" length="9"/>
        <text>DMePDAI 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:07:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="15786" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:08:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="15813" length="82"/>
        <text>glass/FTO/electron transport layer (ETL)/perovskite/hole transport layer (HTL)/ Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">TitaniumDioxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:08:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="15910" length="5"/>
        <text>TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">TinOxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:08:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="15919" length="5"/>
        <text>SnO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:08:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="15936" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:11:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="16170" length="37"/>
        <text>FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">DMePDAI 2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:10:50Z</infon>
        <location offset="16220" length="24"/>
        <text>with DMePDAI 2 treatment</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:10:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="16251" length="73"/>
        <text>simulated 100-mW/cm 2 air mass coefficient (AM) 1.5 G 4 of 6 illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:10:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="16402" length="4"/>
        <text>20.9</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:10:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="16410" length="4"/>
        <text>24.0</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:11:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="16775" length="37"/>
        <text>FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA0.97MA0.03PbI2.91Br0.09</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:13:11Z</infon>
        <location offset="17170" length="32"/>
        <text>FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">22.0</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="17231" length="4"/>
        <text>22.0</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.7</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:20Z</infon>
        <location offset="17239" length="4"/>
        <text>24.7</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">40</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:15:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="18144" length="5"/>
        <text>~40°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:14:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="18173" length="8"/>
        <text>ISOS-L-1</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">DMePDAI 2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="18213" length="9"/>
        <text>DMePDAI 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="18261" length="28"/>
        <text>10% relative efficiency drop</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:15:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="18296" length="10"/>
        <text>1000 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">57</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="18384" length="3"/>
        <text>43%</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:40Z</infon>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:40Z</infon>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R3">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:23:44Z</infon>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18989</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19013</offset>
      <text> Materials Lead oxide (PbO, 99.999%), 1,3-propanediamine, N,N-dimethyl-1,3-propane diamine, N,N-anhydrous dimethylformamide (DMF), ethanol, 2-propanol (IPA), chlorobenzene (CB), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and 57% aqueous hydriodic acid (HI) solution (99.95%, distilled, stabilized by H3PO2) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich and used as-received without any other refinement unless otherwise specified. Formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium bromide (MABr), methylammonium chloride (MACl), and 1,4-butane diammonium iodide (BDAI2) were purchased from Greatcell Solar. Lead iodide (PbI2) and lead bromide (PbBr2) were from TCI Corporation. 2,2',7,7'-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9'-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) was received from Merck Corporation. The titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate), bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide lithium salt, poly(triarylamine) (PTAA), tert-butylpyridine, and cesium iodide (CsI) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. 4-isopropyl-4'methyldiphenyliodoniumtetrakis (pentafluorophenyl)borate (TPFB) was purchased from Lumtec. Substrates are patterned fluorine-doped tin-oxide-coated glass (&lt;15 Ω /square) obtained from Advanced Election Technology Co., Ltd. Synthesis of 1,3-propane diammonium diiodine (PDAI2) and N,N-dimethyl-1,3-propane diammonium diiodide (DMePDAI2) 5 mL of 1,3-propanediamine or N,N-dimethyl-1,3-propane diamine was first mixed with 15 mL ethanol (200 Proof), and the solution was placed in an ice water bath (0 °C). 20 mL HI solution was slowly added to the PDA solution (dropwise). The mixture was allowed to stir for 2 hours. After the reaction, solvents were removed by vacuum and white powders were collected by vacuum filtration. The product was recrystallized from ethanol/diethyl ether and dried in vacuum overnight. DMePDAI2 was synthesized following the same process. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20864</offset>
      <text> Synthesis of [PDAPbI4]15•[PDAI2] single crystals 335 mg (1.5 mmol) of PbO and 492 mg (1.5 mmol) of PDAI2 were fully dissolved in 6 mL of HI solution at 90 °C. The solution was then slowly cooled to room temperature at a rate of 1 °C/h, giving yellow crystals. The crystals were then isolated from the parent solution by vacuum filtration and dried under vacuum. Synthesis of BDAPbI4 single crystals 335 mg (1.5 mmol) of PbO and 516 mg (1.5 mmol) of BDAI2 were fully dissolved in 6 mL of HI solution at 90 °C. The solution was then slowly cooled to room temperature at a rate of 1 °C/h, giving yellow crystals. The crystals were then isolated from the parent solution by vacuum filtration and dried under vacuum. Synthesis of DMePDAPbI4-1 single crystals 335 mg (1.5 mmol) of PbO and 537 mg (1.5 mmol) of DMePDAI2 were fully dissolved in 6 mL of HI solution at 90 °C. The solution was then slowly cooled to room temperature at a rate of 1 °C/h, giving red crystals. The crystals were then isolated from the parent solution by vacuum filtration and dried under vacuum. Synthesis of DMePDAPbI4-2 single crystals 335 mg (1.5 mmol) of PbO and 537 mg (1.5 mmol) of DMePDAI2 are fully dissolved in 6 mL of HI solution at 90 °C. The solution is then cooled to room temperature without controlling the rate, giving red crystals. The crystals are then isolated from the parent solution by vacuum filtration and dried under vacuum. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22296</offset>
      <text> 2D (n=1) perovskites-based device fabrication Devices were prepared on conductive fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)-coated glass substrates. The substrates were cleaned extensively by deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol. A compact titanium dioxide (TiO2) layer about 40 nm thick was deposited by spray pyrolysis of 7 mL of 2-propanol solution containing 0.6 mL of titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution (75% in 2-propanol, Sigma-Aldrich) and 0.4 mL of acetylacetone at 450 °C in air. The precursor solutions were prepared by mixing PbI2 and BDAI2 or DMePDAI2, and PEAI or BAI at a stoichiometric ratio of 1:1 and 1:2, respectively, with a concentration of 0.35 mol/L in DMF. The spin-coating procedure was performed at 4,000 rpm for 30 s. Thereafter, the substrate was put onto a hotplate for 15 min at 100 °C. Subsequently, the hole-transporting layer (HTM) was deposited on the top of the perovskite by spin coating at 4,000 rpm for 15 s. The spiro-OMeTAD solutions were prepared by dissolving the spiro-OMeTAD in 1-mL CB at a concentration of 77.6 mg/mL, with the addition of 20.6 L bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide lithium salt from a stock solution in acetonitrile, 35.5 L of tert-butylpyridine. The fabrication of perovskite layer and HTM layer of devices were executed in a dry air box, where the variation of humidity is from about 1% to 4%, the variation of temperature is from about 20 °C to 24 °C. The devices were finalized by thermal evaporation of 100-nm gold. FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1-based device fabrication Devices were prepared on conductive FTO-coated glass substrates. The substrates were cleaned extensively by deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol. A compact titanium dioxide (TiO2) layer of about 40 nm was deposited by spray pyrolysis of 9-mL ethanol solution containing 0.6-mL titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution (75% in 2-propanol, Sigma-Aldrich) and 0.4-mL acetylacetone at 450 °C in air. On top of this layer, mesoporous titanium dioxide was formed by spin-coating 30-nm-sized nanoparticles (Dyesol 30NRD, Dyesol) diluted in ethanol (1:5.5 w/w) at 4,500 rpm for 15 s. The FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1 precursor solution was prepared in a glovebox from a 1.60 M Pb 2+ with 5% excess of PbI2 and in the mixed solvent of DMF and DMSO; the volume ratio of DMF/DMSO was 4:1. The spin-coating procedure was performed at 2,000 rpm for 10 s followed by 6,000 rpm for 30 s. At 15 s before the last spin-coating step, 140 L of chlorobenzene were pipetted onto the substrate. Thereafter, the substrate was put onto a hotplate for 20 minutes at 120 °C; these are identified as the "control" samples. For DMePDAI2 treatment, different concentrations of DMePDAI2 were dissolved in IPA and spin-coated on the surface of the perovskite at 3000 rpm for 30 s with subsequent annealing for 2 mins at 100 °C. The best condition is designated "DMePDAI2" samples. Subsequently, the HTM was deposited on top of the perovskite by spin coating at 4,500 rpm for 15 s. The spiro-OMeTAD solutions were prepared by dissolving the spiro-OMeTAD in 1-mL CB at a concentration of 77.6 mg/mL, with the addition of 20.6 L bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide lithium salt from a stock solution in acetonitrile, 35.5 L of tert-butylpyridine. For the high humidity/heat stability test, PTAA solution was prepared from 16 mg of PTAA and 1.8 mg of TPFB in 0.8 mL of CB and kept under stirring over 1h before using it. The PTAA was deposited on top of perovskite by spin-coating at 1500 rpm for 30 sec. The devices were finalized by thermal evaporation of 100-nm gold. FA0.97MA0.03PbI2.91Br0.09-based device fabrication FTO glass substrates were washed by ultrasonication in water with detergent, clean water, and 2-propanol sequentially. The SnO2 electron transport layer was deposited using the chemical bath deposition method  (34) , and the resulting sample was annealed at 150 C for 2 h. The perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing 1.55 M PbI2, 1.55 M FAI 0.048 M MAPbBr3 and 0.5 M MACl in a mixed solvent (DMF/DMSO = 8:1). Then the perovskite precursor solution was deposited onto the UV-ozone treated SnO2 film at 5000 rpm for 20s, where 1 mL of diethyl ether was dropped on the rotating film 10 s after spinning. The resulting film was annealed at 150 C for 15 min and 100 C for 5 min, sequentially. For DMePDAI2 treatment, 200 L of 0.5 mg/mL DMePDAI2 in IPA was spin-coated on perovskite film at 3000 rpm for 30 s with subsequent annealing for 2 mins at 100 C. The spiro-OMeTAD layer was deposited on the perovskite layer by spin coating the spiro-OMeTAD stock solution at 4000 rpm for 30 s. Finally, a 100 nm Au electrode layer was deposited by thermal evaporation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27057</offset>
      <text> MAPbI3-based device fabrication Devices were prepared on conductive FTO-coated glass substrates. The substrates were cleaned extensively by deionized water, acetone, and isopropanol. A compact titanium dioxide (TiO2) layer of about 40 nm was deposited by spray pyrolysis of 9-mL ethanol solution containing 0.6-mL titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate) solution (75% in 2-propanol, Sigma-Aldrich) and 0.4-mL acetylacetone at 450 °C in air. On top of this layer, mesoporous titanium dioxide was formed by spin-coating 30-nm-sized nanoparticles (Dyesol 30NRD, Dyesol) diluted in ethanol (1:5.5 w/w) at 4,500 rpm for 15 s. The MAPbI3 precursor solution was prepared in a glovebox from a 1.45 M Pb 2+ with 5% excess of PbI2 and in the mixed solvent of DMF and DMSO; the volume ratio of DMF/DMSO was 4:1. The spin-coating procedure was performed at 2,000 rpm for 10 s followed with 6,000 rpm for 30 s. At 15 s before the last spin-coating step, 140 L of CB were pipetted onto the substrate. Thereafter, the substrate was put onto a hotplate for 30 minutes at 100 °C. For DMePDAI2 treatment, the 200 L of 0.5 mg/ml DMePDAI2 in IPA was spin-coated onto the perovskite film at 3000 rpm for 30 s with subsequent annealing for 2 mins at 100 °C. Subsequently, the HTM was deposited on top of the perovskite by spin coating at 4,500 rpm for 15 s. The devices were finalized by thermal evaporation of 100-nm gold. Perovskite film and device characterizations SEM (FEI Nova 630, field-emission gun) imaging was performed with an electron-beam voltage of 3 kV in the immersion-lens mode. The X-ray diffraction (XRD) and grazing incident XRD (GIXRD) of the perovskite films was characterized using a Rigaku D-Max 2200 diffractometer with Cu Kα radiation. The optical absorption spectra of perovskite films were measured using an ultraviolet/visible (UV/Vis) spectrophotometer (Cary6000i). Water contact angles of perovskite films were measured using a JC 2000D contact angle instrument. Solar cell performance measurements were taken under a simulated AM 1.5G illumination (100 mW/cm 2 , Oriel Sol3A Class AAA Solar Simulator). The photocurrent density-voltage (J-V) characteristics were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter. The J-V curves of all devices were measured by masking the active area with a metal mask of area 0.12 cm 2 . Both backward-scan and forwardscan curves were measured with a bias step of 10 mV and delay time of 0.05 s. The continuous current and power output were measured using a potentiostat (Princeton Applied Research, Versa STAT MC). External quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of solar cells were measured using a solar cell quantum-efficiency measurement system (QEX10, PV Measurements). Single-crystal structure analysis via XRD was performed on a Bruker D8 Venture Photon 2 diffractometer at the University of Kentucky and at the ALS on a Bruker D8 Photon 100 diffractometer. Stability measurements were performed with maximum power-point (MPP) tracking under continuous illumination from a full AM1.5 sun-equivalent white LED lamp in N2 at about 40 C. The TRMC measurements were performed according to our previous report  (28) . Grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS) characterization GIWAXS data were collected at beamline 11-3 at the Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Source (SSRL) at the SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory. The X-ray photon energy used at this beamline is 12.7 keV. Samples were exposed to the beam for 60 s in a sealed chamber under helium flow in grazing incidence geometry at an incident angle in the range of 0.12-3.12. A Rayonix MX225 CCD area detector was placed at a sample-to-detector distance of 200 mm. Collected data was calibrated against a reference sample (LaB6) using a software package pyFAI  (35) . The same python package was used for the data processing to obtain 2D and integrated 1D diffraction patterns as a function of a scattering vector q = 4π λ sin( 2θ 2 ). The integration was performed between 0 &lt; χ &lt; 90, where χ is the azimuthal angle. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31120</offset>
      <text> Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) and conductive atomic force microscopy (C-AFM) characterizations The measurements were performed inside an Ar-filled glovebox with water and oxygen level lower than 0.01 ppm. All the scans were collected via Nanosensor PPP-EFM tips. The KPFM mappings have a spatial resolution of 30 nm and an electrical resolution of 10 mV. We directly cleaved the cells inside the glovebox with no exposure to air or polishing/ion-milling treatments to flatten the surface. Then, KPFM cross-section images were used for alignment to topography and to mark the locations of interfaces. C-AFM scans were all acquired using a single tip and the same scan conditions, at least two areas were examined to ensure the reliability of results. The FTO substrate was connected to the AFM stage and the applied bias voltage was 0.8 V. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31968</offset>
      <text> X-ray and ultraviolet photoemission spectroscopy (XPS and UPS) characterizations XPS measurements were performed on a Physical Electronics 5600 photoelectron spectrometer, which has been discussed in detail previously  (36) . Briefly, radiation was produced by a monochromatic 350 W Al Kα excitation centered at 1486.7 eV. XPS core-level spectra were collected using a step size of 0.1 eV and pass energy of 11.75 eV. The electron binding energy scale was calibrated using the Fermi edge of a copper substrate, cleaned with Argon ion bombardment. Peak areas were fit using a Gaussian-Lorentzian peak fitting algorithm with a Shirley background. Spectra taken with the Al source are typically assigned an uncertainty of 0.05 eV. Compositional analyses and deconvolutions are typically assigned an uncertainty of 5%. UPS measurements were performed on a Kratos Axis Ultra spectrometer using a He I excitation at 21.22 eV at a 5 eV pass energy and 0° take-off angle. Samples were biased at -10.00 V to accelerate low kinetic energy electrons and secondary electrons from the local environment. The Fermi level was calibrated using an Ar sputter-etched, atomically clean gold sample measured prior to characterization of the samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33202</offset>
      <text> Computation The electronic properties were calculated using screened hybrid functional and van der Waals (vdW) interaction (HSE+vdW) to account the effects of organic molecules  (26) . We also employed the Grimme-D3 method to account for the van der Waals (vdW) effect  (27) . The spinorbit coupling is not included in all calculations due to the small effects on the valence band  (37, 38) . The calculations were performed with auxiliary density matrix method (ADMM) implemented in CP2K  (39, 40) . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33705</offset>
      <text> Space-charge-limited-current (SCLC) characterization Vertical hole-only devices (Au/perovskite/Au) were fabricated to extract the out-of-plane hole mobility of 2D perovskite single crystals  (41, 42) . The dark J-V characteristics of hole-only devices were measured by a Keithley 2400 source. Mobilities were calculated at the SCLC region using Child's law, J = 9ɛ0ɛTμhV 2 /8L 3 , where J is the current density, L is the active thickness of the 2D perovskite single crystals, μh is the hole mobility, ɛT is the relative dielectric constant of the transport medium, ɛ0 is the permittivity of free space, V is the applied voltage to the device. Average values and standard deviations were obtained on 10 devices fabricated and tested under the same conditions.        002 ) planes of the PbI2 crystal. These results suggest that the metastable DMePDAPbI4-2 structure is stable up to ~150C, which is significantly higher than normal device operational temperatures. It is also clear from these results that DMePDAPbI4-2 does not transition to DMePDAPbI4-1 under these conditions, but rather decomposes to the lowest energy primary salts. The results are consistent with the calculated high transition energy barrier between the metastable and stable DMePDAPbI4 structures.            The control perovskite has a biexponential fitted average lifetime of 0.91 microseconds, while the DMePDAI2-treated films lifetime had improved lifetimes of 1.32 microseconds, respectively. The fit-extracted t=0 yield-mobility product () value was found to be 36.9 cm 2 /Vs, and 39.7 cm 2 /Vs for the control, and DMePDAI2 treated films, respectively. Since the yield is normally close to unity in high-performance PSCs, the yield-mobility product can be viewed as a measurement of the charge mobility.     Because the electron transport layer (ETL)/perovskite interface should be identical for these devices, we normalized the ETL/perovskite peak to compare the "back-contact" quality at the perovskite/HTL interfaces between the surface-modified devices. It is evident that the DMePDAI2-modified device showed a significantly smaller perovskite/HTL electric field difference peak than that of the control perovskite devices. If consider the main junction at ETL/perovskite interface, the smaller perovskite/HTL peak indicates that the DMePDAI2-modified device has a less leaky interface  (44) , suggesting that a better back contact quality can decrease the energy loss associated with carrier transport over the interface, enabling higher FF and Voc in devices.        Table 1 . 4 . 4 . 144 PV parameters of PSCs based on control and DMePDAI 2 -modified perovskite thin films by using different perovskite compositions. V oc, open-circuit voltage; FF, fill factor. ......................................................................................................................... ......................................................................................................................... &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36719</offset>
      <text> FA 7 . 7 . 7 . 8 . 3 . 5 . 2 . 2 . 8 . 777835228 ......................................................................................................................... .........................................................................................................................FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0......................................................................................................................... .........................................................................................................................FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09 /DMePDAI 2 ......................................................................................................................... ......................................................................................................................... ......................................................................................................................... ......................................................................................................................... ......................................................................................................................... &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37939</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Design concept. (A) Illustration of band offsets between [PbI 6 ] planes and bulky organic cations with a weaker and stronger degree of H-bonding. For clarity, the inorganic framework orbital diagram is omitted in the middle of the panel. (B) Two possible arrangements of asymmetric DMePDA 2+ cations and the sole arrangement of symmetric BDA 2+ cations. (C) HSE+vdW calculated total DOSs of the organic cations in BDAPbI 4 , DMePDAPbI 4 -1 [with orientation-1 in (B)], and DMePDAPbI 4 -2 [with orientation-2 in (B)]. The VBMs were set to 0.0 eV. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38507</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. 2D thin-film structure, transport, and device characteristics. (A) XRD patterns of a solution-grown DMePDAPbI 4 thin film and the powder XRD patterns (measured and calculated) from DMePDAPbI 4 -1 and DMePDAPbI 4 -2 single-crystal structures. X-ray source, Cu Ka radiation. The peak labeled with an asterisk is from the fluorine tin oxide (FTO) substrates. (B) Energy profile along the transition path between DMePDAPbI 4 -1 and DMePDAPbI 4 -2. (C) TRMC comparison of out-ofplane charge transport across the layers of n = 1 2D perovskites. (D) J-V characteristics of PSCs based on n = 1 2D perovskite thin films using a device stack of glass/FTO/compact-TiO 2 / 2D-perovskite/2,2',7,7'-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9'spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD)/Au. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39290</offset>
      <text> Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39391</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Surface layer treatment. (A) Comparison of grazing incident XRD (GIXRD) patterns of thin films of DMePDAPbI 4 and perovskites without (control PVK) and with DMePDAI 2 surface treatment (PVK/DMePDAI 2 ). (Inset) Zoom-in view of the GIXRD pattern from 7°to 10°. The peak &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39683</offset>
      <text> 97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09 FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39751</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Device characteristics. (A to C) J-V characteristics of PSCs based on different perovskite compositions. (A) FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 . (B) FA 0.97 MA 0.03 PbI 2.91 Br 0.09 . (C) MAPbI 3 . (Insets) SPOs of the corresponding devices. (D) Operation ISOS-L-1 stability (maximum power point tracking, in N 2 , continuous one-sun illumination at ~40°C) of unencapsulated PSC based on FA 0.85 MA 0.1 Cs 0.05 PbI 2.9 Br 0.1 . The initial PCE was 20.5% for the control and 23.1% for the DMePDAI 2 -treated device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40292</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. Side view of the crystal structures of (A) BDAPbI4, (B) DMePDAPbI4-1, and (C) DMePDAPbI4-2 single crystals. The average interlayer distances are indicated. The crystal structure of DMePDAPbI4-2 was reported in reference (22). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40542</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. (A) The photoluminescence (PL) spectra and (B) absorption spectra of DMePDAPbI4-1 and DMePDAPbI4-2 single crystal samples. The inset shows the photographs of DMePDAPbI4-1 and DMePDAPbI4-2 single crystal samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40778</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. Side view of the crystal structure of BDAPbI4 and the corresponding hydrogen-bonding configuration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40902</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. Side view of the crystal structure of DMePDAPbI4-1 and the corresponding hydrogenbonding configuration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41030</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. Side view of the crystal structure of DMePDAPbI4-2 and the corresponding hydrogenbonding configuration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41158</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Stability of DMePDAPbI4-2 thin films subjected to elevated temperatures. (A) Absorption and (B) XRD patterns of the DMePDAPbI4-2 thin films aged at different temperatures from 80C to 200C for 30 min. The sample annealed at 200C showed a strong diffraction peak at 12.6 and 25.6, corresponding to the (001) and (002) planes of the PbI2 crystal. These results suggest that &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41568</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. XRD patterns before and after (A) thermal and (B) humidity ageing tests of the DMePDAPbI4-2 thin films.For the thermal test, the samples were heated at 85C for 100 h under ~5% relative humidity (RH) in dark. For the humidity test, the samples were aged for 100 h under &gt;85% RH in dark. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41881</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. Structure of solution grown DMePDAPbI4 thin films under various conditions. (A) Solvents with DMF:DMSO ratio changed from 0:10 to 10:0. (B) Solvents with different combinations of DMF:GBL, DMF:NMP, DMF:CHP (1-Cyclohexyl-2-pyrrolidone), and DMF:DMSO, all with 1:1 ratio. (C) Post-growth annealing temperature is varied from 60C to 120C. These results indicate that only the metastable DMePDAPbI4-2 film can be formed with the solution growth method. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42360</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Comparison of out-of-plane hole transport by SCLC. (A) Dark I-V characteristics of vertical hole-only devices based on 2D perovskite single crystals. (B) Statistical comparison of normalized out-of-plane hole mobilities. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42608</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. External quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum of DMePDAPbI4 based perovskite solar cell using a stack of glass/FTO/TiO2/DMePDAPbI4/spiro-OMeTAD/Au. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42780</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. GIXRD patterns of of perovskites without (3D PVK) and with DMePDAI2 surface treatment (3D PVK/DMePDAI2) using different perovskite compositions: (A) Cs0.05FA0.95PbI3, (B) (FAPbI3)0.95(MAPbBr3)0.05, and (C) FAPbI3. The peaks labeled with "*" are from the FTO substrate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43076</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. GIWAXS of (A) DMePDAI4, (B) control perovskite (Control PVK), and (C) DMePDAI2 modified perovskite (PVK/DMePDAI2) thin films. The incidence angle was 0.12. (D) Radially integrated GIWAXS data from A-C. The low-angle diffraction peak at about q = 0.61 Å -1 corresponds to about 8.57 for the thin-film XRD measurement using Cu K radiation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43451</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. Top view SEM images of (A) the control and (C) DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films (scale bar: 2 m). Cross-sectional view SEM images of (B) the control and (D) DMePDAI2modified perovskite thin films on FTO glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43698</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. (A-D) Top-view SEM images of perovskite thin films without (control; A) and with DMePDAI2 surface treatment (B-D). The concentration of DMePDAI2/IPA solution is varied from 0.25 mg/mL to 0.75 mg/mL as indicated. It shows that with increasing DMePDAI2 solution concentration, the perovskite film surface smoothness is enhanced, and the perovskite grain boundaries gradually disappear. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44109</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. AFM topography of (A) the control and (D) DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films (scale bar: 1 m). C-AFM images of (B) the control and (E) DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films on TiO2/FTO glass (scale bar: 1 m). The corresponding line profiles of C-AFM based on (C) the control and (F) DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44473</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. Comparison of the PL measurements of the control and DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44594</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. Comparison of the TRPL measurements of the control and DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44717</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. Comparison of time-resolved microwave conductivity (TRMC) measurement of the control and DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films. The control perovskite has a biexponential fitted average lifetime of 0.91 microseconds, while the DMePDAI2-treated films lifetime had improved lifetimes of 1.32 microseconds, respectively. The fit-extracted t=0 yield-mobility &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45101</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. (A) Ultraviolet photoelectron spectra (UPS) of the 3D perovskite film (3D PVK) and the 2D perovskite (2D PVK) coated on top of the 3D perovskite film. The baseline 3D perovskite composition is FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1. (B) Schematic energy levels of the 3D and 2D perovskites in this study. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45423</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. The XPS spectra taken on two different spots based on the control perovskite thin film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45538</offset>
      <text> Fig. S22 . S22 Fig. S22. The XPS spectra taken on two different spots on the DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45657</offset>
      <text> Fig. S23 . S23 Fig. S23. Cross-sectional view SEM image of DMePDAI2-modified perovskite-based device stack. (A) The cell architecture (from top to bottom) is Au/spiro-OMeTAD/FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1 /mesoporous-TiO2/compact-TiO2/FTO/glass. (B) The cell architecture is Au/spiro-OMeTAD/ FA0.97MA0.03PbI2.91Br0.09/SnO2/FTO/glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45991</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. KPFM electrical potential and field profiling on the cross-sectional surface for devices based on (A) the control and (B) DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films. Top: potential profile under 0 V, -1 V, and -1.5 V bias voltages. Middle: potential difference between the various applied bias voltages and 0 V. Bottom: change in electric field calculated by taking the first derivatives of the potential difference. The hole transport layer (HTL) is spiro-OMeTAD. The local voltage drop across the device is determined by the competition of equivalent resistance of different layers and interfaces, which can be related to the interface quality. Because the electron transport layer (ETL)/perovskite interface should be identical for these devices, we normalized the ETL/perovskite peak to compare the "back-contact" quality at the perovskite/HTL interfaces between the surface-modified devices. It is evident that the DMePDAI2-modified device showed a significantly smaller perovskite/HTL electric field difference peak than that of the control perovskite devices. If consider the main junction at ETL/perovskite interface, the smaller perovskite/HTL peak indicates that the DMePDAI2-modified device has a less leaky interface (44) , suggesting that a better back contact quality can decrease the energy loss associated with carrier transport over the interface, enabling higher FF and Voc in devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47419</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. Statistical distribution of PCE of perovskite solar cells based on DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films with different concentrations. The control devices are those noted with zero concentration of surface treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47666</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 . S26 Fig. S26. EQE spectra with integrated current densities for the corresponding devices based on FA0.97MA0.03PbI2.91Br0.09-based devices without (Control) and with DMePDAI2 surface modification (DMePDAI2). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47887</offset>
      <text> Fig. S27 . S27 Fig. S27. Statistical comparison of PCEs for solar cells without (Control) and with DMePDAI2 surface modification (DMePDAI2) using three perovskite compositions: (A) FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1, (B) FA0.97MA0.03PbI2.91Br0.09, and (C) MAPbI3. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48147</offset>
      <text> Fig. S28 . S28 Fig. S28. Statistical PCE comparision of PSCs based on the control and different surface treated perovskite thin films. Organo-halide salts including phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI), butylammonium iodide (BAI), and 1,4-butane diammonium iodide (BDAI2) for 2D materials have similar carbon chain length. In this series, PEAI and BAI are known to form RP 2D structures, whereas BDAI2 is a symmetric molecule that can form DJ 2D structure of BDAPbI4. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48612</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 . S29 Fig. S29. Comparison of the moisture and thermal stability of PSCs without and with surface treatments. The baseline perovskite composition is FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1. The PSC without surface treatment is the control. The PSC with DMePDAI2 treatement is denoted by DMePDAPbI4, and the PSC with BDAI2 surface treatment is denoted by BDAPbI4. Here, PTAA with 5 wt%TPFB was used to avoid the effect of hygroscopic additives and thermal degradation in spiro-OMeTAD. (A) Comparison of the moisture stability test of unencapsulated PSCs without and with surface treatment (as indicated) in 85% RH at room temperature for 740 h. The average PCE of unencapsulated control, BDAI2-treated, and DMePDAI2-treated PSCs maintained about 27%, 35%, 73% of their respective initial PCEs after 740 h ageing under &gt;85% RH. The increased stability of DMePDAI2-treated PSCs relative to BDAI2-treated ones is consistent with the increased hydrophobicity (Figure S30). (B) Comparison of the thermal stability test of unencapsulated PSCs without and with surface treatment (as indicated) heated at 85C for 1008 h, in dark, 5% RH. The average PCE of unencapsulated control, BDAI2-treated, and DMePDAI2-treated PSCs maintained about 29%, 53% and 81% of their respective initial PCEs after 1008-h ageing at 85C. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:19:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="48771" length="28"/>
        <text>FA0.85MA0.1Cs0.05PbI2.9Br0.1</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">DMePDAPbI4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:20:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="48898" length="10"/>
        <text>DMePDAPbI4</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">BDAI2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:20:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="48927" length="5"/>
        <text>BDAI2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:20:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="49081" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:21:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="49117" length="23"/>
        <text>moisture stability test</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:22:05Z</infon>
        <location offset="49217" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">740</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:22:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="49248" length="5"/>
        <text>740 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="29">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">BDAI2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:22:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="49298" length="5"/>
        <text>BDAI2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="30">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">DMePDAPbI4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:22:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="49317" length="9"/>
        <text>DMePDAI2-</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="31">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">27</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="49356" length="3"/>
        <text>27%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="32">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">35</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="49361" length="3"/>
        <text>35%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="33">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">73</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:38Z</infon>
        <location offset="49366" length="3"/>
        <text>73%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="34">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">740</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:23:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="49409" length="5"/>
        <text>740 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="35">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:23:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="49429" length="3"/>
        <text>85%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="36">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOST</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:25:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="49601" length="17"/>
        <text>thermal stability</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="37">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:25:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="49707" length="2"/>
        <text>85</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="38">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1008</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:25:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="49716" length="6"/>
        <text>1008 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="39">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:25:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="49733" length="2"/>
        <text>5%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="40">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">29</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="49841" length="2"/>
        <text>29</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="41">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">53</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="49846" length="2"/>
        <text>53</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="42">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">81</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:00:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="49854" length="2"/>
        <text>81</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R4">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:24:19Z</infon>
        <node refid="26" role=""/>
        <node refid="27" role=""/>
        <node refid="28" role=""/>
        <node refid="29" role=""/>
        <node refid="32" role=""/>
        <node refid="31" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R5">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:24:42Z</infon>
        <node refid="26" role=""/>
        <node refid="30" role=""/>
        <node refid="33" role=""/>
        <node refid="31" role=""/>
        <node refid="27" role=""/>
        <node refid="28" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R6">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:26:44Z</infon>
        <node refid="36" role=""/>
        <node refid="40" role=""/>
        <node refid="37" role=""/>
        <node refid="38" role=""/>
        <node refid="39" role=""/>
        <node refid="29" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R7">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-12T04:27:03Z</infon>
        <node refid="36" role=""/>
        <node refid="37" role=""/>
        <node refid="38" role=""/>
        <node refid="39" role=""/>
        <node refid="40" role=""/>
        <node refid="42" role=""/>
        <node refid="30" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49925</offset>
      <text> Fig. S30 . S30 Fig. S30. Comparison of contact angle measurement of (A) BDAPbI4 and (B) DMePDAPbI4 perovskite thin films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50049</offset>
      <text> Table S5 . S5 Lifetimes of the control, and DMePDAI2-modified perovskite thin films extracted by fitting the PL decay curve with a bi-exponential decay function. Samples fast component 1 (ns) slow component 2 (ns) Control 50 101 DMePDAI2 61 181 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50302</offset>
      <text> Table S6 . S6 The constrained fitting procedure (from low binding energy [BE] to high) used by deconvoluted C1s peak. Peak # BE location FWHM C-C/C-H -1.7 to -1.4 1.3 -1.4 C-NH3 x 1.15 -1.25 HC(NH2) +1.75 to +1.85 0.9 -1.1 C-O/C=O +2.75 to +2.85 1.25 -1.35 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50561</offset>
      <text> Table S7 . S7 The constrained fitting procedure (from low binding energy [BE] to high) used by deconvoluted N1s peak. Peak # BE location FWHM CH2-NH + -(CH3)2 -2.35 to -2.25 1.8 -2.0 C-NH2 -1.2 to -1.1 0.8 -1.0 C=NH2 + x 0.95 -1.0 C-NH3 +1.6 to +1.8 1.15 -1.25 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50824</offset>
      <text>			 .......................................................................................................................... Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51051</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 RESEARCH | REPORT Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
