<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025047198DHAIIC</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">3</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">3</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 125&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Initializing film homogeneity to retard phase segregation for stable perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>105</offset>
      <text>The mixtures of cations and anions used in hybrid halide perovskites for high-performance solar cells often undergo element and phase segregation, which limits device lifetime. We adapted Schelling's model of segregation to study individual cation migration and found that the initial film inhomogeneity accelerates materials degradation. We fabricated perovskite films (FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 ; where FA is formamidinium) through the addition of selenophene, which led to homogeneous cation distribution that retarded cation aggregation during materials processing and device operation. The resultant devices achieved enhanced efficiency and retained &gt;91% of their initial efficiency after 3190 hours at the maximum power point under 1 sun illumination. We also observe prolonged operational lifetime in devices with initially homogeneous FACsPb(Br 0.13 I 0.87 ) 3 absorbers. W ith an endless compositional space that is almost continuously tailorable in the full region, halide perovskite materials present tunable electronic and optical properties  (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) . Although perovskite solar cells can have high power conversion efficiency (PCE), their limited device lifetime remains a substantial challenge to commercialization  (6) (7) (8) . The use of mixed cations and anions has led to a more appropriate tolerance factor of the crystal for improved structural stability and extra functionality to strengthen chemical stability in the resultant absorber thin films  (9) (10) (11) . However, mixed perovskite absorbers often undergo element and phase segregation that can decrease device efficiency and lifetime  (12, 13) . Most studies of phase segregation of mixed perovskites focus on film aging to understand cation and anion migration, the formation and development of nanoscale clusters  (14) (15) (16) , thermodynamic driving forces  (17, 18) , and their impacts on film properties and device performance  (12, (19) (20) (21) (22) (23) . Effective strategies such as relaxing residual strain and incorporating low-dimension perovskites can retard phase segregation by suppressing ion migration  (5, 24, 25) . However, relevant metrics are needed to investigate the atomistic aggregation of individual ions to correlate their collective behavior that led to film degradation. We adapted a physical analog of Schelling's model, which was used to illustrate agent (such as isolated particles) segregation caused by even low levels of individual preference in the context of social economics  (26)  and physics  (27) . It bridges the microscale analysis of cation aggregation in perovskites and macroscale observations of their phase separation and film degradation. In the simulation, the initial film homogeneity affected cation aggregation duration and thus device lifetime. On the basis of these findings, we grew homogeneous a-phase FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 (FA, formamidinium) that resulted in a solar cell with enhanced efficiency and prolonged operational lifetime. Furthermore, for the wide-bandgap FACsPb(Br 0.13 I 0.87 ) 3 , the corresponding device retained &gt;80% of its initial PCE after 340 hours at maximum power point (MPP) tracking. It indicates that this model is applicable to various perovskite formulations such as mixed halide perovskites, which demonstrates the generality of the Schelling model for halide perovskites. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">selenophene</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:19:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="547" length="11"/>
        <text>selenophene</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">91</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="753" length="3"/>
        <text>91%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3190</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:44:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="791" length="10"/>
        <text>3190 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:55:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="809" length="45"/>
        <text>maximum power point under 1 sun illumination.</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FACsPb(Br0.13I0.87)3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:21:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="940" length="25"/>
        <text>FACsPb(Br 0.13 I 0.87 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3452</offset>
      <text> Cation aggregation and phase transition The a-phase FA x Cs 1-x PbI 3 (FACs) perovskites have an optimal bandgap and high thermal stability from the resultant crystal structure, with an ideal Goldschmidt tolerance factor  (11, 21, (28) (29) (30) (31) . However, reported devices based on FACs perovskite absorbers have had limited lifetimes, resulting from material degradation that is largely the result of phase separation  (32) . In Fig.  1, A, C,  and D , we show the twodimensional (2D) photoluminescence (PL) mapping by wavelength, intensity, and full width at half-maximum (FWHM), respectively, of the FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 perovskite film. The emission spectra display peak variability between the selected regions. Moreover, although the emission of region 1 was concentrated at 795 nm (attributed to FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 ) (12), both regions 2 and 3 exhibited splitting of the emission peak (Fig.  1B ). This feature was indicative of phase segregation within the perovskite film. We investigated the segregation evolution of films aged under continuous light illumination for 20 min at 80°C at the same location in ambient atmosphere. As shown in the mapping spectra (Fig.  1E ), the phase segregation of the film intensified with increasing areas of both the yellow domains (which represent the longer-wavelength, FA-rich composition) and red domains (which represent the shorterwavelength, Cs-rich composition), which indicated that the local Cs/FA ratio deviated from that observed in the pristine films. Region 1 showed peak splitting at 799 and 789 nm, with increased peak intensity at longer wavelengths. By contrast, for regions 2 and 3, the peak intensity increase was observed at shorter wavelengths (783 and 781 nm, respectively). Moreover, the FWHM increased notably (Fig.  1H ), which indicates the broadening of the PL emission peak after aging. After comparison with the pure FAPbI 3 film, for which no obvious change on the PL mapping was observed after aging (fig.  S1 ), we hypothesized that Cs + cations in region 1 migrated to regions 2 and 3 in the mixed-cations composition of the perovskite with a single halide. This hypothesis was confirmed through time-offlight secondary-ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) mapping (fig.  S2 ). Upon extending the aging duration to 1000 hours (supplementary materials), we observed crystal phase transformation in the film. In addition to the cubic perovskite peak (14.0°), two extra diffraction peaks at 9.7°and 11.6°were dominant in the x-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns (figs. S3 and S4), which indicates the formation of nonphotoactive d-CsPbI 3 and d-FAPbI 3 phases  (18, 33, 34) . To correlate the composition of each region to its crystal structure, we conducted 2D TOF-SIMS mapping on the fully degraded film. The Cs distribution (Fig.  1I ) showed domains at the scale of several to several tens of micrometers, which occurred in parallel to FA seg-regation (Fig.  1J ). The separated Cs/FA domains were also spatially complementary as expected (Fig.  1K ), given the binary cation nature of the perovskite system. Moreover, depth-dependent TOF-SIMS measurement (Fig.  1 , L to N) showed that vertical direction distribution was relatively uniform, so cations at different depths of the bulk ag-gregated in a manner similar as that at the surface (fig.  S5 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6790</offset>
      <text> Cation segregation dynamics by the Schelling model On the basis of the XRD, PL mapping, and TOF-SIMS results, we argue that the degradation of the binary system follows the route 2 of 8 from cation aggregation to phase transition (Fig.  2A ). Local aggregation of cations initiates phase transition that leads to the complete process of phase segregation. The thermodynamic driving force for the phase segregation was investigated by means of density functional theory (DFT) calculations (fig.  S6 ). DFT results identified that the FA 0.89 Cs 0.11 PbI 3 perovskite exhibited an energy change of only -0.133 kJ mol -1 from the homogeneous distribution to cation aggregation (Fig.  2A , stage 1), which is possibly due to the reduction in interfaces between the FA and Cs domains. However, in the subsequent process, the segregated domains experienced phase transition to form d-FAPbI 3 and d-CsPbI 3 phases (Fig.  2A , stage 2), in which the energy change of -9.427 kJ mol -1 acted as the energy sink corresponding for the irreversible segregation. Our observations showed that cation aggregation occurred before phase transition, which provides an opportunity to intervene before d-phase formation occurs  (20, 21) . The Schelling model of segregation can be applied to isolated particles (such as molecules or ions) on the basis of a few simple physical assumptions (see supplementary text S1)  (27) . We adapted the Schelling model to study the cation dynamics in perovskite films by means of a Monto Carlo algorithm (fig.  S7 ). Given that cations at different depths of the film aggregated in the same manner as at the surface (Fig.  1 , I to N), we simplified the simulation to a 2D case  (35, 36)  with a 100 by 100 lattice to accommodate binary cations of Cs (Fig.  1 , red particles) and FA (Fig.  1 , blue particles) that could randomly swap positions with neighbors. In the simulation for any step, each single cation has a probability to exchange its position with neighbors. We defined this probability as moving tendency that is the product of the thermodynamic parameter of the phase transition (h T ) and kinetic parameter of cation aggregation (h K ). DFT results revealed the phase formation energy to identify h T in the Schelling model. Particularly, h T values were assigned to be 1 for all spontaneous processes with a negative value for energy change. The kinetic parameter h K was determined by the  ion migration activation energy, depending on the cation properties and their local chemical environment. In a particular scenario for simulation, we simply normalized the migration activation energy for different cations from DFT or experimental results to obtain h K ranging from 0 to 1. To provide a quantitative measure of the film homogeneity, we defined unsegregated index (U index) as the ratio of presently unsegregated Cs ions to the initially unsegregated ones. Regarding any case of interest, the heavier segregation can be reflected on the smaller U index (Fig.  2, B  and E ). The initial state of cation aggregation affected the phase segregation trajectories. We investigated phase segregation with different initial segregation percentages (ISPs), which stands for the ratio of initially segregated Cs to the total amount of Cs. The values of other core parameters are summarized in tables S1 and S2. The cation aggregation with an arbitrary ISP of 27% was simulated for clear demon-stration (Fig.  2B , case I). After 200 steps, the U index decreased from 1.00 to 0.94. After 500 and 1000 steps, the U index dropped to 0.77 and 0.59, respectively, and heavier aggregation and enlarged domains were observed (movie S1). We compared the initially more homogeneous film (case II, ISP of 2%) with the inhomogeneous one (case I) through simulation. After 200 steps, the U index for case II only dropped to 0.98 (Fig.  2C , middle left), in which the aggregation is negligible as compared with the initial state. After 500 and 1000 steps, the U index remained at 0.95 and 0.88, respectively (movie S2). With linear regression, we obtained the U index decay rate of 0.012 per 100 steps for case II, whereas that for case I is 0.041 per 100 steps. The initial homogeneous film clearly exhibited slower segregation (Fig.  2, B  and C , and fig.  S8 ), which suggests a longer lifetime in the corresponding devices. Increasing the activation energy of ion migration is proven to prolong device lifetime  (10) , which can be reflected as a lower h K in our model. Simulations for the group of films with the same initial homogeneity (ISP of 27%) but decreased h K (1, 0.8, 0.6, and 0.4) showed reduced decay rates of 0.041, 0.022, 0.017, and 0.007 per 100 steps in their linear decay regions, respectively (Fig.  2F , fig.  S9 , and table  S2 ). The initial increase of U index could be observed in some cases, in which a large number of small segregation domains were dissolved to form larger ones (supplementary materials). It reveals the determinant impact of the initial state on the segregation dynamics, which were in good agreement with the experimental data reported elsewhere  (23) . We also simulated the aggregation dynamics of ternary cation perovskites (fig.  S10 ) and 1D and 3D fused perovskites (Fig.  2, D  and E , and fig.  S11 ). For the fused perovskites (case III), the immobile large cations created barriers between each sublattice and retarded cation migration. According to previous observations  (25, 37) , we reasonably assumed the h K of large cations (yellow) to be zero. These boundaries retarded phase segregation (movie S3), and the decay rate further declined to 0.006 per 100 steps, which was just half of that of case II and in agreement with reported experimental data  (37, 38) . The stability enhancement in 1D and 3D perovskites is generally attributed to the prevention of moisture by large hydrophobic cations, but our findings suggest that retarded phase segregation is caused in part by partially immobilized cations. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12783</offset>
      <text> Initializing film homogeneity and device performance We modulated the Cs aggregation in FACs perovskite thin films with a two-step deposition process to introduce CsI when depositing the PbI 2 film in the first step (fig.  S12 )  (39) . The Coulomb interaction between the Cs + cation and the PbI 4 2--based complex led to the formation of CsI-PbI 2 colloids in solution (fig.  S13 ) and subsequent Cs-rich aggregates in the precursor film after thermal annealing at 70°C  (40) . The top-view mapping of Cs + on the PbI 2 / CsI films that were characterized by TOF-SIMS (Fig.  3A ) revealed the inhomogeneous distribution of Cs-rich domains on the micrometer scale. After the organic components were added, the CsI/PbI 2 was converted to perovskite films when annealed at 150°C. The inhomogeneous Cs + distribution was still observed with TOF-SIMS mapping (Fig.  3B ) and the PL measurements (fig.  S14 ). For less inhomogeneity, we modulated the Pb-solvent interactions by introducing a donor molecule to reduce the CsI-PbI 2 colloid size  (41) . Common Lewis bases (such as dimethyl sulfoxide) lead to strong coordination with Pb and form crystalline intermediates  (42) . To achieve a moderate coordination with Pb and disturb those crystalline intermediates, two weak donors, thiophene and selenophene, were separately added to the PbI 2 /CsI precursor solutions to grow films. The 2D TOF-SIMS mapping of both films revealed a more homogeneous distribution of Cs than that of the reference sample (Fig.  3A  and fig.  S15  for selenophene and thiophene, respectively), although the selenophene was more homogeneous. The intensity distribution analysis of CsI-PbI 2 film (Fig.  3A ) showed a reduced FWHM for the selenophene-modified film (0.04 versus 0.08 for the reference), which indicates the smaller intensity difference of Cs at each scanning point (~0.1 by 0.1 mm 2 ). In addition, the x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) mapping (fig.  S16 ) showed a narrow intensity variation in the modified film, which also demonstrated an enhanced film homogeneity. No phase structure difference was detected from the XRD patterns (fig.  S17A ). As expected, the resultant perovskite film (selenophene modified) was more uniform than the reference (Fig.  3B ), with the FWHM of the perovskite peak from XRD patterns at 14.0°decreasing from 0.19 to 0.14 (fig.  S17B ). No obvious phase segregation was detected in the PL mapping measurement for the modified film (fig.  S14 ). We studied the interaction between selenophene and Pb in the precursor solution with several methods. Carbon nuclear magnetic resonance ( 13 C-NMR) revealed that the chemical shift of the a carbon in selenophene at 131.95 parts per million (ppm) moved downfield to 132.05 ppm, which is indicative of chemical bonding between selenium (Se) and PbI 2 (fig.  S19 ). Extended x-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS) spectra of the Pb L 3 -edge (fig.  S20  and table  S3 ) showed that the coordination numbers of Pb in Pb-I before and after the introduction of selenophene were 4.2 ± 0.6 and 3.6 ± 0.5, respectively. The EXAFS results are not conclusive because of its limited sensitivity but are in line with the 13 C-NMR results, which is indicative of an interaction between Pb and Se in the precursor  (43) . Dynamic light scattering (DLS) showed that the mean colloidal size decreased from 622 nm in the reference to 552 nm (Fig.  3C ). We argue that selenophene interacted with Pb to disturb the formation of large colloid clusters in the precursor. As compared with large clusters, smaller clusters effectively diluted the aggregation of Cs, which mitigated the heterogeneity in the resultant film. A series of devices, with the configuration of indium-doped tin oxide (ITO)/SnO 2 / Cs 0.1 FA 0.9 PbI 3 /2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-di(4methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene (Spiro-OMeTAD)/Au, were fabricated by tuning the initial film homogeneity (fig.  S22 ), and the current-voltage (J-V) curves of champion devices are shown in fig.  S23  with the key parameters summarized in table S4. On the basis of the enhanced initial film homogeneity with selenophene, the device performance improved from 20.9 to 23.4% (0.08 cm 2 , average PCE from 20.1 to 22.6%). We observed improved photoelectronic properties in the resultant device with suppressed carrier recombination (fig.  S24 ), lower trap density (fig.  S25 ), enhanced mobility (fig.  S25 ), and better charge extraction (fig.  S26 ). With further optimization, the device with an active area of 1.00 cm 2 showed a certified PCE of 23.7% (reverse scan), with an open-circuit voltage (V oc ) of 1.14 V, a short-circuit current density (J sc ) of 24.7 mA per cm 2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 0.84 (Fig.  3D ). The device was also subjected to continuous illumination by holding at 1.03 V and achieved a stabilized efficiency of 22.4% after 300 s in ambient atmosphere without encapsulation (fig.  S27 ). The absorber films with improved initial homogeneity (with selenophene) exhibited enhanced stability as compared with the reference film. We conducted in situ PL mapping measurements to the films during aging under thermal treatment. After 20 min of thermal aging in an ambient atmosphere at 80°C, the reference sample exhibited two emissive regions, of which the ones at ~785 nm grew larger (Fig.  3, E  and F ). This change was most likely caused by the formation of Cs-rich and Cs-poor domains, in which the local Cs-FA stoichiometry deviated from that in the pristine films. By contrast, the perovskite film with enhanced initial homogeneity exhibited a constant and uniform emission at 794 nm with retarded Cs aggregation. These results were confirmed by means of TOF-SIMS mapping (Fig.  3G ) of films after aging for 144 hours. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images also revealed that the initially segregated film underwent substantial morphology changes after the thermal treatment, whereas no obvious changes were observed for the selenophene-treated film (fig.  S28 ). The homogeneous films also exhibited enhanced light stability. After aging under continuous illumination for 144 hours in an N 2 -filled glovebox, notable morphology changes occurred in the reference at the grain boundaries as shown in SEM images (fig.  S29, A  and B ), and the d-FAPbI 3 phase was identified by means of XRD (fig.  S29, C  and D ). By contrast, no obvious morphology change occurred on the homogeneous films, and we observed a retarded formation of d-FAPbI 3 . The 2D PL mapping measurements show that the PL peak of reference film exhibited blue shift from 790 to 785 nm with the emergence of nonphotoactive regions, possibly owing to the formation of d-FAPbI 3 . However, the film with improved initial homogeneity showed only slight changes of the peak position and distribution, which illustrates the enhanced light stability (fig.  S30 ). The DFT simulations suggested that the remaining selenophene can benefit the suppressing of Cs migration with increased activation energy (fig.  S31 ). XPS data showed that after being stored in the ambient environment for 12 hours, the perovskite films still exhibited the symmetric peaks of Pb (II) at 138.5 and 143.4 eV that are attributed to Pb 4f 7/2 and Pb 4f 5/2 , respectively. It indicates that the film surface was protected from oxidation, which may have originated from the coordination of residual selenophene (fig.  S32 ). However, the remaining amount is small according to the TOF-SIMS measurement (fig.  S33 ), so the enhanced film stability could be mainly attributed to the increased initial film homogeneity. Selenophene-treated perovskite devices were aged under various conditions according to the modified International Summit on Organic Photovoltaic Stability (ISOS) stability protocols  (44)  and presented enhanced stability than that of reference devices. The selenophenetreated perovskite device showed good stability without PCE degradation more than 2000 hours after being stored in the dark in an N 2 atmosphere (fig.  S34 ). The devices that were aged at 85°C in N 2 in the dark (fig.  S35 ) retained ~80% of their initial PCE after 1750 hours. When aged over 1-sun continuous illumination [light-emitting diode (LED) source, 100 mW/ cm 2 ] at open circuit, the devices could retain ~80% of their initial PCE after 960 hours (Fig.  3H  and fig.  S36 ). For the MPP test at 45°± 5°C in an N 2 atmosphere, the device retained 91% of its highest PCE after 3190 hours. In addition, the MPP test was performed at elevated temperatures in the N 2 atmosphere, and the devices retained 91 and 89% of their highest PCE after 500 hours at 65°± 5°C and 85°± 5°C, respectively (Fig.  3J  and fig.  S37 ). For mixed-halide perovskites, the main device issue has been the poor light stability. We fabricated FACsPb(Br 0.13 I 0.87 ) 3 of a bandgap of 1.66 eV with different initial halide segregation. We compared 2D TOF-SIMS mapping on the absorber films, which were subjected to continuous light illumination for 24 hours at 45°± 5°C in an N 2 -filled glovebox. The film without severe initial segregation that was fabricated under the protocol that is reported elsewhere (45) (supplementary materials, materials and methods) retained a homogeneous I - distribution (Fig.  4, A  and B ). However, for the film with heavier initial segregation, the larger I --deficient regions (~5 mm) were identified on the resultant film (Fig.  4, C  and D ). In addition, we conducted in situ PL mapping as films were being aged under light illumination. Similar to cation segregation, the film with initially homogeneous halide distribution showed better stability under continuous illumination (Fig.  4, E  and F ). By contrast, the film with heavier initial halide segregation showed a marked change on the PL mapping spectra (Fig.  4 , G and H, and fig.  S38 ). We observed that the width of longer-wavelength regions (Fig.  4 , G and H, yellow) was increased from ~3 to 6 mm. Moreover, the emission peak was clearly redshifted from 739 to 751 nm (Fig.  4 , G and H, circled region), which indicates the fast halide segregation. The Schelling model simulation results are in good agreement with the experimental observation. As shown in Fig.  4 , I to K, the segregated case (ISP = 28%), presented a decay rate of 0.040 per 100 steps, which is more than four times higher than that of the initially homogeneous film of 0.008 per 100 steps (ISP = 3%). We further fabricated devices based on these two absorbers, which showed PCEs of 18.78% (homogeneous films) and 17.93% (reference), respectively, as shown in fig.  S39 . The mixed halide device with initially homogeneous halide distribution achieved an impressive operational stability during the MPP test at 45°± 5°C in N 2 , which retained 80% of its initial PCE after 340 hours (168 hours for the reference device). To date, this stability result is among the best device operational lifetimes (T 80 ) based on mixed halide perovskites  (46) . In addition, at an elevated temperature of 85°± 5°C, the mixed halide perovskite device with improved homogeneity achieved a T 80 lifetime of 80 hours (fig.  S40 ). We have demonstrated that the Schelling model is a powerful tool to bridge theoretical analysis of perovskites at the atomic scale and macroscale observations of their phase separation and film degradation. From simulation and experiment results, we found that the initial film homogeneity, in terms of elemental distribution, has shown substantial influence on film and device stability. Benefiting from homogeneous films by tailoring precursor chemistry with selenophene, we developed high-performance devices based on mixed perovskites that achieved a long-term stability during the MPP test even at elevated temperatures.  &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">tin dioxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:48:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="16538" length="6"/>
        <text>/SnO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs0.1FA0.9PbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:48:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="16547" length="19"/>
        <text>Cs 0.1 FA 0.9 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:48:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="16638" length="12"/>
        <text>Spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20.9</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:49:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="16963" length="4"/>
        <text>20.9</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:49:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="16971" length="5"/>
        <text>23.4%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:58:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="20852" length="8"/>
        <text>t 85°C i</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:01:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="20862" length="15"/>
        <text>N 2 in the dark</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">80</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="20901" length="3"/>
        <text>80%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1750</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T03:58:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="20932" length="10"/>
        <text>1750 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:05:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="20959" length="97"/>
        <text>1-sun continuous illumination [light-emitting diode (LED) source, 100 mW/ cm 2 ] at open circuit,</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">80</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:16Z</infon>
        <location offset="21083" length="3"/>
        <text>80%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">960</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:05:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="21114" length="9"/>
        <text>960 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">45+-5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="21172" length="8"/>
        <text>45°± 5°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:02:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="21281" length="69"/>
        <text>MPP test was performed at elevated temperatures in the N 2 atmosphere</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">91</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="21377" length="2"/>
        <text>91</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">89</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="21384" length="3"/>
        <text>89%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:02:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="21415" length="9"/>
        <text>500 hours</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65+-5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:54:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="21428" length="8"/>
        <text>65°± 5°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">85</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:03:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="21441" length="8"/>
        <text>85°± 5°C</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R4">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:54Z</infon>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24598</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods Materials PbI2, CsI, anhydrous N, N-dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), isopropanol (IPA), chlorobenzene (CB), acetonitrile, bis(trifluoromethane) sulfonimide lithium salt (LiTFSI), 4-tert-bultypyridine, hydrochloric acid (HCl, 37 wt. % in water), thioglycolic acid (TGA, 98%), urea, and SnCl2•2H2O (&gt;99.995%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Methylammonium iodide (MAI), Methylammonium chloride (MACl), n-Octylammonium Iodide (OAI), HC(NH2)2I (FAI), 4-methoxy-phenethylammonium-iodide, and phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI), were purchased from GreatCell Solar. 2,2',7,7'-tetrakis-(N,N-di-4methoxyphenylamino)-9,9'-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) was purchased from Lumetec. SnO2 (15% in H2O colloidal dispersion) was purchased from Alfa Aesar. PTAA was purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology in China. Selenophene was purchased from TCI. All chemicals were used as received without further purification. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25552</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25562</offset>
      <text> Device Fabrication: The ITO/FTO substrate was sequentially washed with distilled water, acetone, ethanol, and isopropanol. For small area devices, after 30 minutes of UV-O3 treatment of ITO, the SnO2 electron transport layers (ETLs) were fabricated on ITO substrates by spin-casting with SnO2 solution (3%, diluted by water) at 4000 r.p.m. for 30 s, and annealed in ambient air at 150 °C for 30 min. For large area device, the SnO2 layer was formed by the chemical bath deposition.137.5 mg of SnCl2•2H2O, 625 mg of urea, 12.5 μL of TGA, and 625 μL of HCl was added in 50 ml of deionized water. And FTO glass substrates were dipped into the preheated solution for 4 h at 90 o C. After that, the substrates were washed by IPA and deionized water. Then, the substrates were annealed for 1 h at 170 °C before use. Mixed cation perovskite film fabrication: The perovskite film was fabricated by a two-step solution process: the PbI2 (1.5M, dissolved in DMF/DMSO (9:1, vol:vol)) mixed with CsI (5%, 10% and 15% molar ratio) was spin-coated on SnO2 at 1500 r.p.m. for 30 s and annealed at 70 °C for 1 min in a nitrogen glovebox, for the modified precursor the selenophene was added into the PbI2/CsI with molar ratio of 0.75% (mol:mol, selenophene:PbI2). After cooling the PbI2-coated substrate to room temperature in a nitrogen glovebox, a mixed organic cation solution (FAI: MACl, 90 mg: 9 mg) in 1 mL isopropanol (IPA) was spin-coated at 1900 r.p.m. for 30 s and then annealed at 150 °C for 15 min in air. For the large area device, the procedure is similar to that of small area devices (as described above) with modified PbI2 precursor [1.5M PbI2, dissolved in DMF/DMSO (9:1, v/v) mixed with CsI (3%, mol:mol, CsI:PbI2) and selenophene (0.23%, mol:mol, selenophene:PbI2)] and modified mixed organic cation solution, and the film was annealed at 170 °C for 15 min in ambient air. In particular, all the process are conducted with RH &lt; 20% and ideally no higher than Then, 80 nm (200 nm for stability test) Au was deposited using thermal evaporation. The device area of 0.0805 cm 2 and 1.0034 cm 2 was determined by a metal mask. Ageing Condition: Continuous illumination (LED source) for 1000 h in ambient environment with humidity of 30~50% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27816</offset>
      <text> Material and Device Characterization Scanning electron microscope (SEM) images were characterized by Hitachi S4800 field-emission scanning electron microscopy. XRD patterns were recorded on a Rigaku Smartlab X-ray Diffractometer. Photoluminescence (PL) were measured by FLS980 (Edinburgh Instruments Ltd) with an excitation at 470 nm. NMR spectra were measured using a Bruker AVANCE III 300 MHz NMR Spectrometer in the designated deuterated solvent. The J-V curves was recorded by a Keithley 2400 source-measure system, and the illumination intensity was 100 mW/cm 2 (AM 1.5G 3A solar simulator). The scan rate was 0.1 V s -1 (step: 0.02 V, delay time: 200 ms) by reverse scanning from 1.26 V to -0.1 V. For the large area device, the J-V curve was measured by the fourterminal method and certified by National Institute of Metrology (China). The power output of the lamp was calibrated with a National Institute of Metrology (China) calibrated KG5-filtered Si reference cell. The effective device area was defined by metal masks (0.0805 &amp; 1.00355 cm 2 ) during the measurement. The device stability test was performed based on the small area devices with LED light source. Dynamic light scattering analysis was performed on a NanoBrook Omni instrument (Bruker) to study the precursor chemistry. PL mappings were measured by a Confocal Microscopy (SPCM-1000) supported by Enli Technology Co., Ltd. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements were carried out on the PHI QUANTERA-II SXM (ULVAC-PHI, Japan) with the Al Kα radiation (1486.6 eV). ToF-SIMS measurement was performed using a PHI NanoTOF II instrument (ULVAC-PHI, Inc.), a 30 keV Bi + pulsed primary ion beam was used for the analysis. ToF-SIMS depth-profile analysis measurement was performed using a PHI NanoTOF II instrument (ULVAC-PHI, Inc.), where a 3 kV Ar ion beam was used for erosion and a 25 keV Bi + pulsed primary ion beam was used for the analysis. The area of analysis was 100 × 100 μm 2 while the sputtering area was 400 × 400 μm 2 . The Pb &amp; Se concentration was detected using an ICP-MS instrument (Thermo iCAP RQ). The XAFS spectra (Pb L3-edge) of the samples were acquired at the 1W1B beamline in the BSRF. The X-ray beam was monochromatized with a Si (111) double-crystal monochromator. To suppress the high harmonic content, a detuning of about 10% was performed. While the energy was calibrated using a Pb foil, the XAFS data were collected using a fluorescence model through an Ar-filled Lytle detector at room temperature. In addition, the spectra of the reference PbI2 was measured in the transmission mode using a standard 25% Ar-filled ionization chamber. Following the standard procedures, the acquired XAFS raw data were processed by the Athena module of the IFEFFIT software package in a series of ways, such as postedge background subtracted, normalized, and Fourier transformed  (48) . Then, least-squares curve parameter fitting was performed by the Artemis module to obtain the quantitative structural parameters around Pb atoms. The amplitude reduction factor was obtained by fitting PbI2, in which coordination numbers (CNs) were fixed as the nominal values. In the subsequent fitting of the Pb L3-edge of sample, the obtained was fixed, while the CNs, internal atomic distances R, the edge-energy shift ΔE0, and Debye-Waller factor σ were allowed to vary freely. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31193</offset>
      <text> First-principles Density Functional Theory Calculation The results were calculated using the density functional theory (DFT) implementation available in the Vienna Ab-initio Simulation Package (VASP). Several models of 3×3×2 supercells with two FA molecular substituted by Cs atom were established to get the density of α-Cs0.11FA0.89PbI3. And the number of stoichiometric units of pure a phase is consistent with that in α-Cs0.11FA0.89PbI3: 18 units. The generalized gradient approximation (GGA) and projected augmented wave (PAW) were used for the structural relaxation and formation energy calculations. The kinetic energy cutoff is set to be 500 eV. The k-mesh by Monkhorst-Pack grids of (2 2 3) were used for the reciprocal space of the structure. The geometry structures are sufficiently relaxed until the forces on each atom are smaller than 0.01 eV Å -1 . The formation energy of the products during the phase transition was obtained by the following expression: △E = Etot[i] -Etot[α-CsxFA(1-x)PbI3], where i is the transition product, such as α-CsPbI3 and α-FAPbI3, δ-CsPbI3 and α-FAPbI3, δ-CsPbI3 and δ-FAPbI3. The physical explanation of the Schelling model on interface construction of a binary system. To        The decay rates are 0.041, 0.022, 0.017, and 0.007 per 100 steps, respectively. The detail information for simulation is presented in Table  S1&amp;S2 . To be note, the increase of U index was observed in some case, which is due to the aggregation of small segregation domains into larger ones. In the beginning, there are a large number of segregation domains with small size. It leads to sufficient domain edges, which contain segregated Cs to swap out and become unsegregated ones. With the development of segregation, small domains reduce, and less edge Cs are available to become unsegregated ones. It results in the subsequent increase of U index.   S1&amp;S2 .   S1&amp;S2 .           S3 ) Similarly, when the selenophene was added into the PbI2/CsI precursor, the coordination numbers for both Pb-I and Pb-O also changed. In combination with 13 C-NMR results, we find selenophene may compete with I and/or solvent molecule to coordinate with Pb. In addition, we observed negligible change in the XANES spectra for the precursor when selenophene was introduced. It indicates that the majority of selenophene might serve as ligands for the Pb-I-DMSO colloid, which disturb the formation of large clusters (Fig.  3C ). Therefore, Cs + can be dispersed more evenly because they anchor with smaller (but more) clusters. It thus suppresses the aggregation of Cs for improved homogeneity in the resultant film.            Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) identified that a small amount of selenophene residue remained after perovskite film formation, with a Se:Pb molar ratio of about 1:2800. Combining with XRD (Fig.  S17B ), we suggest that the residual selenophene is likely to reside at the grain boundaries and interfaces.          Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Degradation mechanisms for binary FACs perovskites. (A to H) 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) of perovskite film before (A) and after (E) degradation. [(B) and (F)] PL spectra of selected regions from (A) and (E), respectively. [(C), (D), (G), and (H)] The corresponding 2D PL intensity and FWHM mapping spectra of (A) and (E). a.u., arbitrary units. (I to K) The (I) Cs and (J) FA intensity mapping for the degraded film measured with TOF-SIMS and (K) the overlay mapping spectra. Scale bar, 10 mm. (L to N) 3D topographic of Cs and FA for the degraded films measured by TOF-SIMS. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34784</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Schelling model simulations of cation segregation dynamics. (A) Energy change of the degradation processes from a uniform distribution to phase segregation to d-phases, by means of DFT. (B to D) Simulations of segregation process on the basis of the Schelling model. (B) An initially segregated distribution (case I, ISP = 27%). (C) An initially less segregated distribution (case II, ISP = 2%). (D) A 1D and 3D (or 2D and 3D) fused system (case III, ISP = 2%). (E and F) U index evolution of red particles (indicates Cs) derived from (E) cases I to III and (F) cases with different moving tendencies. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35407</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Film homogeneity of mixed cation perovskite and the impacts. (A and B) 2D TOF-SIMS mapping of Cs + for (A) the first step of PbI 2 /CsI film fabricated by reference and selenophene-modified precursor solutions and (B) perovskite films fabricated by reference and modified precursor solutions, as well as the corresponding intensity distribution. (C) Colloid size distribution in the perovskite precursor solutions obtained from DLS. (D) J-V curves of the champion devices from homogeneous film with an active area of 1 cm 2 . (E and F) In situ 2D PL mapping spectra evolution of perovskite films (E) before and (F) after aging under 80°C thermal treatment in an ambient environment with a relative humidity of 40% and the corresponding statistics diagrams. (G) 2D TOF-SIMS mappings of perovskite films (Cs) after continuous thermal treatment in an N 2 -filled glovebox at 85°C for 144 hours with the corresponding statistics diagrams. (H) Time-dependent PCE measurements under continuous light illumination (LED source with 100 mW/cm 2 ) held at the open circuit in an N 2 atmosphere. (I and J) MPP tracking of devices under 100 mW/cm 2 LED source in an N 2 -filled glovebox without encapsulation at (I) 45°± 5°C and (J) elevated temperatures of 65°± 5°C and 85°± 5°C. MPPT, MPP tracking. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36728</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Film homogeneity of mixed halide perovskite and the impacts. (A to D) 2D TOF-SIMS mapping of [(A) and (C)] I -in the mixed halide perovskite films (A) without and (C) with initial segregation and [(B) and (D)] perovskite films aged under continuous light illumination at 45°± 5°C in an N 2 -filled glovebox for 24 hours (B) without and (D) with severe initial iodide segregation. (E to H) In situ 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) evolution of perovskite films [(E) and (F)] without and [(G) and (H)] &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37254</offset>
      <text> Figs. S1 to S40 Tables S1 to S4 References (48, 49) Movies S1 to S3 Submitted 17 November 2021; resubmitted 1 July 2022 Accepted 19 October 2022 10.1126/science.abn3148 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37425</offset>
      <text> 20 o C before thermal annealing. Then, a 4-methoxy-phenethylammonium-iodide solution with concentration of 5 mg/mL in IPA (or an OAI solution with concentration of 6 mg/mL in IPA for the films and devices exhibited thermal stability tests) was spin-coated onto the perovskite surface at a spin rate of 5000 r.p.m. Mixed halide perovskite film fabrication: PbI2 (1.20 M), PbBr2 (0.28 M), CsI (0.28 M), FAI (1.20 M) and MAPbCl3 (0.07 M) were dissolved into a DMF:DMSO (4:1 vol:vol) mixed solvent, The perovskite solutions were spin-cast at 5000 r.p.m. for 30 s with a accelerate speed of 4000 r.p.m. s -1 while 100 μL CB was sequentially dropped on the films at the last 5 s. Then the wet perovskite films were annealed at 100 °C for 30 minutes on the hotplate (Ref sample) or at 100 °C for 3 minutes on the preheated liquid medium (LMA sample). (45) Hole transporting materials deposition: A 30 μL of spiro-OMeTAD solution, containing of 72.3 mg Spiro-OMeTAD, 30 μL of 4 tert-butylpyridine and 35 μL Li-TFSI (260 mg Li-TSFI in 1 mL acetonitrile) in 1 mL of chlorobenzene, were spin-coated on the perovskite layer at 3000 rpm for 30 s. For device stability tests, a PTAA/Spiro-OMeTAD mixed hole transport layer was used. The PTAA solution (10 mg/mL in chlorobenzene containing 10 μL of 4 tert-butylpyridine and 10 μL Li-TFSI) mixed with Spiro-OMeTAD solution (1:1, v/v) and was deposited onto the perovskite layer at 3000 rpm for 30 s. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38869</offset>
      <text> simulate the continuous material behavior, the Schelling model was considered as a finite difference version of a general continuous model, in which the frequency of same colored particle(s) is converted into angular form. As shown in the schematic pictures, one neighboring particle corresponds to 45 o angular coverage. For any convex cluster at an infinitely small region, as shown in Fig. E, its surface experiences a tangential force, which tends to flatten the surface to θ=180 o , thus the similarity threshold equals 0.5. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39402</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 . S2 Fig. S2. Element distribution of the binary cation FACs perovskite film at the early stage of degradation. (A) Photo of the film sample at the early state of degradation with several colorless regions on the black film, and the corresponding colorless region was observed in the microscope image. The corresponding 2D mapping of (B) Cs, (C) FA, and (D) Pb intensity measured by ToF-SIMS, and the (E) overlay spectra, the scale bar is 10 μm. This result showed that the degradation of the mixed FACs film was initially from the Cs aggregation and the following phase transition, as the colorless region showed strong Cs intensity. The formation of boundaries was simultaneously observed from the mapping of Pb as labeled in the red square, which showed lower intensity. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40187</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. The degradation of a binary FACs perovskite film with initially phase segregation. The 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) of the reference perovskite film before (A) and after (D) degradation. (B) and (E) The PL spectra of selected region from (A) and (D). (C) and (F) The corresponded 2D PL mapping spectra of intensity of (A) and (D). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40548</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. (A) The 3D topographic of Cs, FA, and Pb for the degraded films measured by ToF-SIMS. (B) The corresponding profile data which indicated that the detection at the vertical direction included the whole film thickness as the intensity signal of In and Sn only showed slight increasement after 3500 s. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40871</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. The theoretical analysis of cation aggregation and phase transition. The schematic of the degradation process and the example of a cell of a (A) periodic structure, (B) segregated structure, and δ phase structures of (C) CsPbI3 and (D) FAPbI3. (E) Calculated formation energy change of key processes for FACs perovskite films during the degradation process. In the modelling, 2 out of 18 lattice A-sites were occupied by Cs ions corresponding to a mixed perovskite CsxFA1-xPbI3 with x=1/9 (as close as possible to the experimentally observed composition). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41452</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. A schematic of the core parameters incorporated into the Schelling model. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41550</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. The Schelling model simulation with various initial segregation percentage. The simulation of segregation process of perovskite films with various initial segregation percentage (ISP) of (A) 27%, (B) 8%, and (C) 2%, respectively. (D) The U index evolution of red particles (Cs) derived from simulation cases. The decay rates are 0.041, 0.023, and 0.012 per 100 steps, respectively, which are derived from each curve by fitting the linear decay region of U index. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42037</offset>
      <text> Fig. S9 . S9 Fig. S9. The Schelling model simulation with various ηK. The simulation of segregation process of perovskite films of initial segregated distribution with ηK of (A) 0.8, (B) 0.6, and (C) 0.4, respectively. (D) The U index evolution of red particles (Cs) derived from simulation cases (and ηK of 1.0 from Fig.2B). The yellow circles highlight the domains with similar degradation patterns. The decay rates are 0.041, 0.022, 0.017, and 0.007 per 100 steps, respectively. The detail information for simulation is presented in TableS1&amp;S2. To be note, the increase of U index was observed in some case, which is due to the aggregation of small segregation domains into larger ones. In the beginning, there are a large number of segregation domains with small size. It leads to sufficient domain edges, which contain segregated Cs to swap out and become unsegregated ones. With the development of segregation, small domains reduce, and less edge Cs are available to become unsegregated ones. It results in the subsequent increase of U index. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43091</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. The application of the Schelling model simulation on a ternary cation system. The (A) Cs, (B) FA, and (C) MA intensity mapping analysis for the ternary cation perovskite film measured by ToF-SIMS. (D-F) The cations intensity mapping analysis after ageing under ambient environment with humidity of 30~40% RH with continuous thermal treatment of 35 o C for 144 h, the scale bar is 10 μm. (G) The Schelling model simulation results based on the MA (yellow)/FA (blue)/Cs (red) ternary cation perovskite system, in which the red particles (Cs) show aggregation at some regions, meanwhile the yellow particles (MA) remain uniformly distributed. The ratio of MA/FA/Cs was set as 0.1:0.8:0.1. The detail information for simulation is presented in TableS1&amp;S2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43871</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. The Schelling model simulation with various sublattice sizes (SLS).The simulation of segregation process of perovskite films with various boundary conditions, and (D) The U index evolution of red particles derived from simulation cases. The degree of cation segregation is influenced by the sublattice size in the simulation. The decay rates are 0.017, 0.006, and 0.005 per 100 steps, respectively. The detail information for simulation is presented in TableS1&amp;S2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44363</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. A schematic of FACs perovskites film fabrication process based on the two-step method. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44477</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. Colloid size distribution in the corresponding precursor solutions obtained from dynamic light scattering. The introduction of CsI into PbI2 leads to the formation of CsI incorporated colloids with a colloid size of 622 nm, and the size was reduced to 552 nm after selenophene introduction. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44795</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. Modulated film homogeneity with various Cs concentrations. (A-C) 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) of perovskite films with various Cs concentrations (5%, 10% and 15% molar ratio, Cs:Pb mol:mol) and the corresponding (D-F) selenophene-modified films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45074</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. The 2D intensity mapping analysis of Cs with perovskite films fabricated by (A) reference, (B) selenophene-modified precursor, and (C) thiophene-modified precursor measured by ToF-SIMS. The scale bar is 10 μm. (D) The normalized intensity distribution derived from ToF-SIMS mappings. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45386</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. The Cs distribution analysis for the first step of PbI2/CsI film fabricated with (A) reference and (B) selenophene-modified precursor solutions measured by XPS. (C) The intensity distribution derived from the XPS mappings. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45636</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. XRD patterns of (A) CsI/PbI2 and (B) perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45718</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. The 2D intensity mapping analysis of (A) Cs, and (B) FA, for the films fabricated via a one-step method with different precursor solutions measured by ToF-SIMS. The scale bar is 10 μm. The line scan of (C) Cs and (D) FA intensity of perovskite films from (A) and (B), respectively. The scan lines are shown on the mapping figures. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46077</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. The 13 C NMR spectra of selenophene, selenophene/PbI2 and selenophene/PbI2/CsI solutions. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46194</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. (A-C) The X-ray absorption near edge structure of PbI2 and PbI2/CsI DMF/DMSO precursors without/without selenophene. (D-I) The Extended x-ray absorption fine structure spectra and fits in R-space at the Pb L3-edge of PbI2 and PbI2/CsI DMF/DMSO precursors without/without selenophene. After introducing selenophene into the PbI2 precursor, the coordination number of Pb-I changed from 4.2 ± 0.6 to 3.6 ± 0.5. (TableS3) Similarly, when the selenophene was added into the PbI2/CsI precursor, the coordination numbers for both Pb-I and Pb-O also changed. In combination with13 C-NMR results, we find selenophene may compete with I and/or solvent molecule to coordinate with Pb. In addition, we observed negligible change in the XANES spectra for the precursor when selenophene was introduced. It indicates that the majority of selenophene might serve as ligands for the Pb-I-DMSO colloid, which disturb the formation of large clusters (Fig.3C). Therefore, Cs + can be dispersed more evenly because they anchor with smaller (but more) clusters. It thus suppresses the aggregation of Cs for improved homogeneity in the resultant film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47352</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. (A) A microscopy image of the detection region for the thiophene-modified perovskite film. The 2D intensity mapping analysis of (B) thiophene, (C) FA, (D) Cs, and (E) Pb compound/element as measured by ToF-SIMS. The scale bar is 10 μm. Several volcano shaped regions were formed on the surface where the residual thiophene was concentrated, which may be due to the stronger Pb-S interactions compared to Pb-Se coordination. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47804</offset>
      <text> Fig. S22 . S22 Fig. S22. The optimization of selenophene concentration. (A-E) The 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) change of perovskite films with various selenophene concentrations. (F) The efficiency distribution of devices with different selenophene concentrations, with each condition comprising of data from 32 devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48133</offset>
      <text> Fig. S23 . S23 Fig. S23. (A) The J-V curves of the champion devices from different film initial conditions. (B) The PCE distribution of devices, with data from 32 devices in each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48325</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. (A) The PL spectra of perovskite films of different conditions. (B) Normalized transient photovoltage decay curves for the PSCs. (C) Light intensity dependent Voc for PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48525</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. The J-V characteristics of the (A) hole-only and (B) electron-only space-charge-limited current (SCLC) devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48664</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 . S26 Fig. S26. Normalized transient photocurrent decay curves for the PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48752</offset>
      <text> Fig. S27 .Fig. S28 . S27S28 Fig. S27. The perovskite solar cell efficiency certificated by an accredited photovoltaic certification laboratory of 23.7%, NIM, China. The area of tested device is 100.355 mm 2 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48963</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 . S29 Fig. S29. The top-view SEM image of perovskite films aged under continuous light-illumination at 45 ± 5 o C in an N2-filled glovebox for 144 h with and without severe initial phase segregation (A and B, respectively), and (C) the corresponding XRD patterns. (D) The enlarged XRD patterns of the selected region in (C). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49300</offset>
      <text> Fig. S30 . S30 Fig. S30. (A and B) The 2D PL mapping spectra (wavelength) evolution of perovskite films with and without severe phase segregation under continuous light-illumination with 45 ± 5 o C in N2 filled glove box, and the corresponding statistics diagrams. (C) The 2D ToF-SIMS mapping of perovskite films (Cs) after aged under illumination with the corresponding statistics diagrams. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49695</offset>
      <text> Fig. S31 . S31 Fig. S31. (A) Energy profiles along the migration paths of Cs in CsxFA1-xPbI3 with and without selenophene modification. The structure transition at each migration stage (B) with, and (C)without selenophene modification, respectively. The DFT simulation was conducted to calculate the activation energy for Cs migration based on the assumption that selenophene is located at the interfaces/grain-boundaries of the film. 2×2×3 supercells with two FA molecules substituted by Cs atoms and one substituted by a vacancy were established with and without selenophene absorbed at the top-surface. The generalized gradient approximation (GGA) and projected augmented wave (PAW) were used for the structure relaxation and formation energy calculations. The Cs migration paths were investigated by the climbing image-nudged elastic band (CI-NEB) method, and four points evenly distributed between the initial and final states were selected for each migration process. As shown in Fig.S31, 0.55 eV (as activation energy) is required for one Cs atom to migrate and meet another Cs atom without selenophene. When the selenophene is involved, the activation energy increased to 0.80 eV. Therefore, in the resultant perovskite film, the residual selenophene could retard the phase segregation by increasing the energy barrier for Cs migration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51044</offset>
      <text> Fig. S32 . S32 Fig. S32. The XPS spectra of a perovskite film (A) before and (B) after aging, with and without selenophene. (C) Photos of PbI2/CsI precursor solutions with and without selenophene after being stored in ambient environment for 7 days. The perovskite films with/without selenophene exhibited the symmetric peaks of Pb (II) at 138.5 and 143.4 eV, respectively, which were attributed to Pb 4f7/2 and Pb 4f5/2 associated with Pb(II)-I (49). However, after storing in the ambient environment for 12 h, the symmetric peaks of Pb (II) in the reference film shifted to 137.9 and 142.8 eV, which is attributed to Pb(II)-O. In contrast, for the selenophene-modified film, the peaks still located at 138.5 and 143.4 eV. These indicate that the oxidization of perovskite could be suppressed by selenophene. Similar antioxidation phenomena was also observed in the precursor solutions. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51934</offset>
      <text> Fig. S33 . S33 Fig. S33. The ToF-SIMS depth-profile of FACs perovskite films fabricated with selenophenemodified precursor, indicating the tiny amount of residual selenophene in the perovskite film.Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) identified that a small amount of selenophene residue remained after perovskite film formation, with a Se:Pb molar ratio of about 1:2800. Combining with XRD (Fig.S17B), we suggest that the residual selenophene is likely to reside at the grain boundaries and interfaces. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52458</offset>
      <text> Fig. S34 . S34 Fig. S34. PCE tracking of devices stored inside an N2 atmosphere in the dark. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52553</offset>
      <text> Fig. S35 . S35 Fig. S35. The evolution of key parameters of perovskite devices under continuous thermal annealing at 85 o C in an N2 atmosphere. 3 devices were tested under each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52744</offset>
      <text> Fig. S36 . S36 Fig. S36. The evolution of key parameters of perovskite devices aged under continuous light illumination (LED source with 100 mW/cm 2 ) held at the open circuit in an N2 atmosphere. 3 devices were tested under each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52987</offset>
      <text> Fig. S37 . S37 Fig. S37. MPP tracking of Se-modified devices under 100 mW/cm 2 LED source at elevated temperatures of 65 ± 5 o C and 85 ± 5 o C. 3 devices were tested under each condition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53180</offset>
      <text> Fig. S38 . S38 Fig.S38. The evolution of PL spectra of (A) initially segregated film and (B) initially homogeneous film under continuous light illumination. After 24 h illumination, the PL peak of initially segregated film dramatically shifted from 749 nm to 765 nm. In contrast, the film with improved initial homogeneity, the PL shift shifted from 749 to 758 nm after 24 h illumination. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53571</offset>
      <text> Fig. S39 . S39 Fig. S39. The J-V curves of FACsPb(Br0.13I0.87)3 perovskite devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53657</offset>
      <text> Fig. S40 . 11 Figure S4011 Fig. S40. MPP tracking of the FACsPb(Br0.13I0.87)3 perovskite solar cell under 100 mW/cm 2 LED source in N2-filled glovebox without encapsulation at 85 o C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53843</offset>
      <text> Fitting range: 2.5 ≤ k (/Å) ≤10 and 1 ≤ R (Å) ≤ 3.0. c Fitting range: 2.4 ≤ k (/Å) ≤ 10.0 and 1.0 ≤ R (Å) ≤ 3.2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53978</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 Pb L3-edge EXAFS curve Fitting Parameters N, coordination number; R, distance between absorber and backscatter atoms; , Debye-Waller factor to account for both thermal and structural disorders; ΔE0, inner potential correction; R factor (%) indicates the goodness of the fit. was fixed to 0.77 as determined from PbI2 fitting. Bold numbers indicate fixed coordination number (N) according to the crystal structure. b Sample Path Coordination R (Å) σ (Å ) ΔE0 (eV) R, % Number (N) PbI2 b Pb-I 6 3.18 ± 0.01 0.015 ± 0.001 -1.3 ± 0.5 0.2 PbI2 c Pb-O 1.1 ± 0.3 2.47 ± 0.01 0.005 ± 0.001 -10.2 ± 0.6 0.2 Pb-I 4.2 ± 0.6 2.96 ± 0.01 0.016 ± 0.002 PbI2/CsI c Pb-O 0.3 ± 0.1 2.53 ± 0.01 0.005 ± 0.001 -8.3 ± 0.5 0.2 Pb-I 3.2 ± 0.3 2.97 ± 0.01 0.011 ± 0.002 PbI2/CsI+Sel c Pb-O 0.2 ± 0.1 2.54 ± 0.04 0.005 ± 0.001 -7.9 ± 0.6 0.6 Pb-I 3.1 ± 0.3 2.97 ± 0.01 0.011 ± 0.001 PbI2 + Sel b Pb-O 1.1 ± 0.3 2.49 ± 0.01 0.005 ± 0.001 -9.1 ± 0.7 0.3 Pb-I 3.6 ± 0.5 2.96 ± 0.01 0.015 ± 0.002 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54999</offset>
      <text>			 of 8 RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55136</offset>
      <text>			 of &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55144</offset>
      <text>			 RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLEDownloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55275</offset>
      <text>			 of 8 RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:54Z</infon>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="2" role=""/>
      <node refid="1" role=""/>
      <node refid="18" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:54Z</infon>
      <node refid="19" role=""/>
      <node refid="20" role=""/>
      <node refid="23" role=""/>
      <node refid="22" role=""/>
      <node refid="1" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R3">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:54Z</infon>
      <node refid="19" role=""/>
      <node refid="21" role=""/>
      <node refid="22" role=""/>
      <node refid="24" role=""/>
      <node refid="1" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
