<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025049277GEFEHE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 135&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Stabilized hole-selective layer for high-performance inverted p-i-n perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>104</offset>
      <text>P-i-n geometry perovskite solar cells (PSCs) offer simplified fabrication, greater amenability to charge extraction layers, and low-temperature processing over n-i-p counterparts. Self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) can enhance the performance of p-i-n PSCs but ultrathin SAMs can be thermally unstable. We report a thermally robust hole-selective layer comprised of nickel oxide (NiO x ) nanoparticle film with a surface-anchored (4-(3,11-dimethoxy-7H-dibenzo[c,g]carbazol-7-yl)butyl)phosphonic acid (MeO-4PADBC) SAM that can improve and stabilize the NiO x /perovskite interface. The energetic alignment and favorable contact and binding between NiO x /MeO-4PADBC and perovskite reduced the voltage deficit of PSCs with various perovskite compositions and led to strong interface toughening effects under thermal stress. The resulting 1.53-electronvolt devices achieved 25.6% certified power conversion efficiency and maintained &gt;90% of their initial efficiency after continuously operating at 65 degrees Celsius for 1200 hours under 1-sun illumination.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1157</offset>
      <text>P hosphonic acid self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) with a carbazole core have enabled performance advances in perovskite solar cells (PSCs), for both singlejunction (1-4) and perovskite-based tandem solar cells  (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) , because of their high hole selectivity, fast hole transfer rate, and low interfacial trap state density  (10) (11) (12) (13) . However, compared with conventional polymeric and metal oxide hole transporting materials, SAMbased PSCs have exhibited poorer thermal stability  (14) (15) (16) (17) (18) . The investigation of the device's operational stability, with electrical bias under maximum power point (MPP) operation or at open-circuit voltage (V OC ), under elevated temperatures (65Â°to 85Â°C) is critical to improve the confidence in their stability and to meet the qualification of international stability standards (i.e., International Summit on Organic Photovoltic Stability (ISOS) and International Electrotechnical Commission 61215 standards)  (19) . Whereas most studies on the SAM-based PSCs have reported the operational stability at room temperature or enhanced the device's durability under thermal stress by stabilizing perovskite surface and bulk  (20, 21) , the degradation effect of SAM-forming molecules under elevated tem-perature (&gt;65Â°C) have rarely been discussed (fig.  S1  and table  S1 ). The thermal stability of SAM-forming molecules depends largely on their bonding to the selected substrates, as the bond between the anchoring group and the spacer of the molecule can be broken through temperature-induced desorption  (22) (23) (24) (25) . We report a new SAM, (4-(3,11-dimethoxy-7H-dibenzo[c,g]carbazol-7-yl)butyl)phosphonic acid (MeO-4PADBC), which we anchored to the NiO x film to fabricate inverted p-i-n PSCs (fig.  S2 ). The NiO x /MeO-4PADBC exhibited an optimal dipole moment and amenable surface for favorable contact with perovskite that resulted in an ideal energetic alignment, fast hole extraction, and low defect density. Such an interface configuration also immobilized the SAM molecules at the NiO x /perovskite interface and produced a robust hole-selective layer (HSL) for thermally stable PSCs that had thermal-degradation activation energy ~3 times greater than that for ITO/MeO-4PADBC. These synergetic effects enabled 1.53-electron volt (eV) p-i-n PSCs V OC of 1.19 V (95% of calculated potential) and a verified power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 25.6%. 1.68-and 1.80-eVwide bandgap perovskite composition devices also showed encouraging PCEs of 22.7 and 20.1%, respectively. Moreover, 1.53-eV PSCs using NiO x /MeO-4PADBC HSL maintained &gt;90% of initial efficiency in long-term operational stability tests under 65Â°C for 1200 hours, and extrapolation of the Arrhenius energy indicates that the solar cells should maintain 80% of initial efficiency for more than 10 months at 25Â°C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4031</offset>
      <text> SAM design and synthesis Modulating the terminal functional group is an effective way to tune the interfacial interactions between SAMs and perovskite. For ex-ample, the introduction of two methoxy groups (OMe) into [2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl]phosphonic acid (2PACz) enabled a new SAM,  [2-(3,6- dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl]phosphonic acid (MeO-2PACz), which improved the interfacial contact and enabled a higher efficiency of p-i-n PSC compared with 2PACz  (10) . Nonetheless, the OMe substitution on the carbazole core also caused a decrease in dipole moment from ~2.0 D of 2PACz to ~0.2 D of MeO-2PACz, which in turn led to the offset between the highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO) of the SAM molecule and the valence band maximum (VBM) of the perovskite  (10, 26) . This phenomenon can be ascribed to high planarity and symmetry of the carbazole structure; the incorporation of two OMe groups with opposite directions of dipole moment resulted in a net molecular dipole moment of MeO-2PACz close to zero (Fig.  1A ). We addressed this issue by using a non-coplanar screw-shaped dibenzo[c,g]carbazole (DBC) unit as the core to reduce the negative effect on the dipole moment when introducing OMe groups, affording a new SAM of MeO-4PADBC (Fig.  1B ). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations verified that MeO-4PADBC only has a slightly decreased dipole moment (2.   S11C ), which could induce a highly ordered one-dimensional assembly that favors a dense, tilted, highly ordered monolayer on the substrate (fig.  S11D )  (9, 27, 28) . We then calculated the interfacial binding energies between SAMs and perovskite, showing that MeO-4PADBC has a stronger binding with perovskite with a total binding energy (E b ) of -7.19 eV, compared with that of -5.27 eV for MeO-2PACz (fig.  S12 ). The main electrostatic interaction of the calculated SAMs is the O atoms from OMe groups with the Pb from perovskite, however MeO-4PADBC has a more energetically favorable contact with perovskite compared with MeO-2PACz, which can be ascribed to the more concentrated electron distribution of the coordinated OMe group on MeO-4PADBC than that on MeO-2PACz (fig.  S13 ). Moreover, Bader charge analysis also suggests a stronger Pb-O interaction between MeO-4PADBC and perovskite with a shorter calculated interaction length of 4.7 Ã… than that of MeO-2PACz of 4.9 Ã… (fig.  S14 ), which can be further confirmed by the results   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6467</offset>
      <text> Hole-selective layer applications We compared MeO-4PADBC SAM and NiO x / MeO-4PADBC as the HSLs for p-i-n PSCs (Fig.  1C ). Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectra were then collected by scraping the MeO-4PADBC and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC films off the substrates to amplify the signal, in which the P=O (1169 cm -1 ) and P-OH (1035 and 950 cm -1 ) absorption peaks show a clear shift (Fig.  1D ), indicating the formation of a chemical bond  (29) . This can be further confirmed by the changes of the Ni 2p core level of NiO x and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC films deposited on the indium tin oxide (ITO) substrates obtained by x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) spectra (fig.  S16 ). The crystal structure and absorbance of representative perovskite film with a composition of Cs 0.05 FA 0.85 MA 0.1 PbI 3 on both substrates remained unchanged (figs. S17 and S18). However, the perovskite deposited on ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC substrate had larger crystal domains than those on control substrates (fig.  S19 ). This is because of the denser anchoring of SAM molecules onto the ITO/NiO x substrate through more robust tridentate binding absorption, which can not only reduce the surface roughness of ITO/NiO x substrate (30-32) (figs. S20 and S21), but also lead to a more hydrophobic surface (fig.  S22 ) and stronger interaction between perovskite and SAM molecules  (33) (34) (35) . These synergetic effects contribute to facilitating the perovskite crystal nucleation and growth, thus enhancing the perovskite crystallization. We further used ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) to assess the energetic alignment of different substrates relative to perovskite absorbers with different bandgaps (1.53, 1.68, and 1.8 eV, see Fig.  1E  and fig.  S23 ), and the results are summarized in Fig.  1F . The HOMO energy levels are -5.34 eV for ITO/MeO-4PADBC and -5.45 eV ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC, respectively, and the work function (Î¦) of the latter substrate is deeper than that of the former one (-4.95 versus -4.90 eV), indicative of better energetic alignment with different perovskite absorbers. However, upon application of the carbazole-based SAM molecules onto the ITO/ NiO x surface, the ITO/NiO x /MeO-2PACz system exhibited an upward shift of the Î¦, in contrast to the ITO/NiO x /2PACz substrate (26, 36) (fig.  S24 ). This phenomenon can be attributed to the incorporation of OMe groups on 2PACz, which considerably reduced the dipole moment. This reduction can be explained by the highly planar carbazole motif, as discussed earlier. Timeresolved photoluminescence (TRPL) decay data showed a decreased carrier lifetime from 925.5 ns for the perovskite on ITO to 42.9 and 32.3 ns for the perovskite on ITO/MeO-4PADBC and ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC, respectively, indicating a more facilitated hole extraction resulted by the ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC substrate (fig.  S25  and table  S2 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>9355</offset>
      <text> Solar cell performance and characterization We further evaluated the photovoltaic performance of PSCs with a p-i-n device configuration: glass/ITO/HSL/perovskite/two-dimensional (2D) passivation layer/C 60 /bathocuproine (BCP)/ Ag (Fig.  2A ). The 2D passivation layer was a mixture of 4-trifluorophenylethylammonium iodide (CF 3 -PEAI) and methylammonium iodide (MAI) with an optimal volume ratio of 3:1 (4). The cross-section scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images of the PSC (1.53 eV) showed a thickness of ~715 nm for the perovskite films (fig.  S26 ). The device with NiO x /MeO-4PADBC as the HSL (1.53 eV) showed negligible hysteresis and had a high verified PCE of 25.6% for a mask area of 0.0414 cm 2 (figs. S27 and S28), with a V OC of 1.19 V, a short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 25.4 mA cm -2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 84.6%, which outperformed the MeO-4PADBC-based device (PCE = 24.2% with V OC = 1.16 V, J SC = 25.4 mA cm -2 , and FF = 82.1%). The NiO x control device without a SAM only showed a PCE of 21.6%, attributed to a mismatch of energetic alignment and high surface defect density on NiO x film (37, 38) (Fig.  2B ). Moreover, we have also conducted HSL engineering by applying carbazole-based SAM anchoring on NiO x . The V OC of the NiO x /MeO-2PACz-based device (1.15 V) is lower than that of the device with NiO x /2PACz (1.17 V) (figs.  S29, A  and B ). This issue was addressed by replacing the carbazole motif with a nonplanar DBC core in SAM molecules (fig.  S29, C  and D ). To better understand the mechanism of the improved V OC and FF with the use of NiO x / MeO-4PADBC as HSL, we further conducted the FF loss (supplementary text and fig.  S30 ) and V OC loss calculations (supplementary text, fig.  S31 , and table  S3 ). We observed that the improved V OC and FF of NiO x /MeO-4PADBC were mainly attributed to the suppressed nonradiative recombination loss, indicating reduced trap state density at the HSL/perovskite interface. Our NiO x /MeO-4PADBC strategy also worked effectively for 1.68-and 1.80-eV PSCs, resulting in PCEs of 22.7 and 20.1%, respectively (Fig.  2C , fig.  S32 , and table  S4 ). Steady-state power output (SPO) confirmed the reliability of three bandgap devices, with stabilized PCEs of 25.5, 22.3, and 19.5% for 1.53-, 1.68-and 1.80-eV, respectively (Fig.  2D ). Additionally, the calculated J SC values from external quantum efficiency (EQE) of the champion devices were consistent with those extracted from the current density-voltage (J-V) measurements (fig.  S33 ), and the derivatives of EQE spectra can further confirm the perovskite bandgaps applied here (fig.  S34 ). We further presented the EQE with internal quantum efficiency (IQE) results of representative 1.53-eV device with HSLs of NiO x , MeO-4PADBC, and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC in fig.  S35 . The IQE between 550 nm to 700 nm is spectrally flat and approaches nearly 100% for both of MeO-4PADBC and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC-based devices, indicating efficient charge collection and transfer at the perovskite interface achieved by the incorporation of SAM  (12, 39) . The defect density profiles were then studied to identify enhanced photovoltaic performance through the space charge limit current (SCLC) method (fig.  S36 ). The hole-only devices with NiO x /MeO-4PADBC showed the lowest defect density of 1.96Ã—10 15 cm - foot_3  , compared with those with MeO-4PADBC (2.91Ã—10 15 cm -3 ) and NiO x (3.81Ã—10 15 cm -3 ). In addition, the decreased slope of the light intensity dependence V OC plot for NiO x /MeO-4PADBC-based devices supported a reduced interfacial trap density at the HSL/perovskite interface (40) (fig.  S37 ). We note that PSCs based on NiO x / MeO-4PADBC further demonstrated a lower leakage current than those on other HSLs (fig.  S38 ), which we attributed to the compact NiO x layer preventing the perovskite from contacting ITO through the pinholes in the ultrathin SAM layer. These results demonstrated that the NiO x /MeO-4PADBC HSL effectively increased the V OC of the PSCs. To quantify the interface losses, quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) analysis for partial cell stacks was conducted. A laser wavelength of 375 nm was used to illuminate a PSC with 1-sun equivalent intensity by accommodating the generated current near J SC under a standard solar simulator  (41, 42)  (supplementary text, fig.  S39 ). As shown in Fig.  2E , the QFLS of ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC/perovskite stack was comparable to the glass/perovskite stack, with implied V OC of 1.17 V versus 1.18 V for 1.53-eV perovskite film, 1.26 V versus 1.27 V for 1.68-eV perovskite film, and 1.35 V versus 1.36 V for 1.80-eV perovskite film, respectively. These results indicated a low voltage loss on the interface between NiO x /MeO-4PADBC and perovskites. We further performed the QFLS measurements on the ITO/HSL/perovskite/passivation layer/electron-transporting layer (ETL) stacks (Fig.  2F ), with the V OC s of the PSCs listed as a comparison. The differences between the QFLS of PSCs on ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC and the V OC extracted from related J-V measurements were comparable, demonstrating spatially flat Fermi levels throughout the device and low energy offset on the HSL for carrier extraction  (27, 28) . It is noteworthy that the V OC of our 1.53-eV devices (1.19 V) reached 95% of their calculated potential and the V OC of our 1.68-eV (1.25 V) and 1.80-eV (1.34 V) devices also approached 90% of the calculated potential (Fig.  2G ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14831</offset>
      <text> PSC stability studies Previous reports have demonstrated that SAMs desorb under thermal stress from the anchored After aging on a hotplate at 65Â°C for 1200 hours, the NiO x /MeO-4PADBC substrate displayed negligible CPD changes, whereas the ITO/MeO-4PADBC CPD value increased to ~70 mV (Fig.  3, C  and D ). We propose that the fluctuations of CPD for the ITO/MeO-4PADBC substrate could be attributed to desorption, morphological changes under thermal stress, or both. To further explore the binding ability of SAM to the substrate under heating, DFT simulations were conducted to investigate the binding energies between MeO-4PADBC and ITO or NiO x substrate at 300 K (~27Â°C) and 340 K (~67Â°C) (Fig.  3, E  and F ). MeO-4PADBC had a higher binding energy with NiO x (-22.4 eV) than with ITO (-16.7 eV) at 300 K, suggesting a stronger bonding strength on the NiO x film. This difference was attributed to the higher density of hydroxyl groups on the NiO x surface than on the ITO, which is critical to the chemisorption of SAM on the metal oxide  (43, 44) . The tridentate binding between SAM and NiO x was stronger than the bidentate binding between SAM and ITO  (29, 45) . At 340 K, the binding energy between SAM and ITO decreased from -16.7 to -11.6 eV, but that between MeO-4PADBC and NiO x film showed minor changes (-20.3 eV). These results indicated that MeO-4PADBC on the NiO x film is more robust against thermal stress compared with MeO-4PADBC on bare ITO. Thermal accelerated aging measurements were conducted to evaluate the reliability of SAM-based PSCs. To avoid the influence of the 2D capping layer, the encapsulated devices without top passivation were prepared for stability testing. The initial J-V curves and photographs of the encapsulated devices are shown in fig.  S40  and S41 , respectively. The PSCs were operated under constant 1-sun illumination at fixed resistance loads near the MPP with the temperature ranging from 25Â°to 100Â°C, following the ISOS-L-2I procedure  (19) . The MeO-4PADBC-based devices degraded to 85 and 65% of starting PCEs after 1200 hours at 25Â°C and 65Â°C, respectively (Fig.  4A ). When the aging temperature increased to 85Â°C, only 47% of its initial PCE was retained after 800 hours. The NiO x devices retained 85 and 65% of initial PCEs at 65Â°and 85Â°C, respectively, after 1200 hours (Fig.  4B ). However, the NiO x /MeO-4PADBC-based devices retained 90 and 74% of initial PCEs after 1200 hours at 65Â°and 85Â°C, respectively (Fig.  4C ), which was consistent with the degradation analysis in Fig.  3 . Both devices based on NiO x , MeO-4PADBC, or NiO x /MeO-4PADBC as HSL showed a more obvious downward trend when the aging temperature was raised to 100Â°C. For a more comprehensive evaluation of the thermal stability of our NiO x /MeO-4PADBC strategy, we further applied the PSCs with top passivation to conduct the operational stability at 65Â°C for 500 hours (fig.  S42 ). The devices presented a slightly improved stability compared with the device without passivation at the same time stage, which maintained 96% of its initial PCE. This may be due to the higher hydrophobic surface brought by the CF 3 -PEAI passivation  (46) . We then determined the activation energy (E a ) of the temperature-dependent degradation of our PSCs with different HSLs according to a previously reported method (supplementary text)  (47) . The E a value of NiO x /MeO-4PADBCbased devices (0.389 Â± 0.022 eV) was almost three times higher than that of MeO-4PADBCbased devices (0.150 Â± 0.017 eV). The lifetime acceleration factor (AF) of each temperature can be obtained from E a (Fig.  4D ), from which it can be estimated that PSCs with NiO x /MeO-4PADBC HSL could retained 80% of its initial PCE at room temperature after 7567 hours operation, without top passivation treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18666</offset>
      <text> Conclusions We have demonstrated an efficient and stabilized HSL with greatly improved thermal stability for high efficiency SAM-containing inverted p-i-n PSCs. Rational molecular structure design of MeO-4PADBC and in-depth analysis revealed that optimal dipole moment and favorable contact with perovskite are the  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18984</offset>
      <text> Perovskite solar cells (PSCs) fabrication Glass/ITO substrates (15 â„¦ sq -1 ) were sequentially cleaned by sonication with detergent, deionized water, acetone, and isopropyl alcohol for 20 min, respectively. Then, the glass/ITO substrates were dried at 100 Â°C in an oven, and then were treated with oxygen plasma for 10 min and finally transferred into a N2-filled glovebox before use. In this work, nickel oxide (NiOx) nanoparticle, (4-(3,11-dimethoxy-7H-dibenzo[c,g]carbazol-7-yl)butyl)phosphonic acid (MeO-4PADBC), NiOx/MeO-4PADBC were applied as holeselective layers (HSLs). For NiOx-based devices, NiOx nanoparticles were dispersed in deionized water at a concentration of 10 mg ml -1 to form NiOx ink. The as-prepared NiOx ink was spin-coated onto the ITO substrate at 2,000 r.p.m. for 30s, then annealing at 150 Â°C for 30 min in ambient air. For MeO-4PADBC-based devices, SAM was dissolved in ethanol with an optimized concentration of 0.3 mg ml -1 . The as-prepared SAM solution was spin-coated on the ITO substrate at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30s, then annealing at 100 Â°C for 10 min in N2-filled glove box. The substrates were then washing with ethanol through spin-coating at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30s, then annealing at 100 Â°C for 5 min. For NiOx/MeO-4PADBC-based devices, the NiOx ink was firstly spin-coated on ITO substrate, following by the SAM solution spin-coated on the substrates, then the substrates were annealed at 100 Â°C for 40 min in ambient air (Fig.  S2 ). After that, the NiOx/MeO-4PADBC substrates also needed to be transferred to N2-filled glove box and washed with ethanol through spin-coating at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, then annealing at 100 Â°C for 5 min. For perovskite precursor preparation, 1. All steps were conducted in N2-filled glovebox. For 1.53 eV perovskite films fabrication, the perovskite precursor was spin-coated on the asprepared substrates with HSLs at 1,000 r.p.m. for 10 s, subsequently at 5,000 r.p.m. for 40 s, during which 200 Î¼L CB was dripped onto the center of film at 5 s before the end of spincoating. The substrates were immediately transferred to the hotplate and annealed at 100 Â°C for 30 min. As for 1.68 eV, and 1.80 eV perovskite films fabrication, the perovskite precursor was spin-coated on the as-prepared substrates with HSLs at 1,000 r.p.m. for 5 s, subsequently at 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, during which 200 Î¼L CB was dripped onto the center of film at 15 s before the end of spin-coating. The substrates were immediately transferred to the hotplate and annealed at 100 Â°C for 15 min. For the devices with surface passivation treatment, a mixture of CF3-PEAI, 2 mg ml -1 ) and MAI (1 mg ml -1 ) was dissolved in a mixed solvent of IPA: DMF (150:1 in volume) and dynamic spun on the as-prepared perovskite films at 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, then annealing at 100 Â°C for 10 min. The spin-coating processes were conducted in N2-filled glovebox with a controlled temperature of 18-23 Â°C by the integrated air-conditioner, and the water and oxygen level should be both controlled at less than 5 ppm. Finally, 25 nm C60 at a rate of 0.5 Ã… s -1 , 6 nm BCP a rate of 0.5 Ã… s -1 and 100 nm silver electrode a rate of 1.0 Ã… s -1 were thermally evaporated, respectively, under high vacuum (&lt; 4 Ã— 10 -6 Torr). A 120-nm thick magnesium fluoride layer at a rate of 1 Ã… s -1 was deposited on the back of ITO substrate for transmittance enhancement. The device area was defined and characterized as 0.0414 cm 2 by metal shadow mask. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22472</offset>
      <text> Stability tests The long-term operational stability was conducted by following ISOS-L-2I procedure. Before the tests, the PSCs were encapsulated (LT-U001, Luminescence Technology Corp.) with cover glass (1.1 mm). The encapsulated PSCs were operated under 1 sun equivalent LED lamp in a N2-filled glovebox (with the contents of O2 and H2O &lt;5 ppm). The PSCs were biased at maximum-power-point (MPP) voltage and the power output was tracked by using a multipotentiostat (CHI1040C, CH Instruments, Inc.). During the MPP test, the current densityvoltage (J-V) curves of the devices were obtained every 12 h to get the proper loads for the MPP. For testing at 65, 85 and 100 â„ƒ, the devices were mounted on hotplate. The temperature of the devices was monitored by thermometer regularly. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>23257</offset>
      <text> Characterizations Ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorptions were measured by a UV-vis spectrometer (PerkinElmermodel Lambda 2S). X-ray diffraction (XRD) data were collected in the reflection mode at room temperature on a Philips X'Pert diffractometer equipped with a CPS 180 detector using monochromated Cu-KÎ± (Î» = 1.5418 A) radiation. The surface and cross-section morphology of the perovskite films were acquired by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) (QUATTROS, Thermal Fisher Scientific). Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) was conducted in a surface analysis system (VG ESCALAB 220i XL) equipped with a Hedischarge lamp (hv = 21.22 eV) and a monochromatic Al KÎ± X-ray gun (hv = 1,486.60 eV), respectively. Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) data were acquired via Bruker Dimension Kelvin probe force microscopy in Potential Channel equipped with PFQNE-AL probe, which is a platinum-iridium coated tip with a frequency of â‰ˆ300 kHz and a nominal tip radius of â‰ˆ5 nm. To calibrate the KPFM measurements, we developed a method using an Al-Si-Au standard. The average contact potential distribution (CPD) profile was extracted from the calibration sample, and the work function of the tip (ğ‘Š ğ¹ ğ‘¡ğ‘–ğ‘ ) was calculated using the value of the CPD in the gold region (ğ‘Š ğ¹ ğ´ğ‘¢ ) as ğ‘Š ğ¹ ğ‘¡ğ‘–ğ‘ = ğ‘Š ğ¹ ğ´ğ‘¢ -ğ‘’ğ¶ğ‘ƒğ· . The measurements were performed on Bruker Dimension ICON, with the sample fixed in a custom-made vertical sample holder. The chamber was filled with high-purity nitrogen to minimize the influence of ambient conditions on the measurements. Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy was conducted by Fourier transform infrared spectrometer (Tensor 27, Germany Bruker). FTIR spectra were taken from KBr pellet-pressed power samples to amplify the signal. The powder samples were obtained by scrapping the films off the substrates. The time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra were obtained by Edinburgh FLS980 applied with an excitation wavelength of 375 nm. Quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) were calculated by the data extracted from photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) via exciting the corresponding samples by a 375 nm laser (Edinburgh, EPL-375) inside an integrated sphere (Edinburgh FLS980). A PSC was used to adjust the laser intensity to 1 sun equivalent intensity by obtaining a current density at 0 V approximately equal to its short-circuit current density (JSC) under standard solar simulator. Highly sensitive external quantum efficiency (EQE) was measured by an integrated system (PECT-600, Enlitech, Taiwan), where the photocurrent was amplified and modulated by a lock-in instrument. The detailed calculation was discussed in supplementary note as below. The current-voltage (J-V) characteristics of photovoltaic devices were conducted in a N2-filled glovebox at room temperature by using a xenon lamp solar simulator (Enlitech, SS-F5, Taiwan). The power of the light was calibrated to 100 mW cm -2 by a silicon reference cell (with a KG2 filter). All the devices were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under a sweep mode of reverse scan (from 1.35 to -0.1 V) and forward scan (from -0.1 to 1.35 V) with the scan rate of 0.01 V s -1 , and the delay time was 10 ms. No pre-conditioning was needed before measurement. The stabilized power output was conducted by monitoring the stabilized current density output at the MPP bias (extracted from the reverse scan J-V curves). EQE and internal quantum efficiency (IQE) measurements were carried out using a QE-R EQE system (Enlitech, Taiwan). 1 H NMR and 13 C NMR spectra were collected using a Bruker 400/600 MHz instrument spectrometer and referenced to the residual solvent peaks of either CDCl3 at 7.26 ppm and DMSO-d6 at 2.50 and 39.5 ppm, respectively. high-profile inverted p-i-n perovskite solar cells reported previously  (1-3, 10, 16, 18, 20, 21, 48-55) . (T(number) refers to the time to (number)% of its initial efficiency.)               The activation energies (Ea) related to degradation rates can be estimated by from a single Arrhenius function across the entire temperature range  (61) (62) (63) .We use the value of kslow to obtain Ea in the following calculation, since kslow is mainly responsible for device's long-term degradation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27578</offset>
      <text> ğ‘˜(ğ‘‡) = ğ´ğ‘’ğ‘¥ğ‘( -ğ¸ ğ‘ ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ) â‹¯ (ğ‘†9) Where ğ‘˜(ğ‘‡)is a degradation rate at temperature T, A is constant, Ea is the activation energy of degradation, and kB is Boltzmann's constant  (64) (65) (66) (67) . The Ea can be yielded by rearranging equation S9: ğ¸ ğ‘ = - ğœ• ln(ğ‘˜(ğ‘‡)) ğœ• ( 1 ğ‘˜ ğµ ğ‘‡ ) â‹¯ (ğ‘†10) The temperature-dependent slow degradation rate was plotted as a function of inverse temperature in Fig.  4D  (left) and fitted to equation S10. An effective accelerated stress test can quantify the lifetime acceleration factor (AF), which relates to the lifetime under a defined standard operating condition (defined as 1-sun illumination at 25 â„ƒ), kref, to the lifetime under elevated stress conditions, kacc, (Fig.  4D  (right). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28377</offset>
      <text> ğ´ğ¹ = ğ‘˜ ğ‘ğ‘ğ‘ ğ‘˜ ğ‘Ÿğ‘’ğ‘“ = exp( ğ¸ ğ‘ ğ‘˜ ğµ [ 1 ğ‘‡ ğ‘Ÿğ‘’ğ‘“ - 1 ğ‘‡ ğ‘ğ‘ğ‘ ]) â‹¯ (ğ‘†11) Here, the Ea extracted from kslow was used to obtain the AFs for each Tacc (65, 85, and 100 â„ƒ). Given that the experimentally measured the time of PSC retain 80% of its initial PCE with HSL  4 D) compared with that of (4-(7H-dibenzo[c,g]carbazol-7-yl)butyl)phosphonic acid (4PADBC) (2.9 D), which is quite different from those obtained for carbazole-based SAMs (figs. S3 and S4). The synthetic route of MeO-4PADBC is shown in fig. S5, along with structural characterizations presented in figs. S6 to S9. The calculated HOMO and lowest unoccupied molecular orbital distributions are shown in fig. S10, with values of -4.91 and -1.15 eV, respectively. To gain a deeper insight of the SAM molecule structure, we grew a single crystal of 3,11-dimethoxy-7H-dibenzo[c,g] carbazole (MeO-DBC, CCDC number: 2279245), which lacks the anchoring group that would disrupt intermolecular interactions. As shown in fig. S11, A and B, two naphthalene rings are located on different sides of the pyrrole ring and exhibit a dihedral angle of 12.44Â°, which greatly reduces the planarity and symmetry of the skeleton structure to enable a negligible effect on the dipole moment when introducing OMe groups. Moreover, the MeO-DBC core had a slipped p-stacked packing motif with strong C-Hâ€¢â€¢â€¢p (2.72 Ã…) and p-p (3.79 Ã…) interactions (fig. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29841</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Molecular structure and electrical properties of HSLs. Molecular structure and side view of (A) MeO-2PACz and (B) MeO-4PADBC. (C) Schematic illustration of MeO-4PADBC anchoring on NiO x nanoparticle as the HSL in PSC. (D) FTIR spectra of MeO-4PADBC and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC. (E) UPS spectra of ITO substrates covered by NiO x , MeO-4PADBC, and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC. (Left) UPS spectra around the secondary electron cutoff (WF, work function); (right) UPS spectra in the valence band (VB) region. (F) Schematic representation of the band edge positions of the studied HSLs based on values from UPS measurements, referenced to the vacuum level. E F and E VAC represent Fermi and vacuum levels, respectively. E VBM and E CBM represent the energy of valence band maximum and conduction band minimum, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30666</offset>
      <text> of 1 H 1 NMR spectra of the SAMs in DMSO-d 6 with or without mixing with PbI 2 (fig.S15). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30758</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH | RESEARCH ARTICLE Li et al., Science 382, 284-289 (2023) 20 October 2023 substrate (29, 30), but few effective solutions to this problem have been explored. To estimate the thermal stability of the ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC substrate, we applied Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) to record the surface potential evolution of the SAM under heat treatment by taking pristine ITO/MeO-4PADBC as a reference. Before thermal aging, the ITO/ MeO-4PADBC and ITO/NiO x /MeO-4PADBC substrates both exhibited relatively uniform sur-face potential with a narrow contact potential distribution (CPD) of ~40 mV, indicating that the SAM molecules were densely packed onto both of ITO and NiO x surfaces (Fig. 3, A and B). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31476</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Photovoltaic performance of PSCs with different HSLs. (A) Schematic illustration of p-i-n PSC. (B) J-V curves of the best-performing 1.53 eV devices with NiO x , MeO-4PADBC, and NiO x /MeO-4PADBC as HSL. (C) J-V curves of the bestperforming NiO x /MeO-4PADBC-based devices with bandgaps of 1.53, 1.68, and 1.80 eV (Rev., reverse scan; For., forward scan). (D) SPO at the MPP for the bestperforming NiO x /MeO-4PADBC-based PSCs with three bandgaps of perovskite absorbers. (E) QFLS in the case of three bandgaps of perovskite with different HSLs. (F) Comparison of the V OC of actual PSCs with the corresponding QFLS of representative layer stacks. (G) Comparison of the V OC with different bandgaps of devices from the literature to our work. The line represents the V OC extracted from calculated potential. The wide-bandgap region refers to 1.6 to 1.9 eV in the figure. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32369</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 .( 3 , 6 - 336 Fig. 3. Analysis of the degradation mechanism of PSCs. (A to D) Surface potential images obtained by scanning Kelvin probe microscopy (scale bar 500 nm) of the HSLs before and after aging at 65Â°C for 1200 hours. At the bottom of the figure are the statistical potential distributions of film surfaces. (E) DFT calculation of the binding energy of MeO-4PADBC with ITO and NiO x . (F) Binding energies (E b ) of MeO-4PADBC with ITO and with NiO x at the temperatures of 300 and 340 K. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32877</offset>
      <text> Fig. S1 S1 Fig. S1 Comparison of device efficiency and operational stability (MPP tracking) from representative &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32991</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2 S2 Fig. S2 Fabrication process of NiOx/MeO-4PADBC HSL with two-step spin-coating method. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33090</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 S12 Fig. S12 Binding energy (Eb) and corresponding differential charge densities of (A) MeO-4PADBC, and (B) MeO-2PACz SAM molecules. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33234</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S13 Calculated electrostatic potential surface (EPS) of (A) MeO-4PADBC and (B) MeO-2PACz. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33335</offset>
      <text> Fig Fig. S14 Total charge density analysis and Bader charge of Pb and O atoms (A) MeO-4PADBC (B) MeO-2PACz. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33445</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 SEM Fig. S20 SEM images of (A) NiOx and (B) NiOx/MeO-4PADBC thin films deposited on ITO substrate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33555</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 S21 Fig. S21 Atomic force microscopy (AFM) images of (A) ITO/NiOx, and ITO/NiOx/MeO-4PADBC substrates. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33669</offset>
      <text> 2 2 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33675</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 UPS Fig. S24 UPS spectra of ITO substrates covered by (A) NiOx/2PACz, (B) NiOx/MeO-2PACz, (C) NiOx/4PADBC, and (D) NiOx/MeO-4PADBC respectively. Left: UPS spectra around the secondary electron cutoff (WF, work function); right: UPS spectra in the valence band (VB) region. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33959</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 TRPL spectra of 1 . 1 Fig. S25 TRPL spectra of 1.53 eV perovskite deposited on ITO, ITO/MeO-4PADBC and ITO/NiOx/MeO-4PADBC substrates, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34119</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 Fig. S26 Cross-sectional SEM image of PSCs (with 1.53 eV perovskite absorber) with NiOx/MeO-4PADBC as the HSL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34241</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 S29 Fig. S29 Comparison of photovoltaic performance of device based on carbazole-based SAM molecules anchoring on NiOx as HSL, (A) NiOx/2PACz, (B) NiOx/MeO-2PACz; and DBC-based SAM molecules, (C) NiOx/4PADBC and (D) NiOx/MeO-4PADBC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34485</offset>
      <text> Fig. S39 S39 Fig. S39 The highly-sensitive EQE of PSCs with MeO-4PADBC and NiOx/MeO-4PADBC as HSLs. (A) 1.53 eV PSCs; (B) 1.68 eV PSCs and (C) 1.80 eV PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34644</offset>
      <text> Fig. S42 S42 Fig. S42 Operational stability of NiOx/MeO-4PADBC-based PSC with top passivation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34741</offset>
      <text> Supplementary text: accelerated aging test of PSCs operating at different temperatures. The temperature dependence of PCE degradation rate can be fitted to a biexponential function, according to Zhao et. al's work.(47): ğ‘ƒğ¶ğ¸(ğ‘¡) = ğ´1  *  exp(-ğ‘˜ ğ‘“ğ‘ğ‘ ğ‘¡ Ã— ğ‘¡) + ğ´2  *  exp(-ğ‘˜ ğ‘ ğ‘™ğ‘œğ‘¤ Ã— ğ‘¡) + ğµ â‹¯ (ğ‘†8) where A1, A2, and B are constant, t represents time. A fast and slow degradation rate (kfast and kslow) can be extracted from the fitting results with an R 2 &gt;0.95, except for the data extracted from the PSCs with NiOx and NiOx/MeO-4PADBC as HSL operating at 25â„ƒ, since these devices showed less than 10% of efficiency loss within 1,200 hours. The comparable kfast and kslow of three types of devices indicated that the two degradation rates probed a single physical process, suggesting a reliable accelerated aging test. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35621</offset>
      <text> Table S4 S4 of NiOx/MeO-4PADBC is approximately 360 hours at 100 â„ƒ, and the AF of the corresponding device at 100 â„ƒ is 21.02. We can estimate that, PSCs with HSL of NiOx/MeO-4PADBC can maintain 80% of its starting efficiency at 25 â„ƒ after 7,567 hours operational, without top passivation treatment, by multiplying the aging time (360 hours) by AF value (21.02).TableS1Summary of the device efficiency and operational stability from representative highprofile inverted perovskite solar cells papers (refer to fig.S1).TableS2The fitted carrier lifetime of perovskite films obtained from the TRPL measurements.Note: The average lifetime can be calculated with the equation of: ğ‰ ğ’‚ğ’—ğ’ˆ = (ğ‘¨ ğŸ ğ‰ ğŸ ğŸ + ğ‘¨ ğŸ ğ‰ ğŸ ğŸ )/(ğ‘¨ ğŸ ğ‰ ğŸ + ğ‘¨ ğŸ ğ‰ ğŸ ) , where parameters A1 and A2 are the amplitude fraction for each decay component, and ğ‰ ğŸ and ğ‰ ğŸ represent the time constant of the two types of decay.TableS3The analysis results of calculated VOC loss in the PSCs with different HSLs.HSLğ¸ g (ğ‘’ğ‘‰) ğ‘‰ OC SQ (ğ‘‰) ğ‘‰ OC (ğ‘‰) Î”ğ‘‰ 1 (mV) Î”ğ‘‰ 2 (mV) Î”ğ‘‰ 3 (mV) Photovoltaic parameter of the control and target devices.TableS5PLQY and QFLS results of perovskite film on glass substrate, ITO/HSLs/perovskite stack, and ITO/HSL/perovskite/passivation layer/ETL stack. HSLs Ï„1 (ns) Bandgap (eV) VOC (V) Ï„2 (ns) FF (%) JSC (mA cm -2 ) Ï„avg (ns) PCE (%) Year ITO NiOx Bandgap (eV) ITO/MeO-4PADBC Hole-transporting 1.53 Sample stacks PCE 1.14 NiOx 1.53 1.26 1.68 1.18 1.53 Glass/perovskite Operational stability (MPPT) 87.4 990.5 77.3 24.5 PLQY 8.5 410.5 1.14 273.4 76.5 19.4 0.0397 2.3 925.5 QFLS (eV) 21.6 Ref. 42.9 108.6 17.5 1.180 materials SAM ITO/NiOx/MeO-4PADBC 2023 2023 MeO-4PADBC 1.53 1.80 NiOx/perovskite 25.4% 24.1% 1.26 1.25 NiOx/MeO-4PADBC 1.53 1.26 MeO-4PADBC 1.53 1.16 MeO-4PADBC/perovskite &gt;96% of initial PCE, 1,000 hours &gt;85% of initial PCE, 85â„ƒ, 1,560 11.1 194.7 1.16 273.3 72.0 16.1 0.0133 1.19 273.2 82.1 25.4 0.0245 1.68 1.22 80.2 21.4 NiOx/MeO-4PADBC/perovskite 0.0330 2.3 2.3 (2) (20) 32.3 14.5 1.151 76.3 1.167 24.2 50 20.9 1.175 2023 NiOx/MeO- 1.80 1.53 hours No loss of initial PCE, 500 hours 79.8 17.8 NiOx/perovskite/2D/ETL 25.4% 1.31 0.0086 1.19 84.6 25.4 MeO-4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL 0.0171 1.140 (3) 18.6 25.6 1.158 2023 4PADBC 1.68 24.5% 1.25 4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL &gt;90% of initial PCE, 500 hours 84.5 NiOx/MeO- 21.5 0.0307 (48) 22.7 1.173 2023 1.68 1.80 24.5% 1.34 Glass/perovskite &gt;91% of initial PCE, 1,200 hours 83.6 17.9 0.0256 (4) 20.1 1.274 2023 24.2% NiOx/perovskite &gt;88% of initial PCE, 75â„ƒ, 1,000 0.0032 (21) 1.220 MeO-4PADBC/perovskite hours 0.0050 1.232 2023 24.9% NiOx/MeO-4PADBC/perovskite &gt;98% of initial PCE, 1,000 hours 0.0140 (49) 1.258 2022 24.3% NiOx/perovskite/2D/ETL &gt;95% of initial 0.0008 (50) 1.185 2022 PCE, 500 hours &gt;87% of initial MeO-4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL 0.0010 25.4% (1) 1.190 NiOx/MeO- PCE, 2,400 hours 0.0042 1.227 2023 1.80 PTAA 4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL 24.6% &gt;90% of initial PCE, 65â„ƒ, 1,500 hours Glass/perovskite 0.02 (52) 1.363 2022 24.3% NiOx/perovskite &gt;98% of initial PCE, 1,500 hours 0.0023 (18) 1.308 2021 22.6% MeO-4PADBC/perovskite No loss, 1,000 0.0045 (53) 1.325 2020 hours No loss, 1,000 NiOx/MeO-4PADBC/perovskite 22.3% 0.0102 (54) 1.346 2019 hours &gt;97% of initial NiOx/perovskite/2D/ETL 21.1% 0.0004 (55) 1.263 PCE, 65â„ƒ, 1,200 MeO-4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL 0.0009 1.284 2022 hours &gt;92% of initial PCE, 65â„ƒ, 500 4PADBC/perovskite/2D/ETL NiOx 23.8% NiOx/MeO-0.0028 (16) 1.313 hours 2023 NiOx/SAM 24.5% No loss, 3,500 (51) hours 2023 25.6% &gt;90% of initial This work PCE, 65â„ƒ, 1,200 hours; &gt;74% of initial PCE, 85â„ƒ, 1,200 hours; &gt;60% of initial PCE, 100â„ƒ, 1,200 hours &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39368</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39472</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39581</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39690</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39799</offset>
      <text>			 of &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39807</offset>
      <text>			 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39911</offset>
      <text>			 of 6 Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
