<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025048030FHHCEF</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 129&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Nature Research wishes to improve the reproducibility of the work that we publish. This form is intended for publication with all accepted papers reporting the characterization of photovoltaic devices and provides structure for consistency and transparency in reporting. Some list items might not apply to an individual manuscript, but all fields must be completed for clarity. For further information on Nature Research policies, including our data availability policy, see Authors &amp; Referees. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>509</offset>
      <text> Experimental design Please check: are the following details reported in the manuscript? &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>599</offset>
      <text> Dimensions Area of the tested solar cells &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>643</offset>
      <text> Yes No In our lab, the area of the solar cells tested is 0.04 cm2 (Methods section: J-V and EQE measurements). For larger-size device, the device area is 1.008 cm2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>810</offset>
      <text> Method used to determine the device area Yes No In our lab, the area of the solar cells tested is defined by a non-reflective metal mask with an aperture area of 0.04 cm2 for regular device and 1.008 cm2 for larger-size device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1040</offset>
      <text> Current-voltage characterization Current density-voltage (J-V) plots in both forward and backward direction &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1150</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1156</offset>
      <text> No Forward and backward scans were performed on the cell (Supplementary Fig.  S28 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1243</offset>
      <text> Voltage scan conditions For instance: scan direction, speed, dwell times &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1318</offset>
      <text> Yes No For the cells tested in our lab, the scan was performed in the range from -0.2 to 1.0 or 1.2 V, with a scan step of 0.02 V and dwell time of 10 ms. The voltage scan conditions during certifications were provided in Supplementary Fig.  S28 .&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1567</offset>
      <text>acquired results in ambient. The growth stage of the target film has been retarded with GABC addition, taking more than 80 s for the target film to reach the final stage. Also, the PL intensity of the control film reaches its maximum in &lt;10 s, while the PL intensity of the target film reaches its maximum in a much longer time span of ~200 s. Moreover, the full width at half maximum (FWHM) of the stabilized PL peak in the target film is much narrower than that of the control film, indicating better phase homogeneity. These results show that the GBAC can help slow down the film formation and improve the film quality considerably, which is in accord with the results acquired from ambient air.                         For the cells tested in our lab, the cells were non-encapsulated and the measurements were performed in an N2-filled glove box at room temperature. For the cells sent to certification, the cells were encapsulated and the measurements were carried out in ambient atmosphere at room temperature. Further details regarding test environment during certifications were provided in Supplementary Fig.  S28 . Protocol for preconditioning of the device before its characterization &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2764</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2770</offset>
      <text> No For the cell sent to JET for certification, the tests were conducted according to the IEC 60904-9 methods to determine the certified cell performance (Supplementary Fig.  S28 ). For the cells tested in our lab, no preconditioning was applied. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3018</offset>
      <text> Stability of the J-V characteristic Verified with time evolution of the maximum power point or with the photocurrent at maximum power point; see ref. 7 for details. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3185</offset>
      <text> Yes No For the cell sent to JET for certification, the stability of J-V characteristics were confirmed by the MPPT results (Supplementary Fig.  28 ). In our lab, stabilized power output tracking was performed to confirm the stability of J-V characteristics (Fig.  4c ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3457</offset>
      <text> Hysteresis or any other unusual behaviour Description of the unusual behaviour observed during the characterization &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3575</offset>
      <text> Yes No There is no unusual behaviour observed during the characterization, i.e, hysteresis. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3669</offset>
      <text> Related experimental data Yes No We are not reporting an unusual behaviour. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3747</offset>
      <text> Efficiency External quantum efficiency (EQE) or incident photons to current efficiency (IPCE) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3843</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3849</offset>
      <text> No The EQE spectra were collected using an Enlitech QE-S EQE system equipped with a standard Si diode, as shown in Fig.  4d . A comparison between the integrated response under the standard reference spectrum and the response measure under the simulator &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4105</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4111</offset>
      <text> No The values of the integrated current from EQE and the short-circuit current from J-V curve measured under AM 1.5G solar simulator are matched well (within 2% difference). For tandem solar cells, the bias illumination and bias voltage used for each subcell &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4372</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4378</offset>
      <text> No We do not report tandem solar cells in this work. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4433</offset>
      <text> nature research | solar cells reporting summary November 2017 2 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4499</offset>
      <text> Calibration Light source and reference cell or sensor used for the characterization &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4585</offset>
      <text> Yes No In our lab, the cells were measured under AM 1.5G (100 mW cm-2) irradiation using an EnliTech SS-F5 solar simulator. The light intensity was calibrated using a silicon solar cell (with a KG-2 filter) from the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (Methods section: J-V and EQE measurements). For the cells sent to certifications, please refer to Supplementary Fig.  S28 (JET) . Confirmation that the reference cell was calibrated and certified &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5037</offset>
      <text> Yes No The solar simulator in our lab is equipped with a silicon solar cell (with a KG-2 filter) from the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (Methods section: J-V and EQE measurements). For the cells sent to certifications, calibrated and certified reference cells were used (Supplementary Fig.  S28 ). Calculation of spectral mismatch between the reference cell and the devices under test &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5431</offset>
      <text> Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5437</offset>
      <text> No In our lab, the spectral mismatch between the reference cell and the tested devices is calculated to be around 1 with a deviation &lt; 1%. For the cell sent to JET for certification, the spectral mismatch correction factor was calculated to be +2.25%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5691</offset>
      <text> Mask/aperture Size of the mask/aperture used during testing Yes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5757</offset>
      <text> No For the cells tested in our lab, the mask/aperture area is 4 mm2. (Methods section: J-V and EQE measurements). For the cells sent to certifications, the aperture area was defined as 0.04003 cm2. (Supplementary Fig.  S28 ). Variation of the measured short-circuit current density with the mask/aperture area &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6069</offset>
      <text> Yes No For the cells tested in our lab, all cells were measured using one identical mask. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6161</offset>
      <text> Performance certification Identity of the independent certification laboratory that confirmed the photovoltaic performance &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6286</offset>
      <text> Yes No Champion cell was certified by JET (Supplementary Fig.  S28 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6358</offset>
      <text> A copy of any certificate(s) Provide in Supplementary Information &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6426</offset>
      <text> Yes No The copy of certificates are provided as Supplementary Fig.  S28  (JET). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6508</offset>
      <text> Statistics Number of solar cells tested Yes No The data from 20 cells were statistically analyzed. The information is provided in Supplementary Fig.  S27 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6666</offset>
      <text> Statistical analysis of the device performance Yes No The information is provided in Supplementary Fig.  S28 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6779</offset>
      <text> Long-term stability analysis Type of analysis, bias conditions and environmental conditions For instance: illumination type, temperature, atmosphere humidity, encapsulation method, preconditioning temperature &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6990</offset>
      <text> Yes No For thermal stability, the unencapsulated devices were aged under continuous heating at 65±5 °C in N2 atmosphere. The long-term operational stability of the unencapsulated cells were tracked through the high throughput solar cell lifetime test system from CRYSCO cooperation with maximum power point tracking under LED simulated AM 1.5 spectrum in an N2-filled glovebox. Duration between two test is 300 s. Improving the intrinsic film quality of metal halide perovskites is very critical to increase the power conversion efficiency and long-term stability of perovskite solar cells. Here we report a multifunctional, non-volatile additive that can be used to modulate the kinetics of perovskite film growth through a hydrogen-bond-bridged intermediate phase. The additive enables the formation of large perovskite grains and coherent grain growth from bottom to the surface of the film. The enhanced film morphology results in significantly reduced non-radiative recombinations, thus boosting the power conversion efficiency of inverted (p-i-n) solar cells to 24.8% (24.5% certified) with a low energy loss of 0.36 eV. The unencapsulated devices exhibit improved thermal stability with a T 98 lifetime beyond 1,000 h under continuous heating at 65 ± 5 °C in a nitrogen-filled glovebox. This effective approach can also be applied to wide-bandgap perovskites and large-area devices to show reduced voltage loss and high efficiency. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:55:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="8036" length="7"/>
        <text>(p-i-n)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.8</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:55:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="8059" length="5"/>
        <text>24.8%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">98</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:56:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="8187" length="4"/>
        <text>T 98</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65+-5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:56:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="8242" length="11"/>
        <text>t 65 ± 5 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:55:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="8259" length="24"/>
        <text>nitrogen-filled glovebox</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8435</offset>
      <text> nature photonics Organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites have garnered great attention due to their impressive optoelectronic properties  1  . Combining compositional and interfacial engineering strategies, the record power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PVSCs) has now reached 25.7% (ref. 2) ( https://www.nrel.gov/pv/cell-efficiency.html ). However, the reported high-efficiency devices mostly comprise the conventional (n-i-p) architecture  [3] [4] [5]  , whereas inverted (p-i-n) PVSCs still show inferior performance despite their low-temperature processability and better compatibility in fabricating tandem and flexible devices  [6] [7] [8] [9] [10]  . The major challenge stems from the severe energy loss in inverted PVSCs, especially the non-radiative recombination loss associated with defects embedded at the interfaces and grain boundaries  11  . A high-quality perovskite film with intrinsically low defect density is, thus, critical in determining the achievable efficiency and stability for PVSCs  12  . In a typical one-step solution process, perovskite precursors dissolved in polar aprotic solvents are spin coated onto the substrate. The introduction of an antisolvent then quickly extracts the residual solvents and templates the perovskite crystal growth through intermediate phases  13  . Various volatile solvents and organic salts have been employed as additives to tune the intermediate compositions for modulating the crystallization kinetics  [14] [15] [16]  . In one work, N-methyl-2-pyrrolidone was added in the perovskite precursors to form a lead iodide (PbI 2 )-N-methyl-2-pyrrolidone adduct for promoting the black-phase formation at room temperature  15  . In another work, methylammonium chloride (MACl) was used to facilitate the formation of an intermediate phase for stabilizing the perovskite α-phase  16  . However, these additives may volatilize during annealing, creating voids at the perovskite-substrate interface, Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6  organic-inorganic vacancies via Lewis acid-base reactions with the carboxyl and guanidium groups  18  . To verify our hypothesis, we first conducted Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectrometry to study the interactions between GBAC and organic species in perovskites. As shown in Fig.  1a  and Supplementary Fig.  1 , the N-H stretching peak shifted from 3,352 to 3,378 cm -1 for FA + /MA + and the C=N stretching peak in FA + also shifted from 1,713 to 1,709 cm -1 on adding GBAC, suggesting the formation of hydrogen bonds between GBAC and organic cations  19  . These indicate that the interplay between GBAC and FA + / MA + in the perovskite can help strengthen the film stability, especially thermal stability that is mainly governed by the organic species. We then verified this through a thermogravimetric analysis (Supplementary Fig.  2 ), where the impeded decomposition of the target film suggests that more energy is required to disrupt the interaction between GBAC and perovskite  20  , ameliorating the film's thermal stability. We performed high-resolution X-ray photoelectron spectrometry (XPS) to study the surface chemistry of perovskites (Supplementary Fig.  3 ). We clearly observed the peak corresponding to GBAC π-π interaction (293.10 eV, C1s spectrum) and increased the C=O peak area (O1s spectrum) in the target film, further validating the existence of the GBAC linker in the perovskite (Supplementary Figs.  4  and 5 ). In the Pb4f spectrum (Fig.  1b ), the binding energy of 4f 5/2 and 4f 7/2 for divalent Pb 2+ shifted from 141.92 and 137.09 eV to 141.59 and 136.76 eV, respectively, due to the electrostatic interaction between the guanidium group and PbI 6 4-. We further recorded the steady-state PL and time-resolved PL profiles of perovskite films to reveal how GBAC affects the film quality and charge-transport dynamics (Supplementary Fig.  6 ). The target inducing unavoidable recombination loss and fast degradation of the perovskite  17  . Here we report the formation of a hydrogen-bond-bridged intermediate by adding a multifunctional molecule (4-guanidinobenzoic acid hydrochloride (GBAC)) into the perovskite precursor to modulate the crystallization kinetics and serve as an effective non-volatile passivation linker in the annealed film. Combining crystallography, in situ photoluminescence (PL) characterizations and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we reveal that the crystal growth kinetics is regulated by additional energies required for hydrogen-bond breakage and cation exchange between the intermediate phase and perovskite. Therefore, the obtained perovskite films exhibit significantly enhanced crystallinity with larger grains. Besides, the additives can form tight packs at the grain boundaries due to π-π interaction of the aryls to effectively passivate the defects in perovskites. The derived inverted PVSCs achieved a champion PCE of 24.8% with an open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.19 V, short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 24.55 mA cm -2 and fill factor (FF) of 84.78%. A certified PCE of 24.5% was obtained from the Japan Electrical Safety &amp; Environment Technology Laboratories, being among the highest reported for inverted PVSCs (Supplementary Table  1 ). We also applied this strategy to fabricate wide-bandgap and large-area PVSCs, paving the way for developing multijunction and scalable perovskite photovoltaics. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4-guanidinobenzoic acid hydrochloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:54:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="12558" length="37"/>
        <text>4-guanidinobenzoic acid hydrochloride</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4-guanidinobenzoic acid hydrochloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:54:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="12597" length="4"/>
        <text>GBAC</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.19</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:56:11Z</infon>
        <location offset="13426" length="7"/>
        <text>1.19 V,</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13878</offset>
      <text> Characterization of perovskite films We introduced GBAC as an additive into the perovskite precursor solution, which can interact with the uncoordinated lead and  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14043</offset>
      <text> Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6  film exhibits six times stronger PL intensity and three times longer PL lifetime than those of the control film, agreeing well with the FTIR and XPS results that GBAC suppresses the defect-induced non-radiative recombination to reduce energy loss for improving the photovoltaic performance. To understand how GBAC addition affects the film morphology, we collected scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images of the perovskite films. The target film shows considerably larger grains (~1 μm) and fewer residual PbI 2 sheets than the control film (Fig.  1c, d ), with a coherent bottom-to-surface grain growth that can facilitate the transport of carriers to electrodes. Besides good film morphology, the crystallinity of the target film is significantly improved (Fig.  1e ). The decreased PbI 2 sheets in the SEM images was also confirmed by the X-ray powder diffraction (XRD) patterns, suggesting that GBAC can interact with the uncoordinated Pb 2+ and modulate film growth to obtain fully grown grains. Moreover, the addition of GBAC significantly helps modulate the crystal orientation within the film for facilitating charge transport (Supplementary Fig.  7 ). Atomic force microscopy characterization reveals a lower surface roughness after GBAC addition (Supplementary Fig.  8 ). We also applied Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) to evaluate the distribution of the surface potential of perovskite films, which shows an increment of 200-300 mV in the target film (Fig.  1f  and Supplementary Fig.  9 ), indicating a Fermi level (E F ) closer to the conductive band edge  21  . The higher work function measured by KPFM matches well with the results obtained from ultraviolet photoelectron spectrometry (UPS), showing a 0.25 eV shift in E F by adding GBAC (Supplementary Fig.  10 ). The more n-characteristic film surface stems from the modified surface termination after adding GBAC (ref. 22), enabling more efficient charge transfer between the perovskite and electron-transporting materials (Supplementary Fig.  11 ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>16125</offset>
      <text> In situ characterization of film formation To gain more insights into the remarkably enhanced film quality, we adopted in situ PL spectrometry to understand the role of GBAC during film formation  [23] [24] [25]  . The evolution of the PL peak position in both control and target films shows similar trends in the long-term stage (0-750 s) (Supplementary Figs.  12 13 14 ). However, the initial peak position of the wet target film was slightly blueshifted compared with that of the control film due to the additional chloride from GBAC (Fig.  2a, b ). Also, the target film exhibits a much slower shift with negligible fluctuation in the initial stage (0-10 s) compared with those of the control sample, implying that the crystallization process was significantly retarded by adding GBAC (Fig.  2b )  23  . Moreover, the PL peaks of the target film are more symmetric compared with the control film, indicating a more uniform distribution of crystallite sizes, which facilitates the significantly increased grain sizes, as shown in the SEM images (Fig.  1c, d )  25  . We then analysed the evolution of PL peak intensity, which shows typical PL quenching in both films but more severe in the control film (Fig.  2c, d )  24, 25  . Such PL quenching originates from the continuously increased Urbäch energy, indicating the gradual formation of defects in the microstructures of perovskites  24  . However, it is considerably inhibited in the target film, showing a much lower defect density and better ambient stability than the control film (Fig.  2d )  26  . The initial stages (0-2 s for the control sample and 0-30 s for the target sample) were then enlarged to clearly show the PL intensity evolution (Fig.  2e, f ). The control film shows a typical four-stage 'up-down-up-down' process with two states (Fig.  2e )  24  . In state 'I' (0-200 ms), the perovskite grains grow freely and are well crystallized/ordered, resulting in an increased PL intensity ('up'). When the solvent is almost entirely evaporated, the perovskite crystallites are exposed to the surrounding atmosphere and the surfaces of other crystallites, forming grain boundaries and triggering rapid PL quenching ('down'; 200-400 ms). In state 'II', the small crystallites further grow and merge into larger ones on annealing to reduce the overall grain boundaries, resulting in an increased PL intensity again ('up'; 400-600 ms). Such a rapid film formation can also be attributed to the absorbed moisture accumulated within the grain boundaries, inducing grain-boundary creep and subsequent merging of adjacent grains to accelerate the film growth  27  . The partial recovery of PL intensity also comes from the passivation effect of excessive PbI 2 at the perovskite grain boundaries  28  . Eventually, the film is vulnerable under ambient conditions and prone to decomposition. This results in a stabilized but almost one order of magnitude lower PL intensity than that of PL max ('down'; after 600 ms). However, adding GBAC introduces an extra stage involving the intermediate-induced pre-growth process in the target sample (Fig.  2f )  24, 25  . The film formation is significantly slowed down, reaching its maximum PL intensity at ~20 s and maintained for longer time. These results imply that adding GBAC can modulate the crystallization kinetics by forming an additional intermediate to enhance the film quality, leading to larger grain sizes and high crystallinity. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19577</offset>
      <text> Film growth with hydrogen-bond-bridged intermediate To study the GBAC-induced intermediate phase, we grew the single crystal of GBAC-PbI 2 -N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF) (Supplementary Table  2 )  29  . We observed strong cyclic hydrogen bonds between the carboxylic acid and guanidium groups as well as DMF and guanidium groups (Fig.  3a ). The DMF molecules locked by hydrogen bonds help isolate the PbI 2 sheets and GBAC layer, leading to a one-dimensional organic-inorganic hybrid chain structure. Due to the strong dipole of GBAC and the electron delocalization in the guanidium groups (Supplementary Fig.  15 ), these hydrogen bonds are very different from the typical linear hydrogen-bonded chains that serve as supramolecular synthons for layered perovskite structures  30  . This unique interaction mode helps build a bridge to connect the organic-inorganic components. Moreover, the interaction between GBAC and perovskite precursor components in solution was investigated by 1 H nuclear magnetic resonance spectrometry (Supplementary Fig.  16 ), of which the results are in good agreement with those observed from XPS and FTIR measurements  7  . Through these studies, we have identified that GBAC can simultaneously interact with the solvent, organic and inorganic components in the precursor solution through both Coulomb interaction and hydrogen bonding, demonstrating its multifunctionality in solution. We then conducted a thermal analysis of single crystals to study the phase transition from the intermediate state to perovskite. The experimental XRD pattern of the obtained transparent GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF crystals matches well with the XRD pattern simulated from the single-crystal structure, confirming their composition (Supplementary Fig.  17 ). The simultaneous thermal analysis profile shows an intense endothermic peak at ~80 °C corresponding to hydrogen-bond breakage (Supplementary Fig.  18 ). At elevated temperatures, DMF starts to evaporate, destabilizing the intermediate that then transforms into a new one-dimensional structure composed of GBAC-PbI 2 (Fig.  3b  and Supplementary Fig.  19 ). This GBAC-PbI 2 phase can only be identified in a perovskite film with &gt;4 mol% GBAC dosage (Supplementary Figs.  20  and 21 ), where a small dosage of GBAC, in turn, functions as a passivation linker anchoring at the grain boundaries to reduce the defect density and enhance the film stability with its rigid stacking 8 . To understand the impact of such hydrogen-bond-bridged intermediate on film growth, periodic DFT calculations were performed to understand if GBAC + can spontaneously exchange with FA + during the crystallization process. Due to the substantial hydrogen bonding, the formation energy of this intermediate (GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF) (-18.58 eV) is much lower than that of δ-FAPbI 3 (-10.60 eV). Such extra stabilization is not thermodynamically favourable for crystal growth, since extra energy is required to enable the cation exchange between GBAC + and FA + (ref. 31). During the subsequent thermal annealing, the hydrogen bonds in the GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF phase were broken to form GBAC-PbI 2 Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6  with an energy of -11.85 eV (Fig.  3c ). Although this significantly reduced energy barrier (1.25 eV) is easier to overcome, it will still hinder the free exchange between GBAC + and FA + , thereby slowing down the crystallization process  32  . In addition to thermodynamic control, the nucleation rate mediated by kinetic control can also be altered by increasing the activation energy of cation exchange  33  . Compared with the Lewis acid-base adduct formed between PbI 2 and DMF (-0.79 eV) (Fig.  3d ), the stronger ionic bonding between GBAC and PbI 2 (-1.16 eV) will cost extra energy to overcome the saddling point (Supplementary Figs.  22  and 23 )  34, 35  . Moreover, based on the Arrhenius equation, the inherent nucleation and growth kinetics originating from the high volatility of DMF and strong FA-precursor binding to DMF (-1.00 eV) (ref. 36) will also be hindered by the more stable GBAC-PbI 2 phase. Therefore, the crystal growth of the perovskite can be both thermodynamically and kinetically modulated by this hydrogen-bond-bridged intermediate (Supplementary Fig.  24 ). Due to the strong interaction between GBAC and perovskite, the retarded film formation would also accumulate GBAC at the bottom interface (Supplementary Fig.  25 ). Eventually, rigidly stacked GBAC can form at the grain boundaries due to π-π interaction after DMF evaporation, acting as a multifunctional passivation linker to enhance the photovoltaic performance (Fig.  3e )  8  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24235</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic performance The inverted PVSCs with a device configuration of indium tin oxide (ITO)/((2,7-dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl) methyl) phosphonic acid (DC-PA) (ref. 21)/perovskite (with/without GBAC)/C60/bathocuproine/Ag were fabricated to evaluate their photovoltaic performance (Fig.  4a , Supplementary Figs.  26  and 27  and Supplementary Table  3 ). As shown in Fig.  4b , the highest PCE of the control device is 22.8%, with V OC of 1.12 V, J SC of 24.48 mA cm -2 and FF of 83.01%. However, the champion PCE of the GBAC-treated device can be further improved to 24.8% (V OC of 1.19 V, J SC of 24.55 mA cm -2 and FF of 84.78%), which is among the highest efficiencies reported so far for inverted PVSCs. The stabilized power output of the target champion device is 24.4%, matching well with the PCEs from the J-V measurement (Fig.  4c ). The device performance was also validated at an independent laboratory ( Japan Electrical Safety &amp; Environment Technology Laboratories) to show a  certified PCE of 24.5% (V OC = 1.19 V, J SC = 24.45 mA cm -2 and FF = 84.20%) (Supplementary Fig.  28 ). The integrated photocurrent (24.38 mA cm -2 ) from the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum also matches well with the values obtained from the J-V measurements (Fig.  4d ). The bandgap of the perovskite is 1.55 eV, as obtained by calculating the EQE derivative (Supplementary Fig.  29 ). Benefiting from the enhanced film quality and defect passivation aided by GBAC, the average V OC value was boosted from 1.12 to 1.18 V (Fig.  4e ). The overall energy loss of the champion target device can be reduced to 0.36 eV, which is very close to that of GaAs photovoltaics and represents one of the lowest energy losses in high-PCE cases (Fig.  4f )  37, 38  . DFT calculations investigated the typical I Pb antisite defect on a PbI 2 -terminated surface, revealing that GBAC passivation can help reduce these deep-level charge-carrier traps (Supplementary Fig.  30 ). The trap density was reduced from 2.58 × 10 16 to 1.53 × 10 16 cm -3 after adding GBAC, further demonstrating the effectiveness of this strategy (Supplementary Fig.  31 ). Since adding GBAC can modulate crystallization to improve the film quality, this strategy can also be explored for fabricating large-area PVSCs (Supplementary Fig.  32 ). As shown in Fig.  4g , a large-area device (1.008 cm 2 ) delivered a PCE of 22.7% (V OC = 1.18 V, J SC = 24.83 mA cm -2 , FF = 77.43%), which is also one of the highest efficiencies reported for similar-sized PVSCs (Supplementary Table  4 ). Besides, the V OC and J SC values of this device are comparable with those obtained in small-area devices, showing great promise for device upscaling (Supplementary Fig.  33  and Supplementary Table  5 ). To demonstrate the general applicability of this approach to different perovskite compositions, we also fabricated devices based on a larger-bandgap perovskite (1.78 eV). The average PCE showed an increase from 15.70% to 16.61%, with average V OC improvement from 1.19 to 1.25 V, which is highly favourable for fabricating tandem photovoltaics (Supplementary Fig.  34 ). (i) (ii) (ii) (ii) (iii) (i) (i) (ii) (iii) (i) Finally, we investigated the stability of devices under an accelerated aging condition based on the recognized protocols  39  . Unencapsulated devices were aged under continuous heating at 65 ± 5 °C (under N 2 ). The target device showed a very small PCE decay (&lt;3%) after 1,200 h, whereas that of the control device decreased nearly 30% during the same period (Fig.  4h ). This shows that the interaction between GBAC and organic components (MA/FA) helps strengthen the film to avoid severe decomposition and sublimation under heating (Supplementary Fig.  35 ). The long-term operational stability of the unencapsulated devices was also measured by tracking the true maximum power point under continuous one-sun illumination (Supplementary Fig.  36 ) in a N 2 -filled glovebox. The target device maintained ~90% of its initial PCE after 500 h, whereas that of the control device decreased to ~30% of its original value (Supplementary Fig.  37 ). We also performed time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (ToF-SIMS) measurements to probe the compositional changes and ion migration related to device degradation. The control devices show dramatic changes with ions migrated to the perovskite/ETL interface after aging (Supplementary Fig.  38 ). However, only negligible changes were observed in the target sample aged under the same condition. Such improved device stability can be attributed to the enhanced film morphology and inhibited ion migration by adding GBAC. If GBAC can be used in conjunction with more efficient encapsulation techniques and optimal perovskite compositions, further improved PVSC efficiency and stability can be expected to meet the requirements for practical applications  [40] [41] [42]  . &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(2,7-Dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl)methyl phosphonic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:58:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="24334" length="57"/>
        <text>((2,7-dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl) methyl) phosphonic acid</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(2,7-Dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl)methyl phosphonic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:58:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="24392" length="7"/>
        <text>(DC-PA)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:52:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="24441" length="3"/>
        <text>C60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1200</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:59:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="27688" length="8"/>
        <text>1,200 h,</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">70</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:56:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="27732" length="20"/>
        <text>decreased nearly 30%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T05:01:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="27982" length="158"/>
        <text>long-term operational stability of the unencapsulated devices was also measured by tracking the true maximum power point under continuous one-sun illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:56:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="28224" length="3"/>
        <text>90%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T05:01:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="28253" length="5"/>
        <text>500 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">30</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:56:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="28308" length="4"/>
        <text>~30%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29147</offset>
      <text> Conclusion In summary, we report an innovative strategy for achieving high-quality and stable perovskite films by employing a multifunctional, non-volatile additive, GBAC, which forms a unique hydrogen-bond-bridged  We experimentally and theoretically unveil the mechanism of GBAC in assisting perovskite film formation, providing a design guideline for selecting suitable non-volatile additives to enhance the film quality. The greatly ameliorated optoelectronic properties are attributed to improved film morphology and crystallinity, effective defect passivation and more efficient charge transfer at the more n-characteristic film surface. Consequently, an impressive PCE of 24.8% (24.5% certified), low energy loss (0.36 eV) and remarkable device stability were achieved in inverted PVSCs. Our approach can also be extended to fabricate wide-bandgap perovskite devices and upscale devices, providing a simple and effective way towards fabricating scalable and highly efficient PVSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30138</offset>
      <text> Online content Any methods, additional references, Nature Portfolio reporting summaries, source data, extended data, supplementary information, acknowledgements, peer review information; details of author contributions and competing interests; and statements of data and code availability are available at  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6 . Ref.  2  Ref.  3  Ref.  4  Ref.  5  Ref.  6  Ref.  7  This work Ref. PVSCs reported in the literature (listed in Supplementary Table  1 ). g, J-V curve of the champion device with an active area of 1.008 cm 2 , and the inset shows a photograph of the device. h, Intrinsic stability of unencapsulated devices aged under 65 ± 5 °C in a N 2 -filled glovebox. Data from eight cells are collected and presented as mean values ± standard error of the mean. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30991</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31001</offset>
      <text> Materials All the materials are used as received without further purification, including DMF (99.99%, J&amp;K), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, 99.70%, J&amp;K), isopropanol (IPA, 99.50%, J&amp;K) and chlorobenzene (CB, 99.90%, J&amp;K). Caesium iodide, caesium bromide, methylammonium iodide, formamidinium iodide (FAI) and formamidinium bromide were bought from Dysol. PbI 2 (99.9985%) and lead bromide (&gt;98.0000%) were bought from TCI. MACl, bathocuproine (99.9%) and C60 were bought from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. GBAC (99%) was bought from Sigma-Aldrich. Piperazinium iodide  7  and DC-PA (ref. 21) were synthesized according to previous reports. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31639</offset>
      <text> Synthesis of GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF single crystals PbI 2 and GBAC (1/1 by molar, 1.0 M) were dissolved in DMF and stirred overnight at 50 °C. The turbid liquid was filtered and transferred into a 4 mL vial. The vial was then placed into a sealed bottle filled with 2 mL CB. The GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF single crystals were grown along with the slow diffusion of the vapour of the antisolvent CB into the solution. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32042</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication ITO glass (15 Ω sq -1 ; 1.5 × 1.5 cm 2 for a regular device and 2.5 × 2.5 cm 2 for a large-area device) was progressively washed by sonication with detergent (Decon 90), deionized water, acetone and IPA for 15 min. The washed ITO glass was dried in a 75 °C oven for over 12 h. Then, the cleaned ITO substrates were subjected to ultraviolet-ozone for 25 min and transformed in a N 2 -filled glovebox for film fabrication. DC-PA (2 mg mL -1 in IPA) was dynamically spin coated onto the cleaned ITO at 3,000 rpm for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 15 min. The substrates were cooled down to room temperature and washed with pure IPA and then annealed at 100 °C for 5 min. Then, 1.7 M perovskite precursor solutions were constructed by mixing FAI, PbI 2 , methylammonium iodide and caesium iodide in DMF:DMSO mixed solvent (4:1 v:v) with the chemical formula Cs 0.06 MA 0.14 FA 0.80 PbI 3 . Then, 10 mol% MACl was added into the precursor solution. For the target perovskite, 0.8 mol% GBAC was added to the precursor solution, and it was ensured that it is well mixed with the precursor. Then, 50 μL of the prepared precursor solution was spin coated at 1,000 rpm for 10 s and 5,000 rpm for 30 s onto the DC-PA-based ITO substrate; 170 μL CB as the antisolvent was dripped on the film at 10 s before the end of the last procedure and then annealed at 100 °C for 30 min. After deposition of the perovskite active layer, 50 μL piperazinium iodide (0.4 mg mL -1 in IPA) solution was spin coated onto the film at 5,000 rpm for 30 s and annealed at 100 °C for 5 min. For the wide-bandgap perovskite, 1.2 M precursor solution with the chemical formula Cs 0.2 FA 0.8 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 was prepared from FAI, caesium iodide, formamidinium bromide, caesium bromide, PbI 2 and lead bromide, and then dissolved in DMF:DMSO mixed solvents (4:1 v:v). Then, 5 mol% excess of PbI 2 and 5 mol% MACl were added into the precursor solution. The target perovskite with 0.5 mol% GBAC was spin coated onto the DC-PA/ITO substrates at 5,000 rpm with an accelerating speed of 1,500 rpm for 30 s. Then, 150 μL CB as the antisolvent was dripped on the film at 15 s before the ending and then annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. The films were then cooled down to room temperature and readied for thermal evaporation. Subsequently, 25 nm C60, 8 nm bathocuproine and 100 nm Ag electrode were sequentially evaporated under a high vacuum (&lt;4 × 10 -6 torr). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34508</offset>
      <text> Characterizations The 1 H nuclear magnetic resonance spectra were collected on a Bruker AVANCE III HD 300 MHz spectrometer in a DMSO-d6 solution with tetramethylsilane as a reference. The morphology of the samples was recorded by an SEM instrument (Philips XL30 FEG). Steady-state PL and time-resolved PL spectrum were obtained with an FLS980 spectrofluorometer (Edinburgh) with a pulsed excitation laser of 485 nm. The XPS and UPS characterization measurements were conducted in a VG ESCALAB 220i XL surface analysis system equipped with a He-discharge lamp (hv = 21.22 eV) and a monochromatic Al Kα X-ray gun (hv = 1,486.60 eV), respectively. ToF-SIMS (ION TOF-SIMS5) data were analysed with the positive mode (Bi) under 30 keV (1.00 pA) with an area of 100 × 100 μm 2 . The sputter parameters for the device are O 2 under 1 keV (100 nA) with an area of 300 × 300 μm 2 , and the sputter parameters for the film sample is gas cluster ion beam ion gun under 10 keV (10 nA) with an area of 800 × 800 μm 2 . XRD characterization was conducted on a D2 Phaser instrument with Cu Kα (wavelength, 1.5418 Å) radiation. Grazing-incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering measurements were conducted using a Xeuss 2.0 SAXS/WAXS laboratory beamline with a Cu X-ray source (8.05 keV, 1.54 Å) and a Pilatus 3R 300 K detector. The incidence angle is 1.0°. In situ PL spectra were characterized with home-built equipment. An excitation laser (315 nm) was introduced to the sample through a fibre, and the PL spectra were detected by using a detector connected to an Ocean Optics USB2000. PL mapping was collected using a WITec alpha300 M+ confocal microscope. The excitation laser was a diode-pumped solid-state laser (532 nm, Cobolt Laser). The J-V characteristics were measured in a N 2 -filled glovebox by a Keithley 2400 source meter under AM 1.5 G (100 mW cm -2 ) irradiation using an Enlitech SS-F5 solar simulator. The light intensity was calibrated using a silicon solar cell (with a KG-2 filter) from the National Renewable Energy Laboratory. The device areas are 0.040 cm 2 for regular devices and 1.008 cm 2 for the large-size device, both of which are determined by metal aperture masks. A 150-nm-thick magnesium fluoride layer was deposited on the back of the glass before measurements. The EQE values were collected by an Enlitech EQE measurement system. A silicon solar cell calibrated by the National Renewable Energy Laboratory was used to obtain the AM 1.5 G solar simulator's light intensity. The devices used for the stability test had the same structure as that for the J-V test. For thermal stability characterization, the devices were aged on a hotplate at 65 ± 5 °C in a N 2 -filled glovebox and cooled down to room temperature before the J-V test. For maximum power point tracking, the devices were tracked through the high-throughput solar-cell lifetime test system from CRYSCO with maximum power point tracking under light-emitting-diode-simulated AM 1.5 G spectrum. The light source is a superluminescent diode with a range from 400 to 1,000 nm. The superluminescent diode source is equipped with a silicon photoelectric probe to monitor the change in light intensity and automatically adjust the intensity with the control of the host. The intensity of the superluminescent diode source can be adjusted from 0.1 to 1.2 kW m -2 . The duration between the two tests is 300 s. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37907</offset>
      <text> Single-crystal analysis The single-crystal structure of GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF was resolved and refined using the Bruker SHELXTL-2016/6 software package. All the non-hydrogen atoms were anisotropically refined, and all the hydrogen atoms were refined as riding atoms. The crystal data and data collection and refinement parameters are listed in Supplementary Table  1 . Also, CCDC 2141303 contains the supplementary crystallographic data of GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF, which can be obtained free of charge from the Cambridge Crystallographic Data Centre via www.ccdc.cam.ac.uk/ data_request/cif. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38487</offset>
      <text> DFT calculations First-principles calculations based on DFT were performed with the Vienna ab initio simulation package  43  , using the generalized gradient approximation of the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof functional  44  for the exchange-correlation functional. Valence-core electron interactions were treated with the projector-augmented wave method  45  . We employed Grimme's DFT-D3 scheme to include the van der Waals interactions  45  , and dipole correction for slab calculations  46  . The cutoff  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6   energy of plane-wave expansions was set at 500 eV and the Hellmann-Feynman forces acting on atoms were converged below 0.01 eV Å -1 for all the calculations. For the calculation of binding energies (defined as E PbI 2 -molecule -E PbI 2 -E molecule ), 1 × 1 × 1 Γ-centred k-point grid was adopted, and the convergence criteria for the electronic wave function was 1.0 × 10 -6 eV energy difference. For geometry optimizations and energy calculations, 4 × 4 × 4 Γ-centred k-point mesh for δ-FAPbI 3 , 2 × 4 × 2 Γ-centred k-point mesh for GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF, 3 × 4 × 2 δ-centred k-point mesh for GBAC-PbI 2 and 5 × 5 × 5 Γ-centred k-point mesh for α-FAPbI 3 were used. The convergence criteria of the energy difference was set to 1.0 × 10 -5 eV. Note that the formation energy (ΔE δ-FAPbI 3 ) was calculated using the equation For slab calculations, the Brillouin zone was sampled with a 2 × 2 × 1 Γ-centred k-point mesh, and a vacuum of at least 30 Å was used to avoid the interaction of neighbouring interfaces along the z direction. The electrostatic potentials (φ) of the interacting pairs were calculated using the Gaussian 09 package at the B3LYP/def2TZVP level with DFT-D3. The maximum φ (φ max ) and minimum φ (φ min ) values of the interacting pairs were obtained with the help of Multiwfn code  47  . The structure models were drawn with the VESTA software  48  . Some data processing was done by VASPKIT  49  . Figure S2 . S2 Figure S2. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) of the control and target perovskite films scraped from substrates. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40610</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. Full-scale X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) spectrum of control and target perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40737</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 . S4 Figure S4. C1s spectrum of the control and target perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40822</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 . S5 Figure S5. O1s spectrum of the (a) control and (b) target perovskite films. (c) The intensity ratio of O/Pb demonstrates the increased content of O. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40988</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 . S6 Figure S6. Steady-state PL and time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) of the control and target perovskite films on glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41128</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 . S7 Figure S7. GIWAXS images of the (a) control and (b) target perovskite films. (c) Corresponding intensity plots azimuthally along the ring at the qr axis. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41299</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. Atomic force microscopy (AFM) images of the control and target perovskite films. The average surface roughness of the film reduced from 16.8 nm to 12.6 nm after GBAC addition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41503</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 . S9 Figure S9. Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) images of the control and target perovskite films, the scale bar is 1 μm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41643</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 . S10 Figure S10. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) results of control and target perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41767</offset>
      <text> Figure S11 . S11 Figure S11. Energy-level scheme for the control and perovskite films based on the parameters derived from UPS spectra. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41905</offset>
      <text> Figure S12 . S12 Figure S12. The overall PL peak evolution of control and target perovskite films in ambient. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42017</offset>
      <text> Figure S13 . S13 Figure S13. The evolution of the in-situ PL peak position for control and target perovskite films annealed in an N2-filled glove box, which shows similar peak shifting with the results acquired in ambient air, due to the quantum confinement of nanograins and the compositional evolution of perovskite. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42338</offset>
      <text> Figure S14 . S14 Figure S14. The evolution of the in-situ PL intensity for (a-c) control and (d-f) target perovskite films annealed in an N2-filled glove box. The overall evolution of PL intensity of control and target films show the same "up-down-up-down" trends as those &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42613</offset>
      <text> Figure S15 . S15 Figure S15. The dipole of GBAC + (13.1584 D). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42678</offset>
      <text> Figure S16 . S16 Figure S16. The 1 H NMR spectra of GBAC, and its' mixture with PbI2, MAI, and FAI, respectively. (a) The recognition of different protons in GBAC + and FA + , MA + cations. (b) 1 H NMR spectrum of GBAC and mixing with PbI2, showing only guanidino proton presents visible shift. (c) 1 H NMR spectrum of GBAC, MAI, and the mixture of MAI and GBAC, (d) 1 H NMR spectrum of GBAC, FAI, and the mixture of FAI and GBAC, showing that the strong hydrogen bonding between GBAC and MAI/FAI has won the competition with the fast proton exchanges between MAI/FAI, HDO, and DMSO. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43264</offset>
      <text> Figure S17 . S17 Figure S17. Simulated powder XRD and the experimental powder XRD of the PbI2-GBAC-DMF single crystal. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43385</offset>
      <text> Figure S18 . S18 Figure S18. (a) Simultaneous thermal analysis (STA) and (b) thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) of the PbI2-GBAC-DMF single crystal. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43534</offset>
      <text> Figure S19 . S19 Figure S19. XRD patterns of the PbI2-GBAC-DMF film (a) before and (c) after annealing. Insets are photographs of films, showing transparent and light yellow respectively. (b) and (d) are the corresponding simulated XRD pattern from the crystal structure. # denotes the signal of ITO glass. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43843</offset>
      <text> Figure S20 . S20 Figure S20. (a) XRD pattern of perovskite film with excessive GBAC (4 mol%) showing a new peak of the low dimensional structure. (b) The corresponding crystal structure of GBAC-PbI2 after annealing, the orange crystal plane (10-2) corresponds to the peak of 10.7 o in the XRD pattern. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44147</offset>
      <text> Figure S22 . S22 Figure S22. Superposition of electrostatic potential mapped vdW surfaces of interacting pairs (negative regions are indicated in red, and positive regions are indicated in blue). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44345</offset>
      <text> Figure S23 . S23 Figure S23. The molecular structures of interacting pairs and corresponding Gaussian calculated electrostatic potentials (φ). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44491</offset>
      <text> Figure S24 . S24 Figure S24. Cyclic XRD characterization of wet films, collecting the signal from 5.5 o to 18 o within 2 mins and then repeating for another cycle. (a) XRD patterns of the first cycle scan for the as-cast control and target perovskite films. Peak a, c, e: MAI-based intermediated phase (ACS Energy Lett. 2017, 2, 12, 2686; Sci. Adv. 2021; 7, eabb2412), peak b: the (020) plane of the metastable (MAI)2(DMF)2Pb2I6 phase, peak d: CH3NH3PbI3•H2O intermediate phase (J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2014, 136, 46, 16411), peak f: δ-FAPbI3, peak g: PbI2, peak i: α-FAPbI3. (b) The pictures of the wet control and target perovskite films before and after cyclic XRD measurement. (c and d) The XRD patterns of the control and target perovskite films under cycling. Every cycle takes about 2 min. The retarded appearance of peak i and the higher intensity of peak e in the target film also help support that the GBAC could slow down the crystallization process and form other intermediate phases to modulate the film growth. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45516</offset>
      <text> Figure S25 . S25 Figure S25. The ToF-SIMS results of the target perovskite film with an architecture of C60/Perovskite/DC-PA/ITO. The grey, yellow and blue shaded regions represent the C60 film, perovskite film, and substrates, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45760</offset>
      <text> Figure S26 . S26 Figure S26. Statistical analysis of the photovoltaic performance for control and target devices. The data from 20 cells were statistically analyzed. The box represents the median and the quartiles, and the whisker covers the minima up to maxima of the data points. The individual value of each data point is plotted as a point superimposed on the graph. All the box plots below have the same definition. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46183</offset>
      <text> Figure S27 . S27 Figure S27. Box plots of the device's performance for control and target PVSCs (20 devices) without PI surface treatment and anti-reflection (AR) layer. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46355</offset>
      <text> Figure S28 . S28 Figure S28. The certified results of the champion device were measured at JET. The certified PCE is 24.5% certified aperture with an area of 0.04003 cm 2 . The certified J-V curves with double scanning give PCE forward: 24.1% and PCE reverse: 24.5%. The certified stabilized power output is 24.1%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46672</offset>
      <text> Figure S29 . S29 Figure S29. Derivative of EQE curve to identify the bandgap of the perovskite, which is 1.55 eV. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46788</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S30. a, Density of states (DOS) of the surface IPb antisite defect with or without GBAC passivation. b, Partial charge density of the in-gap states in (a) highlighted with the red circle. c, Adsorption configuration of the GBAC on the perovskite surface with IPb antisite defect. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47084</offset>
      <text> Figure S31 . S31 Figure S31. Dark I-V curves of the control and target devices based on the electrononly structure (ITO/SnO2/Perovskites/C60/BCP/Ag). The trap density can be calculated &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47271</offset>
      <text> Figure S32 . S32 Figure S32. (a) Confocal PL intensity mapping and (b) the distribution of PL peak position for a region of 50 × 50 μm in the control and target perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47454</offset>
      <text> Figure S33 . S33 Figure S33. Histogram of device performance for 30 large-area devices (1 cm 2 ) fabricated in one batch. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47578</offset>
      <text> Figure S34 . S34 Figure S34. Box plots of device performance for control and target wide-bandgap (1.78 eV) PVSCs. The data are from 15 devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47724</offset>
      <text> Figure S35. 1 H 1 Figure S35. 1  H NMR spectra of the fresh and aged perovskite films. The films were aged under 85 ± 5 ℃ for about 72 h to accelerate the decomposition. The resonance peaks belonging to the protons (peak ϒ) of the MA amine disappeared in the aged sample, suggesting the loss of MA + in the control film after thermal aging. Also, the conformation of FA + changed in the aged control film, where the resonance of protons from the NH2 groups (peak α) in FA + became broadened after aging. However, for target film aged under the same condition, the resonance of protons (peak ϒ) from MA and the inequivalent protons of the NH2 groups (peak α) in FA + both well remained. These results indicate that GBAC can interact with the organic components to enhance thermal stability. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48523</offset>
      <text> Figure S36 . S36 Figure S36. The spectrum of the SLED source used for the stability test. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48615</offset>
      <text> Figure S37 . S37 Figure S37. The maximum power point (MPP) tracking of the control and target devices. The initial PCE of the control and target device is 21.59% and 23.53%, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48805</offset>
      <text> Figure S38 . S38 Figure S38. The ToF-SIMS profiles of the (a and b) control and (c and d) target devices. The films were aged under continuous heating (at 65 ± 5 ℃) and illumination for about 50 h. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49008</offset>
      <text> 6 Hydrogen 4 , 64 Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-Sei-Hum Jang 5 , Francis R. Lin 2,3 , Sai-Wing Tsang 1 , Xian-Kai Chen 1,2 &amp; Alex K.-Y. Jen 1,2,3,5 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49177</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Chemical interaction and morphology characterization of the perovskite films. a, FTIR spectra of the control and target films. b, Pb4f XPS spectra of the control and target films. c,d, Surface (up) and cross-section (down) SEM images of the control (c) and target (d) perovskite films. Scale bars, 1 μm. e, XRD patterns of the control and target films. Here * denotes the diffraction peak of PbI 2 , and # denotes the diffraction peak of ITO. f, Statistical distribution of surface potential extracted from the KPFM images. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49724</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Comparison of film growth kinetics by in situ PL. a,b, Normalized in situ PL peak position evolution of the control (a) and target (b) perovskite films. c,d, Normalized in situ PL intensity evolution of the control (c) and target (d) perovskite films. e,f, Detailed analysis of PL intensity evolution of the control (e) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50066</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Structure analysis and DFT calculations of the intermediatephase-induced crystallization. a, Crystal structure of the GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF intermediate; hydrogen bonds are marked in cyan-blue. b, Simulated XRD patterns of GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF and GBAC-PbI 2 . c, Formation energies of &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50363</offset>
      <text> Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-023-01180-6 intermediate phase to modulate the perovskite crystallization process and simultaneously functions as an efficient passivation linker. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50551</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 4 Fig. 4 | Characterization of photovoltaic performance and stability of PVSCs. a, Device architecture of the inverted PVSC. b, J-V curves of the champion devices. c,d, Stable output (c) and EQE curve (d) of the target champion device. SPO, stabilized power output. e, Box plot of the V OC distribution for control and target PVSCs. Data from 20 cells were statistically analysed. The box represents the median and quartiles, and the whisker covers the minima up to the maxima of the data points. The individual value of each data point is plotted as a point superimposed on the graph. f, Comparison of PCE and V OC loss of inverted PVSCs reported in the literature (listed in Supplementary Table1). g, J-V curve of the champion device with an active area of 1.008 cm 2 , and the inset shows a photograph of the device. h, Intrinsic stability of unencapsulated devices aged under 65 ± 5 °C in a N 2 -filled glovebox. Data from eight cells are collected and presented as mean values ± standard error of the mean. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51577</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . S1 Representative device performances of PVSCs with an inverted (p-i-n) structure. Reference E g (eV) V OC (V) V OC loss (V) PCE (%) Certified PCE (Organization) This work 1.51 1.19 0.36 24.8 24.5% (JET, Japan) Ref 1: Nat. Photonics 2022, 1.53 1.15 0.38 23.9 23.9% (NREL, U.S.) 16, 352. Ref 2: Science 2022, 376, 1.55 1.18 0.37 25.0 24.3% (NIM, China) 416. Ref 3: Science 2022, 375, 1.55 1.19 0.36 24.3 23.5% (SIMIT, China) 434. Ref 4: Science 2021, 373, 902. 1.49 1.17 0.32 23.8 cm 2 ) (20.1% for 19 19.3% for 18.1 cm 2 (NREL, U.S.) Ref 5: J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1.50 1.17 0.33 23.4 22.8% (IEE, China) 2020, 142, 47, 20134. Ref 6: Nat. Energy 2020, 5, 1.56 1.17 0.39 23.0 22.3% (Newport, U.S.) 131. Ref 7: Nature 2022, 1.53 1.15 0.38 25.5 25.4% (NREL, U.S.) https://doi.org/10.1038 /s41586-022-05268-x. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52389</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Crystal data and refinement of GBAC-PbI2-DMF. Chemical formula C14H24I3N5O4Pb Formula weight 914.27 g/mol Temperature 213(2) K Wavelength 1.54178 Å Crystal system monoclinic Space group P 1 21/c 1 a = 19.2650(5) Å α = 90° Unit cell dimensions b = 8.0266(2) Å β = 117.2290(10)° c = 21.0048(6) Å γ = 90° Volume 2888.09(13) Å 3 Z 4 Density (calculated) 2.103 g/cm 3 Independent reflections 5861 [R(int) = 0.0638] Data/restraints/parameters 5861 / 0 / 249 Goodness-of-fit on F 2 1.050 4912 data; I&gt;2σ(I) R1 = 0.0831, wR2 = 0.2451 Final R indices all data R1 = 0.0904, wR2 = 0.2556 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52994</offset>
      <text> Largest diff. peak and hole 2.475 and -6.294 eÅ -3 R.M.S. deviation from mean 0.354 eÅ -3 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53088</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . S3 Photovoltaic parameters of the target device with GBAC addition fabricated in one batch. Devices VOC (V) FF (%) JSC (mA/cm 2 ) PCE (%) 1 1.18 81.97 24.50 23.70 2 1.18 84.26 24.53 24.39 3 1.18 82.97 24.74 24.22 4 1.18 84.27 24.52 24.38 5 1.18 83.48 24.65 24.28 6 1.18 83.84 24.48 24.22 7 1.18 83.26 24.66 24.23 8 1.18 83.44 24.45 24.07 9 1.18 84.15 23.86 23.70 10 1.18 83.73 24.21 23.92 11 1.19 83.72 24.55 24.46 12 1.18 84.27 24.44 24.30 13 1.18 83.13 24.69 24.22 14 1.18 83.52 24.58 24.23 15 1.19 84.78 24.55 24.68 16 1.18 84.39 24.22 24.12 17 1.18 84.23 24.75 24.66 18 1.18 84.02 24.43 24.23 19 1.17 83.89 24.71 24.25 20 1.17 82.98 24.48 23.74 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53750</offset>
      <text> Table S4 . S4 Representative device performances of single-junction PVSCs with 1-cm 2   active area. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53853</offset>
      <text> Reference V OC (V) J SC (mA/cm 2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Device structure This work 1.18 24.83 77.4 22.7 p-i-n Table S5. Photovoltaic parameters of the large-area (1 cm 2 ) devices with GBAC addition fabricated in one batch. Devices VOC (V) FF (%) JSC (mA/cm 2 ) PCE (%) 1 1.18 72.43 24.89 21.27 2 1.17 78.56 24.47 22.49 Nature 2022, 601, 573. 3 1.20 1.19 22.89 76.98 85.1 23.4 24.81 n-i-p 22.73 Joule 2022, 6, 1. 4 1.15 1.18 24.83 73.75 80.0 22.8 24.74 n-i-p 21.53 5 Nat. Energy 2018, 3, 847. 6 1.18 1.13 1.18 77.14 22.24 75.84 80.5 24.73 20.3 24.96 22.51 p-i-n 22. 34 7 1.17 75.28 24.74 21.79 8 1.18 73.96 24.75 21.60 9 1.19 76.33 24.74 22.47 10 1.17 74.08 24.66 21.37 11 1.17 75.55 24.59 21.74 12 1.18 71.63 24.88 21.03 13 1.18 Yes No 74.04 24.82 21.68 14 1.17 72.67 24.40 20.75 15 1.18 75.37 24.41 21.71 16 1.17 72.17 24.49 20.67 17 1.18 74.95 24.54 21.70 18 1.18 72.59 24.74 21.19 19 1.19 77.05 24.78 22.72 20 1.17 78.56 24.47 22.49 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54786</offset>
      <text> ΔE δ-FAPbI 3 = 2E δ-FAPbI 3 -2E PbI 2 -4E FAI for PbI 2 + FAI→δ-FAPbI 3 , where E δ-FAPbI 3 is the energy of δ-FAPbI 3 , E PbI 2 is the energy of PbI 2 calculated from bulk PbI 2 and E FAI is the energy calculated from gas-phase FAI. The formation energy of bulk GBAC-PbI 2 was calculated by the equationΔE GBAC-PbI 2 = E GBAC-PbI 2 -2E PbI 2 -4E GBAC for PbI 2 + GBAC→ GBAC-PbI 2, where E GBAC is the energy calculated from gasphase GBAC. The formation energy of intermediatephase GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF was calculated with the equation ΔE GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF = E GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF -2E PbI 2 -4E GBAC -8E DMF for PbI 2 + GBAC + DMF→GBAC-PbI 2 -DMF, where E DMF is the energy of the DMF molecules.</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:55Z</infon>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="5" role=""/>
      <node refid="12" role=""/>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
    </relation>
    <relation id="R2">
      <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:55Z</infon>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="15" role=""/>
      <node refid="16" role=""/>
      <node refid="17" role=""/>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
