<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025047612DGEGIE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 127&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>q x = 2π λ (cos Ψ cos α f -cos α i ) (E2) q y = 2π λ (sin Ψ cos α f ) (E3) q z = 2π λ (sin α f + sin α i ) (E4) When the lateral structures are absent, it meets i = f due to the pure specular scattering. The diffuse scattering results from the lateral deviation of the refractive index, which leads to i ≠ f. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>350</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Note 2 The TRPL delay kinetics correlate to charge carrier recombination channels, which are dependent on excitation pulse fluences (initial charge carrier densities) S2-S4 . At very low excitation fluences, trap-mediated nonradiative monomolecular recombination (first-order) channel is dominated, leading to a mono-exponential relationship of TRPL decay kinetics. As excitation fluence increases, higher-order recombination channels such as bimolecular electron-hole radiative recombination (second-order) and trimolecular Auger recombination (third-order) start to contribute, resulting in accelerated TRPL decay kinetics, which can be generally governed by the following rate equation: d𝑁 d𝑡 = -𝑘 1 𝑁 -𝑘 2 𝑁 2 -𝑘 3 𝑁 3 (E5) where N is photoexcited charge carrier density, k1, k2 and k3 are rate constants for the first-order, second-order, and third-order recombination, respectively. To extract specific recombination rate constants, fluence-dependent TRPL analysis under excitation of 640 nm femtosecond laser pulses with various fluences (0.071, 0.177, 0.354, 0.707, 1.415, and 2.829 µJ cm -2 ) were carried out for the studied perovskite films. It is noted that our used excitation fluences are relatively low, under which the third-order Auger recombination is negligible. So, the k1 and k2 values can be extracted by globally fitting the TRPL delay kinetics with various excitation fluences by using the simplified rate equation (E6): d𝑁 d𝑡 = -𝑘 1 𝑁 -𝑘 2 𝑁 2 (E6) The lifetime (τ = 1/k1) of the first-order trap-mediated recombination then can be calculated. The resulting k1, k2 and τ values for the various studied perovskite films are summarized in Supplementary Tables  9  and 10 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2107</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Note 3 Based on Anderson's model  29,S5  , the heterojunctions between two contacting semiconductors can be classified as isotype and anisotype according to the type of conductivity present on either side of the junction. The former involves two semiconductors with similar types of conductivity, which includes n-n and p-p types. The latter comprises of two semiconductors with different types of conductivity, including p-n and n-p types. In the specific n-n isotype heterojunction, there are four cases of energy band profiles depending on the relation between electron affinities (χ), work functions () and bandgaps (Eg) of the two contacting semiconductors, as shown below. Case I: Our studied 3D/LD structures conform to the Case I energy band profile of n-n isotype heterojunction (see Fig.  3f ). In this situation, an accumulation layer is formed on the 3D side of the interface and a depletion layer on the LD side of the interface, accompanied with a selfconsistent quantum well at the interface  29,S5  (see Supplementary Fig.  41a ). According to various models proposed by Anderson and other researchers  29,S5  , thermionic emission and quantum tunneling over the heterojunction barrier are two probable intrinsic mechanisms for the charge transport across the heterojunction interface. Additionally, our LD capping layer with a small optimum thickness (~20 nm, estimated from Supplementary Fig.  16 ) is deposited on a relatively rough 3D perovskite surface (Supplementary Figs.  15  and 26 ) via the solution process, which makes the LD capping layer probably be discontinuous rather than conformal  3  . As illustrated in Supplementary Fig.  41b , both thin and thick regions of the LD capping layer probably coexist. The thin capping region is advantageous for charge transport by tunneling. For the thick capping region, the charge carriers can also diffuse to adjacent thin capping regions to transfer across the interface. 𝜒 1 &gt; 𝜒 2 , 𝑉 OC = 𝑘𝑇 𝑞 ln ( 𝐽 ph 𝐽 th + 1) (E7) where k, T, q, Jph and Jth are Boltzmann constant, absolute temperature, elementary charge, photocurrent density, and thermally generated current density (or dark current density), respectively. In fact, the VOC does not indefinitely increase with the enhancement of Jth according to the E7 relation, especially under relatively high irradiance, because the VOC is also limited by     2PEAX + APbX3 → PEA2PbX4 + AX PEA2PbX4 + APbX3 → PEA2APb2X7 PEA2APb2X7, PEA2PbX4, AX, PEAX PEA2PbX4 APbX3 PEA2PbX4 + APbX3 → PEA2APb2X7 PEA2APb2X7 PEA2ZnX4 (CsxFA1-x)PbX3 - PEA2ZnX4 (Rb2yCsxFA1-x-2y)PbX3 PEA2ZnX4 + (Rb2yCsxFA1-x-2y)PbX3 → (PEA1-yRby)2ZnX4 + 2yPEAX + (CsxFA1-x-2y)Pb1-2yX3(1-2y) + 2yPbX2 2PEAX + PbX2 → PEA2PbX4 PEA2PbX4 + APbX3 → PEA2APb2X7 PEA2ZnX4, (PEA1-yRby)2ZnX4, PEA2APb2X7, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4940</offset>
      <text> PEA2PbX4, PbX2 a A = Rb, Cs, FA; X = Cl/I. Three-dimensional/low-dimensional perovskite solar cells afford improved efficiency and stability. The design of low-dimensional capping materials is constrained to tuning the A-site organic cation, as Pb 2+ and Sn 2+ are the only options for the metal cation. Here we unlock access to a library of low-dimensional capping materials with metal cations beyond Pb 2+ /Sn 2+ by processing a full precursor solution containing both metal and ammonium halides. This enables easier synthetic control of the low-dimensional capping layer and greater versatility for low-dimensional interface engineering. We demonstrate that a zero-dimensional zinc-based halogenometallate (PEA 2 ZnX 4 ; PEA = phenethylammonium, X = Cl/I) induces more robust surface passivation and stronger n-N isotype three-dimensional/low-dimensional heterojunctions than its lead-based counterpart. We exhibit p-i-n solar cells with 24.1% efficiency (certified 23.25%). Our cells maintain 94.5% initial efficiency after &gt;1,000 h of operation at the maximum power point. Our findings expand the material library for low-dimensional interface engineering and stabilization of highly efficient three-dimensional/low-dimensional perovskite solar cells. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">zinc-based halogenometallate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:19:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="5621" length="28"/>
        <text>zinc-based halogenometallate</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">zinc-based halogenometallate</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:19:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="5651" length="11"/>
        <text>PEA 2 ZnX 4</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:19:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="5859" length="5"/>
        <text>p-i-n</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:19:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="5882" length="5"/>
        <text>24.1%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">94.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:55:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="5938" length="5"/>
        <text>94.5%</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6199</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Bi-layered three-dimensional/low-dimensional (3D/LD) perovskite solar cell (PSC) architecture recently emerged as an extremely promising approach to resolve the compromise between photovoltaic performance and operational stability  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9] [10]  . The superincumbent LD capping layer plays a crucial role not only in surface passivation, but also heterojunction construction and environmental stress resistance  [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] [16]  . The most common LD capping materials are types of halogenometallate, such as the popular two-dimensional (2D) Ruddlesden-Popper perovskites with the general formula of A 2 MX 4 (refs.  [17] [18] [19] [20] [21] [22] [23]  ), where A is a bulky ammonium cation, M is a metal cation and X is a halide anion. The widely adopted manufacturing process for the LD capping layer is to deposit a bulky ammonium halide such as phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) on top of a 3D perovskite, followed by a cation exchange reaction  14, 16  , which is known as the half precursor (HP) methodology. The metal cation of the LD capping materials is restricted to Pb 2+ /Sn 2+ and is almost irreplaceable in the current methodology as they are derived from the underlying 3D perovskite. Hence, the most popular strategy in new LD capping materials design is to engineer bulky molecular Article  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01204-z  PEAI salt still partially remained on both 3D perovskites under the same post-treatment, although most of it transformed into PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 (Fig.  1d, e ). The superior controllability of our FP technique for growth of the LD overlayer is further confirmed by the successful realization of a 2D (NMA) 2 PbI 4 (where NMA is 1-naphthylmethylammonium) capping layer with superior intrinsic stability  25  on a 3D perovskite (Supplementary Fig.  2 ), which is inaccessible via the traditional HP process due to the difficult reaction between the 1-naphthylmethylammonium iodide salt and the 3D perovskite  26  . Interestingly, we found that both PEA 2 ZnX 4 and PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 phases were detected in the Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 film (Fig.  1d ), but only PEA 2 ZnX 4 was present in the Cs 15 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 film (Fig.  1e ). It is also noted that halide exchange between I -in PEA 2 ZnX 4 and Cl -in either Rb 5 Cs 10 or Cs 15 perovskite always occurs, ultimately leading to a chloride-rich composition of PEA 2 ZnI 4-x Cl x (x ≥ 2) (Fig.  1d, e ), where the estimated values of x are presented in Supplementary Table  1 . Henceforth, we describe the zinc-based capping component using the simplified formula of PEA 2 ZnX 4 unless specified otherwise, where X is Cl -, I -or their mixture. To reveal the possible reaction pathways between PEA 2 ZnX 4 and Rb 5 Cs 10 perovskite, we investigated the RbCl/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack film under similar conditions and discovered that Rb + partially exchanged with PEA + to generate PEAX salt (Supplementary Fig.  3 ). The exchanged Rb + is probably incorporated into the PEA 2 ZnX 4 structure to form (PEA 1-y Rb y ) 2 ZnX 4 , which is a reasonable deduction as the full-width at half-maximum value for the characteristic diffraction peak of PEA 2 ZnX 4 almost doubled (Supplementary Fig.  3 ), and considering that Rb 2 ZnX 4 has the same β-K 2 SO 4 -type crystal structure as PEA 2 ZnX 4 (refs.  24, 27  ). Hence we conclude that the PEA 2 ZnX 4 capping layer partially reacted with the Rb 5 Cs 10 perovskite to generate (PEA 1-y Rb y ) 2 ZnX 4 and PEA-2 FAPb 2 I 7 via the cation exchange between Rb + and PEA + . The possible reactions between the studied LD capping materials and the 3D perovskites are summarized in Supplementary Table  2 . We further determined the possible conversion ratio of PEA 2 ZnX 4 in the Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack film by means of a rough quantitative XRD analysis (Supplementary Fig.  4  and Supplementary Table  3 ), in which the relative amount of phases present was estimated by using the integral intensity of the corresponding characteristic diffraction peak. Considering the identical preparation and measurement conditions, and similar chemical environments for both Rb   3 ). Meanwhile, ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectra of both Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEAI and Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 films based on a relatively thin Rb 5 Cs 10 layer exhibit a clear and strong excitonic absorption peak at ~570 nm corresponding to PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 , which is barely observed for the Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 film (Supplementary Fig.  5 ). It can therefore be deduced that PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 is a minor capping by-product in the Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 film, although it is difficult to directly identify cations at the A-site  12, 13, 16  . Although an interesting solid-state in-plane growth method was recently demonstrated to have good controllability specifically for 2D BA 2 PbI 4 (where BA is butylammonium) on top of 3D perovskites  5  , the intrinsically weak solid-state interaction/reaction and high-pressure (60 MPa) requirements may limit its applicability to LD materials with metal cations that are distinct from the underlying 3D perovskite layer. Tailoring the metal cation of LD capping materials so far remains an open question. Expanding the library of LD capping materials with metal cations different from those in 3D perovskites opens up another exciting lever for engineering the energy levels and optoelectronic properties of the LD interface for high-efficiency 3D/LD PSCs. Herein we developed a full precursor (FP) solution methodology for LD capping layer deposition, where an FP solution containing both the metal halide and bulky ammonium halide-instead of the traditional HP solution containing only the bulky ammonium halide-is directly spin-coated on top of a 3D perovskite. Our approach enables easier synthetic control of the LD capping layer compared with the traditional HP process due to the co-existence of both ammonium halide and metal halide. This ensures that the metal cation reactant is no longer limited by the upward diffusion from the underlying 3D perovskite layer. Importantly, our approach allows unprecedented access to the vast library of metal cations beyond the widespread use of Pb 2+ /Sn 2+ for LD capping materials, thus affording fresh opportunities for optimizing the interface alignment and charge transfer properties for efficient PSCs. We discovered that the zero-dimensional (0D) zinc-based halogenometallate (PEA 2 ZnX 4 ; PEA = phenethylammonium, X = Cl/I) with a β-K 2 SO 4 -type single crystal structure  24  functions as a more effective surface capping material for 3D perovskites. By contrast to the lead-based counterpart, PEA 2 ZnX 4 can induce better surface passivation and stronger n-N isotype heterojunctions, which in turn results in substantial suppression of charge recombination and remarkable enhancement of the built-in potential (V bi ). Consequently, in combination with a traditional surface passivation molecule tris(2,4-di-tert-butylphenyl) phosphite (TPPi), we achieved one of the highest power-conversion efficiencies (PCEs) of 24.1% for p-i-n-structured PSCs with negligible hysteresis; the corresponding certified PCE reached 23.25%. The target PSC also exhibited enhanced stability, retaining 94.5% of the initial PCE after 1,009 h of operation at the maximum power point (MPP) under an equivalent effective irradiance of 1 sun. Our findings pave the way forward to expand the toolkit of LD capping materials with metal cations different from those in 3D perovskites. Our study opens a valuable research avenue for engineering efficient 3D/LD PSCs. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1009</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:21:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="13489" length="7"/>
        <text>1,009 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:21:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="13543" length="50"/>
        <text>under an equivalent effective irradiance of 1 sun.</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13819</offset>
      <text> Fabrication and characterization of 3D/LD stack films A comparison between the proposed FP and traditional HP processes is shown in Fig.  1a . The solvent of the HP solution is generally prepared using an antisolvent such as isopropanol, whereas a slightly more polar solvent (acetonitrile, ACN) is used to dissolve the FP components, especially the metal halide. Details on the FP process are provided in the Methods (Supplementary Video 1). For simplicity, we chose PEA 2 PbI 4 and PEA 2 ZnX 4 (X = Cl/I) as representatives of the FP-based LD capping materials, with structures given in Fig.  1b . On the other hand, the ubiquitous PEAI was chosen as a representative for the HP capping method. Notably, the distinguishable characteristic low-angle X-ray diffraction (XRD) peaks (Fig.  1c  and Supplementary Fig.  1a ) provide strong and direct evidence for verifying the presence of corresponding LD materials in the 3D/LD films  12  . As a result, the deposited PEA 2 PbI 4 was fully converted into the quasi-2D PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 (where FA is formamidinium) through a reaction with the bottom 3D perovskite of either Rb 0.05 Cs 0.10 FA 0.85 PbI 2.8 Cl 0.2 (abbreviated as Rb 5 Cs 10 ; Fig.  1d  and Supplementary Fig.  1b ) or Cs 0.15 FA 0.85 PbI 2.8 Cl 0.2 (abbreviated as Cs 15 ; Fig.  1e  and Supplementary Fig.  1c ). However, for the conventional capping method,  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01204-z  PEA 2 ZnX 4 in the UV-vis spectrum of the Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 film due to the intrinsic weak absorption of PEA 2 ZnX 4 (Supplementary Fig.  5 ). This is in accordance with the above quantitative XRD analysis results. In summary, the capped PEA 2 ZnX 4 primarily remained on the Rb 5 Cs 10 perovskite, and there is only a slight reaction with Rb 5 Cs 10 perovskite to produce a small amount of PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 by-product. We further assessed the orientation of the LD capping material with respect to the substrate using grazing incidence wide/small angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS/GISAXS) (Fig.  1f , Supplementary Figs. 6-10 and Supplementary Note 1). The control 3D film exhibits Debye-Scherrerlike rings, and the 3D/LD stack films show additional Bragg spots whose positions correspond with those of the relevant peaks in their XRD patterns. Interestingly, all of the Bragg spots shown in the studied 3D/ LD stack films are located along the Q z direction, indicating that the LD capping materials are oriented preferentially with the (0k0) planes parallel to the substrate (that is, the b-axis is oriented perpendicular to the substrate). This is consistent with the orientation of most reported LD capping materials prepared via the conventional HP methodology  8, 10  . The presence and distribution of the zinc-based capping layer on the 3D perovskite surface was further identified using high-angle annular dark-field scanning transmission electron microscopy and energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX) (Supplementary Fig.  11 ), as well as time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectroscopy (TOF-SIMS) (Supplementary Fig.  12 ). Furthermore, the zinc-based capping material probably forms a film on 3D perovskite surface, which inferred from its distribution form on the ITO substrate (Supplementary Fig.  13 ). Lattice microstrain analysis (Supplementary Table  4 ) suggests that the zinc-based capping layer hardly induces any additional lattice strain for the bottom 3D perovskite although their crystal structures are different. It is also noted that our FP-based capping solution barely changes the cross-sectional morphology of the underlying 3D perovskite (Supplementary Fig.  14 ), which indicates negligible damage to the underlying 3D perovskite. Furthermore, all of the capping layers are found to effectively reduce the roughness of the 3D perovskite film (Supplementary Fig.  15 ), which is probably attributed to the filling of 3D perovskite surface valley regions by the capping materials. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>17755</offset>
      <text> Photovoltaic performance comparison of 3D/LD PSCs We then investigated the p-i-n-structured 3D/LD PSCs with a general configuration of ITO/PTAA/3D/LD/C 60 /BCP/Ag (Fig.  2a ), where ITO is indium tin oxide, PTAA is poly(triarylamine), BCP is bathocuproine  and the 3D perovskite is Rb 5 Cs 10 unless specified otherwise. In Fig.  2b -e and Supplementary Table  5  we compare the open-circuit voltage (V OC ), short-circuit current density (J SC ), fill factor and PCE for the control and target PSCs with various capping materials fabricated either via the traditional HP-based process or our FP-based one. The capping layers were prepared using their respective optimum conditions for a fair comparison (Supplementary    Q x (Å -1 ) Q x (Å -1 ) Q x (Å -1 ) Q x (Å -1 ) Q x (Å -1 ) Q z (Å - &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">PIN</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:24:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="17831" length="5"/>
        <text>p-i-n</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triarylamine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:24:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="17895" length="4"/>
        <text>PTAA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:52:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="17906" length="4"/>
        <text>C 60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">poly(triarylamine)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:24:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="17971" length="18"/>
        <text>poly(triarylamine)</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18554</offset>
      <text> Optoelectronic properties evolution in 3D/LD PSCs To explicate the underlying reasons for the extraordinary enhancement of device performance by the PEA 2 ZnX 4 capping material, time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) analysis was conducted to characterize the non-radiative recombination losses of charge carriers in the perovskite films. In view of similar ultimate capping components and comparable performances for both the HP-based 3D/PEAI and FP-based 3D/ PEA 2 PbI 4 devices, the 3D/PEAI stack film was taken as the representative of the lead-based counterpart for comparison. As shown in Fig.  3a , both 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack films exhibit long tails in their pseudo-colour TRPL plots relative to the control film under the same excitation fluence of 0.177 µJ cm -2 at 640 nm, indicating longer photoluminescence lifetimes. A more distinct comparison of TRPL decay kinetics is illustrated in Fig.  3b . Fluence-dependent TRPL analysis and corresponding global fits were performed to extract the specific rate constant (k 1 ) and lifetime (τ) for trap-mediated non-radiative recombination, that is, Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) recombination (Supplementary Figs. 17-19 and Supplementary Note 2). In comparison with the control 3D perovskite, a more substantial decrease of k 1 and increase of τ were observed for 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 compared with a conventional 3D/ PEAI (Supplementary Table  9 ), implying the superiority of PEA 2 ZnX 4 over a traditional lead-based counterpart for surface passivation to suppress charge recombination. As demonstrated in most past works  [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] [16]  , the chemical passivation effect of the halogenometallate family of capping materials is mainly rooted in their interactions with the A-site cation vacancy (V A ) and halide vacancy (V X ) defects, which are regarded as the dominant defect types on 3D perovskite surface. Similarly, in our case, both the main surface capping component PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 in the conventional 3D/PEAI film and PEA 2 ZnX 4 in the 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 film enable interactions with the V A and V X defects depending on the cationic ammonium group (-NH 3 + ) and halide anion in their structures (Supplementary Fig.  20 ). Although both the PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 and PEA 2 ZnX 4 passivators possess the same passivating groups, their interactions with defects may vary due to different chemical environments and structures leading to discrepant passivation effects. On one hand, the calculated electrostatic potential (ESP) maps of PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 and PEA 2 ZnX 4 showed almost identical ESP for the -NH 3 + groups in both passivators (Supplementary Fig.  21a, b ), indicating that the passivation effects induced by the -NH 3 + groups are probably similar for both passivators. We observe a slightly more negative ESP for the halide anion in tetrahedral [ZnI 4 ] than in octahedral [PbI 6 ] (Supplementary Fig.  21c, d ), which is in accordance with the smaller electronegativity of zinc relative to lead. This is conducive to inducing relatively stronger interactions between the halide anion in PEA 2 ZnX 4 and the positively charged V X defect, and thus contributing to the superior passivation effect. On the other hand, the isolated tetrahedral [ZnI 4 ] structure in 0D PEA 2 ZnX 4 is relatively relaxed compared with the strained connected octahedral [PbI 6 ] structure in the quasi-2D PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 (Supplementary Fig.  22 ), which facilitates effective interactions between passivating groups and the defects. Another possible reason for the superiority of PEA 2 ZnX 4 may be related to modification of interface energy level alignment, which is discussed below. Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) analysis was conducted to examine the surface potential evolution of the perovskite films with different capping materials. Figure  3c  presents the KPFM images of the control 3D, 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack films, with the colour-scale bar representing the contact potential difference (CPD) between the tip and sample surface. As 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 exhibits the highest average CPD value (Fig.  3d ), it implies that PEA 2 ZnX 4 induces a more substantial decrease in the surface work function than the traditional lead-based counterpart. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) analysis was also performed to determine the Fermi levels and valence band maxima of the surfaces of pristine 3D, 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack films (Fig.  3e ). It should be noted that the mentioned Fermi levels here are actually quasi-Fermi levels. The conduction band minima were then extrapolated in relation to the optical bandgaps, which were estimated from the UV-vis spectra of pristine 3D perovskite, PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 and PEA 2 ZnICl 3 (Supplementary Fig.  23 ). Note that, in our case, the bandgaps of the surface capping components in the 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack films were approximated from those of pristine PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 and PEA 2 ZnICl 3 films. This is because the initially capped PEAI and PEA 2 ZnX 4 will mostly convert into PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 and PEA 2 ZnICl 3 , respectively (Supplementary Table  1 ), after post-treatment, as shown above. As presented in the resulting energy level diagram (Fig.  3f ), all Fermi levels of the 3D perovskite and surface capping components are much closer to their conduction band minima, revealing n-type properties. Furthermore, the Fermi level of the surface capping component in 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 (-3.98 eV) is relatively higher than that in 3D/ PEAI (-4.15 eV) and both are effectively enhanced relative to the control 3D perovskite (-4.42 eV), which is in agreement with the KPFM results. Importantly, the specific energy level alignment in either 3D/PEAI or 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 conduced to construct an n-N isotype heterojunction with an additional built-in electric field pointing from the surface to the bulk (Fig.  3f  and Supplementary Note 3), which is responsible for enhancement of V bi and in turn V OC (refs.  28, 29  ). As the additional V bi is dominated by the Fermi level difference at the junction  28, 29  ,  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24630</offset>
      <text> Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01204-z  3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 can theoretically induce a stronger n-N isotype heterojunction and produce a higher additional V bi by virtue of a larger Fermi level difference relative to the conventional 3D/PEAI. The possible V bi variation was further investigated by the photosaturation method for the control, 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSCs (Supplementary Note 4). As predicted, the 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 led to a larger increase of V bi compared with the traditional 3D/PEAI (Fig.  3g ), which is consistent with the V OC evolution. On the other hand, the specific built-in electric field at the n-N isotype heterojunction probably induces a departure of holes at the 3D perovskite surface, resulting in decreased hole concentration, which is advantageous for reducing the SRH recombination at the surface (Supple mentary Fig.  24 ) because the SRH recombination rate is strongly dependent on the surface concentration of the minority carrier  30  . This effect is commonly known in silicon solar cells as field-effect passivation  30  , which has also been reported in PSCs recently  31  . Accordingly, there is probably stronger field-effect passivation in 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 on account of a relatively larger built-in electric field at the corresponding n-N isotype heterojunction, which is also responsible for the superior passivation effect of PEA 2 ZnX 4 . Furthermore, the relatively deeper valence band maximum of the surface capping component can also induce a barrier for holes between the 3D perovskite layer and the C 60 electron transporting layer, which effectively restrains undesired recombination at the perovskite/C 60 interface caused by the adverse band tail states of C 60 (ref.  32  and Supplementary Fig.  25 ). The slightly higher hole barrier in 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 also contributes to greater suppression of charge recombination, thus improving device performance. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26550</offset>
      <text> Device performance and stability of 3D/LD PSCs To further improve device performance, we also introduced TPPia traditional surface passivation molecule-to the best-performing 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSCs, considering that the relatively rough 3D perovskite surface probably cannot be sufficiently covered by the PEA 2 ZnX 4 capping layer, which has a narrow optimum thickness (~20 nm) (Supplementary Figs. 13, 15, 16 and 26, and Supplementary Note 3). The chemical structure of the TPPi molecule is presented in Supplementary Fig.  27 , and its passivation efficacy was confirmed by the reduced k 1 and increased τ of the 3D/TPPi film compared with the pristine 3D perovskite film (Supplementary Figs. 17 and 28, and Supplementary Table  10 ), as well as a slight increase in PCE of the 3D/TPPi PSCs (Supplementary Table  11 ), which has also been demonstrated by other similar molecules  33  . As a result, we obtained a maximum PCE of 24.1% with a V OC of 1.198 V, a J SC of 24 mA cm -2 , a fill factor of 83.9% and negligible hysteresis (Fig.  4a ). The device also exhibited an average stable power output of 23.5% at the MPP (Supplementary Fig.  29 ) and good reproducibility, with an average PCE of 22.9% over 103 individual cells (Fig.  4b  and Supplementary Table  12 ). The measured J SC was validated by the integrated J SC from the external quantum efficiency spectrum (Fig.  4c ), with a reasonable relative discrepancy of less than 2%. Our PSCs were also evaluated by an independent national institute, Solar Energy Research Institute of Singapore (SERIS), which offers a high-precision solar simulator with an almost ideal spectral mismatch factor of 1.01 for our PSCs. A certified PCE of 23.25% was obtained (Supplementary Fig.  30 ). Finally, we examined the operational stability of the 3D/LD PSCs based on our FP technology. The operational stability tests were performed at the MPP in a N 2 -filled glovebox (O 2 &lt; 10 ppm, H 2 O &lt; 1 ppm) under illumination of a white light-emitting diode (LED) lamp with an equivalent effective irradiance of 1 sun. It is noted that the Cs 15 3D perovskite and the hybrid LD capping layer of PEA 2 PbI 4 -PEA 2 ZnX 4 were included in the PSCs for the stability tests, considering that a comparable device performance was achieved for the 3D/PEA 2 PbI 4 -PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSC relative to the 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSC (Supplementary Table  13 ), which is due to the intrinsic superiority of PEA 2 ZnX 4 , as demonstrated above. Consequently, 94.5% of the initial PCE was maintained after 1,009 h of MPP operation for the target PSC, which is remarkably enhanced compared with the control PSC (Fig.  4d, e ). To reveal the possible reasons for the stability improvement induced by the LD capping layer, we investigated the surface morphology and defects evolution of the relevant perovskite films after aging them under 1 sun illumination in air without encapsulation. As illustrated in Supplementary Figs. 31 and 32, the LD capping layer effectively inhibited the generation of surface pinholes on the 3D perovskite film, which probably results from the blocking of H 2 O/O 2 penetration/erosion by the hydrophobic organic bulky cations within the structure of the LD capping layer (Supplementary Figs. 33 and 34)  16  . Moreover, a relatively larger decrease in surface photoluminescence intensity for the control 3D perovskite film was also observed (Supplementary Fig.  35 ), indicating that the LD capping layer is probably favourable for suppressing light-induced production of surface defects due to the robust interaction between the LD capping material and the 3D perovskite surface (Supplementary Fig.  33 ). To further verify the role of the LD capping layer in device stability improvement, we also performed the 85 °C heat stability tests for the PSCs under ambient conditions or in N 2 (see Methods). As predicted, the target 3D/LD device also showed enhanced heat stability compared with the control 3D device (Supplementary Fig.  36 ). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.198</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T04:27:33Z</infon>
        <location offset="27500" length="8"/>
        <text>1.198 V,</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30536</offset>
      <text> Conclusion Using a full precursor solution methodology in 3D/LD PSCs, we have paved the way forward to expand the toolkit of LD capping materials to include metal cations different from those in 3D perovskites. Compared with the conventional lead-based counterpart, 0D PEA 2 ZnX 4 functions as a more effective LD capping material for 3D perovskites because it induces more robust surface passivation and forms a stronger n-N isotype heterojunction. The resulting 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSCs achieved a remarkably improved PCE of 24.1% (certified 23.25%) and enhanced operational stability. Although only the representative PEA 2 PbI 4 and PEA 2 ZnX 4 are presented here in detail, our FP technology also showed broad applicability for other commonly studied LD capping materials such as BA 2 PbI 4 and PMA 2 PbI 4 (where PMA is phenylmethylammonium) (Supplementary Table  14 ), as well as BA 2 ZnX 4 (Supplementary Fig.  37  and Supplementary Table  15 ). Aside from the Zn 2+ cation, our FP technology could potentially unlock access to many other divalent metal cations such as Co 2+ (PEA 2 CoX 4 ) (Supplementary Fig.  38  and Supplementary Table  14 ), Mn 2+ , Cu 2+ and so on, as well as trivalent cations such as Sb 3+ , Bi 3+ , Al 3+ and so on, which are promising for tuning energy level alignments at 3D/LD interfaces and/or enhancing the interface stability more effectively. We therefore believe our findings will unlock new opportunities to develop superior LD capping materials from the vast family of halogenometallates, especially the lead-free ones, for more efficient and stable PSCs as well as impact other perovskite optoelectronics such as LEDs, lasers, photodetectors and so on. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32231</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32241</offset>
      <text> Materials All of the chemicals and materials involved in this work were purchased and used as received unless specified otherwise. The patterned ITO-coated glass substrates (sheet resistance ≤10 Ω sq -1 ) were purchased from Shenzhen Huayu Union Technology Company; PTAA (average M n = 6,000-15,000), BCP (99.9%) and 1-naphthylmethylammonium iodide were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corporation; PbI 2 (99.99%) was purchased from TCI; C 60 (99.9%) was purchased from Puyang Yongxin Fullerene Technology Company; formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium bromide, PEAI, n-butylammonium iodide and phenylmethylammonium iodide were purchased from Greatcell Energy; PbCl 2 (99.999%), PbBr 2 (99.999%), ZnI 2 (99.999%), ZnCl 2 (99.999%), CoCl 2 (99.995%), CsI (99.999%), RbI (99.9%), TPPi (98%), LiF (99.99%), N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF, 99.8%, anhydrous), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, 99.9%, anhydrous), toluene (99.8%, anhydrous), 1,2-dichlorobenzene (99%, anhydrous), isopropanol (99.5%, anhydrous), ACN (99.8%, anhydrous) and methylamine solution (2 M in THF) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. rate and is expected to saturate close to the Vbi of the junction. Therefore, the Vbi can be estimated from the photosaturated VOC. The VOC here is identified by measuring the null voltage where the output current of the device is zero. Supplementary Figure 36 | 85 °C heat stability test. The 85 °C heat stability tests for the control 3D and the target 3D/LD PSCs were conducted under ambient conditions (relative humidity ~50%) or in N2, as indicated in the figure. It should be that a simple base encapsulation (see Methods) is made for the device before start of the test in air, and there is no encapsulation for the device tested in N2. The error bars denote standard deviations for 3 individual devices, and the centre for the error bars indicates the mean values. The relatively quick drop of PCE for the target device tested in air, relative to that in N2, is probably due to our poor encapsulation. The widely used triple-cation CsMAFA 3D perovskite was used in the relevant device for the test. The initial average PCE for the control 3D device is (18.5  0.1)%. The initial average PCEs for the target 3D/LD devices tested under ambient condition or in N2 are (20.1  0. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34545</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Fabrication diagram of the 3D/LD stack films and structural characterization. a, Comparison of the proposed full precursor (FP) and traditional half precursor (HP) processes for preparing the 3D/LD stack films. ACN, acetonitrile; IPA, isopropanol. b, Crystal structures of the 2D PEA 2 PbI 4 and 0D PEA 2 ZnX 4 (X = Cl/I). c-e, Enlarged XRD patterns of pristine LD materials (c), control Rb 5 Cs 10 and Rb 5 Cs 10 /LD stack films (d) and control Cs 15 and Cs 15 /LD stack &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35039</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Device architecture and photovoltaic parameter evolution with LD capping materials. a, Schematic illustration and cross-sectional scanning electron microscope (SEM) image of the studied 3D/LD PSC. The charge and terminal symbols indicate the photoinduced electron/hole and device anode/ cathode, respectively. The LD capping material in the cross-sectional SEM image is PEA 2 ZnX 4 . The original uncoloured SEM image can be found in Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35509</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Comparison of optoelectronic properties. a, Pseudo-colour TRPL plots of the control 3D perovskite, 3D/PEAI and 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack films deposited on glass substrates excited at 640 nm with a fluence of 0.177 µJ cm -2 .The colour-scale bar represents the normalized photoluminescence intensity from 0 to unity. b, Normalized TRPL decay kinetics. The fit details can be found in Supplementary Note 2 and Supplementary Table9. c-e, KPFM images (c), corresponding CPD statistical distributions (d) and UPS spectra (e) of the perovskite films deposited on ITO-coated glass substrates. The small vertical lines on left and right panels of the UPS spectra mark the secondary electron cut-off and valence band edge, respectively. The colour-scale bar in c represents the CPD intensity from 1.0 V to 2.8 V. The vertical axis in d represents the &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36370</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 4 Fig. 4 | Device performance and stability. a, Current density-voltage (J-V) curves of the champion 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 PSC with additional TPPi passivation. FS, forward scan; RS, reverse scan. b, PCE distribution histogram of 103 individual target PSCs. The green curve indicates the probability density function of normal distribution. c, External quantum efficiency spectrum of the target PSC. d, Operational stability of the control and target PSCs at the MPP in N 2 under white LED illumination with an equivalent effective irradiance of 1 sun. The initial PCEs for the control and target PSCs were 18.6% ± 0.1% and 21.7% ± 0.1%, respectively. The device temperature was around 40 °C during the test. The error bars denote the s.d. for three different measurements, and the centres of the error bars are mean values. e, J-V curves of the target PSC before and after MPP tracking for 1,009 h. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37277</offset>
      <text> 𝜙 1 &gt; 𝜙 2 , 𝜒 1 + 𝐸 g1 &lt; 𝜒 2 + 𝐸 g2 𝜒 1 &gt; 𝜒 2 , 𝜙 1 &lt; 𝜙 2 , 𝜒 1 + 𝐸 g1 &lt; 𝜒 2 + 𝐸 g2 𝜒 1 &lt; 𝜒 2 , 𝜙 1 &lt; 𝜙 2 , 𝜒 1 + 𝐸 g1 &gt; 𝜒 2 + 𝐸 g2 𝜒 1 &gt; 𝜒 2 , 𝜙 1 &gt; 𝜙 2 , 𝜒 1 + 𝐸 g1 &gt; 𝜒 2 + 𝐸 g2 Case IV: Case II: Case III: &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37577</offset>
      <text> Table 1 | 1 The estimated x values in the capping product of PEA2ZnI4-xClx in the 3D/PEA2ZnX4 (X = Cl/I) stack films according to the characteristic XRD peak position of PEA2ZnX4 (see Fig. 1c-e). Film Characteristic XRD peak position 2θ (°) Product x value PEA2ZnI4 6.6 0 PEA2ZnI2Cl2 6.9 2 PEA2ZnCl4 7.2 4 Rb5Cs10/PEA2ZnI4 6.9 PEA2ZnI4-xClx 2 Rb5Cs10/PEA2ZnI2Cl2 7.1 ~3a Cs15/PEA2ZnI4 7.0 ~3 Cs15/PEA2ZnI2Cl2 7.1 ~3 1)% and (20.9  0.2)%, respectively. More details are provided in Methods. Supplementary a The x value here is estimated to be around 3 as the characteristic XRD peak position is between those of PEA2ZnI2Cl2 and PEA2ZnCl4. 50 Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38239</offset>
      <text> Table 2 | 2 Comparison of the possible reactions between the capping materials and the 3D perovskites, and the corresponding products/residues. Capping material 3D perovskite Possible reaction Possible product/residue PEAX APbX3 a &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38472</offset>
      <text> Table 4 | 4 Lattice micro strain analysis for the control 3D and 3D/PEA2ZnI4 stack films. The 3D perovskite here is Cs15. 3D perovskite Peak position (2) (°) hkl (°) a Micro strain (%) b lattice plane 3D 3D/PEA2ZnI4 3D 3D/PEA2ZnI4 3D 3D/PEA2ZnI4 001 13.996 13.400 0.121 0.123 0.43 0.44 110 19.858 19.865 0.093 0.095 0.23 0.24 002 28.211 28.212 0.127 0.120 0.22 0.21 012 31.636 31.637 0.133 0.125 0.20 0.19 220 40.332 40.340 0.136 0.113 0.16 0.13 strain, crystalline domain size and instrumental contribution. Considering the same instrument being used and similar crystalline domain size for the control 3D and 3D/PEA2ZnI4 samples, it is reasonable that any difference in hkl between the two samples is mainly attributed to the different lattice micro strain. b The lattice micro strain can be estimated using hkl/4tan based on the Debye-Scherrer method S13 . a hkl is the full width at half maximum of the peak, which is related to the lattice micro &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39445</offset>
      <text> Table 6 | 6 Statistics of photovoltaic parameters for PSCs based on the capping materials with various concentrations. The 3D perovskite and PEA2ZnX4 here are Rb5Cs10 and PEA2ZnI2Cl2, respectively. Capping material Concentration (mM) VOC (V) JSC (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) 10 1.072 ± 0.023 a 23.5 ± 0.1 79.7 ± 0.8 20.1 ± 0.4 PEAI 20 1.119 ± 0.017 23.4 ± 0.4 78.4 ± 0.5 20.6 ± 0.6 30 1.126 ± 0.017 22.5 ± 0.8 75.3 ± 4.0 19.1 ± 1.8 12 1.107 ± 0.006 23.4 ± 0.2 79.6 ± 0.7 20.6 ± 0.4 PEA2PbI4 17 1. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39958</offset>
      <text> 135 ± 0.008 23.4 ± 0.3 78.4 ± 1.4 20.8 ± 0.5 23 1.142 ± 0.013 21.4 ± 0.3 79.0 ± 1.5 19.3 ± 0.5 17 1. PEA2ZnX4 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40078</offset>
      <text> 158 ± 0.006 23.8 ± 0.2 80.6 ± 0.5 22.2 ± 0.2 materials. The 3D perovskite and PEA2ZnX4 here are Cs15 and PEA2ZnI2Cl2, respectively. Capping material VOC (V) JSC (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) Control 1.048 ± 0.005 a 22.4 ± 0.2 77.4 ± 1.2 18.2 ± 0.3 PEAI 1.132 ± 0.009 22.0 ± 0.5 78.7 ± 1.1 19.6 ± 0.6 PEA2PbI4 1.135 ± 0.006 22.7 ± 0.4 79.2 ± 1.0 20.4 ± 0.4 PEA2ZnX4 1.150 ± 0.005 22.7 ± 0.4 81.0 ± 1.3 21.2 ± 0.4 26 1.169 ± 0.005 22.9 ± 0.3 79.3 ± 1.8 21.2 ± 0.8 a The data include average values and standard deviations calculated from 8 individual devices. a The data include average values and standard deviations calculated from 13 individual devices. 57 Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40773</offset>
      <text> Table 9 | 9 The extracted constants from global fits for the fluence-dependent TRPL decay kinetics of the 3D perovskite films without or with different capping materials (see Supplementary Figs. 17-19). First-order Second-order Capping material k1 (10 5 s -1 ) τ (ns) k2 (10 -11 cm 3 s -1 ) Control 19.7 ± 0.1 506 ± 2 3.14 ± 0.03 PEAI 5.1 ± 0.1 1950 ± 50 3.69 ± 0.03 PEA2ZnX4 3.8 ± 0.1 2600 ± 100 3.06 ± 0.03 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41194</offset>
      <text> Table 18 | 18 The lattice constants of PEA2FAPb2I7 and PEA2ZnI4. a (Å) b (Å) c (Å) α (°) β (°) γ (°) PEA2FAPb2I7 8.722 8.726 22.533 97.6 93.5 90.4 PEA2ZnI4 8.205 26.832 10.988 90.0 90.2 90.0 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41396</offset>
      <text> Expanding the low-dimensional interface engineering toolbox for efficient perovskite solar cells Senyun Ye 1,5 , Haixia Rao 2,5 , Minjun Feng 1 , Lifei Xi 2,3 , Zhihao Yen 2 , Debbie Hwee Leng Seng 4 , Qiang Xu 1 , Chris Boothroyd 2,3 , Bingbing Chen 2 , Yuanyuan Guo 1 , Bo Wang 1 , Teddy Salim 2,3 , Qiannan Zhang 1 , Huajun He 1 , Yue Wang 1 , Xingchi Xiao 2 , Yeng Ming Lam 2 &amp; Tze Chien Sum 1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41796</offset>
      <text> 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 and Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 stack films, it is plausible to assume that the crystallinity and texture of PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 in both stack films are roughly consistent, suggesting that the ratio of PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 to that in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 can be estimated by directly comparing the corresponding integral intensities of the PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 diffraction peak. It is also inferred that the PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 diffraction peak intensity of Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 should approach that of Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 if PEA 2 ZnX 4 is fully converted into PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 . This is because PEA 2 PbI 4 shows a complete transformation into PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 , and the contents of PEA + in both stack films are probably equivalent due to the same fabrication conditions. Accordingly, a conversion ratio of ~10% of PEA 2 ZnX 4 in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 was obtained by simply comparing the PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 diffraction peak intensity of Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 with that of Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 PbI 4 (Supplementary Table 3), indicating that ~90% of PEA 2 ZnX 4 in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 was retained. To examine the reliability of the results, a similar analysis was performed to directly calculate the retention ratio of PEA 2 ZnX 4 in Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 by comparing the PEA 2 ZnX 4 diffraction peak intensity of Rb 5 Cs 10 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 with that of Cs 15 /PEA 2 ZnX 4 , which led to a similar retention ratio of ~90% (Supplementary Table &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43314</offset>
      <text> Table 6 6 ). Compared 2 ZnX 4 device demonstrated an even greater improvement with a PCE of 22.2% ± 0.3%. These improvements are mainly ascribed to the enhanced V OC . The comparable performance between the FP-based 3D/PEA 2 PbI 4 and HP-based 3D/ PEAI devices is attributed to the similar ultimate capping component (PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 ). The better reproducibility (narrower PCE distribution) 2 ZnX 4 device should be the intrinsic PEA 2 ZnX 4 and not the PEA-2 FAPb 2 I 7 by-product because the PEA 2 ZnX 4 residual is the main capping component (accounting for ~90%) in the 3D/PEA 2 ZnX 4 stack film, as demonstrated above. To eliminate the interference from the small amount of PEA 2 FAPb 2 I 7 by-product, similar PSCs based on the Cs 15 perovskite were also investigated, considering that PEA 2 ZnX 4 can fully remain on the Cs 15 perovskite, as demonstrated above. Consequently, a similar performance improvement was demonstrated (Supplementary &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44268</offset>
      <text> Table 8 ) 8 , further confirming the intrinsic superiority of PEA 2 ZnX 4 as the LD capping material in 3D/LD PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44386</offset>
      <text>			 © The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:54Z</infon>
      <node refid="7" role=""/>
      <node refid="6" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="5" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
