<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025045947ECAECA</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 119&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Transporting holes stably under iodide invasion in efficient perovskite solar cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>97</offset>
      <text>Highly efficient halide perovskite solar cells generally rely on lithium-doped organic hole transporting layers that are thermally and chemically unstable, in part because of migration of iodide anions from the perovskite layer. We report a solution strategy to stabilize the hole transport in organic layers by ionic coupling positive polymer radicals and molecular anions through an ion-exchange process. The target layer exhibited a hole conductivity that was 80 times higher than that of the conventional lithiumdoped layer. Moreover, after extreme iodide invasion caused by light-soaking at 85°C for 200 hours, the target layer maintained high hole conductivity and well-matched band alignment. This ion-exchange strategy enabled fabrication of perovskite solar cells with a certified power conversion efficiency of 23.9% that maintained 92% under standard illumination at 85°C after 1000 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1001</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1011</offset>
      <text>M etal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) with high power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) generally incorporate lithium salt-doped organic hole transporting layers (HTLs) (1-4) that can cause severe device instability issues  (5, 6) . For example, the hygroscopic lithium salts can cause moisture invasion, migration of small Li + ions into perovskite, and irreversible device degradation  (7) (8) (9) (10) . Inorganic HTLs and dopant-free HTLs offer great enhancements in stability but have failed to compete with the doped HTLs for the most efficient PSCs. An additional stability issue arises from the intrinsic soft nature of the perovskites that allows volatile iodide components to enter charge-transporting layers  (11, 12) . Iodide can interact with the positive radicals in HTLs and induce rapid degradation in both hole conductivity and interfacial band alignment, especially for the most efficient PSCs that rely on doped organic HTLs  (3, 4, 6, (13) (14) (15) (16) . Although iodide blocking barriers and interface engineering are promising strategies to hinder the iodide invasion  (11, 12) , these approaches have not been reported to block both Li + migration and iodide invasion completely. Thus, it is highly desirable to find a Li-free doping strategy that can stabilize the hole transport under mass iodide entry. We report a solution strategy to stabilize the hole transport in Li-free organic layers by coupling positive polymer radicals and molecular anions through an ion-exchange process (see methods for details). The molecular anion of 1,1,2,2,3,3-hexafluoropropane-1,3disulfonimide (HFDF -) (fig.  S1 ) was exchanged into poly(triarylamine) (PTAA) films and termed HFDF-HTL (fig.  S2 ). HFDF -has not been used as a noncoordinating ion in a p-type organic semiconductor, as far as we know. We also chose bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide lithium salt/4-tert-butylpyridine (LiTFSI/tBP)doped poly(triarylamine) (Li-HTL) as a reference HTL that is generally used for highly efficient PSCs and offers better stability than LiTFSI/tBP-doped 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis(N,N-di-pmethoxyphenylamine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (Li-Spiro-OMeTAD). The target Li-free-doped HTL, HFDF-HTL, increased hole conductivity to a value 80 times greater than that of the conventional lithium salt-doped HTLs, had a favorable energy-level alignment at the HTL/perovskite heterojunction, and achieved a high conductivity on fresh HFDF-HTL after a few minutes versus the conventional Li-salt doping method that generally takes several hours or days. Under the mass invasion of iodide, hole transport was stabilized through the ionic coupling of positive polymer radicals with introduced molecular anions. Furthermore, hole transport through organic layers withstood thermal stress at temperatures up to 120°C. These results helped us obtain efficient and stable PSCs that achieved a certified PCE of 23.9% and maintained 92% after operation at the maximum power point under AM1.5G solar light (100 mW cm -2 ) at 85°C after 1000 hours. We studied the electronic properties of the aged HTLs in PSCs, with a structure of fluorine-doped tin dioxide (FTO)/SnO x /SnO 2 / formamidinium-based perovskite/HTL/Au, that suffered severe iodide invasion after lightsoaking at 85°C for 200 hours. The iodide invasion into the aged HTLs, as studied by time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) chemical imaging (Fig.  1, A  and B ), showed high concentrations of I -ions distributed over the aged HTLs. The compositional depth profiles of the aged PSCs further revealed that the iodide invasion started from the perovskite/HTL interface (fig.  S3 ). The surface potential measured with Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) (Fig.  1, C  and D ) of the I --rich Li-HTL decreased from an initial 92 mV to a final -678 mV. By contrast, the surface potential of the I --rich HFDF-HTL has a much smaller decrease from 202 to 102 mV, and the decreased value was nearly one-eighth that of the I --rich Li-HTL, exhibiting astonishing durability of HFDF-HTL under iodide invasion during the heat and light aging test. We also characterized the electronic structure of I --rich HTLs with ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS). The Fermi level of the I --rich Li-HTL in aged devices sharply changed from -4.96 to -4.02 eV (fig.  S4 ), which reflected n-doping caused by iodide migration during the entire aging process. However, only a slight change from -5.12 to -4.97 eV in the Fermi level of I --rich HFDF-HTL was found after the aging test. The variation of electronic conductivity of I --rich HTLs of aged PSCs was measured with conductive atomic force microscopy (AFM) (Fig.  1, E  and F ). The average electric current of I --rich Li-HTL quickly decreased from the initial 0.76 to 0.43 nA and maintained only 57% of the initial conductivity. In comparison, I --rich HFDF-HTL exhibited a stable performance with an initial value of 38.6 nA, which was ~50 times greater than that of the fresh Li-HTL, and the aged sample maintained 96% of the initial conductivity (36.9 nA). The conductivity of I --rich HTLs was further investigated under the same iodide concentrations, which were aged through direct injection of formamidinium iodide (FAI), a common volatile perovskite component, into the layer by spin-coating. The conductivity of I --rich Li-HTL decreased by 50% at the FAI concentration of 0.01 mmol liter -1 (Fig.  1G ), whereas the conductivity of I --rich HFDF-HTL remained at 97% under the same conditions (Fig.  1H ). We characterized the compositions of HTLs, especially the positive polymer radicals that can determine their conductivity. In Fig.  2A , Li-HTL was fully occupied by Li + signals, whereas only negligible Li + signals were observed in HFDF-HTL. We also confirmed the absence of Li + cations in HFDF-HTL by highresolution x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy in fig.  S5 . From TOF-SIMS two-dimensional (2D) elemental mapping (fig.  S6A ) and compositional depth profiles (fig.  S3B ), we observed that HFDF -anions were distributed throughout the layer. TOF-SIMS signals of the anions of initiating dopant 2,3,5,6-tetrafluoro-7,7,8,8tetracyanoquinodimethane (F4TCNQ) were negligible in HFDF-HTL (fig.  S6B ), indicating that F4TCNQ -anions were efficiently exchanged with HFDF -and then removed during the spin-coating and washing process. We further verified the ion exchange for HFDF - according to the absence of the F4TCNQ - anions in the ion-exchanged HTL by Fourier transform infrared and Raman spectroscopy (figs. S7 and S8)  (17) . The positive polymer radicals were characterized by electron spin resonance (ESR) spectroscopy, which showed a stronger signal from HFDF-HTL than from Li-HTL (Fig.  2B ), confirming the formation of a high concentration of polymer radicals in HFDF-HTL  (18) . After being aged under iodide invasion, the positive polymer radicals in Li-HTL samples were almost entirely quenched, whereas HFDF-HTL maintained 95.5% of the original value deduced from the second integral of the ESR derivative curves  (19) . By observing the bleaching of the neutral absorption of HTL at 376 nm and swelling of the new absorption of polymer radicals at ~500 nm, an increase in polymer radicals in HFDF-HTL through ion exchange was further verified (Fig.  2C )  (20) . The Raman peak positions of the C=C stretching in conjugated polymers shifted to lower frequencies (Fig.  2D ), indicating higher effective conjugation length and planarization of charged chains  (21) . The density functional theory (DFT) calculation (fig.  S9 ) results supported the observation by Raman spectroscopy, in that the dihedral angles between bridging benzene rings of neutral and one and two positively charged triarylamine dimers were 143.7°, 172.4°, and 178.0°, respectively. The experimental observations of the electronic performance and compositions of HTLs show that the invaded I -ions reduced the positive polymer radicals and caused degradation in hole conductivity for conventional Li-HTL. By contrast, the hole transport was well protected against the iodide invasion in HFDF-HTL. We found that HTLs doped with only F4TCNQ or lithium salts had no obvious enhancement of polymer radicals (fig.  S10 ). For HFDF-HTL that was formed through an ionexchange process with LiHFDF or KHFDF, both HTLs exhibited a similar electronic conductivity (fig.  S11 ), indicating that the HFDF-HTLs are less sensitive to Li + or K + cations. In addition, we found that HFDF-HTLs that were formed through the ion-exchange method had a higher radical doping effect than those fabricated by immersion from the observations of higher characteristic absorption at ~500 nm and much higher conductivity (fig.  S12 ). The spin-coating drop by drop could provide fresh dopant solution continuously for ion-exchange processing and lead to a highspeed washing effect that cleared away some by-products. We also assessed the morphological change of HTL after doping by AFM (fig.  S13 ). Pinholes were observed in Li-HTL, whereas the surface of HFDF-HTL was dense and uniform over the perovskite layer (fig.  S14 ). The effect of different doping strategies on the band alignment of HTLs was further evaluated (fig.  S15 ). The Fermi level deduced from the value of high-binding-energy cut-off downshifted from -4.72 eV for undoped HTL to -4.96 eV for Li-HTL and -5.12 eV for HFDF-HTL, suggesting that the ion-exchange strategy enabled more-efficient p-type doping. The valence band maxima of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL were estimated to be -5.22 and -5.30 eV, respectively, gradually approaching the value of perovskite film (fig.  S16 ). The band alignment of HFDF-HTL reduced the energy loss during charge transfer and increased the opencircuit voltage (V OC )  (22) . We performed steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy and time-resolved   Downloaded from  https://www.science.org  at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 photoluminescence (TRPL) spectroscopy to study the charge transfer kinetics between perovskite and the different HTLs (Fig.  2, E  and F ). Table  S1  summarizes the lifetime of the decay curves fitted by bi-exponential components using the equation Y = A 1 exp(-t/t 1 ) + A 2 exp(-t/t 2 ), where fast decay lifetime t 1 and slow decay lifetime t 2 are related to trapassisted nonradiative and radiative recombination, respectively  (23) . For undoped HTL, the PL intensity and lifetime did not fall off noticeably, indicating a relatively inefficient carrier extraction process without doping (fig.  S17 )  (24) . The conventional doping strategy exhibited a limited PL quenching effect for Li-HTL, whereas a steady PL spectrum was almost completely quenched for HFDF-HTL (Fig.  2E ). The fitted PL lifetimes (t 1 and t 2 ) of perovskite film deposited on bare quartz glass of 56 and 1160 ns, respectively, were shortened more for HFDF-HTL (25 and 230 ns) compared with Li-HTL (54 and 382 ns) (Fig.  2F ), indicating that photogenerated charges were transferred more sufficiently for HFDF-HTL. We applied the ionic coupling between anions and polymer radicals with the ionexchange process to more molecular cations (fig.  S1 )-such as tetrafluoroborate (BF 4 -), hexafluorophosphate (PF 6 -), and bistrifluoromethanesulfonimidate (TFSI -)-for the formation of HTLs with enhanced conductivity and stability. The ESR and optical absorbance spectra show that the formation of polymer radicals was greatly enhanced in the order of HFDF-HTL, TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, and BF 4 -HTL (Fig.  3A  and fig.  S18 ), indicating that these molecular anions preferentially couple with the positive polymer radicals. The ionic coupling between anions and radicals was further evaluated with DFT calculations based on the energetic gain (figs. S19 and S20 and tables S2 to S4), which showed that HFDF -anions were more energetically favorable to couple with polymer radicals than TFSI -followed by PF 6 -and BF 4 -, hence higher ion-exchange efficiency and polymer radical concentration. We measured the conductivity and hole mobility of the different HTLs (figs. S21 and S22). HFDF-HTL exhibited the highest electrical conductivity (Fig.  3B ) followed by TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, BF 4 -HTL, and then Li-HTL. The conductivity of HFDF-HTL, which reached a value of 5.08 × 10 -3 S cm -1 , was ~80 times higher than that of Li-HTL (table  S5 ). HFDF-HTL also exhibited the highest hole mobility (fig.  S23 ), which increased by nearly six times compared with that of Li-HTL (table  S6 ). The exact distribution of charge carriers on the ion-exchanged HTLs and how their interaction with counterions affects electronic mobility pend further study. We further verified the work function in the different HTLs by KPFM (Fig.  3C ). The energy band alignment of the different HTLs and the perovskite film (Fig.  3D ) shows that HFDF-HTL had an optimal energy-level alignment at the HTL/perovskite interface. The thermal stability of the HTLs was evaluated by measuring the conductivity before and after annealing at 80°or 120°C for 24 hours (figs. S24 and S25). The resulting currentvoltage curves of the various HTLs annealed at 120°C showed that the thermally aged HFDF-HTL maintained 95% of the initial conductivity (Fig.  3E ). The conductivity of Li-HTL films was reduced to 55% of initial values after heating at 120°C, possibly because of the undesired volatilization of tBP molecules and spontaneous aggregation of LiTFSI  (25) . By contrast, ion exchange improved the thermal stability in TFSI-HTL, maintaining 83% of the initial conductivity. The thermal stability of the conductivity was also consistent with the results of the DFT calculation on the cohesive energy (figs. S9B, S20, and S26 and tables S7 to S9), which indicated that the ionic coupling between anions and polymer radicals required a large activation energy for the ion decoupling under thermal stress  (26, 27) . The stability of HTLs under iodide invasion shows that the aged HFDF-HTL maintained the highest conductivity (Fig.  3F  and figs. S26 and S27), followed by the aged TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, BF 4 -HTL, and then Li-HTL. Previous research reported that the diffusion of iodide ions from perovskite can reduce the oxidized HTLs  (28, 29) . Both the thermal and chemical stability indicated that the ionic coupling between HFDF -anions and positive polymer radicals is energetically favorable and stabilizes the hole conductivity in HTLs against the reduction effect from the invaded iodide. Moreover, HFDF-HTL also enabled enhanced moisture stability of perovskite through its hydrophobicity. The contact angle of water on Li-HTL was 62.2°but was 85.0°for HFDF-HTL (fig.  S29 ), which lacked hygroscopic Li + cations. During an aging test in the air with a relative humidity (RH) of ~50% for 500 hours, the HFDF-HTL/perovskite film exhibited a stable crystal structure as determined from x-ray diffraction (fig.  S30 ). An n-i-p planar heterojunction PSC fabricated with HFDF-HTL (Fig.  4A ) achieved a maximum PCE of 24.0%, with a V OC of 1.14 V, a shortcircuit current density (J SC ) of 25.2 mA cm -2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 83.7% (Fig.  4B  and table  S10 ). By contrast, the Li-HTL-based devices only obtained a maximum PCE of 20.5% with a V OC of 1.09V, a J SC of 24.8 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 76.0%. The statistical analysis of the device performance with the different HTLs demonstrated that the HFDF-HTL-based devices exhibited superior performance to other devices we tested for all photovoltaic metrics (fig.  S31 ). The improvement in device performance could be attributed to the high hole conductivity and well-matched band alignment  (23, 30) . The best device further performed maximum power point tracking with a voltage of 1.00 V (fig.  S32 ). The photocurrent stabilized at ~23.9 mA cm -2 , corresponding to a stabilized PCE of 23.9%. We sent one of our best target PSCs to an accredited independent photo-voltaic test center for certification. The device obtained a certified PCE of 23.9% with a V OC of 1.15 V, a J SC of 25.1 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 83.0% (fig.  S33 ) and compared favorably to other reported Li-free PSCs to date (table  S11 ). Our results also established advantages of HFDF -compared with the conventional lithium and/or cobalt salts for hole transport (table  S12 ). We further applied the ion-exchange strategy to other polymeric HTLs (fig.  S34 ), such as poly(3-hexylthiophene-2,5-diyl) (P3HT) and poly-{2,1,3-benzothiadiazole-4,7-diyl[4,4bis(2-ethylhexyl)-4H-cyclopenta[2,1-b:3,4-b′]dithiophene-2,6-diyl]} (PCPDTBT), and their devices also showed enhanced V OC and FF. We performed the device stability test to investigate the durability of photovoltaic cells under moisture or combined heat and light. The nonencapsulated HFDF-HTL-based device retained nearly 90% of its initial performance after the aging test for 576 hours under simulated AM1.5G radiation (100 mW cm -2 ) in ambient air (~50% RH) (Fig.  4C ). By contrast, the control devices with Li-HTL rapidly lost 60% of their initial PCE under the same aging conditions after only 100 hours. The operational stability of PSCs under heat and light stress was conducted under full-spectrum sunlight at 85°C (Fig.  4D ). For the control cell with Li-HTL, a 49% drop in PCE was observed after continuous operation for 1000 hours, whereas the devices with HFDF-HTL maintained 92% of their initial PCE over the same aging period and still performed with a PCE of 21.2%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18503</offset>
      <text> Transporting holes stably under iodide invasion in efficient perovskite solar cells Tao Wang foot_1 ,2,3 , Yao Zhang 1 , Weiyu Kong 1,2,3 , Liang Qiao 1,2,3 , Bingguo Peng 1,2,3 , Zhichao Shen 1 , Qifeng Han 1 , Han Chen 1 , Zhiliang Yuan 4 , Rongkun Zheng 5 , Xudong Yang 1,2,3 * Highly efficient halide perovskite solar cells generally rely on lithium-doped organic hole transporting layers that are thermally and chemically unstable, in part because of migration of iodide anions from the perovskite layer. We report a solution strategy to stabilize the hole transport in organic layers by ionic coupling positive polymer radicals and molecular anions through an ion-exchange process. The target layer exhibited a hole conductivity that was 80 times higher than that of the conventional lithiumdoped layer. Moreover, after extreme iodide invasion caused by light-soaking at 85°C for 200 hours, the target layer maintained high hole conductivity and well-matched band alignment. This ion-exchange strategy enabled fabrication of perovskite solar cells with a certified power conversion efficiency of 23.9% that maintained 92% under standard illumination at 85°C after 1000 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19689</offset>
      <text> M etal halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) with high power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) generally incorporate lithium salt-doped organic hole transporting layers (HTLs) (1-4) that can cause severe device instability issues  (5, 6) . For example, the hygroscopic lithium salts can cause moisture invasion, migration of small Li + ions into perovskite, and irreversible device degradation  (7) (8) (9) (10) . Inorganic HTLs and dopant-free HTLs offer great enhancements in stability but have failed to compete with the doped HTLs for the most efficient PSCs. An additional stability issue arises from the intrinsic soft nature of the perovskites that allows volatile iodide components to enter charge-transporting layers  (11, 12) . Iodide can interact with the positive radicals in HTLs and induce rapid degradation in both hole conductivity and interfacial band alignment, especially for the most efficient PSCs that rely on doped organic HTLs  (3, 4, 6, (13) (14) (15) (16) . Although iodide blocking barriers and interface engineering are promising strategies to hinder the iodide invasion  (11, 12) , these approaches have not been reported to block both Li + migration and iodide invasion completely. Thus, it is highly desirable to find a Li-free doping strategy that can stabilize the hole transport under mass iodide entry. We report a solution strategy to stabilize the hole transport in Li-free organic layers by coupling positive polymer radicals and molecular anions through an ion-exchange process (see methods for details). The molecular anion of 1,1,2,2,3,3-hexafluoropropane-1,3disulfonimide (HFDF -) (fig.  S1 ) was exchanged into poly(triarylamine) (PTAA) films and termed HFDF-HTL (fig.  S2 ). HFDF -has not been used as a noncoordinating ion in a p-type organic semiconductor, as far as we know. We also chose bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide lithium salt/4-tert-butylpyridine (LiTFSI/tBP)doped poly(triarylamine) (Li-HTL) as a reference HTL that is generally used for highly efficient PSCs and offers better stability than LiTFSI/tBP-doped 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis(N,N-di-pmethoxyphenylamine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (Li-Spiro-OMeTAD). The target Li-free-doped HTL, HFDF-HTL, increased hole conductivity to a value 80 times greater than that of the conventional lithium salt-doped HTLs, had a favorable energy-level alignment at the HTL/perovskite heterojunction, and achieved a high conductivity on fresh HFDF-HTL after a few minutes versus the conventional Li-salt doping method that generally takes several hours or days. Under the mass invasion of iodide, hole transport was stabilized through the ionic coupling of positive polymer radicals with introduced molecular anions. Furthermore, hole transport through organic layers withstood thermal stress at temperatures up to 120°C. These results helped us obtain efficient and stable PSCs that achieved a certified PCE of 23.9% and maintained 92% after operation at the maximum power point under AM1.5G solar light (100 mW cm -2 ) at 85°C after 1000 hours. We studied the electronic properties of the aged HTLs in PSCs, with a structure of fluorine-doped tin dioxide (FTO)/SnO x /SnO 2 / formamidinium-based perovskite/HTL/Au, that suffered severe iodide invasion after lightsoaking at 85°C for 200 hours. The iodide invasion into the aged HTLs, as studied by time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) chemical imaging (Fig.  1, A  and B ), showed high concentrations of I -ions distributed over the aged HTLs. The compositional depth profiles of the aged PSCs further revealed that the iodide invasion started from the perovskite/HTL interface (fig.  S3 ). The surface potential measured with Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) (Fig.  1, C  and D ) of the I --rich Li-HTL decreased from an initial 92 mV to a final -678 mV. By contrast, the surface potential of the I --rich HFDF-HTL has a much smaller decrease from 202 to 102 mV, and the decreased value was nearly one-eighth that of the I --rich Li-HTL, exhibiting astonishing durability of HFDF-HTL under iodide invasion during the heat and light aging test. We also characterized the electronic structure of I --rich HTLs with ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS). The Fermi level of the I --rich Li-HTL in aged devices sharply changed from -4.96 to -4.02 eV (fig.  S4 ), which reflected n-doping caused by iodide migration during the entire aging process. However, only a slight change from -5.12 to -4.97 eV in the Fermi level of I --rich HFDF-HTL was found after the aging test. The variation of electronic conductivity of I --rich HTLs of aged PSCs was measured with conductive atomic force microscopy (AFM) (Fig.  1, E  and F ). The average electric current of I --rich Li-HTL quickly decreased from the initial 0.76 to 0.43 nA and maintained only 57% of the initial conductivity. In comparison, I --rich HFDF-HTL exhibited a stable performance with an initial value of 38.6 nA, which was ~50 times greater than that of the fresh Li-HTL, and the aged sample maintained 96% of the initial conductivity (36.9 nA). The conductivity of I --rich HTLs was further investigated under the same iodide concentrations, which were aged through direct injection of formamidinium iodide (FAI), a common volatile perovskite component, into the layer by spin-coating. The conductivity of I --rich Li-HTL decreased by 50% at the FAI concentration of 0.01 mmol liter -1 (Fig.  1G ), whereas the conductivity of I --rich HFDF-HTL remained at 97% under the same conditions (Fig.  1H ). We characterized the compositions of HTLs, especially the positive polymer radicals that can determine their conductivity. In Fig.  2A , Li-HTL was fully occupied by Li + signals, whereas only negligible Li + signals were observed in HFDF-HTL. We also confirmed the absence of Li + cations in HFDF-HTL by highresolution x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy in fig.  S5 . From TOF-SIMS two-dimensional (2D) elemental mapping (fig.  S6A ) and compositional depth profiles (fig.  S3B ), we observed that HFDF -anions were distributed throughout the layer. TOF-SIMS signals of the anions of initiating dopant 2,3,5,6-tetrafluoro-7,7,8,8tetracyanoquinodimethane (F4TCNQ) were negligible in HFDF-HTL (fig.  S6B ), indicating that F4TCNQ -anions were efficiently exchanged with HFDF -and then removed during the spin-coating and washing process. We further verified the ion exchange for HFDF - according to the absence of the F4TCNQ - anions in the ion-exchanged HTL by Fourier transform infrared and Raman spectroscopy (figs. S7 and S8)  (17) . The positive polymer radicals were characterized by electron spin resonance (ESR) spectroscopy, which showed a stronger signal from HFDF-HTL than from Li-HTL (Fig.  2B ), confirming the formation of a high concentration of polymer radicals in HFDF-HTL  (18) . After being aged under iodide invasion, the positive polymer radicals in Li-HTL samples were almost entirely quenched, whereas HFDF-HTL maintained 95.5% of the original value deduced from the second integral of the ESR derivative curves  (19) . By observing the bleaching of the neutral absorption of HTL at 376 nm and swelling of the new absorption of polymer radicals at ~500 nm, an increase in polymer radicals in HFDF-HTL through ion exchange was further verified (Fig.  2C )  (20) . The Raman peak positions of the C=C stretching in conjugated polymers shifted to lower frequencies (Fig.  2D ), indicating higher effective conjugation length and planarization of charged chains  (21) . The density functional theory (DFT) calculation (fig.  S9 ) results supported the observation by Raman spectroscopy, in that the dihedral angles between bridging benzene rings of neutral and one and two positively charged triarylamine dimers were 143.7°, 172.4°, and 178.0°, respectively. The experimental observations of the electronic performance and compositions of HTLs show that the invaded I -ions reduced the positive polymer radicals and caused degradation in hole conductivity for conventional Li-HTL. By contrast, the hole transport was well protected against the iodide invasion in HFDF-HTL. We found that HTLs doped with only F4TCNQ or lithium salts had no obvious enhancement of polymer radicals (fig.  S10 ). For HFDF-HTL that was formed through an ionexchange process with LiHFDF or KHFDF, both HTLs exhibited a similar electronic conductivity (fig.  S11 ), indicating that the HFDF-HTLs are less sensitive to Li + or K + cations. In addition, we found that HFDF-HTLs that were formed through the ion-exchange method had a higher radical doping effect than those fabricated by immersion from the observations of higher characteristic absorption at ~500 nm and much higher conductivity (fig.  S12 ). The spin-coating drop by drop could provide fresh dopant solution continuously for ion-exchange processing and lead to a highspeed washing effect that cleared away some by-products. We also assessed the morphological change of HTL after doping by AFM (fig.  S13 ). Pinholes were observed in Li-HTL, whereas the surface of HFDF-HTL was dense and uniform over the perovskite layer (fig.  S14 ). The effect of different doping strategies on the band alignment of HTLs was further evaluated (fig.  S15 ). The Fermi level deduced from the value of high-binding-energy cut-off downshifted from -4.72 eV for undoped HTL to -4.96 eV for Li-HTL and -5.12 eV for HFDF-HTL, suggesting that the ion-exchange strategy enabled more-efficient p-type doping. The valence band maxima of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL were estimated to be -5.22 and -5.30 eV, respectively, gradually approaching the value of perovskite film (fig.  S16 ). The band alignment of HFDF-HTL reduced the energy loss during charge transfer and increased the opencircuit voltage (V OC )  (22) . We performed steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy and time-resolved   photoluminescence (TRPL) spectroscopy to study the charge transfer kinetics between perovskite and the different HTLs (Fig.  2, E  and F ). Table  S1  summarizes the lifetime of the decay curves fitted by bi-exponential components using the equation Y = A 1 exp(-t/t 1 ) + A 2 exp(-t/t 2 ), where fast decay lifetime t 1 and slow decay lifetime t 2 are related to trapassisted nonradiative and radiative recombination, respectively  (23) . For undoped HTL, the PL intensity and lifetime did not fall off noticeably, indicating a relatively inefficient carrier extraction process without doping (fig.  S17 )  (24) . The conventional doping strategy exhibited a limited PL quenching effect for Li-HTL, whereas a steady PL spectrum was almost completely quenched for HFDF-HTL (Fig.  2E ). The fitted PL lifetimes (t 1 and t 2 ) of perovskite film deposited on bare quartz glass of 56 and 1160 ns, respectively, were shortened more for HFDF-HTL (25 and 230 ns) compared with Li-HTL (54 and 382 ns) (Fig.  2F ), indicating that photogenerated charges were transferred more sufficiently for HFDF-HTL. We applied the ionic coupling between anions and polymer radicals with the ionexchange process to more molecular cations (fig.  S1 )-such as tetrafluoroborate (BF 4 -), hexafluorophosphate (PF 6 -), and bistrifluoromethanesulfonimidate (TFSI -)-for the formation of HTLs with enhanced conductivity and stability. The ESR and optical absorbance spectra show that the formation of polymer radicals was greatly enhanced in the order of HFDF-HTL, TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, and BF 4 -HTL (Fig.  3A  and fig.  S18 ), indicating that these molecular anions preferentially couple with the positive polymer radicals. The ionic coupling between anions and radicals was further evaluated with DFT calculations based on the energetic gain (figs. S19 and S20 and tables S2 to S4), which showed that HFDF -anions were more energetically favorable to couple with polymer radicals than TFSI -followed by PF 6 -and BF 4 -, hence higher ion-exchange efficiency and polymer radical concentration. We measured the conductivity and hole mobility of the different HTLs (figs. S21 and S22). HFDF-HTL exhibited the highest electrical conductivity (Fig.  3B ) followed by TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, BF 4 -HTL, and then Li-HTL. The conductivity of HFDF-HTL, which reached a value of 5.08 × 10 -3 S cm -1 , was ~80 times higher than that of Li-HTL (table  S5 ). HFDF-HTL also exhibited the highest hole mobility (fig.  S23 ), which increased by nearly six times compared with that of Li-HTL (table  S6 ). The exact distribution of charge carriers on the ion-exchanged HTLs and how their interaction with counterions affects electronic mobility pend further study. We further verified the work function in the different HTLs by KPFM (Fig.  3C ). The energy band alignment of the different HTLs and the perovskite film (Fig.  3D ) shows that HFDF-HTL had an optimal energy-level alignment at the HTL/perovskite interface. The thermal stability of the HTLs was evaluated by measuring the conductivity before and after annealing at 80°or 120°C for 24 hours (figs. S24 and S25). The resulting currentvoltage curves of the various HTLs annealed at 120°C showed that the thermally aged HFDF-HTL maintained 95% of the initial conductivity (Fig.  3E ). The conductivity of Li-HTL films was reduced to 55% of initial values after heating at 120°C, possibly because of the undesired volatilization of tBP molecules and spontaneous aggregation of LiTFSI  (25) . By contrast, ion exchange improved the thermal stability in TFSI-HTL, maintaining 83% of the initial conductivity. The thermal stability of the conductivity was also consistent with the results of the DFT calculation on the cohesive energy (figs. S9B, S20, and S26 and tables S7 to S9), which indicated that the ionic coupling between anions and polymer radicals required a large activation energy for the ion decoupling under thermal stress  (26, 27) . The stability of HTLs under iodide invasion shows that the aged HFDF-HTL maintained the highest conductivity (Fig.  3F  and figs. S26 and S27), followed by the aged TFSI-HTL, PF 6 -HTL, BF 4 -HTL, and then Li-HTL. Previous research reported that the diffusion of iodide ions from perovskite can reduce the oxidized HTLs  (28, 29) . Both the thermal and chemical stability indicated that the ionic coupling between HFDF -anions and positive polymer radicals is energetically favorable and stabilizes the hole conductivity in HTLs against the reduction effect from the invaded iodide. Moreover, HFDF-HTL also enabled enhanced moisture stability of perovskite through its hydrophobicity. The contact angle of water on Li-HTL was 62.2°but was 85.0°for HFDF-HTL (fig.  S29 ), which lacked hygroscopic Li + cations. During an aging test in the air with a relative humidity (RH) of ~50% for 500 hours, the HFDF-HTL/perovskite film exhibited a stable crystal structure as determined from x-ray diffraction (fig.  S30 ). An n-i-p planar heterojunction PSC fabricated with HFDF-HTL (Fig.  4A ) achieved a maximum PCE of 24.0%, with a V OC of 1.14 V, a shortcircuit current density (J SC ) of 25.2 mA cm -2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 83.7% (Fig.  4B  and table  S10 ). By contrast, the Li-HTL-based devices only obtained a maximum PCE of 20.5% with a V OC of 1.09V, a J SC of 24.8 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 76.0%. The statistical analysis of the device performance with the different HTLs demonstrated that the HFDF-HTL-based devices exhibited superior performance to other devices we tested for all photovoltaic metrics (fig.  S31 ). The improvement in device performance could be attributed to the high hole conductivity and well-matched band alignment  (23, 30) . The best device further performed maximum power point tracking with a voltage of 1.00 V (fig.  S32 ). The photocurrent stabilized at ~23.9 mA cm -2 , corresponding to a stabilized PCE of 23.9%. We sent one of our best target PSCs to an accredited independent photo-voltaic test center for certification. The device obtained a certified PCE of 23.9% with a V OC of 1.15 V, a J SC of 25.1 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 83.0% (fig.  S33 ) and compared favorably to other reported Li-free PSCs to date (table  S11 ). Our results also established advantages of HFDF -compared with the conventional lithium and/or cobalt salts for hole transport (table  S12 ). We further applied the ion-exchange strategy to other polymeric HTLs (fig.  S34 ), such as poly(3-hexylthiophene-2,5-diyl) (P3HT) and poly-{2,1,3-benzothiadiazole-4,7-diyl[4,4bis(2-ethylhexyl)-4H-cyclopenta[2,1-b:3,4-b′]dithiophene-2,6-diyl]} (PCPDTBT), and their devices also showed enhanced V OC and FF. We performed the device stability test to investigate the durability of photovoltaic cells under moisture or combined heat and light. The nonencapsulated HFDF-HTL-based device retained nearly 90% of its initial performance after the aging test for 576 hours under simulated AM1.5G radiation (100 mW cm -2 ) in ambient air (~50% RH) (Fig.  4C ). By contrast, the control devices with Li-HTL rapidly lost 60% of their initial PCE under the same aging conditions after only 100 hours. The operational stability of PSCs under heat and light stress was conducted under full-spectrum sunlight at 85°C (Fig.  4D ). For the control cell with Li-HTL, a 49% drop in PCE was observed after continuous operation for 1000 hours, whereas the devices with HFDF-HTL maintained 92% of their initial PCE over the same aging period and still performed with a PCE of 21.2%. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37081</offset>
      <text> Materials and Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37105</offset>
      <text> Materials All the chemicals were used as received. SnO2 colloid precursor (tin (iv) oxide, 15% in H2O colloidal dispersion) was purchased from Alfa Aesar. SnCl2• 2H2O (&gt;99.995%), Lead iodide (PbI2, 99.999% purity), 4-tert-butylpyridine (tBP) and poly(triaryl amine) (PTAA) and poly-[2,1,3benzothiadiazole-4,7-diyl[4,4-bis(2-ethylhexyl)-4H-cyclopenta[2,1-b:3,4-b′]dithiophene-2,6diyl]] (PCPDTBT) were purchased from Sigma Aldrich. Organic halide salts, lithium 1,1,2,2,3,3hexafluoropropane-1,3-disulfonimide (LiHFDF) and potassium 1,1,2,2,3,3-hexafluoropropane-1,3-disulfonimide (KHFDF) were purchased from Tokyo Chemical Industry (TCI). The dopant 2,3,5,6-tetrafluoro-7,7,8,8-tetracyanoquinodimethane (F4TCNQ) and poly(3-hexylthiophene-2,5diyl) (P3HT) were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. Lithium tetrafluoroborate (LiBF4), lithium hexafluorophosphate (LiPF6), lithium bistrifluoromethanesulfonimidate (LiTFSI), and all the anhydrous solvents were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38104</offset>
      <text> Doping methodology The PTAA thin films were deposited on substrates by spin-coating PTAA solution dissolved in toluene (20 mg/ml) at a spinning speed of 3,000 r.p.m. and as-prepared films were annealed at 100°C for 10 min. For the ion-exchange process, hot dopant solutions (60°C) were dripped onto the resulting PTAA films drop by drop at 5,000 r.p.m, and the residual F4TCNQ and lithium salts or potassium salts and by-products (including Li + or K + and F4TCNQ •-) were washed with ethyl acetate. Dopant solutions were prepared by co-dissolving 0.02 M F4TCNQ and 0.1 M lithium salts or potassium salts in acetonitrile and stirring at 60°C for 1 h. For the immersive ion-exchange process, the as-prepared PTAA film was immersed in a dopant solution for 10 min at 60°C . For the Li-HTL, the dopants of 15 μl Li-TFSI/ acetonitrile (170 mg/mL) and 10 μl tBP were added into the 1 ml PTAA solution (20 mg/ml in toluene). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39033</offset>
      <text> Perovskite film preparation and device fabrication Fluorine-doped tin oxide (FTO)-coated substrates were etched with zinc powder and diluted hydrochloric acid (HCl) to produce desired patterns. The patterned substrates were sequentially cleaned with soap, deionized water, ethanol, and acetone under ultrasonication, and then dried with dry nitrogen. Before use, the substrates were cleaned with ultraviolet ozone for 15 min. Dense blocking layer Tin oxide (bl-SnOx) was deposited onto FTO substrates by chemical bath deposition (CBD)  (7) . Briefly, 1250 mg of urea, 1,250 μl of HCl (37 wt%), 25 μl of thioglycolic acid, and 275 mg of SnCl2• 2H2O were dissolved into 100 mL of deionized water in turn. The as-cleaned FTO glasses were soaked into the preheated reaction mixture at 85℃ for 3.5 hours. The SnOx deposited FTO substrates were washed with deionized water and IPA, and annealed at 180 ℃ for 1 hour. Then the substrate was spin-coated with a diluted SnO2 colloid precursor (2%) at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and annealed at 150°C for 30 min in ambient air. After UV ozone treatment for 10 min, 1.4 M of PbI2 in DMF:DMSO (94:6) solvent was spin-coated onto SnOx/SnO2 substrate at 1,500 r.p.m. for 40 s. After that, a solution of FAI:MABr:MACl (75 mg:2.14 mg:12.86 mg in 1 ml IPA) was spin-coated onto the PbI2 at 1,500 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by thermal annealing at 150°C for 20 min in ambient air conditions (30-40% humidity). After cooling to room temperature, 15 mmol of octylammonium iodide dissolved in IPA was spin-coated onto the perovskite surface at 5,000 r.p.m. Then the 20 mg/ml PTAA solution dissolved in toluene was spin-coated on top of the perovskite layer at 3,000 r.p.m. For the control devices, the dopants of 15 μl Li-TFSI/ acetonitrile (170 mg/mL) and 10 μl tBP were added to the 1 ml PTAA solution. And the Li-HTL contained samples were stored in a desiccator overnight to oxidate the Li-HTL films. For the ionexchange process, 200 μl of dopant solutions were dripped onto the as-prepared PTAA films drop by drop at 5,000 r.p.m, and residual F4TCNQ and metal salts were washed with ethyl acetate. For the P3HT and PCPDTBT solution, 20 mg of P3HT or PCPDTBT was dissolved in 1 ml of chlorobenzene, and the dopants of 15 μl Li-TFSI/ acetonitrile (170 mg/mL) and 10 μl tBP were added into the polymer solution. Finally, 100 nm Au was deposited by thermal evaporation. The device area of 0.08 cm 2 was determined by a metal mask. For the long-term operational stability test, a 10-nm layer of MoO3 was deposited on top of the PTAA by thermal evaporation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41629</offset>
      <text> Characterization &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41648</offset>
      <text> HTL film characterizations The electrical conductivity of pristine and doped HTL films was measured using 2×1.5 cm patterned ITO-coated glass with one vertical etched line engraved by laser. The PTAA solution was spin-coated on pre-patterned substrates from a toluene solution (20 mg/ml) at a spin speed of 3,000 r.p.m. The width and length of the non-conducting channel were 100 μm and 1.5 cm, respectively. The thickness of the ITO was 180 nm. Current-Voltage (I-V) characteristics were measured using a multi-functional electrochemical analysis instrument (Zahner, Germany). Electrical conductivity was calculated as σ = (L/Wd) × (dV/dI), where L = 1.5 cm is the length of the channel, W = 100 μm is the width of the channel, and d = 180 nm is the thickness of the ITO. Hole mobility of pristine and doped HTL films was determined via space-charge-limited current (SCLC) measurement on a hole-only device (ITO/30 nm MoO3/PTAA/30 nm MoO3/70nm Au). The MoO3 and Au layers were all deposited by thermal evaporation. The PTAA thin films were deposited on substrates by spin-coating a PTAA solution (20 mg/ml) at 2,000 r.p.m. and asprepared films were annealed at 100°C for 10 min. The classic Mott-Gurney equation was used to determine the mobility: 𝐽 = 9𝜇𝜀 0 𝜀 r 𝑉 2 /(8𝑑 3 ), where εr≈8.26 is the average dielectric constant of the blended film  (34) , ε0 is the vacuum permittivity of the free space, μ is the hole mobility, V is the applied bias, and d is the film thickness. UV-vis-NIR absorption spectra of pristine and doped HTL film samples were recorded by a Shimadzu UV 2450 and Lamda 950 spectrometry. Infrared absorption spectra were recorded with a Nicolet 6700 FTIR spectrometer (Thermo Fisher). Raman spectroscopy was recorded by a Raman spectrometer on glass substrates with a Renishaw inVia Qontor instrument and using a HeNe (785 nm) laser. Electron spin resonance (ESR) spectroscopy was analyzed by a Bruker EMX-8 spectrometer. XPS spectra for the different HTL films were recorded by AXIS Ultra DLD (Kratos Analytical Ltd.). The ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) was measured by Thermo ESCALAB 250 with a non-monochromated He Iα photon source (hν = 21.22 eV). The static contact angle with the water droplet was conducted on DSA 100 contact angle measuring device (KRUSS GmbH, Germany). Atomic force microscopy, conductive atomic force microscopy (c-AFM), and Kelvin Probe Force Microscopy (KPFM) were all recorded by a Bruker FastScan Bio instrument. Work function can be calculated using the following equation: 𝐶𝑃𝐷 = (𝛷 𝑠𝑎𝑚𝑝𝑙𝑒 -𝛷 𝑡𝑖𝑝 )/𝑒. 𝛷 𝑠𝑎𝑚𝑝𝑙𝑒 and 𝛷 𝑡𝑖𝑝 are the work function of the sample surface and Pt/Ircoated tip, respectively. e is the elementary charge of an electron. 𝛷 𝑡𝑖𝑝 is calibrated with Au (5.2 eV). For the aged HTL films in devices, we removed the package and Au electrode before measurement. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44617</offset>
      <text> Perovskite film characterizations UV-vis absorption spectra of perovskite film samples were recorded by a Shimadzu UV 2450 spectrometry. Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectra and Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra were obtained by FLS1000. The excitation wavelength was set as 520 nm. The TRPL decay data were modeled by a biexponential formula: Y=A1exp(t/τ1)+A2exp(-t/τ2)  (26) . The ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) was measured by Thermo ESCALAB 250 with a non-monochromated He Iα photon source (hν = 21.22 eV). The XRD patterns were recorded on a Rigaku Ultima IV powder X-ray diffractometer using Cu Kα radiation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>45273</offset>
      <text> Device characterizations Field emission scanning electron microscopy (TESCAN MAIA3 GMU model 2016) was used to observe the cross-sectional SEM image of the complete device. Current-Voltage (I-V) curves of the perovskite solar cells were measured with a digital source meter (Keithley 2400) under simulated solar illumination at AM1.5G (100 mW cm -2 ). The light source was calibrated by a standard silicon reference cell (Wacom Denso Co., Japan). The measurement was conducted forward (from -0.2 to 1.2 V) scan. The step voltage and delay time were fixed at 10 mV and 200 ms, respectively. Incident photo-to-electron conversion efficiency (IPCE) spectra measurements were characterized using monochromatic incident light of 1×10 16 photons cm -2 with the alternating current mode. All the tested cells in photovoltaic measurements were covered with a 0.08 cm 2 shading mask. Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (ToF-SIMS) measurements were based on the focused ion beam ToF-SIMS spectrometer (ION TOF ToF SIMS 5-100). A Bi + ion beam was used as the ion beam to peel the samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46367</offset>
      <text> Device stability measurement The moisture stability test was conducted without encapsulation. The devices were placed in the air. The relative humidity in the laboratory was around 50% during the entire aging test. The operational stability tests were carried out at the MPP for the encapsulated devices under AM1.5 illumination (100 mW cm -2 ). The devices were tested in a light-soaking chamber. During the aging test, the temperature of the light aging chamber was set at 85°C . The voltage at the MPP was calculated and applied automatically; the current output of the device was tracked. The devices were encapsulated in a nitrogen glove box. UV-curable epoxy was coated around the device area, and a customized glass cover slide with desiccant was attached to enclose the area. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47154</offset>
      <text> Estimation of the energy gain by ion exchange with the different lithium salts The doping level in HTL thin films is improved dramatically due to the following ionexchange process: [PTAA •+ F4TCNQ •-] + Li + Anion -→ [PTAA •+ Anion -] + Li + +F4TCNQ •- (1 ) This ion-exchange reaction proceeds spontaneously based on spectroscopic analyses. We defined the energy gain ∆Eex within the ion exchange as ∆𝐸 𝑒𝑥 = [𝐸(PTAA •+ Anion -) + 𝐸(Li + ) + 𝐸(F4TCNQ •-)] -[𝐸(PTAA •+ F4TCNQ •-) + 𝐸(Li + Anion -)] (2) where E(X + Y -) is the total energy of the [X + Y -] ion pair. DFT calculations were implemented with the ORCA5.0.1 package  (35) . Geometry optimizations were performed at the M06-2X/Def2-SVP level of theory  (36) . All single point energies were obtained using M06-2X/Def2-TZVPP. PTAA •+ was modeled as a positively charged triarylamine dimer. During the optimization, the structure of the triarylamine dimer was fixed to reduce the calculation costs, which may also help to avoid unrealistic torsion of the ion and better reproduce the actual conformation. The optimized structures of lithium salts and [PTAA •+ anion -] were provided in Fig.  S18  and S19, respectively. And the values of the total energy were listed in Tables  S2  and S3 , respectively. To compare the energy gain by ion exchange with the different lithium salts, the difference in energy gains between two lithium salts is given by ∆𝐸 𝑒𝑥 𝐴 -∆𝐸 𝑒𝑥 𝐵 = [𝐸(PTAA •+ Anion 𝐴 -) -𝐸(Li + Anion 𝐴 -)] -[𝐸(PTAA •+ Anion 𝐵 -) -𝐸(Li + Anion 𝐵 -)] (3) For the reaction with the different lithium salts, the [E(PTAA •+ Anion -)-E(Li + Anion -)] values for the different anions determine the level of ∆𝐸 𝑒𝑥 𝐴 -∆𝐸 𝑒𝑥 𝐵 . The calculated [E(PTAA •+ Anion -)-E(Li + Anion -)] for the different anions were listed in Table  S4 . The sequence of energy gain was HFDF-HTL, TFSI-HTL, PF6-HTL, and BF4-HTL. It could be supposed that in a hybrid anion system, conversion of other Anion-HTL to HFDF-HTL will reduce the total energy, indicating that ion exchange with HFDF -is more energetically favorable than that with TFSI -, PF6 -, and BF4 -. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49391</offset>
      <text> Estimation of cohesive energy of PTAA •+ Anion - The cohesive energy ∆𝐸 𝑐𝑜 is used to determine the strength of ionic interactions. The value of ∆𝐸 𝑐𝑜 is equal to energy difference after the combination of cation and anion: ∆𝐸 𝑐𝑜 = 𝐸 𝑐𝑎𝑡𝑖𝑜𝑛 + 𝐸 𝑎𝑛𝑖𝑜𝑛 -𝐸 𝑖𝑜𝑛𝑝𝑎𝑖𝑟 (4) The optimized structures of anions, PTAA •+ radical cation, and [PTAA •+ anion -] were provided in Fig.  S25 , S8B, and S19, respectively. The calculated total energy values for anions, PTAA •+ radical cation, and [PTAA •+ anion -] were listed in Tables S7, S8, and S3, respectively. The calculated cohesive energy values were listed in Table  S9 . The sequence of cohesive energy was HFDF-HTL, TFSI-HTL, PF6-HTL, and BF4-HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50192</offset>
      <text> Fig. S2. Schematic diagram of ion-exchange doping process. The neutral HTL is p-doped firstly with the molecule F4TCNQ via a charge-transfer interaction. The F4TCNQ radical anions are replaced by the anion of a lithium salt (F4TCNQ •-→Anion -) spontaneously, resulting in the formation of a solid-state donor-acceptor complex ([PTAA •+ Anion -]). [PTAA •+ HFDF -] was used to present the ionic coupling of polymer radicals and HFDF -anions, rather than the actual chemical formula of the product. The residual F4TCNQ and metal salts and by-products (including metal cations and F4TCNQ •-) were washed off the surface using fresh ethyl acetate to obtain pure products. This doping process is completed in a few minutes.                               Table  S2 . Calculated total energy values for lithium salts. The total energy values for lithium salts were calculated using M06-2X/Def2-TZVPP. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51098</offset>
      <text> Lithium salt Total energy (hartree) LiBF4 -432.1089 Fig.  S19a  LiPF6 -948.3063 Fig.  S19b  LiTFSI -1834.9540 Fig.  S19c  LiHFDF -1873.0146 Fig.  S19d  Table  S3 . Calculated total energy values for [PTAA •+ anion -] ion pairs. The total energy values for ion pairs were calculated using M06-2X/Def2-TZVPP. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51409</offset>
      <text> Ion pair Total energy (hartree) BF 4 -HTL -2237.0808 Fig.  S20a  PF 6 -HTL -2753.2911 Fig.  S20b  TFSI-HTL -3639.9474 Fig.  S20c  HFDF-HTL -3678.0281 Fig.  S20d  Table  S4 . Calculated values of [E(PTAA •+ Anion -)-E(Li + Anion -)] for the different HTLs. Ion pair E(PTAA Table  S7 . Calculated total energy values for the different anions. The total energy values for anions were calculated using M06-2X/ma-Def2-TZVPP. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51833</offset>
      <text> Anion Total energy (hartree) BF4 - -424.5997 Fig.  S26a  PF6 - -940.8066 Fig.  S26b  TFSI - -1827.4500 Fig.  S26c  HFDF - -1865.5296 Fig.  S26e  Table  S8 . Calculated total energy values for PTAA •+ radical cation. The total energy value for PTAA •+ was calculated using M06-2X/Def2-TZVPP. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52130</offset>
      <text> Cation Total energy (hartree) PTAA  2 of 5 Fig. 1 . 5 Fig. 2 . 25152 Fig. 1. Degradation of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL under iodide invasion. (A and B) 2D TOF-SIMS elemental mapping of I -signals in Li-HTL (A) and HFDF-HTL (B) after aging. TC, total counts. (C and D) xy-plane surface potential mapping images of Li-HTL/perovskite (C) and HFDF-HTL/perovskite (D) before (top) and after (bottom) aging. Pero, perovskite. (E and F) Variations in the surface conductivity of Li-HTL/perovskite (E) and HFDF-HTL/perovskite (F) before (top) and after (bottom) aging. The devices were all aged at the maximum power point under light-soaking (AM1.5G, 100 mW cm -2 ) for 200 hours at 85°C. TUNA, tunneling AFM. (G and H) The current-voltage curves of Li-HTL (G) and HFDF-HTL (H) before and after spin-coating with 0.01 and 1 mmol liter -1 FAI solution in acetonitrile at a speed of 5000 rotations per minute (rpm). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53032</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Hole-related properties of the pristine and different doped HTLs. (A) ESR spectra of the undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and ion-exchanged HTLs with different lithium salts. The inset shows a zoomed-in view of the low-intensity region. (B) Variations in the electrical conductivity of the different HTLs. The error bars in the conductivity represent the standard deviation. (C) The xy-plane work function mapping images of the different HTLs. The surface work function (WF) was calibrated by Au foil. (D) Energy-level diagrams for the different HTLs and the perovskite layer based on the parameters derived from UPS spectra. CBM, conduction band minimum; VBM, valence band maximum. (E and F) The current-voltage curves of the different HTLs after annealing at 120°C for 1 day (E) and after spin-coating with 0.01 mmol liter -1 FAI acetonitrile solution at a speed of 5000 rpm (F). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53924</offset>
      <text> RESEARCH | REPORTCorrected 30 September 2022. See full text. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53987</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Structure, photovoltaic performance, and long-term stability studies of the PSCs with Li-HTL or HFDF-HTL. (A) Cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy image of the PSCs. (B) Current densityvoltage characteristics of the best-performing n-i-p devices with the different HTLs. (C) Long-term moisture stability of the Li-HTL-and HFDF-HTL-based devices under simulated AM1.5G radiation (100 mW cm -2 ) in the air (~50% RH) without encapsulation. The shaded regions represent standard deviations from the average PCE obtained from eight aged cells. The insets show pictures of the devices after aging for 576 hours. (D) Long-term operational stability for the most-stable encapsulated devices among eight aged cells with the different HTLs under AM1.5G illumination (100 mW cm -2 ) and heat stress at 85°C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54815</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 . 1 Fig. 1. Degradation of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL under iodide invasion. (A and B) 2D TOF-SIMS elemental mapping of I -signals in Li-HTL (A) and HFDF-HTL (B) after aging. TC, total counts. (C and D) xy-plane surface potential mapping images of Li-HTL/perovskite (C) and HFDF-HTL/perovskite (D) before (top) and after (bottom) aging. Pero, perovskite. (E and F) Variations in the surface conductivity of Li-HTL/perovskite (E) and HFDF-HTL/perovskite (F) before (top) and after (bottom) aging. The devices were all aged at the maximum power point under light-soaking (AM1.5G, 100 mW cm -2 ) for 200 hours at 85°C. TUNA, tunneling AFM. (G and H) The current-voltage curves of Li-HTL (G) and HFDF-HTL (H) before and after spin-coating with 0.01 and 1 mmol liter -1 FAI solution in acetonitrile at a speed of 5000 rotations per minute (rpm). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55659</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 . 2 Fig. 2. Li + and radical content and charge transport properties of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL. (A) Mapping of TOF-SIMS signals of Li + cations in Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL. (B) ESR spectra of Li-HTL and HFDF-HTL before and after treatment with 0.01 mmol liter -1 FAI solution. The inset shows a zoomed-in view of the low-intensity region. (C and D) The optical absorbance (C) and Raman spectra within the range of 1550 to 1670 cm -1 (D) of the undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HFDF-HTL. (E and F) Steady PL spectra (E) and TRPL decay profiles (F) of perovskite films with and without the different doped HTLs. a.u., arbitrary units. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56285</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 . 3 Fig. 3. Hole-related properties of the pristine and different doped HTLs. (A) ESR spectra of the undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and ion-exchanged HTLs with different lithium salts. The inset shows a zoomed-in view of the low-intensity region. (B) Variations in the electrical conductivity of the different HTLs. The error bars in the conductivity represent the standard deviation. (C) The xy-plane work function mapping images of the different HTLs. The surface work function (WF) was calibrated by Au foil. (D) Energy-level diagrams for the different HTLs and the perovskite layer based on the parameters derived from UPS spectra. CBM, conduction band minimum; VBM, valence band maximum. (E and F) The current-voltage curves of the different HTLs after annealing at 120°C for 1 day (E) and after spin-coating with 0.01 mmol liter -1 FAI acetonitrile solution at a speed of 5000 rpm (F). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57177</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 . 4 Fig. 4. Structure, photovoltaic performance, and long-term stability studies of the PSCs with Li-HTL or HFDF-HTL. (A) Cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy image of the PSCs. (B) Current densityvoltage characteristics of the best-performing n-i-p devices with the different HTLs. (C) Long-term moisture stability of the Li-HTL-and HFDF-HTL-based devices under simulated AM1.5G radiation (100 mW cm -2 ) in the air (~50% RH) without encapsulation. The shaded regions represent standard deviations from the average PCE obtained from eight aged cells. The insets show pictures of the devices after aging for 576 hours. (D) Long-term operational stability for the most-stable encapsulated devices among eight aged cells with the different HTLs under AM1.5G illumination (100 mW cm -2 ) and heat stress at 85°C. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58005</offset>
      <text> Fig. S3 . S3 Fig. S3. The influence of the aging test on the component distribution in the devices. The depth profiles of ToF-SIMS for the aged devices with (a) Li-HTL, and (b) HFDF-HTL. All the cells were aged under continuous light soaking (AM1.5G, 100 mW cm -2 ) at the maximum power point and 85°C for 200 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58325</offset>
      <text> Fig. S4 . S4 Fig. S4. Energy-level characterization of HTLs after aging. (a) The high-binding-energy and (b) the low-binding-energy cutoffs in UPS spectra of Li-HTL after aging. (d) The high-bindingenergy, and (e) the low-binding-energy cutoffs in UPS spectra of HFDF-HTL after aging. Energylevel diagrams for (c) Li-HTL, and (f) HFDF-HTL based on the parameters derived from UPS spectra. The cells were aged under continuous light soaking (AM1.5G, 100mW cm -2 ) at the maximum power point and 85°C for 200 hours. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58842</offset>
      <text> Fig. S5 . S5 Fig. S5. XPS spectroscopy to assess residual Li + cations in the different HTLs. High-resolution XPS spectra of Li 1s for the different HTLs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58999</offset>
      <text> Fig. S6 . S6 Fig. S6. Surface component distribution after doping. Mapping of TOF-SIMS signals of (a) entire HFDF -anions and (b) entire F4TCNQ -anions in HFDF-HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59166</offset>
      <text> Fig. S7 . S7 Fig. S7. Raman spectroscopy to assess resulting ions in the different HTLs. Raman spectra of undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59356</offset>
      <text> Fig. S8 . S8 Fig. S8. FTIR spectroscopy to assess residual F4TCNQ •-radical anions in the different HTLs. FTIR spectra of undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts at the range of 2,000-2,500 cm -1 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59599</offset>
      <text> Fig. S10 . S10 Fig. S10. Absorption spectra to assess the role of F4TCNQ and lithium salt. Optical absorption spectra of HTLs after spin-coating only F4TCNQ or LiHFDF solution and washing with ethyl acetate. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59809</offset>
      <text> Fig. S11 . S11 Fig. S11. Comparisons of two HFDF -salts. (a) Optical absorbance, and (b) Current-Voltage curves of HFDF-HTL doped with LiHFDF and KHFDF. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59964</offset>
      <text> Fig. S12 . S12 Fig. S12. Comparisons of two doping strategies. (a) Optical absorbance, and (b) Current-Voltage curves of HFDF-HTL doped via the ion-exchange method based on spin coating or solution immersing. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60175</offset>
      <text> Fig. S13 . S13 Fig. S13. Surface characterization of the different HTLs. AFM height images of (a) the undoped HTL, (b) Li-HTL, (c) BF4-HTL, (d) PF6-HTL, (e) TFSI-HTL, and (f) HFDF-HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60362</offset>
      <text> Fig. S14 . S14 Fig. S14. Surface images of the different HTLs on the perovskite layer. Photograph of (a) the undoped HTL, (b) Li-HTL, (c) BF4-HTL, (d) PF6-HTL, (e) TFSI-HTL, and (f) HFDF-HTL on the perovskite layer. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60580</offset>
      <text> Fig. S15 . S15 Fig. S15. Energy-level characterization of the different HTLs. (a) The high-binding-energy and (b) the low-binding-energy cutoffs in UPS spectra of the different HTLs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60765</offset>
      <text> Fig. S16 . S16 Fig. S16. Energy-level characterization of the perovskite film. (a) The high-binding-energy and (b) the low-binding-energy cutoffs in UPS spectra. (c) UV-vis spectrum of the perovskite film. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60973</offset>
      <text> Fig. S17 . S17 Fig. S17. Charge transport properties of the different HTLs. (a) Steady PL spectra and (b) TRPL decay profiles of glass/perovskite (FAPbI3)0.92(MAPbBr3)0.08 and the different HTLs deposited on the perovskite. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61199</offset>
      <text> Fig. S18 . S18 Fig. S18. Optical testing to check the doping level. The optical absorbance of the undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61381</offset>
      <text> Fig. S19 . S19 Fig. S19. Optimized structures of the lithium salts. (a) LiBF4, (b) LiPF6, (c) LiTFSI, and (d) LiHFDF. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61501</offset>
      <text> Fig. S20 . S20 Fig. S20. Optimized structures of [PTAA •+ anion -] ion pairs. (a) BF4-HTL, (b) PF6-HTL, (c) TFSI-HTL, and (d) HFDF-HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61641</offset>
      <text> Fig. S21 . S21 Fig. S21. Electrical measurement to check the doping level of different strategies. The Current-Voltage curves of undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts. The inset is the design pattern for the measurement. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61907</offset>
      <text> Fig. S22 . S22 Fig. S22. Electrical measurement to check the hole transport characteristic of the different HTLs. (a) Schematic device architectures of the hole-only device for SCLC measurement. (b) log(J)-log(V) plots for undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62214</offset>
      <text> Fig. S23 . S23 Fig. S23. Charge transport properties of the different HTLs. Variations in the hole mobility of the undoped HTL, Li-HTL, and HTL doped via ion exchange with different lithium salts. The error bars in the conductivity represent the standard deviation of six samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62497</offset>
      <text> Fig. S24 . S24 Fig. S24. Electrical measurement to check the thermal durability of the doped HTLs with different strategies. The Current-Voltage curves of (a) Li-HTL, (b) BF4-HTL, (c) PF6-HTL, (d) TFSI-HTL, and (e) HFDF-HTL before and after annealing at 80°C and 120°C for 1 day. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62781</offset>
      <text> Fig. S25 . S25 Fig. S25. Thermal durability of the doped HTLs. Ratios of conductivity before and after annealing at 80°C and 120°C for 1 day. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62927</offset>
      <text> Fig. S26 . S26 Fig. S26. Optimized structures of the different anions. (a) BF4 -, (b) PF6 -, (c) TFSI -, and (d) HFDF -. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63050</offset>
      <text> Fig. S27 . S27 Fig. S27. Electrical measurement to check iodide durability of the doped HTLs with different strategies. The Current-Voltage curves of (a) Li-HTL, (b) BF4-HTL, (c) PF6-HTL, (d) TFSI-HTL, and (e) HFDF-HTL before and after spin coating 0.01 and 1 mmol/L FAI acetonitrile solution at a speed of 5,000 r.p.m. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63372</offset>
      <text> Fig. S28 . S28 Fig. S28. Iodide durability of the doped HTLs. Ratios of conductivity before and after spin coating 0.01 and 1 mmol/L FAI at a speed of 5,000 rpm. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63536</offset>
      <text> Fig. S29 . S29 Fig. S29. Hydrophobicity test for the different HTLs. Water contact angle measurements of (a) the undoped HTL, (b) Li-HTL, (c) BF4-HTL, (d) PF6-HTL, (e) TFSI-HTL, and (f) HFDF-HTL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63734</offset>
      <text> Fig. S30 . S30 Fig. S30. The humidity duration of perovskite films with the different HTLs. The XRD patterns of the perovskite films with the coverage of (a) Li-HTL and (b) HFDF-HTL after being aged in the dark with a humidity of around 50% RH for 500 h. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63991</offset>
      <text> Fig. S31 . S31 Fig. S31. Device photovoltaic performance of devices with the different HTLs. PCE, JSC, VOC, and FF statistics for PSCs with the different HTLs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64153</offset>
      <text> Fig. S32 . S32 Fig. S32. The steady-state measurement of the champion device. The stabilized power output (black) and photocurrent (brown) of the champion device at an MPP voltage of 1.00 V. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64346</offset>
      <text> Fig. S33 . S33 Fig. S33. Certified PV performance from Shanghai Institute of Microsystem and Information Technology (SIMIT) for the HFDF-HTL based device. It should be noted that the PCE of 23.88% with negligible hysteresis is a record-certified efficiency for Li-free PSCs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64623</offset>
      <text> Fig. S34 . S34 Fig. S34. Effects of ion exchange on the optical and photovoltaic properties of other polymeric HTLs. Optical absorbance spectra of (a) P3HT and HFDF-P3HT, and (b) PCPDTBT and HFDF-PCPDTBT films. J-V characteristics of typical n-i-p devices with (c) Li-P3HT and HFDF-P3HT, and (d) Li-PCPDTBT and HFDF-PCPDTBT. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64950</offset>
      <text> Table S5 . S5 •+ Anion -)-E(Li + Anion -) (hartree) The average conductivity of the different HTLs. Ion pair Average Conductivity (S cm -1 ) BF 4 -HTL Undoped HTL -1804.9719 2.74×10 -8 PF 6 -HTL Li-HTL -1804.9848 6.24×10 -5 TFSI-HTL BF 4 -HTL -1804.9934 2.35×10 -4 HFDF-HTL PF 6 -HTL -1805.0135 2.41×10 -3 TFSI-HTL 3.82×10 -3 HFDF-HTL 5.08×10 -3 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65306</offset>
      <text> Table S6 . S6 The hole mobility of the different HTLs. Ion pair Hole mobility (cm 2 (Vs) -1 ) Undoped HTL 2.174×10 -5 Li-HTL 3.914×10 -4 BF 4 -HTL 1.411×10 -4 PF 6 -HTL 1.546×10 -3 TFSI-HTL 1.547×10 -3 HFDF-HTL 2.299×10 -3 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65537</offset>
      <text> Table S9 . S9 Calculated cohesive energy for the different ion pairs. Ion pair Cohesive energy (hartree) •+ BF4-HTL -1812.4038 0.07722 Fig. S9b PF6-HTL 0.08064 TFSI-HTL 0.09355 HFDF-HTL 0.09461 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65735</offset>
      <text> Table S10 . S10 The detailed parameters for the cells in Fig.4b. Devices JSC (mA/cm 2 ) VOC (V) FF (%) PCE (%) Li-HTL 24.76 1.091 75.99 20.53 HFDF-HTL 25.16 1.139 83.66 23.98 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65912</offset>
      <text> Table S12 . S12 An account of various common HTLs in PSCs. HTM Conductivity (S cm -1 ) Hole Mobility (cm 2 (Vs) -1 ) PCE (%) Reference PTAA/HFDF - 5.08×10 -3 2.299×10 -3 23.88 This work Spiro-OMeTAD/LiTFSI, tBP &amp; FK209 1.59×10 -4 6.590×10 -3 25.8 (5, 26) Spiro-mF/LiTFSI, tBP &amp; FK209 2.60×10 -4 7.475×10 -3 24.82 (26) Spiro-DM/LiTFSI, tBP no 1.5×10 -4 23.2 (33) P3HT 6×10 -4 0.2 22.7 (45, 48) PEDOT:PSS 1.2 0.045 20.68 (49, 50) NiOx 1.66×10 -4 0.3 21.4 (51-53) CuSCN 10 -4 1.2×10 -3 20.4 (37, 54) CuxO 10 -5 11.84 19.0 (55, 56) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66452</offset>
      <text>			 of 5 RESEARCH | REPORT Corrected 30 September 2022. See full text. Downloaded from https://www.science.org at University of California San Diego on November 07, 2024 SOLAR CELLS &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66635</offset>
      <text>			 of 5 1 State Key Laboratory of Metal Matrix Composites, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66736</offset>
      <text>			 200240, China.2  Center of Hydrogen Science, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.3  Zhangjiang Institute for Advanced Study, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 201210, China.4  Beijing Academy of Quantum Information Sciences, Beijing 100193, China.5  School of Physics, Sydney Nano Institute, The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW 2006, Australia. *Corresponding author. Email: yang.xudong@sjtu.edu.cn &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>67211</offset>
      <text>			 of 5 RESEARCH | REPORT</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
