<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025051792AFFADG</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 146&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Synthetic details: 1,2-bis(4-phenyl)-1,2-dicarba-closo-decaborane (CB-ph) dodecahydro-arachno-bis(acatonitrile)decaborane (1021 mg, 5 mmol), diphenylacetylene (979 mg, 5.5 mmol), and silver nitrate (84.9 mg, 0.5 mmol) were added to a 100 mL three-neck flask. The reactant was degassed and flushed with dry nitrogen for several times. Then dry toluene (50 mL) was added to dissolved the reactant. The mixture was heated to 80 o C with stirring for 12 h, cooled down and quenched with methanol (10 mL). The mixture was then extracted with CH2Cl2, washed with brine, and dried over anhydrous Na2SO4. At last, the solvent was removed by rotary evaporation, and crude product was purified by column chromatography silica gel (petroleum ether) to give a white solid in 42% yield (626 mg). 1 H NMR (CDCl3/TMS, 400 MHz, δ, ppm):7.41-7.43(d, J=7.5 Hz, 4H, phenyl-H), 7.24(m, 2H, phenyl-H), 7.15(m, 4H, phenyl-H), 1.6-4.0(br, m, 10H, boron-H). 1,2-bis(4-nitrobenzene)-1,2-dicarba-closo-dodecaborane (CB-NO2) A mixture of H2SO4 (97% w/w, 32 mL) and HNO3 (61% w/w, 6.4 mL) was stirred and cooled in ice-bath. 1,2-dicarba-closo-decaborane (1193.6 mg, 4 mmol) was dissolved in 40 mL CH2Cl2 and added dropwise. Then the solution was stirred at room temperature for 6 h. The mixture was poured into ice-cold water (100 mL) and extracted with CH2Cl2. The organic phase was washed with saturated NaHCO3 solution and brine, then dried over anhydrous Na2SO4. The solvent was removed by rotary evaporation, and crude product was purified by column chromatography silica gel (petroleum ether: EtOAc, 8:1) to give a pale yellow solid (233 mg, 15%).&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1640</offset>
      <text>V oc (V) This manuscript reports a novel interface passivation layer for inverted perovskite solar cells with C60 electron transport layers. C60 is by far the most widely used ETL material in inverted (pin) perovskite cells, but it is also responsible for the relatively poor voltage performance of these cells relative to nip cells. This work clearly demonstrates that non-radiative recombination at the C60/perovskite interface is the cause of this voltage loss, and demonstrates an effective solution with the functionalized carborane passivation. The passivation mechanism is carefully investigated using both experimental and theoretical (DFT) methods. The improved stability of the passivated cells with the hydrophobic interlayer is also promising. The manuscript is well written, the experimental and theoretical analysis is thorough and clearly presented, and the conclusions are well supported by the evidence. This work is likely to be of significant interest to the perovskite research community and therefore I recommend it for publication with only minor revisions as listed below: 1. The introduction (line 85) cites Peng [ref 21] as demonstrating PMMA for passivating the perovskite/C60 interface. This is not quite correct: ref 85 only reported results for pin structured cells passivated by PMMA. 2. Line 156: "The optical energy gaps (EG) were calculated by the intersection of normalized absorption and emission spectra". This method for estimating the optical bandgap is not commonly used in perovskite literature, although it may be standard in other fields. I suggest that the authors either provide a suitable reference, or else provide a brief explanation/justification in the SI. 4. Line 333: trap densities extracted from SCLC measurements are quoted to three significant figures. Is this level of precision appropriate given sample-sample variation and the assumptions required to extract these values? 5. Line 391: The conductive AFM results show &gt;3x increase in photocurrent for CB-NH2 samples at 1V bias. It is not obvious whether there is a quantitative relationship between these results and the device performance. In particular, why is the difference in (averaged) nanoscale photocurrent so much larger than the photocurrent observed at the device level? 6. There are multiple typos and a few grammatical errors throughout the manuscript. Careful proofreading is recommended before final submission. Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author): For the "Overcoming C60-induced interfacial recombination in inverted perovskite solar cells by stable electron transporting carborane", the authors introduced carborane as electron transport layer in perovskite solar cell structure. However, the manuscript lacks novelty on the use of caborane and progressive discussion of defect passivation in this study and needs further investigation and improvement of the experimental data. Therefore, this manuscript is insufficient to be published in Nature Communications. 1. Although carborane is a material that exhibits unique properties, there are more cases of perovskite solar cells applied in previous studies than the authors mentioned. Therefore, authors should add references related to perovskite photovoltaics applied with carborane. 2. It is hard to understand that the carborane did not affect the perovskite even though the carborane was deposited on top of the perovskite. Since the carborane has a great ability to absorb neutrons, the carborane can control charge flows and ion movements. As the author mentioned, if only a small amount of carborane remains on top of the perovskite, is the carborane very poorly coated on the perovskite? If coating properties are not secured, it would be a meaningful result to use a material other than CB-NH2 with an ammonium functional group. Therefore, the authors should present the special properties of carborane alone. 3. Moreover, it has been reported in previous studies that inhibition of non-radiative recombination has a great effect on Jsc as well as Voc. In this study, CB-NH2 reduced the loss occurring at the interface through defect passivation. However, defect states will also impede the flow of photogenerated charges. Why is the effect at Jsc smaller than the effect at Voc? The authors report a novel interlayer material, which helps to achieve efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. In detail, o-carborane decorated with phenylamino groups (CB-NH2) was introduced on the perovskite surface to eliminate the non-radiative recombination loss across the perovskite/C60 interface. The results are interesting although some of the claims along with the work novelty are overrated. This manuscript shows almost all the data I want to see. Therefore, I suggest accepting the manuscript after addressing the following concerns. 1. The authors introduced a novel material CB-NH2, so is it the unique advantage of CB or the amino group that plays the leading role? The authors claim that CB-NH2 can not only passivate surface defects (due to bonding effect from N-H•••I and N-Pb), but also block holes (due to the type-I band alignment). That is to say, CB-NH2 can reduce both the non-radiative recombination assisted by surface defects and the carrier quenching at the perovskite/C60 interface. Which effect contributes more to reducing VOC losses? Since the synthesized intermediates contain CB-ph and CB-NO2 (almost no bonding effect with perovskite), I wonder how they affect the device performance. 2. As type-I band alignment (as shown in Fig.  1c ), why does perovskite/CB-NH2 increase electron extraction? 3. "As shown in Fig.  2e , the stabilized current density of control and CB-NH2 treated cell are 23.73, 23.26 mA/cm2 under a bias of 0.97 and 0.91V, respectively, confirming a stabilized PCE of 23.04% and 21.10%, which are consistent with JV results." The data for control and CB-NH2 treated cell were reversed. 4. "To quantify the stability, we performed MPP tracking on the devices in a glovebox… The improved operational stability is attributed to... as well as the increased hydrophobicity and resistance to moisture." Stability results obtained in the glovebox should not be related to moisture. 5. The caption of Fig.  S15  is incorrect. In addition, the resolution of light intensity up to 0.0001 sun is incredible. Please provide the corresponding J-V curves of the devices under different light intensity in Fig  S15 . -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------Reviewer(s)' Comments to Author and the Point-to-Point Response: -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------Reviewer: 1 Recommendation: Publish after minor revisions (as noted below). Comments: This manuscript reports a novel interface passivation layer for inverted perovskite solar cells with C60 electron transport layers. C60 is by far the most widely used ETL material in inverted (pin) perovskite cells, but it is also responsible for the relatively poor voltage performance of these cells relative to nip cells. This work clearly demonstrates that nonradiative recombination at the C60/perovskite interface is the cause of this voltage loss, and demonstrates an effective solution with the functionalized carborane passivation. The passivation mechanism is carefully investigated using both experimental and theoretical (DFT) methods. The improved stability of the passivated cells with the hydrophobic interlayer is also promising. The manuscript is well written, the experimental and theoretical analysis is thorough and clearly presented, and the conclusions are well supported by the evidence. This work is likely to be of significant interest to the perovskite research community and therefore I recommend it for publication with only minor revisions as listed below: Thank you very much. We are delighted to receive such a positive feedback. 21 was cited at the following sentence in the introduction: "For example, commercially available insulating polymers (such as PMMA and PS) have been widely utilized as interlayers between the perovskite and C60 for pin-type and for nip-type PSCs  [21] [22] [23] [24]  ." 2. Line 156: "The optical energy gaps (EG) were calculated by the intersection of normalized absorption and emission spectra". This method for estimating the optical bandgap is not commonly used in perovskite literature, although it may be standard in other fields. I suggest that the authors either provide a suitable reference, or else provide a brief explanation/justification in the SI. We agree that this method is not often used for perovskites, however, it can be applied to determine the optical bandgap of organic semiconductors such as CB-NH2  6, 7  . In addition, we now use Tauc plots of the absorption spectra to estimate the bandgap of CB-NH2 (although less often employed for organic semiconductors, see ref.  8  ). The optical band gap from the Tauc plot is 3.96 eV, which is close to what we get from the intersection of normalized absorption and emission spectra (4.10 eV). We have revised the following sentence in the manuscript and added the corresponding reference: "Then optical energy gaps (EG) were calculated by the intersection of normalized absorption and emission spectra (Supplementary Fig.  S5 ), and with Tauc plots from the absorption spectra (Supplementary Fig.  S6 )  6, 7  " Supplementary Fig.  S6 . Tauc plots of the absorption spectra of CB-NH2, the optical bandgap is estimated to 3.96 eV. That's a good point. Because of technical limitations, no temperature controller was used during MPP setup. However, we monitored the temperature on the holder with an infrared sensor and we found that it is around 26 °C. We now added this information to the caption of Figure  3 . To address the question of reproducibility, we repeated the MPP measurement at the lab in Shanghai, which is in air (30% RH) and temperature at 40 °C. The result is shown below; the unencapsulated CB-NH2 based device maintains 89% of the initial PCE, compared the 79% of the control device after ~350 h of operation which is similar to the result in the manuscript. This result confirms the consistently improved stability upon addition of CB-NH2 as reported in the manuscript. We now added this result in the manuscript and the following statement: "We further confirm the improved operational stability during maximum power point tracking under 1 sun equivalent illumination with a white LED in air (30% RH) and at a temperature of 40 °C. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  S12 , the CB-NH2 devices also demonstrate a better stability under these conditions. Therefore, the improvement might be also related to the increased hydrophobicity and resistance to moisture." Supplementary Fig.  S12 . Maximum power point tracking under 1 sun illumination of CB-NH2 based and control PSCs in air (~30% RH and ~40 °C). 4. Line 333: trap densities extracted from SCLC measurements are quoted to three significant figures. Is this level of precision appropriate given sample-sample variation and the assumptions required to extract these values? We thank the reviewer for pointing this out. Indeed, according to a recent study by Le Corre and coworkers  9  as well as Siekmann and co-workers  10  , the trap density data from SCLC measurement need to be treated carefully when the electrode charge density per cell volume (CU/eV) is higher or equal to the trap density. This is typically the case for thin active layers of 500 nm.  10  We therefore decided to not specify the traps density, rather that the unipolar SCLC characteristics is in principal consistent with the improved VOC: ". As shown and discussed in Supplementary Fig.  S14 , the current in the ohmic region is smaller for the CB-NH2 based device, which could be correlated with a lower overall trap density and the improved VOC  50  . However, the measurable trap density from this experiment is limited by the electrode charge per unit cell volume, which is typically very similar to the apparent trap density in thin film (~500 nm) devices as recently shown in ref.  51, 52  " 5. Line 391: The conductive AFM results show &gt;3x increase in photocurrent for CB-NH2 samples at 1V bias. It is not obvious whether there is a quantitative relationship between these results and the device performance. In particular, why is the difference in (averaged) nanoscale photocurrent so much larger than the photocurrent observed at the device level? This is an interesting question. Although there are similarities, there are also significant differences between C-AFM and the JV measurement. First of all, we would like to note that the power of the lamp is only ~5 mW/cm 2 (not 20 mW/cm 2 as wrongfully specified in the manuscript, which is now corrected). Therefore, the produced photocurrent is less than the photocurrent under AM1.5G illumination of the solar simulator and the dark current is the dominant factor in the experiment. We have now clarified this in the main text: "In addition, the samples were illuminated with a 5 mW/cm 2 white LED to generate electron hole pairs." In any case, the tip we used for the C-AFM measurement (NSG10 with Pt coating at the tip) has a radius of only 35 nm. This strongly limits the extracted current. In addition, although the gold contact is in contact mode with the C60-terminated film, the configuration of samples measured in this experiment differs from actual device, which might influence the dynamic of the charge carriers. Therefore, we would not expect the exact same trend as in the JV. Nevertheless, the higher signal for electron extraction indicates directional transport of electrons to the top surface in both devices. In addition, the higher electron signal in the case of the CB-NH2 treated devices means a higher conductivity or lower contact resistance. Regarding the hole extraction, a slightly lower signal is observed in the CB-NH2 device consistent with the lower dark current. We have now clarified these considerations in the paper: "Note due to the low light intensity (5 mW/cm 2 ) the measurement is in essence a dark JV measurement, and the low values of the current are limited by the small radius of the tip of 35 nm. Therefore, the current signal measured from C-AFM is not comparable to JSC from JV curves." Finally, we note that this method has been used in Xu  12  and Pietro's paper  13  which are now cited in the manuscript. 6. There are multiple typos and a few grammatical errors throughout the manuscript. Careful proof-reading is recommended before final submission. Thank you, we carefully checked the whole manuscript and corrected several spelling mistakes and several sentences, for example: "The detailed synthesis, a description of the CB-NH2 molecule and additional molecular structure characterizations (such as nuclear magnetic resonance spectra) can be found in the Supporting Information." "Any improvement is surprising given the volatile nature of the CB molecule, therefore we speculate there remains a small amount on the surface." "We use a laser of 520 nm wavelength with a spot size of near 0.5 cm 2 to illuminate the samples with a 1 sun equivalent intensity by adjusting the produced current close to the JSC under a standard solar simulator." "In addition, electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements were performed to characterize the charge carrier recombination at open circuit conditions (≈1 V)." Reviewer: 2 Recommendation: insufficient to be published (as noted below). Comments: For the "Overcoming C60-induced interfacial recombination in inverted perovskite solar cells by stable electron transporting carborane", the authors introduced carborane as electron transport layer in perovskite solar cell structure. However, the manuscript lacks novelty on the use of caborane and progressive discussion of defect passivation in this study and needs further investigation and improvement of the experimental data. Therefore, this manuscript is insufficient to be published in Nature Communications. We thank the reviewer for the feedback, however, we disagree with the statement of insufficient novelty, because it is the first time that a carborane based material was applied as electron-selective and passivation layer in perovskites photovoltaics and this particular molecule was never used in any other electronic device. In light of the reviewer comments, we have now improved the discussion of the defect passivation and the interpretation of the experimental data. For example, we further verified the importance of carborane moiety by studying the performance of a phenyl substituted carborane (CB-ph) without the amino group as demonstrated below. We hope that these changes the manuscript will persuade the reviewer to accept the paper. 1. Although carborane is a material that exhibits unique properties, there are more cases of perovskite solar cells applied in previous studies than the authors mentioned. Therefore, authors should add references related to perovskite photovoltaics applied with carborane. We thank the reviewer for bringing this to our attention. Unfortunately, we actually overlooked one paper where a CB-derivate was used as a part of the hole transporting layer (HTL), however with a different functional group (N,N-bis(4-methoxyphenyl)aniline). The applications of this molecule led to an improved device performance due to an improved FF which was attributed to better carrier transport at the HTL side. We have now cited this paper as ref.  14  However, our work is the first time that a carborane based material is applied as electron/selective passivation layer and this derivate has never been reported before. We focus on the electron transport properties, passivation ability, and elimination of C60-induced interfacial non-radiative recombination, which are unique features of our CB-NH2 based devices that have not been previously reported. Finally, we also found another interesting paper where the electron-accepting properties of carborane are discussed which is now cited in the main text  15  : "They are also tunable as one can functionalize these molecules with various functional groups to tune the electronic structure and other properties of interest  29, 30  . Furthermore, they have previously been used in light-emitting diodes  31, 32  and as building block of hole transporting materials in PSCs to improve the charge transfer rate  33  ." 2. It is hard to understand that the carborane did not affect the perovskite even though the carborane was deposited on top of the perovskite. Since the carborane has a great ability to absorb neutrons, the carborane can control charge flows and ion movements. To address the question whether the perovskite can be affected by the CB-NH2, we first compared the crystallinity and morphology with/without CB-NH2, we have compared the absorbance of films with and without CB-NH2 which did not reveal significant changes in the bulk properties as seen from the absorbance spectra (new Supplementary Fig.  S10 ). Also, no obvious difference was found from the XRD measurement (Supplementary Fig.  S11 ). These results are expected because we use a very low concentration so that the CB-NH2 layer is very thin (a few nm). However, the PLQY and PL lifetime of perovskite films were remarkably improved upon coating carborane derivatives, as shown in Figure  4a  and Supplementary Fig.  S14 . Moreover, we detect the presence of B signal in the CB-NH2 treated perovskite surface by XPS (Supplementary Fig.  S23 ) and the variation of binding energy for the Pb signal, which prove the influence of CB-NH2 on the electronic properties of perovskite surface. Regarding the flow of charges and mobile ions as mentioned by the reviewer. Indeed, our experimental results reveal significant changes in the charge transport, for example the suppression of non-radiative recombination and differences in the extraction of electrons in C60-terminated partial cell stacks with C-AFM. Regarding the impact of mobile ions, although we also agree that the presence of CB-NH2 at the perovskite surface can also impact the movement of mobile ions and the ion induced losses, we believe that this is outside the scope of the present study which focuses on the impact on non-radiative recombination and stability. 2. As the author mentioned, if only a small amount of carborane remains on top of the perovskite, is the carborane very poorly coated on the perovskite? If coating properties are not secured, it would be a meaningful result to use a material other than CB-NH2 with an ammonium functional group. Therefore, the authors should present the special properties of carborane alone. This is a good and important point. It is important to note that the carborane unit is of particular importance in our materials design. Different from many other reported interfacial passivation materials, the carborane derivatives exhibit good electron-transporting properties due to the unique three-dimensional aromaticity. This allows to maintain a high electron transfer across this interface while minimizing interfacial non-radiative recombination through better hole blocking as a result of the deep HOMO level. Unfortunately, as stated in the manuscript, the unmodified carborane undergoes obvious sublimation during annealing and reduced pressure. We speculate that is due to the weak intermolecular forces. To tackle this problem, we attached the phenylamino group to the carborane molecule to increase the intermolecular force and the adsorption to the Pb-terminated (Pbrich) surface. As such, after incorporation of the phenyl amino group, the film formation and thermal and device stability are greatly enhanced. We note the coating of CB-NH2 is secured as proven by the presence of Boron on the surface in XPS (Supplementary Fig.  S23 ). Moreover, the amine group passivates surface defects. Therefore, the carborane moiety and amino group are working synergistically and are indispensable. Finally, we note that compared to literature, CB-NH2 outperforms similar passivating molecules. For example, Yang et al. had used a phenethylamine as passivation layer between perovskite and C60, similar to the functional phenylamine group in CB-NH2, which however did not result in an improved FF compared to the control device.  20  This is likely related to the insulating properties of phenethylamine which restricts the transport of major carriers. We also conduced additional PLQY measurements on partial cell stacks to evaluate the effect of CBph on the non-radiative recombination process. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  S22  below, for the ITO/HTL/pero/C60 stack, we notice a ~10 mV improvement in the quasi-Fermi level splitting, but for the ITO/HTL/pero stack, we did not see any difference with and without CB-ph. This confirms the ability of carborane to reduce non-radiative recombination between perovskite and C60 without the amino group. However, the unchanged QFLS for ITO/HTL/pero stack indicates that there is no passivation effect from carborane. This is in contrast to the CB-NH2 molecules which also passivate the perovskite surface. Supplementary Fig.  S22 . Photoluminescence spectrum and the calculated photoluminescence quantum yield measurements (PLQY) and internal quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) with/without CB-ph. Overall, the results suggest that there is some contribution of the improved hole blocking to the total VOC gain with the CB-NH2 functionalized device (50 mV), although the effect of the amino group is more significant. As for the FF improvement, our results indicate a similar improvement between CBph and CB-NH2, which suggests that the improvement originates from the hole blocking and electron extraction ability of the CB molecule. We have now included this discussion in a new section in the revised manuscript: "Contribution to device performance from carborane and amino moiety. In order to investigate the contribution from the carborane and amino group moiety in CB-NH2 to the improvement of device performance, we also studied the intermediate phenyl functionalized carborane (CB-ph) without the amino group because the bare carborane suffers from sublimation on the perovskite layer. As can been seen in Supplementary Fig.  S21 , CB-ph leads to a significant FF improvement (~2%) but only slight VOC improvement (~10 mV), indicating that the carborane alone reduces non-radiative recombination less effectively than CB-NH2 but has a significant effect on the electron extraction which is consistent with the C-AFM result. This conclusion can be further confirmed by the improved PLQY of the ITO/perovskite/C60 stack with the CB-ph interlayer but identical PLQY of the ITO/perovskite with and without the CB-ph interlayer (Supplementary Fig.  S22 ). These results suggest that there is a small contribution (~10 mV) of the carborane moiety to the total VOC gain of the CB-NH2 functionalized device (~50 mV) which we attribute to the improved hole blocking ability of the carborane. However, the effect of the amino group is more significant. As for the FF improvement, our results indicate a more significant contribution of the carborane moiety (~2%) to the total gain (~4%), which suggests that the improvement originates partially from the hole blocking and electron extraction ability of the CB molecule. Nevertheless, considering that the packing and adsorption ability of the CB-ph and the CB-NH2 molecules are likely different, the exact contribution of the carborane moiety is difficult to quantify. Given that the performance of the CB-NH2 device is optimum, we can conclude that the carborane and the amino group are working synergistically and are indispensable. " 3. Moreover, it has been reported in previous studies that inhibition of non-radiative recombination has a great effect on Jsc as well as Voc. In this study, CB-NH2 reduced the loss occurring at the interface through defect passivation. However, defect states will also impede the flow of photogenerated charges. Why is the effect at Jsc smaller than the effect at Voc? Here we respectfully disagree with the reviewer. Although, non-radiative recombination can in principal effect the JSC, as long as the JV curve is flat until the maximum power point, an impact of nonradiative recombination is not expected. Only at the point where the current starts to decrease (at forward bias voltages close to the maximum power point). The simulation based on the model described in the work by Diekmann et al.  21  shows the impact of a 10-fold reduced density at the perovskite/C60 interface compared to the control, Figure  R1 . In panel b, the corresponding recombination current are shown for both cases, passivated and control. It can be seen that the recombination currents, in particular the interfacial recombination, are strongly voltage dependent and increase with applied forward bias. We note, that bulk recombination can be more independent with voltage in case of nearly flat energy bands under short-circuit conditions. In this case, nonradiative recombination can be significant at 0V, however, an optimization of the interface, as it was done in this work, will not affect these bulk losses. Reviewer: 3 Recommendation: Publish after addressing the following concerns &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29027</offset>
      <text> Comments: The authors report a novel interlayer material, which helps to achieve efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. In detail, o-carborane decorated with phenylamino groups (CB-NH2) was introduced on the perovskite surface to eliminate the non-radiative recombination loss across the perovskite/C60 interface. The results are interesting although some of the claims along with the work novelty are overrated. This manuscript shows almost all the data I want to see. Therefore, I suggest accepting the manuscript after addressing the following concerns. We thank the reviewer for the critical feedback and the recommendation to publish our work. 1. The authors introduced a novel material CB-NH2, so is it the unique advantage of CB or the amino group that plays the leading role? The authors claim that CB-NH2 can not only passivate surface defects (due to bonding effect from N-H•••I and N-Pb), but also block holes (due to the type-I band alignment). That is to say, CB-NH2 can reduce both the non-radiative recombination assisted by surface defects and the carrier quenching at the perovskite/C60 interface. Which effect contributes more to reducing VOC losses? Since the synthesized intermediates contain CB-ph and CB-NO2 (almost no bonding effect with perovskite), I wonder how they affect the device performance. We thank the reviewer for raising this important point. The reviewer is correct that we interpret the improved performance with the CB-NH2 functionalization based on the synergistic working mechanism of the carborane moiety and the amino group, where the former passivates defects, while the latter improves the hole blocking due to the deep HOMO energy level, while providing sufficient electron transport (in contrast to many other commonly used molecules). We note that this important comment also goes back to comment 2 of Reviewer 2 which has been addressed above. Briefly again, in order to understand the relative impact of the carborane moiety without the amino group as suggested by the reviewer, we fabricated a phenyl functionalized carborane molecules (CB-ph without the amino group) and carefully compared the JV performance metric and PLQY with the control devices. We studied the CB-ph instead of the bare carborane as the latter suffers from the problem of sublimation, thus the film quality is not secured. As shown above in response to Reviewer 2, the JV and PLQY results (Supplementary Fig.  S21  and S22 ) suggest that there is some contribution (~10%) of the improved hole blocking due carborane moiety to the total VOC gain with the CB-NH2 functionalized device (~50 mV), although the effect of the amino group is more significant. As for the FF improvement, our results indicate a similar improvement between CB-ph and CB-NH2, which suggests that the improvement originates from the hole blocking and electron extraction ability of the CB molecule. We have also included these considerations in in a new section in the revised manuscript. Lastly, regarding the CB-NO2 molecule mentioned by the reviewer, we actually also tried this molecule, however, the performance was strongly negatively affected (Figure  R2 ). We believe that this is due to the NO2 which has been linked to increasing recombination in previous works. 2. As type-I band alignment (as shown in Fig.  1c ), why does perovskite/CB-NH2 increase electron extraction? We thank the reviewer for raising this interesting question. Although the C-AFM does show an improved electron extraction the underlying mechanism is not clear. First, we note that the energy level depicted in Figure  1c  represent the energy levels measured on individual layers, therefore we expect the energy alignment in the device to be different. Apart from the exact energy alignment at the interface, we believe a plausible explanation for the improved electron extraction observed in the C-AFM measurement might stem from reduced defect density at the interface as trapped electrons can repel the extraction of following electrons. Evidence for the reduced trap states is provided in the manuscript, for example from the PLQY and JV results, while the FF of the CB-NH2 treated device is also improved which is consistent with the improved electron extraction. We now, included this possible interpretation in the manuscript. In addition, we also measured ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) of the perovskite/C60 (thickness from 1nm to 30 nm) film with/without CB-NH2. As shown in Figure  R3  below, with increasing C60 thickness up to 30 nm, we observed a significant upwards bend banding in the C60 layer in the control sample, which can be explained and modelled by a n-doped perovskite surface. In contrast, in the perovskite/CB-NH2/C60 films, we did not detect obvious energy level offset on thin and thick C60 samples. Moreover, CB-NH2 raises the conduction band of the perovskite which better aligns with the perovskite bulk energy level. We note that the perovskite energy levels only represent the energetics at the surface of the perovskite accessible to UPS, thus not representative of the bulk. Although, the interpretation of these results is still ongoing and thus not presented in the main text, these results may provide further clues as to why CB-NH2 improves the electron transporting. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34351</offset>
      <text> Figure R3 . Energy alignment at the perovskite C60 interface as deduced from ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) of films with a variable C60 thickness. The graph demonstrates a significant flattening of the C60 bend bending in case of CB-NH2 which could be linked to the better charge extraction although further investigations are required towards a quantitative description of the interfacial energy levels. We note, the perovskite energy levels only represent the energetics at the surface of the perovskite accessible to UPS, thus not representative of the bulk. We agree with the reviewer that this measurement does not allow us to conclude about the benefit of the increase hydrophobicity on the stability of the devices and we have now removed the conflicting sentence from the manuscript. In light of comment 3 from Reviewer 1, we also performed another maximum power point tracking measurement of devices outside the glovebox in air with a relative humidly of ~30% RH and a temperature of ~40 °C. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  S12 , the encapsulated CB-NH2 is more stable than the control device which strongly points to the benefit of a more hydrophilic interface for the device stability. We thank the reviewer for pointing out this mistake which we have now corrected. We note that Supplementary Fig.  S15  (Supplementary Fig.  S19  in revised Supplementary Information) only shows the VOC as a function of light intensity, which we measure by continuously decreasing the intensity using an automated filter wheel as shown below (Figure  R4 ). For each intensity we measure VOC for ~2 seconds before measuring the JSC for the same time (JSC not plotted in this graph). Then the filter wheel is moved to the next position and the routine is repeated. We have now provided experimental details in the Methods section. We also note that although, these measurements where conducted by measuring VOC and JSC only, we can also measure the full JV curves over the same intensity range with the same setup. I appreciate the significant effort by the authors to address my comments and those of the other reviewers. The responses and manuscript amendments adequately address all of the points raised in my previous review, so I am happy to recommend the mansucript for publication without further changes. Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author): The authors prepared to response the reviewers' questions by faithfully performing additional experiments requested by the reviewers. The manuscript has improved in the first review round. However, the material effect of carborane is still not clear and the novelty seems pretty lack. Many previous studies have reported an increase in Voc due to penetration of PCBM and C60 along the grain boundaries of the perovskite. It is thought that the carborane in this study will also have the effect of increasing the interface by the carborane infiltrating along the grain boundary as in the previous study. Since the mobility of electrons is affected by the difference in electron affinity between C60 and carborane, it is recommended to check electron deflection through DFT simulation. Also, reviewers doubt whether it is difficult to drive the carborane on its own without the C60. It is expected that the effects of carborane, which the authors mention, can replace as well as supplement the C60. The reviewer is wondering if the perovskite device with only carborane as thick as C60, which has secured coating, works. Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author): The authors have addressed my previous concern, and therefore I recommend its publication in Nature Communications. - --------------------------------------------------------------------------- Point-by-point Response to Reviewer(s)' Comments: ---------------------------------------------------------------------------- Reviewer: 1 I appreciate the significant effort by the authors to address my comments and those of the other reviewers. The responses and manuscript amendments adequately address all of the points raised in my previous review, so I am happy to recommend the manuscript for publication without further changes. We are delighted to receive such a positive feedback, thank you very much. Reviewer: 2 The authors prepared to response the reviewers' questions by faithfully performing additional experiments requested by the reviewers. The manuscript has improved in the first review round. We appreciate that the reviewer acknowledges our efforts with the last revision. However, the material effect of carborane is still not clear and the novelty seems pretty lack. Many previous studies have reported an increase in Voc due to penetration of PCBM and C60 along the grain boundaries of the perovskite.It is thought that the carborane in this study will also have the effect of increasing the interface by the carborane infiltrating along the grain boundary as in the previous study We would like to note that the observed improvement of the device performance is not related to the penetration of the grain boundaries with PCBM, or C60 nor increasing the interface [area?] by the infiltration of carborane along the grain boundaries. In fact, we would disagree with both of these implied conclusions of the reviewer. Compared to the neat perovskite with its grain boundaries, we have consistently shown that the deposition of C60 and PCBM actually lowers the open-circuit voltage potential or quasi-Fermi level splitting  [1] [2] [3]  . This is due to interfacial recombination losses which greatly outweigh the recombination at the grain boundaries and at the perovskite surface. A large fraction of the community now agrees on this general conclusion  [4] [5] [6]  . We also disagree with the postulation that carborane increases the interfacial area thereby reducing recombination, not least because the interface area needs to be reduced to have a positive effect. As highlighted before, the positive synergic effect of the here functionalized carborane CB-NH2 as an exemplary molecule of a novel class of electron transport layers for various optoelectronic perovskite devices is to block the holes from the C60-interface via its deep HOMO level and by passivating traps on the neat perovskite while maintaining a high electron extraction rate. To proof these points we have provided substantial additional data during the last revision which leads to different conclusions than suggested by the reviewer. Therefore, in our opinion, these reviewer's comments do not challenge the novelty of our paper. Since the mobility of electrons is affected by the difference in electron affinity between C60 and carborane, it is recommended to check electron deflection through DFT simulation. We would like to point out that electron mobility is independent of the energy levels and is thus not related to different electron affinity between C60 and carborane. The relatively high LUMO of the carborane may reduce the (effective) electron conductivity in the C60 layer in the device by allowing less charges through. However, as we have demonstrated with selective conductive AFMmeasurements, this is not the case experimentally for a thin layer of CB-NH2 as the extraction of electrons through the C60 is actually improved with respect to C60-only as shown by conductive AFM. As noted before, this could be related to the reduced defect density at the surface as trapped electrons could repel the extraction of the remaining ones. Moreover, our UPS measurements shown in the last rebuttal letter indicate a better energy alignment between the perovskite and C60 with the carborane. Finally, regarding the suggestion to check the "electron deflection" with DFT simulation, we have discussed this internally but unfortunately we do not know what was meant with electron deflection. We believe that our DFT simulations already provide substantial additional evidence of the strong adsorption of the CB-NH2 layer on the perovskite surface and the passivation effect of the amino moiety. Therefore, we do not think that more DFT simulations will provide further insights at this point. Also, reviewers doubt whether it is difficult to drive the carborane on its own without the C60. It is expected that the effects of carborane, which the authors mention, can replace as well as supplement the C60. The reviewer is wondering if the perovskite device with only carborane as thick as C60, which has secured coating, works. Although we agree with the reviewer that it would be indeed nice to be able to entirely replace the C60 with a carborane, we have not claimed to do so with this particular carborane in this paper, rather we employ it as a thin interlayer as stated in the manuscript. To address the reviewer comment, we prepared a batch of devices to replace C60 with a thicker layer of CB-NH2, which however showed poorer performance. We believe that this is due to the still lower mobility of the carboranes compared to C60. Nevertheless, it is important to point out that carboranes are highly tuneable allowing to attach various functionalized groups, which will undoubtedly allow to tailor the properties of this exciting class of molecules. Notwithstanding this point, this manuscript clearly demonstrates various other beneficial properties of the CB-NH2 molecules, which already allows to essentially overcome the C60induced interfacial recombination, which has been a major limiting factor of pin-type cells. Reviewer: 3 The authors have addressed my previous concern, and therefore I recommend its publication in Nature Communications. We thank the reviewer for the recommendation to publish our work. Inverted perovskite solar cells still suffer from significant non-radiative recombination losses at the perovskite surface and across the perovskite/C 60 interface, limiting the future development of perovskite-based single-and multi-junction photovoltaics. Therefore, more effective inter-or transport layers are urgently required. To tackle these recombination losses, we introduce ortho-carborane as an interlayer material that has a spherical molecular structure and a three-dimensional aromaticity. Based on a variety of experimental techniques, we show that ortho-carborane decorated with phenylamino groups effectively passivates the perovskite surface and essentially eliminates the non-radiative recombination loss across the perovskite/C 60 interface with high thermal stability. We further demonstrate the potential of carborane as an electron transport material, facilitating electron extraction while blocking holes from the interface. The resulting inverted perovskite solar cells deliver a power conversion efficiency of over 23% with a low non-radiative voltage loss of 110 mV, and retain &gt;97% of the initial efficiency after 400 h of maximum power point tracking. Overall, the designed carborane based interlayer simultaneously enables passivation, electron-transport and hole-blocking and paves the way toward more efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Perovskite-based tandem solar cells are almost exclusively based on inverted (pin-type) perovskite cells due to their thin charge transport layers (nm to tens of nm) and absence of high-temperature treatments during fabrication (below 100 °C)  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8]  . Thus, improving the performance of these pin-type devices is an important task as this is where perovskites will likely enter the market for renewable energy generation. For record-level pin-type cells it has been shown that the voltage loss is governed by the top electron transport layer (e.g., C 60 or PCBM), and this is quite irrespective of the involved perovskite composition (Fig.  1a ). However, the non-radiative recombination at the perovskite/C 60 interface and the involved defect states remain fundamentally poorly understood  [9] [10] [11] [12]  . predominantly across the interface  12  , likely due to a small energy level offset between the conduction band minimum of the perovskite and the lowest unoccupied molecular orbital (LUMO) level of C 60 13   , or charge transfer states at the interface  12, 14  . Thus, it is critical to improve the energy alignment, passivate defects on the perovskite surface or repel minority carriers from the interface. However, to our knowledge, up to now, no study has been able to entirely suppress the interfacial recombination in the presence of the C 60 layer. Notwithstanding this point, there have been many attempts to reduce recombination at the perovskite surface and across the perovskite/transport layer interfaces. Noteworthy for nip-structured perovskite solar cells (PSCs), Sutuanto et al.  15  showed that the implementation of a two-dimensional (2D) layer (~50 nm thick) on the perovskite surface essentially eliminates the interfacial recombination by preventing minority carriers from reaching the interface between Spiro-OMeTAD and the perovskite. This is due to the nearly lossless interface between the 3D and 2D perovskites and the appreciable thickness of the 2D perovskite layer, which physically separates electrons and holes, thus reducing interface recombination. Indeed, the use of 2D/3D perovskites at the top interface in nip cells is very prevalent and enabled high open-circuit voltages (V OC s)  [16] [17] [18]  . It, therefore, follows that a similar hole-blocking layer for pin cells should lead to reduced voltage losses, however, given the opposite charge polarity, the implementation of these 2D/3D layers in pin-type cells has been challenging. Nevertheless, the formation of 2D wide gap perovskites was recently demonstrated in several publications via phenethylammonium (PEA)based molecules which improved the V OC of pin-type perovskite cells  [19] [20] [21]   ) dissolved in isopropanol or toluene  22, 23  . Employed as a surface treatment, these molecules form a thin lead oxysalt layer (PbSO 4 and Pb 3 (PO 4 ) 2 ) on the perovskite surface, which can stabilize under-coordinated bonds on the perovskite surface and improve the stability (T 80 lifetimes of over 1000 h at 65 °C were reported)  22  . Despite this success, the long-term stability of 2D layers remains a concern, for example, due to the possible interdiffusion and mixing of the 2D/3D perovskite layers as discussed in a previous work  24  . Alternatively, some insulating layers were used to reduce the interfacial recombination without the concern of interdiffusion. For example, commercially available insulating polymers (such as PMMA and PS) have been utilized as interlayers between the perovskite and C 60 for pin-type and for nip-type PSCs  [25] [26] [27] [28]  . Moreover, the inorganic insulator LiF has been found effective at reducing the non-radiative recombination loss at the interface for various perovskite systems via the formation of a surface dipole that facilitates the extraction of electrons  9, 29  . However, it should be noted that LiF/C 60 still reduces the photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) of the neat layer by a factor of ~10 in the case of triple-cation perovskites, and again there are concerns regarding the long-term stability  29, 30  . Generally, the application of insulating layers leads to the formation of a tunneling contact. However, the application of intrinsically insulating layers limits the ability to block minority charges without compromising the charge transport and thus fill factor (FF) performance. In addition, insulating layers may also cause a loss of the V OC as their low conductivity can lead to a gradient in the quasi-Fermi level of majority charges, resulting in a mismatch between internal and external V OC ("quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS)-V OC " mismatch)  [30] [31] [32]  . This is, for example, observed when increasing the thickness of a PMMA interlayer (Supplementary Figs.  1  and 2 ). Thus, an effective and highly selective electron transport layer requires good hole-blocking properties and good electron transport capacities to simultaneously increase the FF and V OC . In this regard, carboranes are an interesting class of spherical molecules with three-dimensional aromaticity, which are potential electron-transporting materials but have not yet been explored in the field of PSCs. These molecules are composed of carbon, boron, and hydrogen and often form polyhedrons. Polyhedral and spherical molecules with delocalized π-orbitals are ideal for thin film organic transport layers due to their omnidirectional charge transport. They are also tunable as one can functionalize these molecules with various functional groups to tune the electronic structure and other properties of interest  33, 34  . Furthermore, they have previously been used in light-emitting diodes  35, 36  and as building block of hole-transporting materials in PSCs to improve the charge transfer rate  37  . Herein, we introduced ortho-carborane (CB, C 2 B 10 H 12 ) as an interfacial layer in low-gap triple-cation pin-based PSCs to assist electron extraction and reduce across interface non-radiative recombination. We demonstrate the electron transport potential of functionalized caboranes. We additionally investigated CB functionalized by phenylamino groups (CB-NH 2 ), which are Lewis bases that are reported to passivate perovskite surface defects. Besides, carborane exhibits a large ionization potential thus, it is effective at blocking holes when employed as a selective transport layer. It is also hydrophobic, which effectively improves the water resistance of the perovskite device. Using CB-NH 2 as an interlayer we achieve a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of over 23% with low non-radiative voltage losses of 110 mV, in pin single junctions, and the PCE retains over 97% of its initial value after 400 h operation under maximum power point (MPP) conditions at 1-sun illumination and room temperature. A variety of experimental investigations indicate that CB-NH 2 can overcome the long-standing C 60 -induced interfacial recombination in inverted PSCs. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ortho-carborane</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:17:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="44376" length="15"/>
        <text>ortho-carborane</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenylamino groups</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:18:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="44587" length="18"/>
        <text>phenylamino groups</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">97</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T02:54:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="45098" length="2"/>
        <text>97</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">400</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:18:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="45134" length="5"/>
        <text>400 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ortho-carborane</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:20:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="51222" length="2"/>
        <text>CB</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ortho-carborane</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:20:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="51226" length="13"/>
        <text>C 2 B 10 H 12</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenylamino groups</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:27:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="51520" length="18"/>
        <text>phenylamino groups</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenylamino groups</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:21:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="51540" length="7"/>
        <text>CB-NH 2</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52353</offset>
      <text> Results &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>52363</offset>
      <text> Molecular synthesis and energy levels of carborane O-carborane is commercially available, however, due to its low molecular weight in combination with weak intermolecular forces it has a low sublimation temperature under reduced pressure. This limits its use as an ETL because the thin films can evaporate under high vacuum during the completion of the device (e.g., evaporation of metal electrodes). We therefore chose to synthesize a derivative of o-carborane to increase its molecular weight and further modify its electronic/ passivation properties. We target a phenylamine functionalized o-carborane (structure Fig.  1b , CB-NH 2 henceforth) to raise the LUMO by increased conjugation, and reduce electronic traps from previously mentioned DOS broadening via the Lewis base lone pairs on the primary amines  [38] [39] [40] [41]  . The direct addition of functional groups on the carbon sites of o-carborane is very challenging. We, therefore, started the molecular synthesis (Supplementary Fig.  3 ) from dodecahydro-arachno-bis(acatonitrile)decaborane which is available commercially. An electrophilic addition reaction with diphenylacetylene was employed to yield phenyl functionalized CB (in short CB-ph). The amino functionalization of the phenylene group was achieved by an initial nitrification and subsequent reduction reaction to yield CB-NH 2 . The detailed synthesis, a description of the CB-NH 2 molecule and additional molecular structure characterizations (such as nuclear magnetic resonance spectra) can be found in the Supplementary Note 1, and Supplementary Figs.  4 5 6 7 . To estimate the energy levels of highest occupied and lowest unoccupied molecular orbitals (HOMO/LUMO), we employed cyclic voltammetry (CV) to measure the reduction potential (LUMO energy levels, Supplementary Fig.  8 ). Then optical energy gaps (E G ) were calculated by the intersection of normalized absorption and emission spectra (Supplementary Fig.  9 ), and with Tauc plots of the absorption spectra (Supplementary Fig.  10 )  42, 43  . Finally, the HOMO energy levels were obtained by subtracting the LUMO energy level from the E G (Supplementary Table  1 ). As shown in Fig.  1c , the CB-NH 2 has different energetics from CB. As predicted, the functionalized phenylamine groups in conjugation with the carborane core significantly raise the HOMO/ LUMO levels. Further in Fig.  1c , we compare the measured energetics with those of FAPbI 3 and C 60 where we observe the much deeper HOMO of the carboranes than C 60 . This should improve its hole-blocking ability as predicted. The energy levels of the perovskite and the electron and hole transport layers (details below) were obtained from photoemission yield spectroscopy and referred from literature  30  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55130</offset>
      <text> Electron transport properties of CB-NH 2 To evaluate the electron-transporting potential of carborane, we measured electron mobility of CB-NH 2 via the space-charge limited current (SCLC) method and compared it with C 60 . We used the following configuration for the electron-only device ITO/ZnO/CB-NH 2 (100 nm) or C 60 (200 nm)/BCP/Ag, which precluded the ability to also assess the electron mobility of CB due to the previously mentioned volatility. As shown in Fig.  1d , the CB-NH 2 device exhibits textbook-like SCLC behavior with a clear slope variation from 0-3 V. Using the Mott-Gurney equation of J = 9ε r ε 0 μ(V app -V bi ) 2 /8L 3 , where V app the applied field and V bi the built-in voltage, ε 0 is the vacuum permittivity (8.85 × 10 -12 F m -1 ), ε r (3.5) is the dielectric constant, and L is the device thickness, the voltage-dependent mobility can be extracted in the SCLC region. As plotted in the inset picture in Fig.  1d , both the CB-NH 2 and C 60 device reveals the SCLC region (&gt;1 V). This allows us to extract a mobility of 7.3 × 10 -4 cm 2 V -1 s -1 for CB-NH 2 , which is one order of magnitude lower than that of C 60 (6.7 × 10 -3 cm 2 V -1 s -1 ). When compared to other non-fullerene organic transport materials from the literature, the mobility of CB-NH 2 is middling  44, 45  . Nevertheless, when compared to commonly applied interlayer materials such as the widely used Lewis bases (PEAI) and the polymers PS, PMMA, which are basically insulating materials, the electron-transporting capability of CB-NH 2 is comparatively high. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56704</offset>
      <text> Solar cell fabrication and photovoltaic performance We then applied CB and CB-NH 2 as hole-blocking layers in pin-structured triple-cation PSCs using Cs 0.05 (MA 0.05 FA 0.95 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 with an optical bandgap of 1.56 eV as shown from the derivative of the external quantum efficiency (EQE) in the Supplementary Fig.  11 . The full device structure was ITO/MeO-2PACz/perovskite/carborane interlayer/C 60 /BCP/Ag. The CB-based interlayers were implemented by spin coating a diluted solution (1 mg/mL in chlorobenzene) on top of the perovskite. Further methods are presented in the Methods. Figure  2a-c  show the PV parameter distribution of the control, CB and CB-NH 2 -treated solar cells (over 14 cells for each type). The best control cell delivered a PCE of 21.5%, with a V OC of 1.128 V, a J SC of 23.52 mA cm -2 , and an FF of 81.15%. This provides us with a good starting point for further interfacial improvements and pursuing record-level efficiency. When introducing the CB as an interlayer, we find that the V OC remains unchanged, while there is a statistical improvement in fill factor (FF) and short-circuit current (J SC ). The best CB-based devices exhibit a slightly lower V OC of 1.120 V, with a J SC of 23.77 mA cm -2 , and an FF of 81.68%, which represents only a small improvement compared to the control device. Any improvement is surprising given the volatile nature of the CB molecule, therefore we speculate there remains a small amount on the surface. The introduction of CB-NH 2 has a far more profound effect on the device parameters. The JV curves of the best-performing cells with and without CB-NH 2 are shown Fig.  2d . The champion CB-NH 2 treated cell exhibit a PCE of 23.05%, with a high voltage of 1.170 V for the given bandgap of the absorber (1.56 eV) and a small hysteresis at a scan speed of 20 mV/s as shown in Supplementary Fig.  12 . Based on the EQE spectrum (Supplementary Fig.  13 ), we calculated the radiative recombination current in the dark (J 0,rad ), which corresponds to a radiative V OC limit of 1.28 eV. Therefore, the non-radiative voltage losses are approximately 110 mV. This is among the smallest V OC deficits for pinstructured cells, with only few reports that achieved even smaller voltage losses  23, 46, 47  . We also measured the steady-state power output (SPO) of the devices at their MPP voltage for 600 s. As shown in Fig.  2e , the stabilized current density of CB-NH 2 treated and control devices are 23.73, 23.26 mA/cm 2 at a bias of 0.97 and 0.91 V, respectively, confirming a stabilized PCE of 23.04% and 21.10%, which are consistent with JV results. We note that there was a PCE drop in the initial 10 s for both devices, which is likely due to current losses related to ion movement in the perovskite absober  48, 49  . We also note that the integrated current density from the EQE spectrum matches well with the JV results (Fig.  2f ). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs0.05(MA0.05FA0.95)0.95Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:22:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="56855" length="53"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 (MA 0.05 FA 0.95 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.05</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:23:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="58426" length="6"/>
        <text>23.05%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.170</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:23:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="58457" length="7"/>
        <text>1.170 V</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59637</offset>
      <text> Passivation and device operational stabilities Highly motivated by the excellent performance improvements rendered by the CB-NH 2 interlayer, we proceeded to quantify the deviceand passivation stability. We first confirmed that the CB-NH 2 molecules do not change the absorption spectrum of the perovskite layer therefore unlikely to alter the perovskite bulk properties (Supplementary Fig.  14 ). We then performed water contact angle measurements to evaluate the influence of CB-NH 2 on the surface properties of perovskite. A larger water contact angle of 75°was determined for the CB-NH 2 coated perovskite film, in comparison to the 41°of the bare perovskite (Fig.  3a ). The hydrophobicity of the carborane is beneficial for protecting perovskite from the ingress of moisture. Thermal stability is another concern for various interfacial passivation materials. We note that carboranes are regarded as thermally stable molecules that have been used as a building block for high-temperature-resistant materials  50  . A previous study has proven that the passivation effect of PEAI, one of the most popular passivation materials, deteriorates at elevated temperatures, causing decreased V OC in devices as a result of the formation of the 2D phase  51  . Similarly, LiF has also been suggested to negatively influence device stability  29  . We, therefore, compared CB-NH 2 with these two widely used materials at elevated temperatures (50 °C to 100 °C), and measured the PLQY variation to assess the "passivation stability". As shown in Fig.  3b , the CB-NH 2 coated perovskite sample shows the highest initial PLQY value, indicating an effective passivation of defects. At higher temperatures, the PLQY values of all samples decreases, e.g., the PEAI sample retains only 27% of its initial value, and this value for LiF sample is 41.2%. For comparison, the CB-NH 2 coated film demonstrates a smaller decline, retaining 74% of its initial PLQY. Moreover, we noticed that after cooling down to room temperature, the PLQY of PEAI and LiF samples remained at a similar value as at 100 °C, indicating an irreversible process, while the CB-NH 2 sample almost returned to its initial value. We noted that no new diffraction peak was detected in the CB-NH 2 sample after annealing, indicating neither the molecule nor any degradation product entered the perovskite and no 2D phase was formed (Supplementary Fig.  15 ). To quantify the stability, we performed MPP tracking on the devices in a glovebox using a white-light-emitting diode (LED) without UV at 26 °C. The devices comprising CB-NH 2 maintained over 97% of the initial PCE (Fig.  3c ) under MPP and 1-sun equivalent illumination for 400 h, indicating superb operational stability. In contrast, the control sample retains 89% of its initial efficiency over the same time. The improved operational stability is attributed to effective passivation, which reduces the surface reactivity and retards the degradation rate. We further confirm the improved operational stability during maximum power point tracking under 1-sun equivalent illumination with a white LED in air (30% RH) and at a temperature of 40 °C. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  16 , the CB-NH 2 devices also demonstrate better stability under these conditions, thus the improvement might be related to the increased hydrophobicity and resistance to moisture. f Incident photon-to-current conversion efficiency and the integrated current density results of CB-NH 2 treated and control cells. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">89</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T02:54:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="62417" length="3"/>
        <text>89%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">30</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:25:31Z</infon>
        <location offset="62764" length="3"/>
        <text>30%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">40</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T12:25:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="62796" length="5"/>
        <text>40 °C</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63204</offset>
      <text> Suppression of perovskite/C 60 interfacial recombination To understand the simultaneous improvement of the FF and the V OC in case of CB-NH 2 , we first employed PLQY measurements to analyze the non-radiative recombination in perovskite films, multilayer partial cell stacks, and complete PSCs. Given that it is a non-contact technique, PLQY characterization allows one to decouple the contribution of every layer/interface to the non-radiative recombination loss. We measured different partial cell stacks and compared the results with complete devices to enable insights into the working mechanism of CB-NH 2 . We use a laser of 520 nm wavelength with a spot size of near 0.5 cm 2 to illuminate the samples with a 1-sun equivalent intensity by adjusting the produced current close to the J SC under a standard solar simulator. As shown in Fig.  4a  and Supplementary Fig.  17 , the PLQY of the bare perovskite on glass is improved from 2.3% to 5.2% due to the CB-NH 2 treatment, indicative of surface trap passivation. To correlate the PLQY results with the kinetic properties of photogenerated charges, time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) characterization was performed. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  18 , a neat perovskite film without charge transport layers exhibit approximately a mono-exponential decay. In this case, then a Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) recombinationdominated lifetime (τ SRH ) can be deduced to be 1800 and 1000 ns for CB-NH 2 treated and control films, respectively. The extended τ SRH of CB-NH 2 coated perovskite films is favorable for carrier collection. When capped with C 60 , the PLQY of the control sample was reduced from 2.3% to 0.67% by a factor of ~4. In contrast, the C 60 induced PL quenching was substantially reduced for the CB-NH 2 treated perovskite/C 60 stacks (from 5.2% to 2.1%). The PLQY of perovskite/CB-NH 2 /C 60 stack is nearly identical to the bare perovskite sample (2.3%), indicating that we overcame the critical C 60 -induced non-radiative recombination upon introducing the CB-NH 2 interlayer for this system. To our knowledge, this is the first time that this was achieved for pin-type perovskite cells based on a C 60 ETL. As a result, we obtained a very high PLQY of 1.45% in full device, which is rarely achieved in pin-type cells, demonstrating the unique passivation effect of carborane interlayer. To quantify the open-circuit voltage potential for every individual stack, we calculated the internal electron-hole quasi-Fermi level  splitting (QFLS) from PLQY results by using the equation QFLS = k B T*ln(PLQY × J G /J 0,rad ), where J G is the generated current density at 1-sun and J 0,rad is the radiative recombination current in the dark as shown in Supplementary Fig.  13 . As shown in Fig.  4a , the neat perovskite exhibits an implied V OC of 1.183 V. This value increases to 1.204 V after the introduction of CB-NH 2 , which is attributed to the passivation effect on the perovskite surface. The perovskite/C 60 half stack exhibits a lower QFLS of 1.150 V, while the CB-NH 2 treated perovskite/C 60 sample shows QFLS of 1.180 V, which is nearly equal to the neat perovskite, indicating that the C 60 -induced interfacial recombination is effectively overcome. The PLQY and QFLS values mentioned above are collected in Table  1 . Moreover, the difference between the QFLS and V OC of the cells is negligible in both samples (w/ and wo/CB-NH 2 ). This demonstrates spatially flat Fermi levels throughout the device and well-aligned energy levels for majority carriers. Note any misalignment (downhill energy offset for electrons and uphill offset for holes) in combination with a finite interface recombination velocity would readily cause a gradient in the electron/hole quasi-Fermi levels and a QFLS-V OC mismatch. Figure  4b  depicts the voltage loss mechanism in the control and CB-NH 2 -based devices. Under the limitation of thermodynamic radiative which is 1.28 eV for the given bandgap, the perovskite loss and interface loss dominate the voltage loss in both samples whereas the transport loss is negligible (see the identical QFLS and V OC of the full device). After the introduction of CB-NH 2 , the simultaneously suppressed perovskite loss and interface loss result in the improved V OC . In order to gain more insight into the influence of charge recombination dynamics in complete devices, we also performed transient photovoltage (TPV) measurements under a white LED with an equivalent intensity of 1-sun. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  19 , the CB-NH 2 treated device exhibits a long lifetime (4.43 μs) which is nearly twice as much as the blank device (2.26 μs). The improved carrier lifetime is consistent with the PLQY results. We note that this value is larger than the bulk SRH lifetime obtained from TRPL, which is likely related to capacitive effects impacting TPV  52, 53  . In addition, electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements were performed to characterize the charge carrier recombination near opencircuit conditions (≈1 V), the series resistance (R s ), and recombination resistance (R rec ) of the CB-NH 2 and the reference device. All of these parameters can be obtained from the Nyquist plots intuitively. The equivalent circuits are presented in Supplementary Fig.  20 . The semicircle of the CB-NH 2 -based devices is larger than that of the blank device, indicating a significant reduction in charge carrier recombination rate, attributed to the lower R s and higher R rec . We also estimated the apparent trap density (n trap ) of the perovskite films by measuring the dark JV profiles of the electron-only devices. As shown and discussed in Supplementary Fig.  21 , the current in the ohmic region is smaller for the CB-NH 2 -based device, which could be correlated with a lower overall trap density and the improved V OC 54 . However, the measurable trap density from this experiment is limited by the electrode charge per unit cell volume, which is typically very similar to the apparent trap density in thin film (~500 nm) devices as recently shown in refs. 55, 56.   We then aimed towards an understanding of impact of our carborane passivation on the ideality factor (n ID ), fill factor losses, and efficiency potential and therefore investigated the intensity (or voltage) dependence of the non-radiative recombination losses. To this end, we employed three techniques: intensity-dependent quasi-Fermi level splitting, intensity-dependent V OC , and injection-dependent electroluminescence (EL). We first measured the intensity-dependent PLQY (iPLQY) of the different stack of samples. Upon converting the PLQY at different laser intensities to the QLFS, we obtain the QFLS as a function of light intensity (Fig.  5a ). Furthermore, we construct a pseudo-dark JV curve by plotting the recombination current minus the voltage-independent generation current under AM1.5 G ( J SC ) on the y-axis and the QFLS as x axis. As a result, we create a pseudo-light JV curves which allow us to quantify the implied JV performance of the film including the FF potential in the absence of R s . As shown in Fig.  5a , CB-NH 2 -based samples demonstrates a holistically higher QFLS value in the complete device, half stack, and bare perovskite. The pseudo-JV curves are shown in Fig.  5b  with photovoltaic parameters collected in Table  2 . With regard to the ideality factors, in Fig.  5a  for the control cell we obtain an n ID of 1.55 while it is 1.43 for the CB-NH 2 treated cell. We note that the difference between the pFF on the cells from the pseudo JVs reflects the different FF of the devices. Thus, the improved FF of the CB-NH 2 -based device is largely due to a lower ideality factor rather than improved charge transport. We also measured the iPLQY and corresponding QFLS on perovskite and perovskite/C 60 stack with and without C 60 (Fig.  5c, d ). The pseudo JVs are plotted in Supplementary Fig.  22  and the parameters are shown in Table  2 . The implied FF lost from the neat perovskite to perovskite/C 60 half stack is 1.5% in the control films, while this decline of FF is reduced to 0.4% for the CB-NH 2 coated samples. This demonstrates the introduction of CB-NH 2 compensates for the compromised FF caused by the deposition of C 60 due to dark recombination. For the perovskite and perovskite/C 60 half stacks, we noticed an increase in n ID by 0.15 from the neat perovskite (1.33) to the perovskite/C 60 film (1.48), whereas for the CB-NH 2 treated sample displays an n ID of 1.43 (Fig.  5c, d ). This is again consistent with reduced non-radiative recombination between the C 60 and the perovskite. We further performed intensity-dependent V OC measurement and conducted injection-dependent EL measurements to further analyze the n ID and pFF as shown in Supplementary Figs.  23  and 24 . Both measurements, further confirm the higher pseudo FF, demonstrating the improved FF due to suppressed non-radiative recombination. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>72186</offset>
      <text> Electron extraction and hole blocking To reveal the working mechanism of the CB-NH 2 layer, we quantified the charge selectivity at the perovskite/C 60 interface. To this end, we carried out conductive atomic force microscopy (C-AFM) on ITO/MeO-2PACz/Pero/(CB-NH 2 )/C 60 films with and without CB-NH 2 interlayer. This method has been used by Xu and Caprioglio et al. previsouly  57, 58  . In addition, the samples were illuminated with a 5 mW/cm 2 white LED to generate electron-hole pairs. To demonstrate the different transport behavior between electrons and holes, we applied a step-by step voltage variation from positive to negative bias to the tip to imitate the process of electron and hole extraction. Electron extraction is imitated when we apply a positive voltage to the tip while hole extraction is imitated when we apply a negative voltage. Figure  6  demonstrates that the CB-NH 2 treated samples exhibits a higher current in the positive bias region, whereas the current is lower at a negative bias with respect to the control sample. To be specific, when 1 V bias is applied to the tip, CB-NH 2 treated samples approach an average current of -0.72 nA, while the control sample exhibits a lower average current (-0.2 nA). In contrast, CB-NH 2 treated samples exhibit a lower current when -1 V is applied to the tip (0.02 nA) compared to the control sample (0.07 nA). The averaged values were obtained from area-averaged profiles. We note that the isolated spikes could be related to the carrier diffusion The improved electron extraction is also consistent with the improved FF and decreased trap density observed with PL. Note, due to the low light intensity (5 mW/cm 2 ) the measurement is in essence a dark JV measurement, and the low values of the current are limited by the small radius of the tip of 35 nm. Therefore, the current signal measured from C-AFM is not comparable to the J SC from JV curves. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>74114</offset>
      <text> Contribution from carborane and amino moiety to device performance In order to investigate the contribution from the carborane and amino group moiety in CB-NH 2 to the improvement of device performance, we also studied the intermediate phenyl functionalized carborane (CBph) without the amino group because the bare carborane suffers from sublimation on the perovskite layer. As can been seen in Supplementary Fig.  25 , CB-ph leads to a significant FF improvement (~2%) but only slight V OC improvement (~10 mV). This indicates that the carborane alone reduces non-radiative recombination less effectively than CB-NH 2 but has a significant effect on the electron extraction which is consistent with the C-AFM result. The slight V OC improvement can be further confirmed by the improved PLQY of the ITO/perovskite/C 60 stack with the CB-ph interlayer but identical PLQY of the ITO/perovskite with and without the CB-ph interlayer (Supplementary Fig.  26 ). These results suggest that there is a small contribution (~10 mV) of the carborane moiety to the total V OC gain of the CB-NH 2 device (~50 mV) which we attribute to the improved hole-blocking ability of the carborane. However, the effect of the amino group is more significant. As for the FF improvement, our results indicate a more significant contribution of the carborane moiety (~2%) to the total gain (~4%), which suggests that the improvement originates partially from the hole-blocking and electron extraction ability of the CB molecule. Nevertheless, considering that the packing and adsorption ability of the CB-ph and the CB-NH 2 molecules are likely different, the exact contribution of the carborane moiety is difficult to quantify. Given that the performance of the CB-NH 2 device is optimum, we can conclude that the carborane and the amino group are working synergistically and are indispensable. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>75987</offset>
      <text> Surface passivation and Pb-CB-NH 2 interaction To further explore the passivation mechanism of CB-NH 2 , we examined the intermolecular interactions between CB-NH 2 and perovskite. We conducted Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements to study the interactions between CB-NH 2 and perovskite moieties. We dissolved CB-NH 2 and PbI 2 in DMF solvent and then dried the solution to obtain a  mixed powder  40, 59  . The FTIR spectra of the mixture and pure CB-NH 2 powders, displayed in Supplementary Fig.  27 , reveal that the addition of PbI 2 results in the variation of the v(N-H) interaction. Given that the lone pairs of N contained functional groups, especially in the amino group, can interact with Pb 2+ , we speculate the shift of the v(N-H) peak originates from the interaction between the N atom and Pb 2+ . We further performed XPS measurements on perovskite films with/without CB-NH 2 to study the interaction between the interlayer and the perovskite. As shown in Supplementary Fig.  28 , the Pb signals between 136 eV and 146 eV binding energy demonstrate 2 main peaks, which can be ascribed to the excited electrons of the 4f 7/2 and 4f 5/2 orbitals. Apparently, the signal of the perovskite film with CB-NH 2 shows a visible shift towards lower binding energies, indicating the interaction between under-coordinated Pb and CB-NH 2 . Since the undercoordinated Pb 2+ on the perovskite surface are typically active sites for interfacial reactions that act as electronic traps  60, 61  , the interaction between CB-NH 2 and Pb might explain the decreased surface trap density, as well as the improved operational stability. We note that the detected B 1 s signal proves the existence of CB-NH 2 . The observed interaction is likely related to the improvement of PL intensity and lifetime for neat perovskite. To obtain more atomistic information regarding to the interaction between the perovskite and CB-NH 2 density functional theory (DFT) simulations were performed. We choose α-FAPbI 3 perovskite and a (001) PbI 2 -terminated surface as model system in accordance with the studied perovskite. A detailed description of the DFT calculations can be found in Supplementary Note 2. Figure  7a   passivates the under-coordinated Pb atoms on the perovskite surface. These short bond lengths result in an extraordinarily high adsorption energy of -3.42 eV  [64] [65] [66]  . To further corroborate these findings, we calculated the iodine Frenkel (interstitial/vacancy pair) defect formation energy (DFE) and we find an increased DFE by ~0.2 eV upon the CB-NH 2 incorporation (Supplementary Fig.  29 ), indicating reduced creation and diffusion of iodide defects. Based on the above results, we can draw the conclusion that the synergistic bonding effect from N-H•••I and N-Pb realize a strong interaction between the perovskite and CB-NH 2 , which is beneficial for simultaneously passivating surface defects and improving the surface stability. V -0.5 V 0 V 0.5 V 1.0 V -1.0 V -0.5 V 0 V 0.5 V 1.0 V 0 -0.5 -1 -1.5 -2 -2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>79092</offset>
      <text> Discussion In this work, we demonstrate effective control of non-radiative recombination losses at the perovskite/C 60 interface by implementing a carborane-based interlayer in pin-type PSCs. This is achieved upon the introduction of a phenylamine functionalized carborane derivative CB-NH 2 , which enables efficient defect passivation and selective electron transport with mobility of 7 × 10 -4 cm 2 /Vs. The inverted PSCs with CB-NH 2 incorporated as an interfacial layer reach high PLQYs of 1.4% and PCEs over 23%, with non-radiative voltage losses as low as 110 mV. By analyzing the PLQY and the QFLS of different partial cell stacks, we demonstrate that the implementation of CB-NH 2 as an interlayer nearly eliminates the C 60 -induced interfacial recombination, which has not yet been achieved with other interfacial modifications. Based on a series of experimental methodologies, we demonstrate that the concomitantly improved V OC and FF with CB-NH 2 is a result of the passivation of the perovskite surface, reduced nonradiative recombination across the perovskite/C 60 interface combined with an increased charge carrier selectivity. The CB-NH 2 interlayer also improves the thermal and operational stability of the complete devices, which is attributed to the stabilization of defects on the perovskite surface and the hydrophobic nature of CB-NH 2 . This work addresses one of the most critical issues of inverted PSCs and demonstrates the potential of carborane derivatives as interfacial and electron transport materials in perovskite-based opto-electronic devices. As such, we believe that future molecular design and optimization will pave the way for a particular class electron transport materials based on carboranes. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>80834</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>80844</offset>
      <text> Materials and reagents The raw material dodecahydro-arachno-bis(acatonitrile)decaborane was purchased from Zhengzhou Yuanli Biological Technology Co., Ltd, China, Diphenylacetylene was purchased from Shanghai Macklin Biochemical Co., Ltd, China. PbI 2 , PbBr 2 , MABr, MACl, PEAI, BCP, and MeO-2PACz were purchased from TCI. Patterned indium tin oxide (ITO) glass, FAI, C60, and PCBM were purchased from Advanced Election Technology Co., Ltd. CsI was purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. DMSO, DMF, ethanol, chlorobenzene, and isopropanol were purchased from Acros. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>81405</offset>
      <text> PSCs fabrication Patterned ITO-coated glass substrates were cleaned sequentially for 15 min in suds, deionized water, ethanol, and acetone in ultrasonic bath. Then the substrates were treated with ultraviolet ozone (UV-Ozone) for 30 min and transferred to a nitrogen-filled glove box. All subsequent procedures were done in nitrogen-filled glove boxes. The solutions of MeO-2PACz (1 mmol mL -1 in ethanol) were spin-coated on the ITO substrates at 3000 rpm for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. The FA-based triple-cation perovskite precursor solution with a formula of Cs 0.05 (MA 0.05 FA 0.95 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 was prepared by mixing two 1.5 M FAPbI 3 and MAPbBr 3 perovskite solutions in DMF:DMSO (4:1 volume ratio, v-v), as well as the solution of CsI (1.5 M) and MACl in DMSO (20 mol% MACl were added into the precursor solution for better crystallization). The triple-cation perovskite films were deposited by spin-coating at 4000 rpm for 40 s (5 s for acceleration). 5 s before the end of the procedure chlorobenzene (300 μL) was dispensed onto the still spinning substrate in one continuous flow which lasts for approximately 1 second, following by annealing at 100 °C for 1 h. Subsequently, the carborane molecules were spin-coated from 1 mg/mL solution in chlorobenzene at an rpm of 6000 (3 s for acceleration). Then, the samples were transferred to an evaporation chamber where C 60 (Sigma-Aldrich, 30 nm) at 0.2 Å/s, 8 nm BCP (Sigma-Aldrich) at 0.2 Å/s and 100 nm copper (Sigma-Aldrich) at 0.6 Å/s were deposited under vacuum (p = 10 -7 mbar). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>82996</offset>
      <text> Characterization and measurements Absolute photoluminescence measurements. Excitation for the PL measurements was performed with a 520 nm CW laser (Insaneware) through an optical fiber into an integrating sphere. The intensity of the laser was adjusted to a 1-sun equivalent intensity by illuminating a 1 cm 2 -size PSC under short-circuit and matching the current density to the J SC under the sun simulator (22.0 mA/cm 2 at 100 mW cm -2 , or 1.375 × 10 21 photons m -2 s -1 ). A second optical fiber was used from the output of the integrating sphere to an Andor SR393iB spectrometer equipped with a silicon CCD camera (DU420A-BR-DD, iDus). The system was calibrated by using a calibrated halogen lamp with specified spectral irradiance, which was shone into to integrating sphere. A spectral correction factor was established to match the spectral output of the detector to the calibrated spectral irradiance of the lamp. The spectral photon density was obtained from the corrected detector signal (spectral irradiance) by division through the photon energy (ℎv), and the photon numbers of the excitation and emission obtained from numerical integration using MATLAB. Electroluminescence measurements (EL). The absolute EL intensity was measured with a calibrated Si photodetector and a Keithley 485 pico Ampere meter. The detector (with an active area of ~2 cm 2 ) was placed directly in front of the device (0.13 cm 2 ), and the total photon flux was evaluated considering the emission spectrum of perovskite and silicon sub-cell, their relative intensities from the previously measured relative EL spectra and the external quantum efficiency of the detector. A slight underestimation of the EQE EL (≈1.08×), originating from an additional glass encapsulation, and some photons that escaped to the side and were not detected was compensated. A forward bias was applied to the cell using a Keithley 2400 source meter, and the injected current was monitored. Measurements were conducted with a home-written LabVIEW routine. Typically, the voltage was increased in steps of 20 mV, and the current stabilized for typical 1 s at each step. Intensity-dependent V OC measurements. Steady-state intensitydependent V OC (i-V OC ) was measured under mimicked AM1.5 G illumination (Oriel class AAA Xenon lamp-based sun simulator), appropriated neutral density filters, and a Keithley2400. The samples were irradiated by using a 445 nm continuous wave laser (Insaneware). A continuously variable neutral density filter wheel (ThorLabs) was used to attenuate the laser power (up to OD 6). The light intensity was thereby simultaneously measured with a silicon photodetector and a Keithley 485 to improve the accuracy of the measurement. For each intensity, the V OC is measured for ~2 s before the J SC is measured for the same time. The filter wheel is then moved to the next position and the routine is repeated. A homemade lab view program controlled the variable neutral density filter wheel and measured the V OC using a Keithley2400. class AAA Xenon lamp-based sun simulator was used for illumination providing approximately 100 mW cm -2 of simulated AM1.5 G irradiation and the intensity was monitored simultaneously with a Si photodiode. The exact illumination intensity was used for efficiency calculations, and the simulator was calibrated with a KG5-filtered silicon solar cell (certified by Fraunhofer ISE). The temperature of the cell was fixed to 25 °C and a voltage ramp of 20 mV/s was used. The active area of tested cells was 12 mm 2 as defined from the area of overlap of the electrodes. To measure the JV-characteristics an illumination mask with an area of 9 mm 2 was used. The spectral mismatch factor (S M ) was calculated to be 0.982 for the optimized devices with EQE spectra presented in Fig.  2f , however, the obtained current has not been upscaled by 1/S M . Conductive atomic force. Conductive Atomic Force Microscopy was performed with a Solver NT-MDT instrument with a hardware linearized 100 mm scanner and scanning tip. The measurements were performed in contact mode by measuring both spreading resistance and topography. The tip used was a platinum NSG10/Pt. Other Measurements. The 1 H NMR spectra were recorded with the Bruker AM 400 spectrometer. The cyclic voltammograms were measured by using a CHI660E electrochemical workstation (Chenhua Co. Ltd, Shanghai, China) in a three-electrode cell. X-ray diffraction measurements were obtained by a Rigaku Ultima IV (Cu Ka radiation, λ = 1.5406 Å) in the range of 5°-90°(2θ). The time-resolved photoluminescence decay lifetimes were determined with the single photon counting technique by Edinburgh FLS1000 spectrometer. Transient photovoltage test was conducted under a white-light (LED) which was adjusted to produce the V OC at 1-sun conditions (1-sun equivalent), and the laser pulses (532 nm, 2 Hz) to measure the decay of transient photovoltage signals. EQE measurements were measured by Newport-74125 system (Newport Instruments). The operational stability of the unencapsulated PSCs was performed at the MPP tracking under continuous white-light LED array illumination in N 2 atmosphere, the light intensity was calibrated to achieve the same J SC from the PSCs measured under a standard solar simulator (AM1.5 G, 100 mW cm -2 ). Supplementary Figure 13 .Supplementary Figure 21 . 1321 Photonflux &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>88391</offset>
      <text> 3 . 3 Was the cell temperature controlled during the MPP stability tracking measurements in Fig 3c? If so, the temperature should be specified. Also related to Fig 3c, were multiple cells tested for stability, or only one of each type? Given the typical performance spread of individual perovskite cells, stability conclusions based on single device measurements are not very reliable. The authors should provide stability data for multiple cells or if not, they should comment on the confidence of their conclusions. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>88911</offset>
      <text> 3 . 3 Was the cell temperature controlled during the MPP stability tracking measurements in Fig 3c? If so, the temperature should be specified. Also related to Fig 3c, were multiple cells tested for stability, or only one of each type? Given the typical performance spread of individual perovskite cells, stability conclusions based on single device measurements are not very reliable. The authors should provide stability data for multiple cells or if not, they should comment on the confidence of their conclusions &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>89430</offset>
      <text> Absorption spectra of control and CB-NH2 treated films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>89488</offset>
      <text> To further emphasize the indispensability of carborane moiety, we compared the performance of CBph (without amino) based samples and control samples. The JV distribution is shown as below. The CB-ph based samples show a ~10 mV improvement in VOC and a ~2% increased FF compared to the control samples. The improved VOC indicates that the hole blocking effect originates from the carborane moiety, while the improved FF is consistent with the improved electron extraction seen in C-AFM. Supplementary Fig. S21. Parameters distribution of VOC, JSC, FF, and PCE for control, and CB-ph treated devices, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>90103</offset>
      <text> Figure R1. a a Figure R1. a Simulated current-voltage characteristics of cells with and without a passivation at the perovskite/C60 interface which reduces the interfacial defect density by a factor of 10. b Corresponding parallel recombination currents for the 2 simulated cells shown in panel a. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>90403</offset>
      <text> Figure R2 . R2 Figure R2. JV characteristics and performance metric of devices treated with nitrobenzene and phenyl substituted carboranes (CB-NO2 and CB-ph, respectively). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>90578</offset>
      <text> 3 . 3 "As shown in Fig.2e, the stabilized current density of control and CB-NH2 treated cell are 23.73, 23.26 mA/cm2 under a bias of 0.97 and 0.91V, respectively, confirming a stabilized PCE of 23.04% and 21.10%, which are consistent with JV results." The data for control and CB-NH2 treated cell were reversed.Thank you very much, indeed the data for control and CB-NH2 treated cell were reversed.we revised the sentence as follow: "As shown in Figure2e, the stabilized current density of CB-NH2 treated and control devices are 23.73, 23.26 mA/cm2 under a bias of 0.97 and 0.91V, respectively, confirming a stabilized PCE of 23.04% and 21.10%, which are consistent with JV results." 4. "To quantify the stability, we performed MPP tracking on the devices in a glovebox… The improved operational stability is attributed to... as well as the increased hydrophobicity and resistance to moisture." Stability results obtained in the glovebox should not be related to moisture. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>91555</offset>
      <text> 5 . 5 The caption of Fig.S15is incorrect. In addition, the resolution of light intensity up to 0.0001 sun is incredible. Please provide the corresponding J-V curves of the devices under different light intensity in Fig S15. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>91781</offset>
      <text> Figure R4 . R4 Figure R4. Filter wheel and laser used for automatic VOC measurements. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>91869</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Universal photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) losses induced by C 60 , device structure and energy level diagram. a C 60 -induced recombination losses in various pin-type perovskite systems. Data reproduced with permission from Warby, J. et al. Understanding Performance Limiting Interfacial Recombination in pin Perovskite Solar Cells. Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12, 2103567. 10.1002/ aenm.202103567 under a CC BY license https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/ 4.0/.12 C 60 lowers the PLQY to ≈1 × 10 -4 -1 × 10 -3 of the neat layer, for various perovskite compositions represented by the different shading, such as methyl ammonium lead iodide (MAPbI 3 ), double cation (FA 0.8 MA 0.2 PbI 3 ) and triple-cation perovskites (Cs 0.05 FA x MA y Pb(I x Br y ) 3 ) which are denoted as "TC", where the x:y ratio reflects the molar ration of FAPbI 3 versus MAPbBr 3 , 2D/3D perovskites are denoted by the spacer cation butylammonium (BA) and the number of layers of octahedra between spacer cations, e.g., n = 4 is BA 4 . b Device structure and molecule structures of o-carborane (CB) as well as phenylamino decorated carborane (CB-NH 2 ). c Energy levels based on cyclic voltammetry and literature values. d Space-charge limited current measurement of electron-only devices with the configuration of ITO/ZnO/ CB-NH 2 (100 nm) or C 60 (200 nm)/BCP/Ag. The inset shows the mobility variation under different bias voltages. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>93363</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Device performance of CB-NH 2 , CB treated and control cells. a-c Parameter distributions and corresponding standard deviations of V OC , FF, and PCE for control, CB, and CB-NH 2 treated devices, respectively. d JV curves of the champion devices. e Stable power output results of CB-NH 2 based and control cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>93698</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 41 Fig. 3 | 4413 Fig. 4 | Photoluminescence quantum yield measurements (PLQY) and internal quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) diagram. a PLQY and QFLS diagram and V OC from JV results for perovskite film, perovskite/C 60 half stack, and full cell with/ without CB-NH 2 . The almost identical PLQY value between pero and pero/CB-NH 2 / C 60 samples indicates the elimination of interfacial recombination. The bars represent the QFLS results from PLQY measurement and the stars the V OC from JV results, respectively. b Voltage loss mechanism for the control and CB-NH 2 -based samples. Source data are provided as a Source Data file. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>94342</offset>
      <text> 2Fig. 7 | 7 Fig. 7 | Interaction between CB-NH 2 and perovskite from DFT calculations. Top views of PbI 2 -terminated perovskite surface a without and b with CB-NH 2 . c Side views of the perovskite surface adsorbed with CB-NH 2 . Notes: the length of N-H•••I/ N-Pb are depicted. Color scheme: Pb: gray; I: light blue; C: pink; N: dark blue; B: green; H: white. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>94712</offset>
      <text> Fig. 6 | 6 Fig. 6 | Improved electron extraction and hole blocking at perovskite/C 60 interface. 3D conductive-AFM images (5 × 5 μm) of the samples with a structure of ITO/MeO-2PACz/Pero/CB-NH 2 / C 60 (CB-NH 2 treated) and ITO/MeO-2PACz/Pero/ C 60 (control). The images represent a step-by-step applied voltage variation from -1.0 V applied to the tip (left) for hole extraction to 1.0 V applied to the tip (right) for electron extraction. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>95157</offset>
      <text> . A similar surface modification strategy is based on sulfate (SO 4 2-) and phosphate (PO 4 3- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>95254</offset>
      <text> Table 1 | 1 PLQY and QFLS results of perovskite film, perovskite/ C 60 half stack, and full cell with/without CB-NH 2 Sample PLQY QFLS (eV) V OC (V) pero/CB-NH 2 0.0523 1.204 neat pero 0.0234 1.183 pero/CB-NH 2 /C 60 0.021 1.180 pero/C 60 0.0067 1.150 cell-CB-NH 2 0.0145 1.170 1.170 cell-control 0.00345 1.133 1.128 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>95573</offset>
      <text> Table 2 2 | Parameters of pseudo JV curves constructed based on iPLQY from perovskite film, perovskite/C 60 half stack, and full cell with/without CB-NH 2 cell V OC (V) J SC (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) PCE (%) CB-NH 2 Device 1.164 23.7 86.3 23.8 Half stack 1.177 23.7 86.8 24.1 Perovskite 1.202 23.7 87.2 24.8 control Device 1.135 23.5 85.1 22.7 Half stack 1.146 23.5 85.6 23.0 Perovskite 1.181 23.5 87.1 24.1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>95976</offset>
      <text>			 https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-34203-x Nature Communications | (2022) 13:7454</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:53Z</infon>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="12" role=""/>
      <node refid="13" role=""/>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
