<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025041541IAEHAH</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 98&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Perovskite Bifunctional Device with Improved Electroluminescent and Photovoltaic Performance through Interfacial Energy-Band Engineering&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>149</offset>
      <text>The organic-inorganic halide perovskite receives great attention for various high performance optoelectronic applications due to its excellent properties, such as strong light absorption, high charge carrier mobility, and long intrinsic carrier lifetime.  [1, 2]  For perovskite solar cells (PSCs), the state-of-the-art device has surged to a certified power conversion efficiency (PCE) of more than 24.2%, mainly owing to the recent efforts in morphological control, defect management, and component optimization for the bulk perovskite absorbed layer.  [3] [4] [5]  In addition, the&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>734</offset>
      <text>[6, 7]   The highest reported electroluminescent (EL) external quantum efficiencies (EQE EL ) of PLEDs have surpassed &gt;20%.  [8] [9] [10] [11]  Due to the similar device architectures for PSC and PLED, one attractive possibility is to develop photovoltaic/ electroluminescent (PV/EL) bifunctionalities in the same device. However, there is a fundamental tradeoff between solar cell (SC) and light emitting diode (LED) due to the inverse photoelectricity interconversion process and this concept is thus rarely demonstrated yet with high performance.  [12] [13] [14]  Based on the detailed balance (Shockley-Queisser, S-Q) theory, the voltage loss in SC can be attributed to the two basic factors shown in Equation (1)  [15, 16]   where E g is the bandgap energy; V OC the open-circuit voltage; q the elemental charge, k is the Boltzmann constant; and T is the Kelvin temperature. V V , oc rad oc nonrad ∆ ∆ are V OC losses via radiative recombination and nonradiative recombination, respectively. The first term due to the radiative recombination is unavoidable for SC and the energy loss is around 0.28 eV for the PSCs.  [17, 18]  According to Equations ((1) and (  2 )), the same approach to S-Q limit for SC and LED performance is to reduce the nonradiative recombination. In PLED, it is found that near 100% internal quantum efficiencies can be achieved by minimizing interfacial and bulk nonradiative losses.  [11]  In PSCs, the EL metrics can be used to monitor the photovoltage loss, for example, high EQE EL always means high-voltage for SC.  [16, 19, 20]  Several methods have been reported to improve the EQE EL of PSCs, such as improving the perovskite crystal quality by antisolvent engineering, suppressing nonradiative defects by small excess of PbI 2 and using a solution-processed secondary growth (SSG) technique.  [12, 14, [21] [22] [23]  Notably, the EQE EL of PSCs has reached 3.8% through incorporation of rubidium cation into perovskite due to enhanced optoelectronic properties.  [3]  Very recently, surface passivation by PEAI layer has also improved the EL properties of PSCs.  [44]  In principle, nonradiative recombination in perovskite device mainly originates from the interfacial defect states at various interfaces and the native defects.  [24] [25] [26]  In the state-of-the-art perovskite device, recombination in the bulk seems to be negligible since the high quality of perovskite absorber materials have been achieved through morphological control and defect management, confirmed by the long carrier lifetime and diffusion length.  [27, 28]  It is reported that TOPOpassivated MAPbI 3 films can achieve a quasi-Fermi-level splitting as high as 1.28 ± 0.01 eV.  [29]  If such perovskite films could be successfully implemented in a SC device with appropriate selective contacts, it is possible to deliver a V OC of 1.28 V with only 0.04 V loss to S-Q limit, which corresponds to an encouraging EQE EL of ≈21.5% according to Equation (2). Therefore, in principle, it is possible to develop PV/EL PBDs with high comprehensive performance. Except for high quality perovskite films with low defect states, the main challenge is to reduce the energy band barrier at the interface between the perovskite and charge transport layers, which determine the charge extraction or injection loss.  [24]  For the SC, it requires light-generated electron-hole pairs being effectively separated from the perovskite layer and therefore prefers to the type II (staggered gap) charge extraction band alignment as shown in Scheme 1a.  [30]  Inversely, the LED with charge injection alignment is shown in Scheme 1b (straddling gap, type I alignment), to enhance the electron/hole recombination through charge confinement in the active layer.  [7]  Therefore, the energy driving forces in SC and LED are inverse to each other. However, if we can modulate the energy offset at the interface approaching to zero and ensure a barrier free bidirectional charge transfer as shown in Scheme 1c, it is possible to minimize the V OC loss and maximum the EL performance. V E q V E q V V V V V + OC g OC g oc rad oc rad OC oc rad oc nonrad ( ) ∆ = - = -       + - = ∆ ∆ (1) V kT q = ln EQE oc nonrad EL ∆ - (2 Herein, we perform interfacial energy band engineering between perovskite and hole-transport layers (HTLs) through adding corrosion-free 3,3′-(2,7-dibromo-9H-fluorene-9,9-diyl) bis(n,n-dimethylpropan-1-amine) (FN-Br) additive into HTLs and thus improve the PV/EL performance and stability of PBD. We firstly reveal that the serious surface states of perovskite show n-type and thus uplift the Fermi energy of adjacent HTLs using Kelvin probe force microscope (KPFM) measurement. Such perovskite/HTLs interface energy band shows a downward band-bending misalignment, leading to serious nonradiative recombination at interface. The FN-Br can turn the n-type perovskite surface into p-type and lower the Fermi level (E F ) of HTL as well. The tailed device forms a well-defined N-I-P heterojunction structure to approximate the Scheme 1c, and hence reduces the energy offset at the perovskite/HTLs interface. The best-performing MAPbI 3 devices achieve a maximum PV efficiency of 21.54% and an improved EQE EL of 4.3%, which is among the highest comprehensive performance so far for PBDs. Due to nondestructive additives, our unencapsulated devices show an excellent stability and maintain &gt;92% of their initial PV performance after continuous operation for 500 h at maximum power point (MPP) under 1-sun illumination. We demonstrate it is a general interface energy band engineering for efficient and stable perovskite photoelectric device. The structure of N-I-P planar PBDs in our study is ITO/ SnO 2 /perovskite/HTLs/Au, showing a switchable dual functionality of SC and LED (Figure  1a ). Here, we blend small amount of FN-Br additive into spiro-OMeTAD to form composite HTLs and the chemical structure is shown in Figure  1a . We assume that there is a thin interlayer formed at the perovskite/HTL interface due to self-organization of -N(CH 3 ) 2 functional group. In order to achieve stable SC/LED PBDs, we use dopant-free spiro-OMeTAD (DFS) as HTLs, without the humidity sensitive additives of LiTFSI and detrimental 4-tert-butylpyridine (TBP) which are generally thought to be necessary for high performance PSCs. Interestingly, we find that the PV efficiency of devices based on DFS can be improved largely through reducing the DFS thickness which dominates the series resistances in PBD (Figures  S1-S3 , Supporting Information). The highest PCE of 17.29% with a V OC of 1.05 V, a fill factor (FF) of 72.6%, and a short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 22.70 mA cm -2 can be achieved when the thickness of DFS is ≈80 nm (Figure  1b ; Table  S1 , Supporting Information). After introducing FN-Br, the device based on DFS (DFS:FN-Br) achieves an improved V OC of 1.16 V and reaches an efficiency of 19.31% (Figure  1b ; Table  S1 , Supporting Information). To understand the improvement of V OC , we estimated the ideality factor (n), which is an indicator of the dominant recombination mechanism occurring within a working device. The n values of the control and DFS:FN-Br based devices are 1.76 and 1.34, respectively, through fitting the J SC dependence of the V OC curves using the equation S1 in the Supporting Information  [31]  (Figure  S4 , Supporting Information). The much smaller n value indicates that the serious interfacial recombination has been effectively reduced by FN-Br. To achieve high V OC in a SC, not only external photoluminescence of the perovskite should be maximized, but also any additional nonradiative losses at the interface in the devices must be minimized.  [28]  Figure  1c ,d compares the EL intensity of the perovskite devices based on the same structure with and without FN-Br. We can indeed observe enhanced EL intensity which is the consequence of a significantly improved hole injection at the perovskite/HTL interface (Figure  1d ). However, in the control device without FN-Br, current injection is much lower and EL becomes weaker (Figure  1c ). To find the physical mechanism for the improved V OC of SC mode and enhanced EL of LED mode, we measured the work function (WF) of the perovskite layer and DFS HTLs by using KPFM. As shown in Figure  2a ,b, we perform the surface potential mappings of MAPbI 3 -Au interface on a HTLfree device with the structure of ITO/SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 (with and without treating by FN-Br solution)/Au and MAPbI 3 /DFS-Au interface on a complete device with the structure of ITO/SnO 2 / MAPbI 3 /DFS(with or without FN-Br additive)/Au, respectively. It is noticed that the Au electrode should be freshly prepared without contamination, which has a WF of ≈5.1 eV calibrated by highly oriented pyrolytic graphite (HOPG) electrode and thus can be used as a reference to investigate the energy level change of perovskite and DFS in practical device. We observe that both the pristine MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 /DFS have a large surface potential gap with Au electrode, which are ≈0.69 and ≈0.58 eV, respectively (Figure  2a, b ). The WF of DFS (4.52 eV) on the perovskite is even lower than its intrinsic value of ≈4.9 eV, which suggests that the surface state of perovskite influences the WF of DFS (Figure  2b   Based on these measurements, we deduce the band diagram at the interface between perovskite and DFS with/without FN-Br (Figure  2d, e ). First, our results show that the pristine perovskite surface is n-type because its E F (-4.41 eV by KPFM; -4.3 eV by UPS) is closed to the conduction band (E C ) (-4.2 eV), which can be seen from the energy band of MAPbI 3 perovskite (Figure  S9 , Supporting Information). In previous study, it was demonstrated that the n-type character of crystal perovskite is caused by donor-type surface states (Pb 0 )  [32]  (Figure  2d ). The formation of surface state on the perovskite film seems to be inevitable, since the periodic array of lattice is broken at the terminal of crystal, and meanwhile organic component of perovskite shows relatively low thermal stability during annealing.  [33]  Under thermal equilibrium, the energy bands show a downward bending at the perovskite surface since the crystal perovskite is close to an intrinsic semiconductor in the bulk  [32, 34]  (Figure  2d ). The electron concentration of perovskite and hole concentration of DFS have been attained by Hall measurement, which are ≈8.0 × 10 16 and ≈1.1 × 10 15 cm -3 , respectively. When contacting with the perovskite active layer, the DFS will also show downward band bending on the perovskite layer side, and the MAPbI 3 /DFS interface form an N-P -junction (Figure  2d ). It can be attained that the depletion region will distribute in the side of DFS according to the equation D &gt;&gt; N A ) N x N x A p D n = (3) where the N D is the electron concentration; N A is the hole concentration; x P , x n are the widths of the positive and negative space charge region, respectively. Namely, in thermal equilibrium the hole concentration in DFS will largely decrease due to the diffusion of electron from perovskite surface, leading to the reduction of WF in DFS. It could be verified by the Boltzmann relation  [35]  p N E E kT exp V V F = × -       ( 4 ) where p is the number of holes (occupied valence-band levels); E V is the valence-band edge; N V is the effective density of states in the valence band; k is the Boltzmann constant; and T is the Kelvin temperature. This interfacial band structure of N-P -junction would block the hole and trap electron at the interface between perovskite and HTLs, leading to serious recombination (Figure  2d ). As the FN-Br is dipole molecule with electron-rich sites on the side of -N(CH 3 ) 2 functional group, the lone electron pairs at the N can be delocalized to the empty 6p orbits of positive metal center (Pb 2+ ). The binding energy of the FN-Br on the MAPbI 3 surface was estimated to be 44.3 kJ mol -1 by density function theory calculation (Figure  S10 , Supporting Information). The molecular adsorption of FN-Br can be used to indicate the elimination of donor-type states (Pb 0 ) on perovskite surface. Figure  S11  in the Supporting Information shows Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectra for FN-Br, PbI 2 /FN-Br, and MAPbI 3 /FN-Br film. Stretching frequency of C-N appears at 1270 cm -1 for the bare FN-Br, which is shifted to 1253 and 1249 cm -1 for PbI 2 /FN-Br and MAPbI 3 /FN-Br, respectively. The decreased C-N stretching frequency of PbI 2 /FN-Br indicates that the CN bond strength is decreased due to the interaction with Pb 2+ ions and we find that there exists the similar stretching frequency of C-N in PbI 2 /FN-Br and MAPbI 3 /FN-Br, indicating the coordination between MAPbI 3 and FN-Br. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis was conducted to investigate the surface composition for perovskite films. For the pristine perovskite film, two additional peaks can be observed at 138.0 and 142.9 eV, which can be attributed to metallic lead on the surface  [36]  (Figure  S12 , Supporting Information). After treating by FN-Br, the metallic lead peak almost disappears. Excess FN-Br at the interface even may attract mobile holes to compensate for the negative charge and then p-dopes the surface of perovskite, resulting in a slight upward band bending (Figure  2e ). In the HTLs, the FN-Br incorporation can also lower the E F of DFS toward a deeper level as well (Figure  2c ; Figure  S8 , Supporting Information), which will reduce the energy barrier at the perovskite/DFS interface. Based on these results, we deduce that the FN-Br can effectively tune the band structure of device from N-[N]-I-[N]-P -to N-[N]-I-[P]-P ([] represents the interface). This adjusted energy band structure is beneficial to suppress the interfacial nonradiative recombination both for photogenerated electron/hole extraction in SC and electron/hole injection in LED (Figure  2e ). Figure  2f  gives the Mott-Schottky (MS) plots 1/C 2 versus voltage attained by EIS measurements for the control and FN-Br device. According to the Equation (  5 ), the slope gives the charge concentration of the substrate (-2/qɛN), and the intercept of 1/C 2 = 0 gives the built-in potential (ψ bi -2kT/q)  [35, 37]   C A q N V kT q bi 1 2 2 2 2 0 ε ε ψ = --       (5) where C is the depletion-layer capacitance; ψ bi the built-in potential at equilibrium; q the unit electronic charge (1.60 × 10 -19 C), V the applied voltage, A the active area, ɛ the relative permittivity ( = 32), ɛ 0 the vacuum permittivity (8.85 × 10 -12 F m -1 ), N the charge concentration. By fitting the voltage dependence of the 1/C 2 curves, we find that the slope of the FN-Br devices is one order of magnitude higher than control devices, illustrating the much lower charge density at the perovskite/HTL interface due to the passivation of FN-Br (Figure  2h ). Meanwhile, it is clear that the intercept at 1/C 2 = 0 based on the device with FN-Br is much larger than that based on control device. It illustrates that the built-in potential in device is improved due to adjusted energy band structure, leading to the improved V OC in SC mode. In addition, it is found that this tailed N-I-P structure can achieve a better charge injection balance when the device is operated as a LED mode. As shown in Figure  2g , we measured the J-V characteristics of electron-only devices (ITO/SnO 2 / perovskite/PCBM/Au) and hole-only devices (ITO/PTAA/ perovskite/with or without FN-Br/DFS/Au). The results show that electrons dominate injection into the devices, whereas the FN-Br can improve the hole injection and balance the charge injection which is critical for the PLED. We find that adding the FN-Br into DFS can achieve a better PV performance and reproductivity than spin coating the FN-Br and DFS on the perovskite layer in sequence (Figure  S13  and Table  S2 , Supporting Information). It is possible that a thin FN-Br interlayer could form well through self-organizing on the perovskite surface due to the chemical bonding between the functional group -N(CH 3 ) 2 and under-coordinated Pb as aforementioned, and the FN-Br incorporation can shift the E F of spiro-MeTAD toward a deeper level (Figure  2c ). We systematically optimized the FN-Br concentration dependent performance, as shown in Figure  S14  in the Supporting Information, which suggested that FN-Br could increase the V OC in small concentration. In order to further improve the device efficiency, we added slight FK209 (≈0.5 wt%) into the HTLs and it results in a mild improvement for V OC and J SC , and an obvious enhancement for FF (Figure  S15 , Supporting Information). In previous reports, FK209 was usually used as a p-dopant to enhance the hole transport and overall efficiency.  [38, 39]  In this study, the FK209 additive plays the similar role for improving the device performance. The J-V curves of the champion device after optimization are shown in Figure  3a . The device exhibits a V OC of 1.186 V, a J SC of 23.25 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 78.2%, achieving an overall PCE of 21.54% under reverse scan (V OC to J SC ) and an overall PCE of 20.88% with a V OC of 1.188 V, a J SC of 23.28 mA cm -2 , and a FF of 75.6% under forward scan. It shows a rapid increase in stabilized output PCE to a value of 21.4%, confirming the little hysteresis in our device. The superior performance of our MAPbI 3 -based PSCs is mainly attributed to the improved V OC , which shows an average value of 1.168 V, much higher than those of device doped by conventional LiTFSI/TBP (Figure  S16  and Table  S2 , Supporting Information).  [40, 41]  The J SC value obtained by integrating the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum is 22.8 mA cm -2 , which is consistent with the measured value (Figure  3b ). In some devices, we have measured a record V OC of 1.208 V and it has been confirmed by the V OC over time (Figure  3c ). The only 0.39 V loss-in-potential is one of the lowest energy losses recorded in PSCs and 91.5% of the S-Q limit in potential, implying the effectivity of our strategy. To verify our device efficiency measurements, we sent one of our unsealed devices to the National Institute of Metrology, China, for independent certification and obtained a PCE of 20.24% (V OC = 1.151 V, J SC = 23.16 mA cm -2 , and FF = 76.15%) (Figure  S17 , Supporting Information). It has been demonstrated the universality of our strategy to different HTLs, including poly (3-hexylthiophene) (P3HT), poly(9,9-dioctyl-fluorene-co-N-(4-butylphenyl)diphenylamine) (TFB), and poly (diketopyrrolopyrrole-terthiophene) (PDPP3T). It can be seen that all the PSCs based on FN-Br additive exhibits the V OC in a range of 1.1-1.2 V, which is much higher than those of referenced PSCs, with a value around 1 V (Figure  S18 , Supporting Information). The MAPbI 3 is used because it has a single phase and constant bandgap which are beneficial to exactly determine the V OC loss in device. At present, mix-cation based PSCs with a tunable bandgap show an efficiency advantage than MAPbI 3 based PSCs.  [4, [42] [43] [44]  Encouragingly, it is found that our strategy is effective regardless of composition of perovskite materials (Figure  S19 , Supporting Information). The results show that all of the devices based on double cation (MAFA, CsFA) or triple cation (CsMAFA) achieve an improvement of V OC through interfacial energy band management (Figure  S20 , Supporting Information). The device based on triple-cation (CsFAMA) perovskite exhibits a highest PCE of 20.6% with an improved V OC of 1.20 V from 1.06 V (Figure  S20 , Supporting Information). One of these devices even reaches a high V OC of 1.247 V (Figure  S21 , Supporting Information). However, compared with the MAPbI 3 based devices, our mix-cation based PSCs show a relative low performance mainly due to the reduced J SC or FF parameters (Figure  S20 , Supporting Information). It is because that halide segregation usually occurs during the device preparation, which leads to bandgap instabilities in mixed-halide perovskite systems, and thus reduces the performance and reproductivity of device (Figure  S22 , Supporting Information). The tailored N-I-P energy band configuration also delivered an improved EL performance when the MAPbI 3 -based PBDs were operated as LED mode under a bias voltage (Figure  3d ). The EQE EL -V characteristics of the best-performing PBDs show a maximum EQE EL of 4.3% at 2.3 V, which is among the highest values reported so far in PSCs  [12, 14, [19] [20] [21] [22] 45, 46]  and the EL emission peak is located at 772 nm. The EQE EL value can maintain above 4% at a high current density from 150 to 350 mA cm -2 mostly due to the improved balance of the electron/hole injection. Owing to the low interfacial energy barrier, the EQE EL of 2.6% can be attained for a driving current density of around the J SC of 23.2 mA cm -2 (Figure  3e ) and a nonradiative V OC loss of 98 mV has been achieved according to Equation (2). Figure  3f  shows the J-V and radiance versus voltage (L-V) characteristics of the champion bifunctional device, showing a high radiance and current density with a low driving voltage of 1.3 V due to the reduced energy losses from carrier injection and transport. We present a video in the SM showing that the device with FN-Br displayed an obviously visible red emission under ambient light. In Figure  S23  and Table  S3  in the Supporting Information, we give the time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) decays for the MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 /HTLs films with/ without FN-Br, which was fitted to a biexponential equation: Y = A 1 exp(-t/τ 1 ) + A 2 exp(-t/τ 2 ). We attributed quenching of the short PL lifetime to defect-induced nonradiative recombination and of the long PL lifetime to radiative recombination. When contacting the HTLs, the DFS can lead to PL quenching of perovskite due to charge extraction. Obviously, it is found that the suppression of the interfacial defect states by FN-Br can improve both short and long decay times in MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 /HTLs films, illustrating a reduced nonradiative recombination. It can be double confirmed by the improved external photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQYs) in FN-Br based films (Table  S4 , Supporting Information). The stability is the most important for the commercialization of perovskite photovoltaic device. Compared with the PSCs based on conventional additives TBP/LiTFSI, our PBDs show much better photovoltaic stability (Figure  4a, b ) since FN-Br is corrosion-free for the perovskite active layer (Figure  4c -f; Figure  S24 , Supporting Information). The unencapsulated devices stability has been tested under AM1.5 G Sun illumination at maximum power point (MPP) tracking in ambient air with ≈60% humidity (Figure  4a ). The device based on TBP/LiTFSI doped spiro-OMeTAD shows a rapid loss of PCE and only remains ≈30% initial value. However, the device with FN-Br/FK209 has an excellent stability, maintaining 95% of their initial performance after continuous operation for 4 h. In a nitrogen atmosphere, the control device showed a rapid loss of PCE within 2 h and retained &gt;85% of their initial PCE after continuous MPP for 25 h (Figure  S25 , Supporting Information), indicating that the additives of TBPs and Li-salt in spiro-OMeTAD play a vital role in stability. It has been demonstrated that the TBP can react with perovskite or evaporation, thus become the source of degradation  [47, 48]  (Figure  4c, e ). Encouragingly, as seen from the XRD results, no decomposition product was observed in perovskite film after FN-Br treatment (Figure  S26 , Supporting Information). As a result, the device based on FN-Br can maintain 92% of its initial photovoltaic performance after continuous operation for 500 h of MPP under 1-sun illumination. These results demonstrate the importance of corrosion-free interfacial materials for the stability of perovskite devices. In conclusion, we have demonstrated the effectiveness of interfacial energy band engineering using FN-Br for reducing the nonradiative recombination and maximizing the luminescence which are crucial for high PV as well as EL. FN-Br can turn the n-type surface of perovskite into p-type to form a welldefined N-I-P structure for device and thus tailor the interfacial energy band misalignment. The resultant SC/LED PBD achieves a high PV efficiency of up to 21.54% (certified 20.24%) and 4.3% EQE EL . Furthermore, by using nondestructive additives, the unsealed devices can maintain &gt;92% of their initial photovoltaic performance for 500 h under continuous operation at their maximum power point. Therefore, this corrosion-free interfacial energy band engineering opens an attractive route for the realization of high PV/ EL comprehensive performance of PBD with excellent stability. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FN-Br</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:28:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="5076" length="86"/>
        <text>corrosion-free 3,3′-(2,7-dibromo-9H-fluorene-9,9-diyl) bis(n,n-dimethylpropan-1-amine)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FN-Br</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:35:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="5163" length="6"/>
        <text>(FN-Br</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:28:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="5729" length="5"/>
        <text>N-I-P</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbI 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:27:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="5880" length="7"/>
        <text>MAPbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21.54</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:29:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="5931" length="5"/>
        <text>21.54</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">92</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:23:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="6142" length="3"/>
        <text>92%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:29:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="6209" length="5"/>
        <text>500 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:30:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="6218" length="50"/>
        <text>maximum power point (MPP) under 1-sun illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:30:20Z</infon>
        <location offset="6410" length="5"/>
        <text>N-I-P</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:30:32Z</infon>
        <location offset="6444" length="30"/>
        <text>ITO/ SnO 2 /perovskite/HTLs/Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:30:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="6882" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.29</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:37:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="7312" length="5"/>
        <text>17.29</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FN-Br</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:37:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="7554" length="5"/>
        <text>FN-Br</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.31</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:31:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="7662" length="5"/>
        <text>19.31</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:38:50Z</infon>
        <location offset="9169" length="87"/>
        <text>ITO/SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 (with and without treating by FN-Br solution)/Au and MAPbI 3 /DFS-Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:41:45Z</infon>
        <location offset="23462" length="53"/>
        <text>AM1.5 G Sun illumination at maximum power point (MPP)</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:41:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="23546" length="3"/>
        <text>60%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:44:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="23594" length="29"/>
        <text>TBP/LiTFSI doped spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">30</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:23:43Z</infon>
        <location offset="23667" length="4"/>
        <text>≈30%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:44:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="23712" length="11"/>
        <text>FN-Br/FK209</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">95</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:23:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="23764" length="3"/>
        <text>95%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-15T06:44:23Z</infon>
        <location offset="23828" length="3"/>
        <text>4 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">performance_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:59Z</infon>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:59Z</infon>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
        <node refid="22" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25697</offset>
      <text> Experimental Section Materials: The MAI, FAI iodide was purchased from Dyesol, and the lead iodide was purchased from TCI. The FN-Br powder was purchased from Lumitech Corp. Diethyl ether was purchased from Sinopharm Chemical Reagent limited corporation. Spiro-OMeTAD was purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corp. Indium tin oxide (ITO) substrate was purchased from Hangzhou Hong Shi Technology Corp. Other materials not specified were from Sigma-Aldrich. Solution Preparation: For the MAPbI 3 , the perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing 461 mg PbI 2 , 159 mg MAI in a mixed solvent of DMF/DMSO (632 µL/78 µL). For the mix-cation perovskite including Cs 0.05 FA 0.95 PbI 3 (CsFA), FA 0.83 MA 0.17 Pb(Br 0.17 I 0.83 ) 3 (FAMA), Cs 0.05 (MA 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 (CsFAMA), the perovskite precursor solution composed of mixed cations (lead (Pb), formamidinium (FA), methylammonium (MA) and (Cesium) Cs) and halides (I, Br) was dissolved in mixed solvent (DMF/DMSO = 4:1). For FN-Br solution, 15 mg FN-Br was dissolved in 1 mL CB. For FK209 solution, 1 mg FK209 was dissolved in 10 mL CB, forming a concentration of 0.1 mg mL -1 . For dopant-free spiro-OMeTAD (DFS) solution, pure spiro-OMeTAD was dissolved in CB solution with different concentration of 9, 18, 32, 48, 72 mg mL -1 , respectively. For DFS:FN-Br solution, 60 µL 15 mg mL -1 FN-Br CB solution was added into the 1 mL 20 mg mL -1 DFS CB solution. For, DFS:FN-Br:FK209 solution, 20 mg DFS powder and 60 µL FN-Br solutions (10 mg mL -1 ) was added into 1 mL FK209 CB solution of 0.1 mg mL -1 . For DFS:TBP:LiTFSI (traditional doping) solution, 72.3 mg spiro-OMeTAD, 17.5 µL solution of 520 mg mL -1 lithium bis (trifluoromethylsulfonyl) imide in acetonitrile, and 28.8 µL TBP were dissolved in 1 mL chlorobenzene. Device Fabrication: The ITO was cleaned sequentially in deionized water, cleaning fluid, acetone, and ethanol under sonication for 5 min, respectively. Then the ITO was dried by nitrogen gas and treated with a UV-ozone machine for 20 min. The SnO 2 ETLs were attained through spin coating the SnCl 2 • 2H 2 O ethanol solution (23 mg mL -1 ) with adding 0.5% graphene quantum dots (GQDs) water dispersion on the ITO.  [41]  The films were annealed in air at 180 °C and then treated with a UV-ozone machine for 5 min. The prepared MAPbI 3 solution was dropped on the ITO/SnO 2 substrates and then rapidly spin coated at 1000 rpm for 10 s and 5000 rpm for another 20 s. 0.6 mL of diethyl ether was drop casted quickly 15 s before the 5000 rpm spin coating ended. The perovskite films were heated at 70 °C for 1 min and 100 °C for 10 min on a hot plate, respectively. All the MAPbI 3 perovskite films were fabricated in air under a relative humidity below 45%. For the mixed-cation perovskite, the spin-coating procedure was performed by 1000 rpm for 5 s followed with 6000 rpm for 30 s. At 15 s before the last spin-coating step, 100 mL of CB was dropped onto the substrate. The mixed-cation perovskite films were heated at 100 °C for 30 min in N 2 glovebox. All the hole-transport materials were spin coated on the top of perovskite film at the rotation speed of 3000 rpm for 30 s in N 2 glovebox. At last, 100 nm thick Au electrodes were deposited under a high vacuum (&lt;1.0 × 10 -3 Pa). Current-Voltage Measurements: For all devices, photovoltaic performance was measured by masking on the active area with a metal mask (certified area was 0.08567 cm 2 ). The current density-voltage (J-V) curves of solar cells were measured a Keithley 2400 source meter with a solar simulator (94022A, Newport) under AM 1.5 G condition at an illumination intensity of 100 mW cm -2 , calibrated by a standard Si solar cell (PVM937, Newport) with KG5 filter. The J-V measurements were carried out in ambient air. The sweeping conditions were: reverse scan (1.4 V → -0.2 V, scan rate 10 mV s -1 , and delay time 200 ms) and forward scan (-0.2 V → 1.4 V, scan rate 10 mV s -1 , and delay time 200 ms). Stability Test: For the device stability in a nitrogen atmosphere, the test of the nonencapsulated solar cell was carried in a nitrogen glovebox and measured using a Keithley 2400 Source Measure Unit under100 mW cm -2 simulated 1.5 Global (AM 1.5 G) solar simulator (Enli Technology Co., Ltd., SS-F5-3A). The light intensity was calibrated by a standard Si solar cell solar cell (SRC-2020, Enli Technology Co., Ltd.). A 420 nm UV filter was applied when testing the stability. For the device stability in a ambient air, the test of the nonencapsulated solar cell was measured a Keithley 2400 source meter with a solar simulator (94022A, Newport) under AM 1.5 G condition at an illumination intensity of 100 mW cm -2 , calibrated by a standard Si solar cell (PVM937, Newport). KPFM Test: The KPFM mapping images were measured by Kelvin Probe (Bruker Dimension Icon system) in air. The type of cantilever used was NSG10/Pt (Chip size: 3.6 × 1.6 × 0.4 mm, length: 100 ± 5 µm, width: 35 ± 5 µm, resonant frequency: 190-325 kHz, force constant: 5.5-22.5 N m -1 ). Kelvin probe measurements were taken on the perovskite-Au and DFS-Au interface. To avoid the moisture, O 2 and organics in the air shift the WF of sample, the sample was measured once the preparation had been finished. Before measurement, each sample was stored in a single glass bottle filled with nitrogen, avoiding contamination by the ambient. Electrical &amp; Magnetic Lift Mode and Surface potential (AM-KPFM) mode were adopted. The drive frequency was 276 kHz. The lift scan height was 50 nm. The voltage was applied to the tip, and the work function of the sample was given by φ sample = φ tip -eV CPD . V CPD was the contact potential difference between the tip and sample. The HOPG was used as a reference to calibrate the tip WF and the measured WF of gold electrode was 5.1 eV. The WFs of perovskite or HTL could be attained according to their potential differences with Au. UPS and XPS Test: The samples were coated on the highly conductive and clean ITO substrates. UPS and XPS measurements were performed in two interconnected vacuum chambers, one for sample loading and the other for spectroscopy analysis with a base pressure at the order of 1 × 10 -9 Torr. The photoelectrons from UPS and XPS were counted with a hemispherical analyzer with an overall resolution of 0.05 eV, as determined from the width of the Fermi step measured on a gold substrate cleaned by Ar-ion sputtering. All the UPS measurements of the onset of photoemission for determining the work function were done using standard procedures with a -9.8 V bias applied to the sample. The spectra were recorded with an Imaging Photoelectron Spectrometer (Axis Ultra), with a nonmonochromated He Iα photon source (hν = 21.22 eV). The work function of a metal can be determined from the UPS spectrum using: WF = hν -E SECO , where hν = photon energy (21.22 eV) and E SECO = secondary electron Cutoff energy. An error of 0.12 eV was a typical value of the energy analyzer resolution. FTIR Spectroscopy Measurements: FTIR spectroscopy of pure FN-Br, PbI 2 /FN-Br, and MAPbI 3 /FN-Br thin film samples were performed using a on a Vertex 70 V (Bruker). Hall Measurement: The DFS film was prepared on a glass substrate by spin coating a 15 mg mL -1 DFS CB solution. All four electrodes were Au. Hall effect measurement was conducted on the DFS films. The majority carrier was determined to be holes based on the Hall voltage sign. The free hole carrier concentration (n) in DFS was attained by n = -IB/eV H t, where I is the applied bias current across the DFS, B is the magnetic field, V H is the measured Hall voltage, t is the thickness of the DFS (about 50 nm), and e is the elementary charge. LED Test: Electroluminescence was performed by applying different voltages to the device with Keithley 2400 Source Measure Unit. The device was placed on a Fiber Optic Integrating Sphere (FOIS-1), and the emitted photon flux was recorded by OceanView spectroscopy software with graphical user interface. The HL-3 plus Vis-NIR Calibrated Light Source was used to calibrate the Integrating Spheres. Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM): The SEM data were scanned by an S-4800 (Hitachi) field-emission scanning electron microscope (FESEM). Photoluminescence Spectroscopy: The time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectroscopy was measured with the PL spectrometer (Edinburgh Instruments, FLS 920). The samples were excited by a pulsed laser, with a wavelength and frequency of 635 nm and 1 MHz. A band pass filter at 655 nm was used to filter out the excitation light in the transient PL measurements. EQE Measurement: The EQE of solar cells was measured by an EQE measurement system (Model QEX10, PV Measurements, Inc.) across a wavelength range of 300-850 nm. DFT Calculation: The first-principles calculation was based on the density functional theory (DFT) and implemented in the Vienna Ab initio Simulation Package (VASP), with the frozen-core all-electron projectoraugment wave (PAW) method. The Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (PBE) of generalized gradient approximation (GGA) was adopted to describe the exchange and correlation potentials. A p(2 × 2) unit cell was considered for the (110) surface of MAPbI 3 , and the reciprocal space was sampled by a grid of (4 × 4 × 1) k-points using the Monkhorst-Pack method. A 15 Å vacuum region between the slabs was used to separate the surface from its periodic image in the direction along the surface normal. The geometry optimizations were performed until the forces on each ion were reduced below 0.03 eV Å -1 . The adsorption energies reported herein were calculated using the equation where E ads was the binding energy of adsorbate on MAPbI 3 (110), E adsorbate was the energy of the free adsorbate, E surface was the energy of the clean slab, and E adsorbate/surface was the energy of the adsorbate/ surface adsorption system. By this definition, a positive E ads implies a stable adsorption system. E E E E Figure S1 . S1 Figure S1. J-V characteristics of the devices based on DFS with different concentrations. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35821</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 . S2 Figure S2. SEM of the DFS-based PSCs with different thickness. The DFS-based device &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35922</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. Box and whisker plots to summarize the statistics distribution of the series &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36027</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 .Figure S5 . S4S5 Figure S4. V OC as a function of J SC in the device based on DFS and DFS:FN-Br. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36137</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 . S6 Figure S6. KPFM measurement of the DFS. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36194</offset>
      <text> Figure S7 . S7 Figure S7. The energy band structure of the DFS, perovskite/DFS and perovskite/DFS:FN-Br &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36300</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. Box and whisker plots to summarize the statistics distribution of the WFs for the &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36410</offset>
      <text> Figure S9 . S9 Figure S9. MAPbI 3 band structure. a) UPS, b) UV-absorption of the MAPbI 3 perovskite. c) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36517</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 . S10 Figure S10. Adsorbed FN-Br on the surfaces of perovskite. Pb, I, C, N, and H atoms are &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36623</offset>
      <text> Figure S11 . S11 Figure S11. Fourier transform infrared spectrometer (FTIR) of FN-Br, PbI 2 /FN-Br, &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36725</offset>
      <text> Figure S12 . S12 Figure S12.XPS spectra of Pb 4f of perovskite films with and without FN-Br treatment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36830</offset>
      <text> Figure S13 . S13 Figure S13. Box and whisker plots to summarize the statistics distribution of the performance &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36943</offset>
      <text> Figure S14 . S14 Figure S14. Box and whisker plots to summarize the statistics distribution of the performance &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37056</offset>
      <text> Figure Figure S15. J-V characteristics of the devices with and without FK209. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37136</offset>
      <text> Figure S16 . S16 Figure S16. Histogram of the V OC values among 114 devices with FN-Br. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37226</offset>
      <text> Figure S17 . S17 Figure S17. An independent testing report. One of our unsealed PSCs was independently &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37331</offset>
      <text> Figure . . Figure. S18. J-V characteristics of the devices with/without FN-Br based on different HTLs. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37436</offset>
      <text> Figure S19 .Figure S20 .Figure S19S20 Figure S19. J-V characteristics of the devices with and without FN-Br/FK209 based on &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37561</offset>
      <text> Figure S22 . S22 Figure S22. (a) A typcial PL of the mixed-cation based perovskite (CsFAMA) films with &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37666</offset>
      <text> Figure S23 . S23 Figure S23. Time-resolved photoluminescence decays spectra of MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 /HTLs &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37773</offset>
      <text> Figure S24 .Figure S25 .Figure S26 . S24S25S26 Figure S24. Photographs of the MAPbI 3 films after treatment by TBP chlorobenzene solution &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37913</offset>
      <text> ) Currently, photovoltaic/electroluminescent (PV/EL) perovskite bifunctional devices (PBDs) exhibit poor performance due to defects and interfacial misalignment of the energy band. Interfacial energy-band engineering between the perovskite and hole-transport layer (HTL) is introduced to reduce energy loss, through adding corrosion-free 3,3′-(2,7-dibromo-9H-fluorene-9,9-diyl) bis(n,n-dimethylpropan-1-amine) (FN-Br) into a HTL free of lithium salt. This strategy can turn the n-type surface of perovskite into p-type and thus correct the misalignment to form a well-defined N-I-P heterojunction. The tailored PBD achieves a high PV efficiency of up to 21.54% (certified 20.24%) and 4.3% EL external quantum efficiency. Free of destructive additives, the unencapsulated devices maintain &gt;92% of their initial PV performance for 500 h at maximum power point under standard air mass 1.5G illumination. This strategy can serve as a general guideline to enhance PV and EL performance of perovskite devices while ensuring excellent stability. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38956</offset>
      <text> Scheme 1 . 1 Scheme 1. Energy band structure of three types of device. a) SC with charge extraction alignment (type II), b) LED with charge injection alignment (type I), and c) PBD with barrier-free alignment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39168</offset>
      <text> ; FigureS6, Supporting Information). After introducing the FN-Br, the barriers of MAPbI 3 -Au and MAPbI 3 /DFS:FN-Br-Au are largely reduced and WF increases from ≈4.41 to ≈5.15 eV for perovskite, from ≈4.52 to ≈5.08 eV for MAPbI 3 /DFS (the value of WF can be calculated from the relationship shown in FigureS5in the Supporting Information), illustrating that the energy barrier among perovskite, DFS and Au has been almost eliminated. Separate ultraviolet photoemission spectroscopy (UPS) measurement further confirms that the role of FN-Br for the energy band adjustment. WFs of bare DFS, MAPbI 3 /DFS and MAPbI 3 /DFS:FN-Br are 4.8, 4.3, and 5.0 eV, respectively, according to the secondary electron cutoff spectrum (Figure2c; FigureS7, Supporting Information). The quantitative values of the WF measured by KPFM and UPS experiments are consistent with each other although they are carried out in different conditions (ambient condition vs ultrahigh voltage (UHV)). In addition, systematic KPFM measurements show that MAPbI 3 /DFS:FN-Br has a little deeper energy level with increasing the concentration of FN-Br (FigureS8, Supporting Information), approaching to energy alignment in Scheme 1c.Adv. Mater. 2019,31, 1902543    &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40407</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Schematic of PBD and the performance. a) Device structure of PBD with FN-Br and the schematic of SC/LED bifunctional mode in the same device. b) Current density-voltage (J-V) characteristics of the device based on DFS and DFS:FN-Br. Current density-voltage and radiance-voltage characteristics of the device based on DFS (c) and DFS:FN-Br (d). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40776</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. The effects of FN-Br on the energy band structure of PBD. a) KPFM measurements of the MAPbI 3 -Au interface based on a structure of ITO/ SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 (with or without FN-Br treatment)/Au. b) KPFM measurements of the DFS-Au interface based on a structure of ITO/SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 / DFS(with and without FN-Br additive)/Au. c) UPS spectra of the DFS, perovskite/DFS, and perovskite/DFS:FN-Br. d) Space-charge distribution and energy-band diagram of the device without FN-Br in thermal equilibrium, showing N-[N]-I-[N]-P -junction. e) Space-charge distribution and energyband diagram of the device with FN-Br in thermal equilibrium, showing N-[N]-I-[P]-P junction. f) Mott-Schottky plots of the devices with and without FN-Br. g) Current density-voltage curves for the electron-only and hole-only devices, showing that the FN-Br results in one order of magnitude increase in hole injection. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41688</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. PV/EL performance of the SC/LED PBDs. a) J-V curve of the highest photovoltaic performance device. The inset shows the stabilized power output of 21.4% at 1.0 V over 100 s. b). EQE spectrum and J SC integrated from the EQE spectrum of the champion device. c). J-V curve of the highest V OC device. The inset shows the V OC over 120 s resulting in 1.21 V. d) Best EQE electroluminescence as a function of voltage (photovoltaic performance: PCE of 21.1%, J SC of 23.2 mA cm -2 , V OC of 1.195 V, and FF of 76.1%). The left inset shows the corresponding EL spectrum over wavelength. The right area is operated as an LED displaying a clearly visible red emission under ambient light. e) EQE EL versus current density. The inset shows the EQE EL at an injection current that equals J SC . f) J-V and radiance versus voltage (L-V) characteristics of the PBD. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42566</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Photovoltaic stability a) Operation of unencapsulated control and FN-Br/FK209 based device under MPP Continuous for 500 h of an unsealed device with FN-Br/FK209 in a nitrogen atmosphere under1-sun illumination with a 420 nm cutoff UV filter. c,d) Photographs of the pristine MAPbI 3 films. e) Photograph of the MAPbI 3 film after treatment by TBP chlorobenzene solution. f) Photograph of the MAPbI 3 film after treatment by FN-Br chlorobenzene solution. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43045</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . Summary of the parameters for the devices based on different HTLs. S2 Sample DFS 1.035±0.02 22.56±0.18 69.3±3.0 16.43±0.92 FN-Br/DFS 1.12±0.04 22.48±0.32 70.50±2.35 17.62±0.950 (two-step) DFS:FN-Br 1.16±0.01 22.59±0.23 70.8±1.42 18.56±0.36 DFS:FN- 1.17±0.01 23.01±0.22 76.37±1.54 20.63±0.53 Br:FK209 DFS:TBP:LiTFS 1.11±0.01 23.03±0.27 75.36±1.51 19.37±0.47 I &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43437</offset>
      <text> Table S3 . τ 1 and τ 2 from PL decay spectra with different substrates. S3 Substrate τ 1 (ns) τ 2 (ns) A 1 (%) A 2 (%) τ (ns) MAPbI 3 57 161 32 68 128 MAPbI 3 /FN-Br 81 218 28 72 180 MAPbI 3 /DFS 2.4 18.1 20 80 15 MAPbI 3 /DFS:FN- 5.3 49.4 43 57 30 Br &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43696</offset>
      <text> Table S4 . PLQY of MAPbI 3 and MAPbI 3 /HTLs films on different substrates with and without FN-Br. S4 continuously tunable bandgap of the perovskite through chemical-composition engineering opens up applications for colorful perovskite light emitting diode (PLED). Sample PLQY (W/O FN-Br) PLQY (W/ FN-Br) Glass/MAPbI 3 2.18 11.2 Glass/MAPbI 3 /DFS 0.82 4.9 Glass/Al 2 O 3 /MAPbI 3 5.01 25.6 Glass/Al 2 O 3 /MAPbI 3 /DFS 1.12 7.8 ITO/MAPbI 3 1.2 3.16 ITO/MAPbI 3 /DFS 0.21 1.82 SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 1.3 5.34 SnO 2 /MAPbI 3 /DFS 0.32 3.46 DOI: 10.1002/adma.201902543 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44257</offset>
      <text>			 15214095, 2019, 33, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/adma.201902543 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License © 2019 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44669</offset>
      <text>			 15214095, 2019, 33, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/adma.201902543 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
