<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025024387GIIEED</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">0</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">0</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 12&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Record Open-Circuit Voltage Wide-Bandgap Perovskite Solar Cells Utilizing 2D/3D Perovskite Heterostructure&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>119</offset>
      <text>wide-bandgap organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites (WBPs) exhibiting a bandgap of E G ∼ 1.7-1.8 eV are a key focus of current research since they are ideally suited for the top absorber material in tandem PV architectures based on established low-bandgap PV technologies, such as the market-dominating crystalline Si waferbased solar cells or copper indium gallium diselenide (CIGS) thin-film devices. [11][12][13][14] In recent years, the record power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite/Si tandem solar cells rose quickly, reaching 26.4% for perovskite/Si tandem solar cells in 4-terminal configuration and 27.3% in 2-terminal configuration. A PCE of 23.9% was reported for perovskite/CIGS tandem solar cells. [12,15,16]  Moreover, WBPs are of key relevance for the emerging perovskite/perovskite thin-film tandem PV technology. [17]  For all of these perovskite-based multijunction solar cell technologies, promising first steps toward the upscaling to solar modules architectures have been demonstrated. [15,[18][19][20] In order to enable perovskite-based multijunction PV technologies to significantly outperform the market-dominating crystalline Si single-junction solar cells (record PCE of 26.6%), further advancement of WBP solar cells with regard to stability In this work, the authors realize stable and highly efficient wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells that promise high power conversion efficiencies (PCE) and are likely to play a key role in next generation multi-junction photovoltaics (PV). This work reports on wide-bandgap (≈1.72 eV) perovskite solar cells exhibiting stable PCEs of up to 19.4% and a remarkably high open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.31 V. The V OC -to-bandgap ratio is the highest reported for wide-bandgap organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite solar cells and the V OC also exceeds 90% of the theoretical maximum, defined by the Shockley-Queisser limit. This advance is based on creating a hybrid 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure. By spin coating n-butylammonium bromide on the doublecation perovskite absorber layer, a thin 2D Ruddlesden-Popper perovskite layer of intermediate phases is formed, which mitigates nonradiative recombination in the perovskite absorber layer. As a result, V OC is enhanced by 80 mV.&#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T14:20:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="2110" length="23"/>
        <text>n-butylammonium bromide</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2381</offset>
      <text>(2 of 10) and PCE is of uppermost importance.  [9, 10, 21]  WBPs conventionally consist of organic-inorganic mixed-halide lead perovskites, represented by the crystal structure ABX 3 . The bandgap (E G ) of these perovskites can be tuned by changing the stoichiometric ratio of Br and I at the halogen anion site X as well as the incorporation of Sn at the Pb cation site.  [22] [23] [24] [25] [26]  In order to circumvent the instabilities in WBPs with high Br content due to phase segregation, compositional engineering of the A cation site using methylammonium (MA), formamidinium (FA), Cesium (Cs), or Rubidium (Rb) was proven to be successful. Starting from double-cation (FA/Cs) compositions at the A cation site, a large variety of different A cation compositions has shown high PCE and enhanced stability, including both triple-cation (FA/MA/Cs) and quadruple-cation (FA/MA/Cs/Rb) compositions.  [12, 14, [27] [28] [29] [30]  In addition to the compositional engineering of the perovskite structure, several complementary strategies have been explored to further advance the stability and PCE, e.g., i) by controlling the crystallization of the perovskite film; ii) the incorporation of additives, such as Pb-(SCN) 2 , potassium or formamide; and iii) the use of surface passivation layers, such as quaternary ammonium halide anions or fullerenes like C 60 .  [31] [32] [33] [34] [35] [36] [37] [38]  Recently, 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures have emerged as a new concept to further enhance the stability and increase the open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of multication perovskite solar cells by employing alkylammonium organic cations (e.g., butylammonium (BA), phenylethylammonium iodide) in the perovskite structure.  [39] [40] [41] [42] [43] [44] [45] [46] [47]  The resulting 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures mitigate nonradiative recombination, resulting in an impressive V OC of 1.24 V for a bulk perovskite absorber bandgap of 1.72 eV.  [41]  There is virtue of layered perovskite materials that can be explored in the future for the Ruddlesden-Popper (RP) or 2D Dion-Jacobsen (DJ) families of perovskites.  [48, 49]  Despite the remarkable progress, the maximum V OC of all WBP solar cells in the optimal optical bandgap range for perovskite-based tandem PV (1.7-1.8 eV) remains limited to 1.24 eV (see Figure  1 ) and a PCE of 17.2%.  [50, 51]  In this work, a significant advance is demonstrated in this regard, making use of 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures. By depositing n-butylammonium bromide (BABr) on the 3D perovskite surface, a hybrid 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure is created at the interface toward the hole-extracting layer of the WBP solar cells (E G ∼ 1.72 eV). For very thin 2D perovskite layers, an unprecedented stable power output conversion efficiency (SPCE) of 19.4% and a V OC up to 1.31 V in planar architecture WBPs solar cells is demonstrated (see Figure  1  and Figure  S1 , Supporting Information). The WBP solar cells in focus of this study employ a doublecation perovskite absorber layer based on the cations FA and Cs in the composition Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 , exhibiting a bandgap of 1.72 eV (see Figure  S2 , Supporting Information), as first reported by McMeekin et al.  [27]  The devices were fabricated using the following planar device architecture: glass substrate, indium tin oxide (ITO) front electrode, nanoparticle-based SnO 2 electron transport layer (ETL), double-cation perovskite absorber layer (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ), 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis(N, N′-di-p-methoxy phenylamine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) hole transport layer (HTL) and Au back electrode (see Figure  2a ). The detailed device fabrication is presented in the Experimental Section. The reference device (without interlayer) exhibits a SPCE under constant illumination at AM 1.5G for 5 min of 16.7% and a V OC of 1.23 V (see Figure  2b, c ). By spin coating BABr dissolved in isopropanol (2 mg mL -1 ) on top of the perovskite absorber layer, an interlayer is introduced in between the bulk perovskite layer and the HTL. As shown later, this interlayer is likely composed of 2D-RP perovskite in intermediate phase of n = 2, resulting in a thin 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure at the hole-extracting side of the solar cell. The device incorporating the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure demonstrates a very high PCE of 19.8% and SPCE of 19.4% with less hysteresis under continuous illumination of one-sun irradiation intensity (AM 1.5G with 1000 W m -2 ) (see Figure  2b ,c and Figure  S3 , Supporting Information). Moreover, an enhancement in V OC of up to 80 mV is observed, leading to a stable unprecedented V OC for WBPs (E G ∼ 1.72 eV) of up to 1.31 eV (see Figures  1  and 2b,d ). This V OC reaches &gt;90% of the maximum V OC attainable for this bandgap according to the Shockley-Queisser limit (S-Q limit) and represents the highest ratio of qV OC /E G (0.76) reported for any perovskite solar cell of PCEs &gt; 13% (see Figure  1  and Table  S1 , Supporting Information). It shall be noted that the E G is determined in different ways for the various references provided in Figure  1 , which introduces a small inaccuracy (&lt;2%) in the comparison of qV OC /E G . In this work, we determine the bandgap from a Tauc plot, which is sufficient considering the sharp absorption edge of perovskites (see Figure  S2 , Supporting Information). While the ratio qV OC /E G serves as a coarse but convenient figure-of-merit to quickly examine the quality of any PV absorber material, the ratio of the experimental V OC to the maximum attainable V OC according to the S-Q limit represents a fundamental comparison to a hypothetical perfect solar cell Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 Figure  1 . Open-circuit voltage (V OC ) as a function of bandgap (E G ) for the best mixed-halide perovskite solar cells with decent PCE (&gt;13%) reported in the literature (gray circles) in comparison to the best V OC obtained in this work (red and black circle). The dash line indicates a V OC representing 90% of the maximum V OC for a certain E G defined by the S-Q limit. The gray region indicates the ideal top cell bandgap range (1.7-1.8 eV) for perovskite-based multijunction solar cells with a crystalline Si bottom solar cell. All references are provided in Table  S1  in the Supporting Information. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.24</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T21:57:12Z</infon>
        <location offset="4275" length="4"/>
        <text>1.24</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">butylammonium bromide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T21:57:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="4877" length="21"/>
        <text>butylammonium bromide</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.31</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T21:57:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="5207" length="4"/>
        <text>1.31</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T21:58:40Z</infon>
        <location offset="5702" length="314"/>
        <text>glass substrate, indium tin oxide (ITO) front electrode, nanoparticle-based SnO 2 electron transport layer (ETL), double-cation perovskite absorber layer (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ), 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis(N, N′-di-p-methoxy phenylamine)-9,9′-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) hole transport layer (HTL) and Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.8</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T21:59:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="6760" length="4"/>
        <text>19.8</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8740</offset>
      <text> (3 of 10) that exhibits exclusively radiative recombination and no nonradiative recombination losses.  [52] [53] [54]  Thus, the demonstrated high experimental V OC manifests the high quality of the presented 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure in the wide context of PV materials. Along with the improved V OC , the fill factor (FF) also increases (up to 0.78), without any loss in short-circuit current density (J SC ), indicating that the efficiency of charge extraction at low external fields is also very good. The stable and reproducible performance of the perovskite solar cells employing the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure is proven further by providing data on the statistics of a number of devices (&gt;29) that all demonstrate a significant V OC enhancement compared to the 3D reference perovskite devices (see Figure  2e ). Besides, devices with 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure exhibit stable V OC over time if kept under one-sun illumination (see Figure  2f ) and stable power output up to 20 h (see Figure  S3 , Supporting Information). The high V OC and PCE of WBP solar cells require optimization of the thickness of the 2D-RP perovskite interlayer, as presented in Figure  3 . Here, the statistics of the PV characteristics of several devices using 2D-RP perovskite interlayers processed by spin coating of BABr solution with various concentrations (2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 ) are provided. The V OC increases up to 1.32 V for a concentration of 5 mg mL -1 , but drops for higher concentrations. The FF and J SC increase slightly for an optimal concentration of 2 mg mL -1 compared to the reference case and decrease strongly for higher concentrations along with a significant increase in series resistance (see Table  S2 , Supporting Information). This trend is attributed to the low conductivity of the disordered 2D-RP perovskite interlayers and the expected increase in thickness of the interlayers with increasing BABr concentration (2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 ), which is indicated in the scanning electron microscope (SEM) images of the surface of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures (Figure  S4 , Supporting Information) and cross-sectional SEM images (Figures S5 and S6, Supporting Information).  [55, 56]  In addition, the absorptance spectra (Figure  S7 , Supporting Information) show a thickness reduction of the 3D perovskite layer explained by the increasing 2D-RP perovskites interlayer thickness along with increasing BABr concentration, which in turn also accounts for a reduction in short-current density. It should be noted further that the J SC derived from external quantum efficiency (EQE) measurements of the 3D reference perovskite and 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure solar cells treated with different BABr concentrations (2, 5, 7.5 mg mL -1 ) are 18.4, 18.6, 17.4, and 11.8 mA cm -2 , respectively, which is in good agreement (± 0.8 mA cm -2 ) with the J SC obtained from the J-V scans of the corresponding devices (see Figure  S8 , Supporting Information). In order to confirm that the interlayer formed by spin coating BABr solution on top of the perovskite is indeed a 2D-RP perovskite, X-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements were performed. The as-prepared double-cation perovskite thin-film exhibits the typical XRD peaks resulting from perovskite crystal plane diffraction of (100), (110), (111), and (200), corresponding to the Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 perovskite lattice (see Figure  4a ).  [31]  A very prominent new periodic diffraction pattern with peaks at 2θ ≈ 4.5°, 9.0°, 13   &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:01:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="9628" length="29"/>
        <text>exhibit stable V OC over time</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:02:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="9672" length="20"/>
        <text>one-sun illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:02:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="9741" length="4"/>
        <text>20 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:02:38Z</infon>
        <node refid="8" role=""/>
        <node refid="7" role=""/>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12285</offset>
      <text> (4 of 10) stars in Figure  4a ) and is well pronounced for the samples with high concentration BABr surface treatments (5 and 7.5 mg mL -1 ). This new periodic diffraction pattern corres ponds neither to the XRD pattern of the double-cation perovskite nor the pure precursor BABr (see Figure  S9 , Supporting Information). Instead, the additional periodic XRD peaks are characteristic for layers of stacked 2D perovskite material (superlattice), namely, a periodic pattern with Δ2θ ∼ 4.5° and peaks at low angles below the first diffraction peak of the 3D perovskite structure are indicative of a material with a larger unit cell.  [57] [58] [59] [60]  From the periodic diffraction pattern peaks and the fundamental Bragg's law of diffraction, the superlattice spacing of the 2D-RP perovskite interlayers, formed on top of the 3D perovskite layer, is determined to be around 2.0 nm (see Figure  S10 , Supporting Information). The XRD peaks of the 2D-RP perovskite are indexed based on the cell parameters (a = 8.559, b = 38.117, c = 8.770 Å, α = β = γ = 90°) found for the high-concentration (7.5 mg mL -1 ) BABr-coated sample. Comparing the cell parameters and the superlattice spacing to very similar 2D-RP perovskite materials reported in literature (e.g., (BA) 2 (MA)Pb n I 3n+1 with n = 2), the 2D-RP perovskite in this work is considered to be an intermediate phase with n = 2, which implies that the 2D-RP perovskite exhibits two unit cells of the perovskite crystal structure orthogonal to the 2D plane, as illustrated in Figure  4c .  [59, 60]  Given that BABr is a long-chain organic cation that commonly features the formation of the 2D-RP perovskite crystal structure (BA) 2 (B)Pb n I 3n+1 on CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 (where the B cation site is FA, Cs, or MA, and n is referring to the number of the intermediate phase), it is consistent that 2D-RP perovskites are created when the double-cation perovskite is exposed to BABr.  [31, 58]  This suggests that a 2D-RP perovskite of the structure BA y (Cs x FA 1-x ) 1-y Pb 2 (Br 0.4 I 0.6 ) 7 is formed, where x and y remain yet unknown. It should be noted that the distinct XRD pattern of the 2D-RP perovskite is not apparent in the overview XRD scan (see Figure  4a ) for the very thin interlayer prepared from a low-concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ), which nevertheless demonstrates optimal device performance (high V OC and stable PCE as shown in Figure  3 ). In order to confirm that the very thin interlayers also exhibit a 2D-RP perovskite material, extended XRD studies using higher X-ray intensities and long integration times were conducted with the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure prepared from 2 mg mL -1 BABr solution. As shown in Figure  4b , the samples using a thin interlayer indeed show a distinct peak at the same angle (4.5 and 9°) as the thicker 2D-RP perovskite interlayers. The significantly lower intensity and increased width of this XRD peak are attributed to the limited sensitivity of the XRD measurement to very thin superlattices of the 2D-RP perovskites formed on top of the bulk double-cation perovskite. Since the above reported XRD signal of layered 2D-RP perovskites originates from diffraction at superlattices of stacked 2D perovskite layers, these peaks are expected to be weak and broad as the number of stacked 2D perovskite layers is small for interlayers prepared from low-concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ). In addition to the previous material analyses, it should be noted that there are also further clear indications that the interlayers consist of the 2D-RP perovskite independent on the concentration Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15952</offset>
      <text> (5 of 10) of the BABr solution. For example, a characteristic reflectance maxi mum at ≈500 nm is observed for all samples with 2D-RP interlayer (see Figure  S11 , Supporting Information). This maximum in reflectance is not apparent for the double-cation reference. Top-view SEM images and atomic force microscopy (AFM) images further confirm the substantially modified surface. With increasing the concentration of BABr solution (&gt;2 mg mL -1 ), the surface morphology alters and reveals a disordered appearance which is very different from the characteristic features of the 3D perovskite layer. For the high BABr concentrations of 5 and 7.5 mg mL -1 , flake like features appear as reported for other 2D-RP perovskite layers without obvious changes to the bulk 3D double perovskite layer (see Figures  S4  and S12 , Supporting Information).  [31, 41]  In order to complement the XRD analyses of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure prepared from the low-concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ) with surface-sensitive characterization techniques, X-ray and UV photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS and UPS) experiments were performed. The XPS survey spectrum (see Figure  S13 , Supporting Information) of the 3D double-cation perovskite reference (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) shows emission lines of all expected elements (cesium, nitrogen, carbon, lead, iodine, and bromine). Compared to the 3D perovskite, the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure prepared from the low-concentration BABr (2 mg mL -1 ) exhibits an intensity decrease of the I, Pb, and Cs signals, an intensity increase of the Br lines, and significant changes in the spectral shapes of the C 1s and N 1s signals. To further investigate these changes, the C and N 1s, as well as the Cs 3d 5/2 , I 3d 3/2 , Pb 4f 5/2 , and Br 3d detailed spectra are presented in Figure  5  and Figure  S14  in the Supporting Information, respectively. The C 1s spectrum of the 3D reference exhibits two peaks at 284.3 and 288.0 eV. Upon addition of BABr, the spectral signature changes significantly (see Figure  5a ). The peaks indicative of the 3D double-cation perovskite decrease in intensity and a new feature between 284 and 287 eV is observed, which is attributed to the butylammonium cation on the surface of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure.  [61]  For the N 1s signal, a similar behavior is found: the peak at 400.2 eV, indicative for the 3D perovskite, decreases in intensity for the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure and an additional feature at ≈402 eV appears (see Figure  5b ). This feature is assigned to the amine group in the butylammonium cation of the 2D-RP perovskite layer.  [61]  In contrast to C 1s and N 1s, the spectral changes of the Cs 3d 5/2 , I 3d 3/2 , Pb 4f 5/2 , and Br 3d lines are less prominent (see Figure  S14 , Supporting Information). The detailed evaluation presented in the Supporting Information, reveals peak shifts between 68 meV (Cs 3d 5/2 ) and 175 meV (Br 3d) as well as a peak broadening for I 3d 3/2 , Pb 4f 5/2 , and Br 3d, indicative of a changed chemical environment for these elements. The qualitative XPS analysis thus corroborates the conclusions drawn from XRD analysis, namely, that also the 2D/3D perovskite   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19182</offset>
      <text> (6 of 10) heterostructure prepared from the low-concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ) exhibits a modified chemical surface environment of C, N, Pb, I, and Br, as expected for the 2D-RP perovskite. In addition to the changes in the chemical environment, the UPS measurements demonstrate that also the electronic structure at the surface of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure prepared from the low-concentration BABr (2 mg mL -1 ) differs from the 3D perovskite reference. As shown in Figure  6a , the work function decreases from 4.27 ± 0.05 to 3.94 ± 0.05 eV, i.e., by 0.33 ± 0.07 eV, as determined by a linear extrapolation of the secondary electron cutoff. Moreover, a substantial variation in the spectral shape over the whole energy range indicative for the different valence band/orbital structure of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure is observed (see Figure  6b ). To evaluate the change in valance band maximum (VBM), the corresponding energy region is magnified in Figure  6c  and the linear extrapolation of the leading edge gives 1.84 ± 0.10 eV for the VBM of the 3D perovskite, and 2.08 ± 0.10 eV for the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure.  [62]  It should be noted that the VBM of the reference is slightly larger than the bulk bandgap of 1.72 eV, which is an indication of a possible bandgap widening at the perovskite surface. Surface bandgap widening can be helpful in suppressing interface recombination and is also found in Cu(In,Ga)(S,Se) 2 -based solar cells, where a widened bandgap at the absorber surface is revealed to be a key property to achieve high efficiencies.  [63] [64] [65]  In addition, the VBM of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure shifts down by 0.24 eV as compared to the 3D perovskite reference (see Figure  6d ). This downward shift, in conjunction with the decrease of the work function and the shifts of the XPS signals of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure, suggests a downward band bending (i.e., shift of all energy levels). However, as the average XPS shift of 0.12 eV is smaller than the VBM shift, the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure might feature a further bandgap widening at the 2D/3D surface as also confirmed by further PL measurements (see Figure  S15 , Supporting Information). Such a bandgap widening due to the BABr treatment and, in particular, the additional downward band bending at the surface along with an unchanged bandgap of the bulk 3D perovskite (see Figure  S2 , Supporting Information) are expected to be beneficial for the operation of the solar cells with 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure as they can reduce interface recombination. Reduced interface recombination will, in turn, lead to an increase in V OC , which is also observed in the devices shown in Figures  1  and 2 . This strongly suggests that the band alignment in the wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells presented in this work is improved by the addition of BABr. Having demonstrated that the performance enhancement is due to the existence of a 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure based on the formation of a 2D-RP perovskite interlayer before the HTL, the photophysics of the material is now investigated to determine the causes for the performance increase, in particular Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22444</offset>
      <text> (7 of 10) the enhancement in V OC . Recent literature has established that the V OC is highly sensitive to interfacial recombination at the spiro-OMeTAD/perovskite interface (which in turn is sensitive to the concentration of dopants and additives in spiro-OMeTAD), and to the Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH)-type nonradiative recombination in the bulk.  [66, 67]  In a first step, the ideality factor (n id ) of the perovskite solar cells with and without 2D-RP perovskite interlayer is examined by light intensity-dependent V OC measurements, in accordance with established procedures.  [67]  For the reference solar cells without 2D-RP perovskite interlayer, the n id is found to be ≈1. 35 (Figure  S15  and Table  S3 , Supporting Information), representing a low dependence of V OC on the light intensity in the reference device (≈78 mV dec  -1  ). An n id in the range of 1 and 2 indicates that at least two (likely three) dominant recombination mechanisms with n id = 1 and n id = 2 coexist. Among the recombination mechanisms leading to n id = 1, radiative recombination as well as surface recombination are prominent candidates.  [67]  The recombination mechanism that leads to an n id = 2 in perovskite solar cells is typically assigned to bulk SRH recombination.  [66]  The n id decreases to 1.18 for the solar cells using a thin 2D-RP perovskite interlayer prepared by the low concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ). Given that the solar cell parameters are broadly comparable for both the samples, the decrease in n id indicates that the recombination mechanism that leads to n id = 2 (bulk SRH) is mitigated by the thin 2D-RP perovskite interlayer, which again is consistent with the enhanced V OC in these devices (see Figure  2 ) and the time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) discussed below. In order to understand the extent to which the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure can help to reduce nonradiative recombination and enhance the lifetime of the charge carriers in the device, both steady-state and transient PL spectroscopy were performed. For these measurements, the samples were prepared on glass substrates to avoid lifetime quenching due to electron extraction. In Figure  7a , the PL spectra from films of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures that were processed by the deposition of different concentrations of BABr are compared with a reference 3D double-cation perovskite layer. In all cases, the PL intensity is increased by the 2D layer, the peak position of the PL is shifted to higher energy (from 1.70 to 1.72 eV), and the full-width at half-maximum (FWHM) is narrowed (from 0.128 to 0.115 eV). This is consistent with a reduction of nonradiative recombination, and also fewer tail states below the absorption edge. In addition to the PL from the low-bandgap material, Figure  7b  confirms that higher energy PL peaks centered around 2.3 eV (540 nm) are observed for the 2D-RP perovskite interlayer prepared from high-concentrated BABr solutions (5 and 7.5 mg mL -1 ) for an excitation with 3.1 eV (400 nm) photons. The PL spectra feature two emission maxima (2.2 and 2.4 eV). This points toward a more complex scenario such as: i) two intermediate phases; ii) the appearance of exciton states; or iii) reabsorption Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 Figure  7 . PL spectroscopy. a) PL spectra (excitation wavelength 480 nm) of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures processed by the deposition of different concentrations of BABr (2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 ) on top of the 3D double-cation perovskite. b) Higher energy PL peaks centered around 2.3 eV (540 nm) observed for the 2D-RP perovskite interlayer prepared from high-concentrated BABr solutions (5 and 7.5 mg mL -1 ) for an excitation with 3.1 eV (400 nm). c) TRPL measurements were conducted to compare the lifetimes of the double-cation perovskite reference layer to double-cation perovskite layers with 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures. d) TRPL measurements of the same samples as in (c), but with a spiro-OMeTAD HTL, to examine hole extraction through the 2D-RP perovskite interlayers. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:24:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="22585" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:24:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="26436" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26528</offset>
      <text> (8 of 10) of emitted light.  [68]  Irrespective, these high-energy PL peaks correspond roughly to the bandgap of the 2D-RP perovskite and are absent in the reference sample, and also not apparent in the sample prepared from low concentration BABr solution (2 mg mL -1 ) due to the low thickness of these layers as discussed above. This observation of the additional high-energy PL peaks emerging further confirms the XRD and XPS/UPS results presented previously, which suggest the growth of a 2D-RP perovskite on top of the underlying 3D perovskite, and also with observations of higher-energy luminescence from 2D-RP perovskite structures on top of a 3D perovskites reported in the literature.  [45, 47]  It should also be noted that the PL emission related to the 2D-RP perovskite on top of the underlying 3D perovskite is only apparent for PL measurements excited from the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure side (see Figure  S16 , Supporting Information), which shows that the 2D-RP perovskite is not mixed into the entire 3D perovskite, but is concentrated at the HTL contact. Following this, TRPL measurements were performed in order to ascertain how the deposition of the 2D interlayer before the spiro-OMeTAD layer affects the process of hole extraction. Figure  7c  compares the lifetimes of the doublecation perovskite reference layer to double-cation perovskite layers with 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures. In particular, for the interlayers with the best device performance (2 mg mL -1 ), the enhancement in lifetime is very strong. This indicates that the deposition of the 2D-RP perovskite passivates the 3D double-cation perovskite layer and reduces the nonradiative recombination, but that the 2D-RP perovskite interlayer does not extract a large portion of holes from the 3D layer (which would quench the PL signal). Furthermore, Figure  7d  presents the TRPL series for samples with spiro-OMeTAD layer, to examine the hole extraction through the 2D-RP perovskite interlayers. The TRPL lifetime is substantially reduced upon the addition of the HTL for the reference and for the thin 2D-RP perovskite interlayer sample (2 mg mL -1 BABr solution), whereas for the samples with thicker 2D-RP perovskite interlayers (5 and 7.5 mg mL -1 BABr solution), the lifetime remains similar to the samples without the spiro-OMeTAD. These results demonstrate that hole extraction into the spiro-OMeTAD layer can occur for the thin 2D-RP interlayer, but is significantly hindered by thicker layers. This is consistent with the 2D-RP perovskite interlayer introducing a series resistance to the cells, which has the effect of significantly reducing FF at higher thicknesses, as observed in the device data (see Figure  3c  and Table  S2 , Supporting Information). However, by passivating the double-cation perovskite absorber layer, and improving the known-to-be-problematic perovskite/spiro-OMeTAD interface, the thin 2D-RP perovskite interlayer can improve all aspects of photovoltaic performance, most drastically the V oc . In summary, this work reports on a novel hybrid 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure that provides passivation while maintaining fast carrier extraction at the hole-extracting side of wide-bandgap hybrid organic-inorganic mixed-halide perovskite solar cells. By coating BABr on the double-cation perovskite absorber layer, a 2D-RP perovskite interlayer of intermediate phase (n = 2) is formed in between the absorber layer and the HTL. Given the limited conductivity of disordered 2D-RP perovskite layers, only very thin interlayers provide the passivation of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure while being compatible with a fast hole extraction. The resulting device performance and high open-circuit voltage, reach an unprecedented 19.4% in PCE for wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells (≈1.72 eV) along with a V OC of up to 1.31 V. This corresponds to the highest observed ratio of V OC over the maximum possible V OC based on the S-Q limit, as well as the highest ratio qV OC /E G (of 0.76) reported for a WBP solar cell. These results inspire a pathway to further raise the V OC for perovskite absorber materials of other bandgaps by engineering the HTL interface. This will become particularly important for the next-generation high-efficiency perovskite-based tandem PV, addressing PCEs above 30% in the near future. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">hole_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Spiro-OMeTAD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:25:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="27731" length="12"/>
        <text>spiro-OMeTAD</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.31</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:25:29Z</infon>
        <location offset="30381" length="4"/>
        <text>1.31</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30881</offset>
      <text> Experimental Section Device Fabrication: The devices were fabricated in planar device architecture: glass/ITO/SnO 2 /Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 /spiro-OMeTAD/ Au. The glass substrates with 120 nm thick ITO coating (sheet resistance 15 Ω □ -2 , Luminescence Technology, CAS: 50926-11-9) were cleaned in 10 min ultrasonic bath with deionized (DI) water, acetone, and isopropanol followed by 3 min of oxygen plasma treatment. A thin (≈30 nm) SnO 2 ETL was deposited on the ITO substrate by spin coating (4000 rpm for 30 s), followed by an annealing step at 250 °C for 30 min and oxygen plasma treatment for 1 min. The SnO 2 precursor solution was prepared by diluting a 15 wt% aqueous colloidal dispersion of SnO 2 nanoparticles (Alfa Aesar) in DI water to a concentration of 2.04 wt%. The precursor solution of the Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 perovskite absorber layer was prepared by dissolving 0.83 mmol formamidinium iodide (Dyesol, CAS: 879643-71-7), 0.17 mmol CsI (Alfa Aesar, CAS: 7789-17-5), 0.4 mmol PbI 2 (Alfa Aesar, CAS: 10101-63-0), and 0.6 mmol PbBr 2 (Alfa Aesar, CAS: 10031-22-8) in a 1 mL solvent mixture of N,Ndimethylformamide (CAS: 68-12-2):dimethylsulfoxide (CAS: 67-68-5) 4:1 (v:v). The double-cation perovskite absorber layer was deposited from solution by a two-step spin coating process: i) 1000 rpm for 10 s, ii) 5000 rpm for 30 s. Chlorobenzene (100 µL) was poured on the spinning substrate 10 s before the end of the second step. The samples were annealed at 100 °C for 30 min in inert atmosphere. The interlayers were processed by spin coating (5000 rpm for 30 s) 100 µL of BABr (Dyesol, CAS: 15567-09-6) dissolved in isopropanol (Sigma-Aldrich, CAS: 67-63-0) (concentration of 2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 ) on top of the perovskite absorber layer and a subsequent annealing at 100 °C for 5 min in inert atmosphere. As an HTL, spiro-OMeTAD was deposited by spin coating (4000 rpm for 30 s). The corresponding precursor solution contained 80 mg spiro-OMeTAD (Luminescence Technology) dissolved in 1 mL chlorobenzene with the additives 17.5 µL lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl) imide (520 mg mL -1 in acetonitrile) and 4-tert-butylpyridine (28.5 µL). The samples coated with spiro-OMeTAD were exposed to dry air for ≈12 h before a 60 nm thick Au electrode was deposited by thermal evaporation through shadow masks to define the active area to 0.105 cm  2  . Device Characterization: Current-Density-Voltage (J-V) Measurements: The J-V characteristics were measured with a Newport solar simulator (Oriel Sol3A) providing an AM 1.5G solar irradiation spectrum in both forward and backward direction. The solar simulator was calibrated with a certified Si photodiode (Fraunhofer ISE) equipped with a KG5 band pass filter. The stable PCE of the perovskite solar cells was determined by the power output at constant voltage close to the maximum power point under continuous AM 1.5G illumination under continuous AM 1.5G illumination. The temperature of the devices (25 °C) was actively controlled by a Peltier element connected to a microcontroller while conducting the J-V analyses and MPP tracking. SEM: High-resolution field emission cross-sectional and topview SEM images of high-bandgap perovskite films with the different treatment concentrations of 0, 2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34213</offset>
      <text> (9 of 10) taken with a scanning electron microscope (Zeiss LEO1530) with an in-lens detector and an aperture size of 20 µm. UV/Vis Spectrophotometry: The absorbtance, transmitance, reflectance, and EQE spectra of the perovskite layers and devices were measured with a Bentham PVE300 Photovoltaic Device Characterization System by illuminating the solar cell with modulated monochromatic light. A chopper frequency in the range of 400 Hz was used. XRD: The crystal structure of perovskite layers with different treatment concentrations were examined by XRD (D2Phaser from Bruker) with Cu K α radiation (λ = 1.5405 Å) in Bragg-Brentano configuration using a LynxEye detector. The XRD data were taken from unfinished devices on the same layer sequence as the perovskite solar cell, but excluding the Au electrode and the spiro-OMeTAD HTL. High-resolution XRD was performed by a Bruker D8 DISCOVER system with Cu-K α radiation in Bragg-Brentano configuration. Steady-State and TRPL) Spectroscopy: Transient PL measurements were performed using a streak camera system (Hamamatsu Universal Streak Camera C10910) coupled to a spectrometer (Acton SpectraPro SP2300). The streak camera was used in single sweep mode to allow for a 1000 ns time window and an FWHM of the instrumental response function of 20 ns. For the excitation, a mode-locked Ti:sapphire laser (Coherent, Chameleon Ultra) with a pulse width of 140 fs and a repetition rate of 80 MHz was used. The 960 nm output was frequency doubled by a second harmonic generator (Coherent, Chameleon Compact OPO-Vis) and the repetition rate was reduced to 0.7 MHz using a pulse picker (APE pulseSelect). All transient PL spectra were measured with a pump fluence of 46 nJ cm -2 . The steady-state PL spectra were either measured with a spectrofluorometer (Varian Cary Eclipse) using an excitation wavelength of 480 nm or a fiber-coupled UV/vis spectrometer (Avantes, AvaSpec-2048L) and excitation at 400 nm by the previously described mode-locked laser. XPS and UPS: For XPS and UPS, the samples were sealed under Ar gas and introduced into the ultra-high vacuum (UHV) system via an Ar-filled glovebox without air exposure.  [69]  The UHV experimental system in the Materials For Energy (MFE) lab at KIT was equipped with an Omicron Argus CU electron analyzer, a DAR 450 twin anode (Mg K α and Al K α ) X-ray source, and a He gas discharge lamp. The energy scale for XPS was calibrated according to Moulder et al. and for UPS by measuring the energy position of a sputter-cleaned Au foil.  [70]  During all UPS measurements, a bias of -15 V was applied to the sample. In order to avoid beam-induced changes due to X-rays or UV radiation, prior to the reported measurements extensive time-resolved measurements were performed to characterize beam damage. Based on this study, measurement times of 3 min (or less) for UPS and 10 min (or less) for XPS were determined suitable to avoid an influence of beam-induced changes on the spectra. Table  S1 . Photovoltaic performance metrics of state-of-the-art organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite solar cells with high V OC for bandgaps ranging from 1.5-1.8 eV and a PCE &gt; 13%.    reference double cation surface topography, d-f) 2 mg/mL, g-i) 5 mg/mL, and j-l) 7.5 mg/mL of BABr dissolved in isopropanol. The data confirms the gradual change of the surface of the 3D perovskite layer. It is hypothesized that 2D flakes appear on the 3D perovskite layer for the samples treated with higher concentrations of BABr (5 and 7.5mg/mL). The data o fthe height sensor (a), (d), (g), and (j) contains the information on the surface topography of the samples. Amplitude error (b), (e), (h), and (k) is shown for a better illustration of the contrast. The phase images (c), (f), (i), and (l) represent the phase changing while the sensor is scanning the surface morphology. We observe peak shifts between 68 meV (Cs 3d 5/2 ) and 175 meV (Br 3d), which we attribute to changes in band bending. The difference spectra in the lower panel highlight the changes in the chemical environment caused by the addition of BABr. For the Cs 3d 5/2 , the difference shows only noise, which suggests that the chemical environment of Cs is not altered by the addition of BABr. In contrast, the I 3d 3/2 , Pb 4f 5/2 , and Br 3d difference spectra reveal additional spectral weight, and their full-width-at-half-maxima (FWHM) increase. Both findings indicate that some of the Pb, I and Br atoms are present in a modified chemical environment at the surface of the 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure, compared to the 3D perovskite reference. Note that the additional spectral weight seen in the difference spectra is not a quantitative measure of the number of "modified" atoms. (c)    &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38962</offset>
      <text> PL emission Glass Glass 2D/3D Pero. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39000</offset>
      <text> PL emission 2D/3D Pero. Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Device architecture and photovoltaic performance. a) Schematic of the solar cell based on wide-bandgap Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 perovskite thin-film absorber layers with 2D-RP interlayer processed by depositing BABAr solution on top of the perovskite. b) J-V characteristic of champion devices with and without BABr (2 mg mL -1 ) passivation layer measured from reverse (open symbols) and forward (closed symbols) scans under AM 1.5G (1000 W m -2 ) irradiation. c) SPCE under continuous illumination of the champion devices. d) Steady-state open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of the champion device measured at continuous illumination (AM 1.5G). e) Histogram of V OC and (f) PCE for a total of 48 devices fabricated without and with BABr treatment (2 mg mL -1 ), respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39831</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Photovoltaic parameters determined form the J-V characteristic of a statistically relevant number (&gt;70 in total) of double-cation perovskite solar cells (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) with and without 2D-RP perovskite interlayer, processed by BABr treatment with various concentrations of 0, 2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 : a) PCE, b) open-circuit voltage (V OC ), c) short-circuit current density (J SC ), and d) fill factor (FF). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40289</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Crystal structure. a) Overview XRD diffraction pattern of the perovskite film with and without 2D-RP perovskite interlayers processed by spin coating of BABr on top of the (Cs 0.17FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) absorber layer in various concentrations of 2, 5, and 7.5 mg mL -1 . The typical XRD peaks resulting from perovskite crystal plane diffraction of (100), (110), (111), and (200) are corresponding to the Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 perovskite lattice. New peaks appear upon spin coating of BABr on top of the absorber (denoted by stars). The new peaks are related to periodic diffraction at the superlattice of stacked 2D perovskite interlayers of intermediate phase n = 2 and a superlattice spacing of 2.0 nm. b) Extended XRD studies with higher X-ray intensities and longer integration times were conducted showing the same peaks as for the samples with thicker 2D-RP interlayers. c) Schematic representations of the 2D-RP perovskite and relevant spacing. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41288</offset>
      <text> Figure 6 . 6 Figure 6. UPS measurements of a) the secondary electron cutoff, b) the valence band, and c) the VBM region of the 3D perovskite and the 2D/3D perovskite. A sputter-cleaned Au foil and its Fermi edge (green) are used for energy calibration. The work function and VBM were determined with a linear extrapolation of the secondary electron cutoff (±0.05 eV) and the leading edge of the valence band (±0.10 eV), respectively. d) Schematic of the energy levels of the corresponding samples. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41790</offset>
      <text> Figure 5 . 5 Figure 5. XPS spectra of a) the C 1s region and b) the N 1s region of the 3D perovskite (black) and the 2D/3D perovskite (red) treated with 2 mg mL -1 BABr. The spectral changes of the Cs 3d 5/2 , I 3d 3/2 , Pb 4f 5/2 , and Br 3d lines are shown in Figure S14 in the Supporting Information. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42096</offset>
      <text> Figure S1 . S1 Figure S1. Power conversion efficiency (PCE) of mixed-halide perovskite solar cells &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42197</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 .Figure S4 . S3S4 Figure S3. Stable power output conversion efficiency (SPCE) of the 2D/3D perovskite &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42311</offset>
      <text> Figure S5 .FigureFigure S7 .Figure S8 .Figure S9 . S5S7S8S9 Figure S5. Cross-section SEM image of the layer stacks without 2D interlayer a) and with &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42462</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 .Figure S11 .Figure S12 . S10S11S12 Figure S10. Superplastic spacing estimation of 2D-RP interlayers from the periodic &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42594</offset>
      <text> Figure S13 .Figure S13 Figure S13. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) of the 3D perovskite (black) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42699</offset>
      <text> Figure S15 .( 1 )( 2 ) 1 ( 4 ) 27 Figure S16 . S15121427S16 Figure S15. Diode ideality factor derived from light-intensity dependent open-circuit voltage &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42855</offset>
      <text> .5°, 18.0°, 22.6°, and 27.2° appears (denoted by Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42946</offset>
      <text> -1 BABr solution were Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 16146840, 2019, 21, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aenm.201803699 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>43362</offset>
      <text> Table S2 . S2 Photovoltaic parameters of wide-bandgap double-cation perovskite solar cells processed in the planar device architecture glass/ITO/SnO 2 /FA 0.83 Cs 0.17 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 /spiro-Direct optical bandgap determined by the Tauc plot method for wide-bandgap double-cation perovskite layers (FA 0.83 Cs 0.17 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 ) with a 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure processed by various concentrations of BABr (2, 5, 7.5 mg/mL). No considerable changes in the bandgap are apparent, indicating that the bandgap of the 3D bulk perovskite is not changed by the treatment with the BABr solution. It should be noted that the Tauc plot is based on an effective absorption coefficient α eff accounting for the full Perovskite Architectur e Eg (eV) VOC (V) JSC (mA/cm 2 ) FF PCE (%) SPCE (%) g qVOC/E Ref CH3NH3PbI3-xClx n-i-p planar 1.55 1.13 22.7 0.75 19.3 N.A. a 0.72 Csx(MA0.17FA0.83)(100-x)Pb(I0.83Br0.17)3 2 planar 1.6 1.23 N.A. N.A. N.A. N.A. 0.76 14 16 18 20 22 BA0.05(FA0.83Cs0.17)0.95Pb(I0.8Br0.2)3 (a) BA-MAPbI3 MAPbI3 (Rb/Cs/MA/FA)PbIBr (Rb/Cs/MA/FA)PbIBr OMeTAD/Au: (1) Reference and 2D/3D heterostructure fabricated by spin coating of BABr 70% S-Q limit Literature 2D/3D Pero.* 3D Ref.* 1S 2S 3S 4S 5S 6S 7S 22S 24S p-i-n planar 1.57 1.11 22.5 0.78 19.56 N.A. 0.70 p-i-n planar 1.59 1.17 21.8 0.78 19.89 N.A. 0.73 n-i-p planar 1.61 1.14 22.7 0.8 20.6 19.5 0.70 mesoporous 1.63 1.24 N.A. N.A. N.A. N.A. 0.76 mesoporous 1.63 1.18 22.8 0.81 21.8 21.6 6 (eV/cm) 0.72 (CsI)0.17(FAI)0.83(PbI2)0.4(PbBr2)0.6 Planar 1.79 1.28 17.2 0.73 N.A 16.5 0.72 dissolved in isopropanol (concentration (2) 2 mg/mL, (3) 5 mg/mL, and (4) 7.5 mg/mL) on 9 4 * 10 3D Ref. PCE (%) 7S 7S 12S 10S 13S 12S 14S 18S 19S 25S FAxMA1-xPbBryI1-y mesoporous 1.64 1.14 22.7 0.76 20.7 N.A. 0.69 Cs0.15(CH5N2)0.85Pb(I0.71Br0.29)3 Planar 1.72 1.22 15.4 0.73 -13.8 Sample Scan direction JSC mA/cm² VOC (V) FF PCE (%) Rs (Ω) 1.7 1.8 1.9 2.0 0 0.70 15S 8S 16S 17S 20S 23S Cs0.1FA0.74MA0.13PbI2.48Br0.39 mesoporous 1.62 1.14 22.73 0.76 20.08 N.A. 0.70 (FA0.95PbI2.95)0.85(MAPbBr3)0.15 p-i-n planar 1.62 1.17 21.9 0.81 20.9 20.9 0.72 CH3NH3PbI3 Planar 1.6 1.26 20.5 0.76 20.5 20 0.78 top of the perovskite absorber layer. 2 2 2 mg/mL hu) 5 mg/mL (a eff 7.5 mg/mL (1) Reference a) N.A.: not available FAxMA1-xPbBryI1-y (1) Reference 12 1.6 (*this work) JSC -&gt; VOC N.A. 1.66 1.7 18.9 11S 1.10 VOC -&gt; JSC 19.2 hu (eV) 1.8 1.22 18.3 1.24 0.69 0.66 0.74 16.2 13.2 17.5 N.A. 47.3 0.66 46.0 Bandgap E G (eV) n-i-p planar 1.68 1.1 19.3 N.A. 1.68 1.18 19.1 N.A. 1.68 1.15 23.7 n-i-p planar 1.71 1.2 19.7 n-i-p planar 1.72 1.18 19.8 n-i-p planar 1.72 1.10 17.3 n-i-p planar 1.72 1.02 17.5 VOC -&gt; JSC 19.3 1.31 JSC -&gt; VOC 19.3 1.31 VOC -&gt; JSC 18.2 1.32 JSC -&gt; VOC 18.3 1.28 VOC -&gt; JSC 12.4 1.18 JSC -&gt; VOC 11.9 1.15 Figure S2. perovskite layer stack (2D perovskite + 3D perovskite). Since the 2D perovskite layer has a Cs0.25FA0.75PbI2.4Br0.6 0.82 17.5 N.A. 0.65 FAxMA1-xPbBryI1-y 0.65 14.7 N.A. 0.70 FAxMA1-xPbBryI1-y 0.76 18.5 N.A. 0.68 (FA0.83MA0.17)0.95Cs0.05Pb(I0.6 Br0.4)3 0.78 18.3 18.2 0.70 BA0.09(FA0.83Cs0.17)0.91Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 0.73 17.2 17.3 0.68 MAPb(Br0.2I0.8)3 0.82 15.9 N.A. 0.63 10 MAPb(I0.8Br0.2)3 0.74 13.1 N.A. 0.59 11 (2) Treated w. BABr (2 mg/mL) 0.78 19.8 43.2 (2) Treated w. BABr (2 mg/mL) 0.75 19.2 43.3 (3) Treated w. BABr (5 mg/mL) 0.60 14.7 291.4 (3) Treated w. BABr (5 mg/mL) 0.58 13.54 378.9 (4) Treated w. BABr (7.5 mg/mL) 0.49 7.1 1814.4 (4) Treated w. BABr (7.5 mg/mL) 0.47 6.4 3245.8 BZA-Cs0.15FA0.85PbI2.19Br0.81 noticeable thickness and partially replaces the 3D perovskite layer with increasing BABr mesoporous 1.72 1.24 19.8 0.73 18.13 17.1 0.72 12 FA0.83MA0.17Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 w/ QAH passivation concentration, the slop of the Tauc plot decreases with increasing thickness of the 2D layer. p-i-n planar 1.72 1.15 19.4 0.77 17.2 N.A. 0.66 13 FA0.75MA0.15Cs0.1Rb0.05 Pb(I0.67Br0.33)3 mesoporous 1.73 1.13 N.A. N.A. 17.4 17.3 0.65 14 FA0.83Cs0.17Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 n-i-p planar 1.74 1.2 19.4 0.75 17.1 16 0.68 15 Cs0.40FA0.60PbI2.1Br0.9 p-i-n planar 1.75 1.17 17.5 0.8 16.3 N.A. 0.70 FA0.8Cs0.2Pb(I0.7Br0.3)3 w/ Pb(SCN)2 additive n-i-p planar 1.75 1.23 18.5 0.79 17.7 17.18 0.70 16 FA0.8Cs0.2Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 w/ FA additive n-i-p planar 1.75 1.23 18.3 0.79 17.8 17.2 0.70 17 MAPb(I0.64Br0.26)3 p-i-n planar 1.75 1.21 15.8 0.77 14.9 N.A. 0.69 18 MA0.6FA0.4Pb(I0.6Br0.4)3 p-i-n planar 1.76 1.17 16 0.78 14.7 N.A. 0.66 19 K0.1CsFAMAPbI1.2Br1.8 mesoporous 1.78 1.23 17.9 0.79 17.5 17.1 0.69 &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:26:47Z</infon>
        <location offset="44191" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:26:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="44698" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">control_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">17.5</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:27:52Z</infon>
        <location offset="45798" length="4"/>
        <text>17.5</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:28:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="45907" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">19.8</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:28:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="46601" length="4"/>
        <text>19.8</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T22:28:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="46849" length="25"/>
        <text>Cs0.15FA0.85PbI2.19Br0.81</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47846</offset>
      <text>			 16146840, 2019, 21, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aenm.201803699 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48207</offset>
      <text>			 © 2019 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48263</offset>
      <text>			 Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 16146840, 2019, 21, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aenm.201803699 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48660</offset>
      <text>			 Adv. Energy Mater. 2019, 9, 1803699 16146840, 2019, 21, Downloaded from https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aenm.201803699 by University Of California, Wiley Online Library on [07/11/2024]. See the Terms and Conditions (https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/terms-and-conditions) on Wiley Online Library for rules of use; OA articles are governed by the applicable Creative Commons License Copyright WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, 69469 Weinheim, Germany, 2019.</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
