<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025040071DIBFBA</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 91&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Methylammonium Chloride Induces Intermediate Phase Stabilization for Efficient Perovskite Solar Cells&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>114</offset>
      <text>Skyscraper Banner Ad (160 x 600) &amp; Large Rectangle Banner Ad (300 x 250) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>188</offset>
      <text> Electronic Table of Contents (eToC) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>226</offset>
      <text> Email Targeting Broadcast your message in the audience's inbox through our electronic Tables  of Contents (eToCs) . Recipients are all opt-in subscribers, so emails are all fully permission based. Opportunities are available for all primary Cell Press research journals and are delivered the day before each journal's cover date. Two sponsored message slots are available: • Top: 728 x 90 (before the Table of Contents) • Middle: 336 x 280 (within the body) Campaign Subscribers Average Open Rate AJHG Supplemental Information 1. AFM images Figure s1. AFM phase images of the perovskite films: (a) pristine, (b) MA-10, (c) MA-20, (d) MA-30, (e) MA-40, and (f) MA-50, respectively.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>912</offset>
      <text>About Cell Press About &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>936</offset>
      <text> Contacts With each passing year, the scientific community experiences massive leaps in the discovery and promise of new scientific breakthroughs, and for more than 40 years, Cell Press has been privileged to publish many of those impactful findings. And, as the science continues to evolve and change, so does Cell Press. At Cell Press, we understand your main objective is to find highly qualified researchers. Whether it is with an online job posting on the Cell Career Network, sponsorship in one of our several email alerts (eTOCs), or with online banners and print advertising in our targeted journals, we offer opportunities to generate interested applicants by connecting your organization with our targeted audience. The highest quality, sought-after candidates read content that represents the greatest value. Cell Press offers that high-quality content and an environment that connects you with value and thought leadership. We aim to help you reach far beyond the static, into the inboxes and consciousness or our subscribers. Thank you for taking the time to review our 2018 Recruitment Media Kit. We look forward to assisting you with your next candidate search, conference or grant announcement. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2148</offset>
      <text> Contents &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2159</offset>
      <text> Cell Career Network Cell Career Network is the premier web platform for your recruiting efforts and events. Our highly-qualified audience uses Cell Career Network to keep tabs on industry trends and meetings, and for career advancement such as job openings and funding opportunities. • Promote an upcoming course, conference, or event As screens gradually permeate each aspect of our lives, banner advertising generates awareness for your brand or product in the moment your targeted customer is in their "science zone". Readers come to Cell.com, individual journal homepages, and the Elsevier online platform, ScienceDirect, to read and research the latest great science. Choose from standard banners, flash banners, and rich media. Geo-target your markets. Select regional targets to push specific examples and messaging. Cater to international customers with distinct messaging! &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3045</offset>
      <text> Standard banner • Acceptable formats: .gif and/or .jpeg • Animations should run for less than three rotations or 30 seconds • All ads with a white background must include a colored border • All available ad sizes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3268</offset>
      <text> Flash banner • Animations should run for less than three rotations or 30 seconds • All ads with a white background must include a colored border • Flash ads should use Click-Tag. When submitting rich media, an alternate .gif is required • 336 x 280 pixels • 728 x 90 pixels &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3554</offset>
      <text> Specifications It's contextual, with a Phd (SciClick) Discover a comprehensive marketing solution. Our readers turn to Cell Press for landmark discoveries and a host of fascinating article formats, including our highly popular Previews, Minireviews, and Reviews. Generate maximum awareness through Marketplace Recommendations. Rather than guessing where your messaging should land, our Marketplace Recommendations tool uses SciClick software to read every article in real time and match it to product notes that you've supplied. This ensures that every reader is being shown your relevant product lines at every juncture of their research. Marketplace Recommendations with Cell Press offers an unrivaled opportunity to drive readers directly to your applications and products relevant to their work. • Drive highly qualified traffic to your website from a robust content-rich environment • Deliver a focused and targeted message alongside first-rate, peer-reviewed content  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4534</offset>
      <text> Relevance and impact factor At Cell Press, we understand that impact factor is just one measure of journal performance, and you can find additional metrics at: cell.com/impact 26 issues per year • Molecular biology (transcription, RNAi splicing, RNA editing, DNA replication and repair, protein synthesis and editing, protein modification and degradation, and chromatin) • Cell biology (cell cycle, subcellular organization, protein and membrane transport, protein folding and stability, and signal transduction) • Systems biology • Stem cells • Human disease (infectious diseases including HIV and other viruses, cancer, and human disease genes) • Developmental biology (differentiation and morphogenesis, organogenesis, sex determination, stem cell biology, apostosis, and embryology in all model organisms including plants, mice, fish, flies, chicks, and worms) • Genetics and genomics (bacterial regulation, fly and worm genetics, and eukaryotic genomics) • Proteomics • Cancer research • Immunology (T cell selection, lymphocytes and immunoglobulins, and somatic hypermutation) • Neuroscience (learning and memory, neuronal guidance and connections, and synaptic transmission) • Structural biology • Microbiology • Virology • Physiology (receptors, hormone action, obesity, and lifespan) • Evolution       • &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5883</offset>
      <text> 13.287 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5906</offset>
      <text> 11.020 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5929</offset>
      <text> 10.732 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5952</offset>
      <text> 11.124 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5975</offset>
      <text> 6.333 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5997</offset>
      <text> 12.797 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6020</offset>
      <text> 11.911 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6029</offset>
      <text> Society partner journals Cell Press is proud to publish 8 journals on behalf of learned societies, including the American Society of Human Genetics, the American Society of Gene and Cell Therapy, the Biophysical Society, and the International Society of Stem Cell Research as well as partner institutions such as the Institute of Plant Physiology and Ecology, the Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and the Chinese Society of Plant Biology. Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6529</offset>
      <text> 9.025 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6551</offset>
      <text> 3.656 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6573</offset>
      <text> 8.827 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6595</offset>
      <text> 7.338 12 issues per year   I N T E R N A T I O N A L S O C I E T Y F O R S T E M C E L L R E S E A R C H &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6702</offset>
      <text> Molecular Therapy family of journals Cell Press is delighted to announce our partnership with the American Society of Gene and Cell Therapy to publish the Molecular Therapy family of journals. Commencing January 2017, this premier collection of journals in the exciting areas of molecular and cellular therapeutics is published alongside the high-quality, cutting-edge research that you've come to expect from Cell Press journals. www.cell.com/molecular-therapy-family/home Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7192</offset>
      <text> 6.688 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7214</offset>
      <text> 2.610 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7236</offset>
      <text> 6.392 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7258</offset>
      <text> 12 issues per year Molecular Therapy is the leading international journal for research on the development of molecular and cellular therapeutics to correct genetic and acquired diseases, including, but not limited to, research on gene transfer and editing, vector development and design, stem cell manipulation, vaccine development, pre-clinical target validation, safety/efficacy studies, and clinical trials.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7672</offset>
      <text> issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7690</offset>
      <text> issues per year Molecular Therapy -Nucleic Acids publishes research targeted to the advances in nucleic acidbased therapeutics to treat and/ or correct genetic and acquired disease. Subject areas include development of therapeutics based on nucleic acids and their derivatives, vector development and design for the delivery of RNA-based therapeutics, and applications of gene-modifying agents. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8087</offset>
      <text> issues per year Molecular Therapy -Oncolytics is an international, open-access journal focusing on the development and clinical testing of viral, cellular, and other biological therapies targeting cancer. While providing a unique forum for work in the burgeoning fields of oncolytic virotherapy, as well as T cell-and stem cell-based therapies, the journal will consider all top-quality research that employs innovative molecular and cellular approaches that target cancer cells for destruction. Biophysical Journal (BPJ) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8611</offset>
      <text> Society partner journals &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8638</offset>
      <text> Detailed demographics &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8662</offset>
      <text> Monthly visits per journal per region Volume(Issue) 114(  1 ) 114(  2 ) 114(  3 ) 114(  4 ) 114(  5 ) 114(  6 ) 114(  7 ) 114(  8 ) 114(  9 ) 114(  10 ) 114(  11 ) 114 (12)   Issue Date 9-Jan-18   4 ) 115(  5 ) 115(  6 ) 115(  7 ) 115(  8 ) 115(  9 ) 115(  10 ) 115(  11 ) 115(  12 ) Issue Date 3-Jul-18  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8969</offset>
      <text> Cell (CELL) Volume(Issue) 172(1 and 2) 172(  3 ) 172(  4 ) 172(  5 ) 172(  6 ) 173(  1 ) 173(  2 ) 173(  3 ) 173(  4 ) 173(  5 ) 173(  6 ) 173(  7 ) Issue Date 11-Jan-18   4 ) 174(  5 ) 174(  6 ) 175(  1 ) 175(  2 ) 175(  3 ) 175(  4 ) 175(  5 ) 175(  6 ) 175(  7 ) Cell Host &amp; Microbe (CHOM) Issue Volume(Issue) 23 (1) 23(2) 23(3) 23(4) 23(5) 23(6) 24(1) 24(2) 24(3) 24(4) 24(5) 24(6) Issue Date 10-Jan-18 14-Feb-18   4 ) 24(  5 ) 24(  6 ) 24(  7 ) 24(  8 ) 24(  9 ) 24(  10 ) 24(  11 ) 24(  12 ) 24(  13   Dates and deadlines: review journals     Note that the formation energy (ΔEf) of the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure prepared with chloride, cation, or cationic chloride was calculated using the equation (s1), f system FA Pb I cation Cl E E nE mE lE kE tE  = - - -- - (s1) where, Esystem is the total energy of the chloride, cation, or cationic chloride-incorporated perovskite system. EFA, EPb, EI, Ecation, and ECl are the energies per unit of the reference states, which are the FA, Pb, I2, cation, and Cl, respectively. n, m, l, k, and, t are the number of atoms in the system.  is the distance between atomic layers, θ is the diffraction angle, n is the order of reflection, which is an integer (for this case, n is 1), and λ is the wavelength of the radiation (for this case, λ is 1.54056 Å (copper source)). In this study, we calculated the doping formation energy to investigate the formation energy to dope the α-phase perovskite structure with additive. In this calculation, we considered one formation step of α-phase perovskite structure with cationic chloride additive; α-phase perovskite structure incorporated cationic chloride additive before annealing process (pre-annealing step). In the pre-annealing step of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure, the doping formation energy of cationic chloride additive into the perovskite structure (ΔEd) was calculated by using the following equation (s2), d cation Cl doping non-doping A out A in C out C in ( ) ( ) E E E n m      = - + - + - (s2) where Ecation Cl doping is the total energy of perovskite system incorporated cationic chloride. Enon-doping is the total energy of the system that does not incorporate the cationic chloride. μA out (μC out) and μA in (μC in) are the chemical potentials of anions (cations), which are deleted from or inserted to the perovskite structure with cationic iodide and cationic chloride. n and m are the number of anions and cations, respectively. In order to investigate the effect of the concentration of cationic chloride additive on the crystallinity of the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure, we have theoretically tested the α-phase perovskite structure, which described the system before (pre-annealing) and after (post-annealing) a thermal annealing, based on the model systems of Figure  s16 . Through these systems, we calculated the formation energy (see Figure  s13 ) and the doping formation energy (see Figure  s18 ). Note that in the preannealing step, the α-phase perovskite is doped with cationic chloride as an additive, and in the postannealing step, the α-phase perovskite is doped with I, which occupies the Cl site through anionic exchange. In Figure  s19 , the doped model systems are described, which are at their most stable states, over the concentration range of 11 % to 44 %. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T13:03:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="9571" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">FAPbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T13:03:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="10719" length="6"/>
        <text>FAPbI3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12323</offset>
      <text> FACl We found that the formation energy decreased as the MACl concentration increased at the preannealing step (Figure  s19 (a)), implying that the performance of materials increased from their increased structural stabilities. But, one can readily expect that there exists a limit of the additive concentration effect to increase the performance since the doping formation energy increases (Figure  s19(a) ). Thus, we examined the formation energy at the post-annealing step, where I was substituted with Cl through the annealing process (Figure  s19(b) ). And, we found that the formation energy was stabilized between 33 % and 44 %, which corresponded to the best performance shown in the experiment (i.e., 40 %).  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13043</offset>
      <text> INTRODUCTION Within a short period of time, organic-inorganic lead halide perovskites have demonstrated powerful applications in solar cells as a result of high-power conversion efficiencies now exceeding 23%, 1 unprecedented in the field of photovoltaics. The high-efficiency outputs of perovskite solar cells are attributed to their exceptional material properties, 2-4 which include high optical absorption cross-sections, 5 low exciton binding energies,  6  long-range charge carrier diffusion lengths,  3, 7, 8  and easy tuning of the band gaps 8-10 via simple interchanges of the precursor components. Among the perovskite materials, formamidinium lead iodide (FAPbI 3 )-based perovskite materials are also widely used because the band gap, 1.48 eV, is closer to the optimum value of a single-junction solar cell  [11] [12] [13]  and displays a broader light absorption spectrum that extends to 840 nm, although stability can be an issue in these cells. In general, FAPbI 3 has two crystal structures: a non-perovskite yellow d-phase and a 3D perovskite black a-phase. Only the a-phase perovskite is a useful photoactive phase.  12, 14  Black a-phase perovskite readily transforms to the yellow d-phase non-perovskite because of the large size of the FA cation.  15  Studies have shown that substituting some FA + species with MA + or Cs + can inhibit this phase transformation.  12   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>14436</offset>
      <text> Context &amp; Scale Numerous effective methods have been developed toward achieving high-performance perovskite solar cells. The additives are one of the most effective ways of achieving high performance. Clbased additives are among the most prevalent in literature; however, their exact role is still uncertain. Herein, we systematically researched the effects of methylammonium chloride (MACl) additive using analysis of photo-physical properties and density functional theory. The highest efficiency achieved was 24.02%, certified as 23.48%, and the resultant devices showed better thermal stabilities and photostabilities than the pristine devices. The important factors for achieving high-performance perovskite solar cells include controlling the well-defined morphologies and maintaining the high crystallization of the perovskite film.  16, 17  These features can be controlled through the choice of perovskite precursor,  18  fabrication method,  19  solvent mixing,  17  annealing conditions,  20, 21  manufacturing humidity conditions,  22  surface passivation,  23  and processing additives.  24  Recently, the incorporation of additives into the perovskite precursor solution was widely studied to provide an effective approach to improving the film morphology and crystallinity. Several additives, including polymers,  [25] [26] [27]  fullerene derivatives,  [28] [29] [30]  organic halide salts,  [31] [32] [33] [34] [35]  metal halide salts,  [36] [37] [38] [39]  inorganic acid,  [40] [41] [42] [43]  and others  [44] [45] [46]  can be used to create a uniform perovskite layer with a high crystallinity and improve the device performance. Among these, additives containing iodide ions, such as cesium iodide (CsI),  [47] [48] [49] [50]  rubidium iodide (RbI),  [51] [52] [53]  guanidinium iodide (GuI),  [54] [55] [56]  methylammonium iodide (MAI),  57  and other iodide  [58] [59] [60] [61]  have driven the high-performance efficiencies. Just 5% or 10% CsI addition to perovskite mixtures suppressed non-perovskite yellow phase impurities and induced the formation of uniformly large perovskite grains that extended the electron-to-hole collecting layer, consistent with seed-assisted crystal growth.  50  Recently, alkali iodide (LiI, NaI, and KI) was used for defect engineering and perovskite doping to reduce hysteresis and increase efficiencies using small doping concentrations of 10 mmol.  62  Apart from the cationic iodide additives, chloride-based additives have been studied recently, although few studies have compared the chlorides with the iodides. Wang et al. explored the additions of FACl and MACl in equal molar amounts to the FAPbI 3 precursor solution, demonstrating that they were good additives for increasing the crystallization of a-FAPbI 3 via the formation of intermediate mixtures, which suppressed crystallization of the d-phase FAPbI 3 .  63  A new perovskite growth method was presented using MACl to assist the vertical recrystallization in an FA perovskite film and provide an efficiency of 20.6%.  64  Mu et al. showed that MACl was a transitional ''stabilizer'' that preserved the crystal structure and formed the black FA perovskite.  65  Qing et al. also showed that the synergistic effects of dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and MACl additives, which assisted crystallization of the perovskites, lead to a single-crystal-like film with a smooth surface and a low defect density, thereby providing a high-efficiency perovskite solar cell.  66  However, the efficiencies of the perovskite solar cells prepared with cationic chloride additives were lower than those prepared using cationic iodide additives. Furthermore, it is not yet clear why MACl additives would be better than others. This effect requires further investigation of the role and theoretical calculation. In this work, we systematically studied the role of MACl additive in FAPbI 3 -based perovskite solar cells. The grain size in films prepared using various contents was dramatically greater, by a factor of 6, compared to the film prepared without additive. Interestingly, MACl effectively stabilizes an intermediate to the pure FAPbI 3 a-phase without annealing-only through cationic site substitution. From the fabricating high crystallinity of ultra-pure a-phase FAPbI 3 -based perovskite, the photoluminescence lifetimes also increased by a factor of 4.3. Using density functional theory (DFT), we provide a theoretical framework for understanding the interaction of MACl with a perovskite active layer. The formation energy of the resulting perovskite structure is related to the amount of incorporated MACl. Consequently, MACl additive induces intermediate phase stabilization for over 24% efficiency. The highest efficiency achieved was 24.02%, which was obtained with the addition of 40 mol% MACl. These results suggest that the MACl additive is a promising material for high-quality film formation and high-performance device that offers great opportunities for the practical applications. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:03:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="14798" length="30"/>
        <text>methylammonium chloride (MACl)</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19452</offset>
      <text> RESULTS AND DISCUSSION The surface morphologies of the different film compositions were evaluated by collecting top-view images using a scanning electron microscope (SEM). The interesting results were that the grain sizes of perovskite films are directly related to the amount of incorporated MACl. Figure  1A  shows the photographs of the film surfaces manufactured using the MACl introduced in concentrations of 10 mol%, 20 mol%, 30 mol%, 40 mol%, and 50 mol% (denoted MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively). The grain size obtained without the additive (pristine) was approximately 250 nm (average). However, the MA-10 produced a film with a larger grain size of 600 nm (see Figure  1B ). The grain size obtained from the MA-20 was 1,000 nm, and the grain size further increased to 1,500 nm for the MA-40 (see Figures  1C-1F ). The grain size distributions obtained with different additions of MACl contents is shown in Figure  1G . Atomic force microscopy (AFM) phase images (Figure  S1 ) also showed that the grain sizes were increased as a function of the additive amounts. The film roughness was measured by calculating the root-mean-square (RMS) roughness as listed in Table  S1 . The pristine film consisted of small crystals with an RMS roughness of 64.7 nm. The roughness decreased to 45.8 nm, 41.0 nm, 33.6 nm, and 24.7 nm with MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, and MA-40, respectively. These results indicated that the film roughness was reduced when the MACl contents were increased. To check the substitution of the cationic site with MA ion and anionic site with Cl ion, the perovskite films were characterized elementally using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), as shown in Figure  S2 . The intensity of nitrogen (N) peak decreased with the MACl contents, indicating that the MA ion was substituted for FA in the cationic site because the MA ion included one N atom and the FA ion included two N atoms. Therefore, if the FA ion had been substituted by MA ions, the intensity of N would decrease as the MACl addition increased. In contrast with the N ion, the Cl ion was not substituted into the anionic sites. Some studies have shown that the addition of Cl ions to a perovskite does not facilitate the formation of a continuous perovskite phase because Cl ions readily evaporate away during the annealing process.  63, 65  To evaluate the Cl ion content, XPS measurements of the Cl ions were conducted as a function of the MACl contents from MA-10, MA-30, and MA-50. As shown in Figure  S2B , the signal corresponding to the Cl ion content in the film was not detected in all samples. These results indicated that the Cl ion had evaporated during annealing. MACl easily decomposed into MA ion and FACl, which was easily removed from the film through evaporation with annealing.  65  To support this result, the Cl ion was monitored using energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) analysis to observe any changes in the Cl ion concentration during annealing. The results shown in Figure  S3  reveal a large initial amount of Cl present compared to the amount of Pb (Cl/Pb atomic ratio) present in a perovskite film not subjected to annealing. After annealing at 150 C for 5 min, the Cl ion content was reduced to a 0.12 Cl/Pb atomic ratio, and no EDS-detectable Cl ion was observed in the perovskite film after annealing at 150 C for 10 min. These results agree with the XPS analysis. The intensities of the Pb and I ion signals did not change, indicating that the halide mixture composition did not change. Another interesting result is that the crystallinity can be changed with different concentrations of MACl. Figure  2A  shows the diffractograms obtained from pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively. The pristine perovskite film (prepared without additive) showed peaks at 12.7 and 13.9 , corresponding to the PbI 2 and a-phase perovskite peaks. The small PbI 2 peak intensity indicated that the film was not fully converted into a pure a-phase perovskite film during annealing at 150 C for 10 min. The crystallinity with addition of MACl, in MA-10, MA-20, and MA-30, slightly increased the a-phase peak at 13.9 , and the PbI 2 peak at 12.7 disappeared. The a-phase perovskite peak further increased at MA-40. However, the intensity of a-phase peak is slightly decreased at MA-50. The film crystallinities obtained from different MACl contents were compared by plotting the reciprocal full width at half maximum (FWHM) from the XRD spectra as shown in Figure  2B . The FWMH values were compared under the best conditions for each additive: pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50. The narrower diffraction peaks were observed in the films prepared with additive as compared to the pristine film. The highest value was obtained from MA-40, which indicated that large crystallites could be obtained. These results agreed with the grain size results, as shown in Figure  1 . The very interesting result is that MACl successfully induces an intermediate to the pure FAPbI 3 a-phase without annealing, effectively stabilizing this structure. The pristine film, for example, prepared without additives and without annealing, displayed numerous unknown diffraction peaks, as shown in Fig-  ure 2C . After annealing at 150 C for 10 min, the peak corresponding to the a-phase perovskite was dominant, but some d-phase and PbI 2 were still present, indicating that it was not easy to obtain only ultra-pure a-phase perovskite film from a pristine perovskite precursor solution. However, the perovskite film, obtained using MA-40, featured only a pure a-phase perovskite peak (no detectable d-phase and PbI 2 ) even without annealing (Figure  2D ). After annealing at 150 C for 10 min, the peak corresponding to the a-phase perovskite was sharply increased with only ultra-pure structure. These results indicate that the MACl additive can influence the formation of a-phase structure even before the annealing step and that the stabilized imtermediate can be induced into the ultra-pure a-phase perovskite after the annealing step. To see the intermediate phase of FAPbI 3 perovskite with MACl addition more clearly, we measured the XRD of FAPbI 3 perovskite included with MA-40 according to the annealing time (Figure  S4 ) and magnified the peak position around 14 (Figure  S5 ). As expected, the peak position was slightly shifted to a smaller degree as the annealing time was increased, which indicated that the Cl ion was substituted by I ion during the annealing process (Figures  S2  and S3 ). The photophysical measurements were conducted from the perovskite films prepared with different additive contents. Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) decay profiles were obtained from the perovskite films. The PL decay curves, measured at the peak emission (800 nm), showed bi-exponential decays with a fast (t 1 ) and a slow (t 2 ) component. The t 1 decay component corresponded to non-radiative recombination from defects (surface traps near the grain boundaries), and the t 2 component corresponded to radiative recombination from the bulk perovskite.  57  Figure  2E  plots the PL decay curves obtained from the different concentrations of the MACl addition. The pristine film provided t 1 (331 ns) and t 2 (68.7 ns), but the highest values were obtained at MA-40: 1,441 ns (t 1 ) and 450 ns (t 2 ), as shown in Table  S2 . The higher decay values indicated that the deposited perovskite films possessed larger numbers of carriers after 1,000 ns, attributed to the strong suppression of non-radiative recombination. Longer components suggest improved Schottky order in the bulk perovskite as a result of additives.  57  Steady-state PL measurements were collected from the perovskite films deposited on glass. The corresponding curves for all compositions are shown in Figure  2F . The intensities of the PL peaks gradually increased with the MACl contents, and a slight blue shift was observed in the emission peak due to the MA ion substitution. As discussed above, the PL was only slightly affected if only the cations were substituted, in agreement with the smaller observed shift in the band gap.  67  The highest PL intensities were found in MA-40, indicating a high crystal quality, in agreement with the XRD results. The solar cell efficiencies with different concentrations were investigated, and the results are summarized in Figure  3A  and Table  S3 . The efficiency prepared with pristine was lower than the MA-10 and MA-20 devices. It was reasonable to assume that lower crystallinity of a-phase perovskite dominated the films prepared with MA-10 and MA-20. The performances of devices prepared with MACl-30 improved, to an efficiency of 22.52%, further increased to 24.02% (MA-40), and slightly decreased to 23.36% with further addition (MA-50). These result trends agreed with the XRD, optical adsorption, and PL measurements discussed above. Larger grain size, better crystallinity, and higher absorption intensities gave rise to better performance efficiencies. The intensity of the absorption band was highest at MA-40, and the PL lifetimes were also maximized. The reliability of the efficiency results was determined by testing the devices at an external institute, as shown in Figure  S6 . The certified efficiency of 23.48% from Newport Corp. was obtained. Figure  3B  shows the J-V curves as a function of the MACl contents. The relative distribution efficiencies of the pristine film, MA-20, and MA-40 are also shown in Figure  3C . The current densities were found to be 24.99 mA cm À2 (MA-10), 25.23 mA cm À2 (MA-20), 25.45 mA cm À2 (MA-30), 25.92 mA cm À2 (MA-40), and 25.38 mA cm À2 (MA-50), better than the current density measured from the pristine perovskite, 24.84 mA cm À2 . It may be postulated that the current densities were also affected by the perovskite crystallinity. The higher crystallinity had the higher current density, which was consistent with UV-absorption spectra as shown in Figure  S7 . The large PbI 2 peak observed in the pristine perovskite film indicated that the pristine perovskite film was not fully converted into a pure a-phase perovskite film. Apart from the current density, V oc significantly differ according to the different additives. The V oc of a pristine device was 1.027 V, but higher values were obtained with the MA-10 (1.034 V), MA-20 (1.083 V), MA-30 (1.101 V), MA-40 (1.130 V), or MA-50 (1.123 V). The V oc depends on the recombination rate in the perovskite film. The efficiencies obtained from the FACl and MAI additives were also measured by fabricating the various devices using the procedures described above, and the resulting J-V curve efficiencies are shown in Figures  S8  and S9 . The cell efficiencies obtained with FACl additive were higher than those of pristine, but the MAI additions were lower than those obtained from the cationic chloride addition at all concentrations. These results suggested that the chloride ion significantly affected the device performance. Figure  3D  showed the J-V curve of reverse and forward scan for the best and pristine devices. A pure perovskite film has a slow recombination rate. The case of MA-40 had a longer lifetime and a strong PL intensity (see Figures  2E  and 2F ) compared to pristine and other additive devices, which was a major contributor to higher V oc values. The FF also has higher value at MA-40, but the difference of FF is smaller compared to the other values (Figure  3B ). Figure  3E  shows the external quantum efficiency (EQE) values and its integrated J sc of pristine and best devices. The EQE spectra show that the average EQE is well matched with each current density. Because of substituting MA ion, the EQE spectra also can be slightly shifted with shorter wavelength as shown in Figure  S10 . Figure  3F  shows the stabilized steady-state current measured at the maximum power point (at 0.98 V) over 100 min. Although inorganic-organic hybrid perovskites have displayed dramatic advances in photovoltaic applications, overcoming instabilities against light, heat, and moisture remains a challenge in the development of commercial applications. Device stability tests were conducted under room temperature (RT) and 40 C, and photo stabilities were conducted under constant AM 1.5G illumination at 25% relative humidity (RH) and without encapsulation. The stability at RT showed 90% retaining of its initial performance over 1,200 h as shown in Figure  S11A . The 40 C thermal stability test showed that the pristine device degraded to 60% of its initial performance over 300 h, but the MA-40 were more stable, retaining 90% of its initial performances (Figure  S11B ). The photostabilities of the pristine and MA-40 devices also give higher stability in conditions of continuous illumination, as shown in Figure  S11C . The improved stability against thermal and light illumination was attributed to the large grain size and high crystallinity of the perovskite films. Perovskite degradation appears to initiate at grain boundaries and surface defects upon exposure to moisture or constant light.  68  The grain size in the MA-40 film was almost 1,000 nm (average), 2.7 times the value of the pristine film (370 nm [average]; see Figure  1A ). Therefore, degradation at the grain boundary sites in large-grain films was lower than in smallgrain films. The MA-40 device was more stable than the pristine device. An additional factor supporting the improved thermal and photostability was the high film crystallinity. As shown in the XRD analysis, the film prepared with MA-40 displayed a higher crystallinity in the a-phase perovskite crystal, as shown in Figures  2A  and 2B . The higher crystallinity of the film reduced surface defects capable of reacting and degrading the material. Therefore, the MA-40 device displayed a strong stability against thermal and light illumination. The mechanism by which cationic chloride improved the physical properties and efficiencies of the perovskite films was studied by using the DFT calculations (see Experimental Procedures). In view of the factors and experimental observations, we investigated the role of MACl additive on the perovskite crystal structure from three important points of view: roles of Cl and MA and concentration effect of MACl on the a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure. First, to understand the role of Cl on the perovskite crystal structure, the formation energies of the a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure and that including Cl, MA, or MACl were calculated (Figure  4A ) from model systems (Figures  S12  and S13 ). The formation energies revealed that Cl stabilized the perovskite structure thermodynamically compared to the system without Cl. To better understand the role of Cl in electronic properties, the highest-occupied molecular orbital (HOMO) was calculated (Figure  4B ). It has been reported that the FA interacts weakly with the I of perovskite structure with a cubooctahedral structure favored by Pb and I in the a-phase FAPbI 3 , resulting in an unstable perovskite structure.  48  Interestingly, Cl induced p orbital localization of I (red dashed circle in the Figure  4B ), and the projected density of states (PDOS) results revealed that Cl enhanced the intensity of the p orbital of I at the HOMO state (Figures  4C  and S14 ). Accordingly, the interactions of FA and I could be enhanced by the above-mentioned effects of Cl, which contributes to improving the stability of the FAPbI 3 perovskite structure. These results can be supported by the XRD and XPS results (Figures  2D  and S2 ). Second, we investigated the effects of MA cation incorporated into the perovskite structure. Lee et al. reported that the incorporation of the Cs cation at the FA site improved the stability of the perovskite by enhancing interactions between FA and I through shrinkage of the cubo-octahedral volume.  48  Based on this observation, we also confirmed the total volume shrinkage in the MA cation-incorporated system (i.e., $0.57%) compared to the bare a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite system (Figure  4D ). The main contribution for this volume shrinkage is attributed to the contraction of MA-included cubo-octahedral site compared to the bare system (i.e., $0.89%) (Figure  S15 ). Moreover, we predicted that the dipole effect of the MA cation was another factor of lower formation energy of the MA system (Figure  4A ) because the MA cation had a dipole moment 10 times that of the FA cation.  69  Our calculations indicated that p orbital localization of I in the MA system resulted from the dipole effect of the MA cation (blue dashed circle in Figure  4B ). The PDOS of the MA cation-incorporated system revealed that the intensity of the p orbital of I in the HOMO state was higher than the bare a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure (Figure  4E ). Therefore, we conclude that the effects of the volume shrinkage and the dipole enhance the interactions between FA and I, which improved the stability of the perovskite structure. We additionally investigated the volume shrinkage of perovskite structure in terms of the MA concentration. For this investigation, the four concentration systems were constructed (Figure  S16 ). It was found that the volume shrinkage increased as the concentration of MA increased from calculation and experiment results. The degree of the volume shrinkage from both methods agreed well with each other (Figure  S17 ). Thus, we confirmed that MA induced the volume shrinkage of the perovskite structure and its concentration influenced the degree of volume shrinkage. Third, to elucidate the appropriate concentration of MACl additive for obtaining high crystallinity of a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure, the concentration effect of MACl was investigated. Based on the four concentration systems in Figure  S16 , we predicted that the optimal concentration ranges for high crystallinity of perovskite solar cell could exist and be elucidated by considering formation energy (Figure  S13 ) and doping formation energy (Figure  S18 ). Our theoretical prediction was in good agreement with experimental observation. In Figure  S19 , the optimal concentration of MACl was caused by the doping formation energy of MACl into the a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure in the pre-annealing step and the formation energy of the perovskite structure including MAI in the post-annealing step. Especially, the formation energy was stabilized between 33% and 44%, which corresponded to the best performance shown in the experiment (i.e., 40%). These theoretical predictions were in good agreement with experimental observations of results of the J-V curve (Figure  3B  and Table  S3 ). Overall, from the three points of DFT calculation, we can understand why MACl additive stabilized the perovskite formation and showed high performance. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride - 40%</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:05:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="19945" length="5"/>
        <text>MA-40</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride - 40%</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:05:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="20269" length="5"/>
        <text>MA-40</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:09:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="22136" length="4"/>
        <text>MACl</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">23.36</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:53Z</infon>
        <location offset="28231" length="5"/>
        <text>23.36</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treated_voc</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1.130</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="29852" length="5"/>
        <text>1.130</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:10:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="31654" length="16"/>
        <text>room temperature</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:09:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="31738" length="20"/>
        <text>AM 1.5G illumination</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:10:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="31762" length="3"/>
        <text>25%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:20:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="31843" length="2"/>
        <text>90</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1200</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="31889" length="5"/>
        <text>1,200</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">40</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:12:14Z</infon>
        <location offset="31928" length="4"/>
        <text>40 C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOST</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-08T12:11:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="31933" length="17"/>
        <text>thermal stability</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:11:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="31972" length="15"/>
        <text>pristine device</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="32000" length="2"/>
        <text>60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">300</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="32036" length="3"/>
        <text>300</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride - 40%</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:11:58Z</infon>
        <location offset="32051" length="5"/>
        <text>MA-40</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:20:10Z</infon>
        <location offset="32085" length="2"/>
        <text>90</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">methylammonium chloride - 40%</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T09:12:07Z</infon>
        <location offset="32175" length="5"/>
        <text>MA-40</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:58Z</infon>
        <node refid="9" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:58Z</infon>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38309</offset>
      <text> Conclusion In summary, we investigated the MACl effects in the perovskite films, which construct the intermediate-phase into the perovskite film for the high-quality pure a-phase perovskite film. With achieved high-quality pure a-phase perovskite film, the surface morphology, crystallographic properties, optical absorption, and photoluminescence properties were enhanced, which resulted in high-performance perovskite solar cells. We achieved 24.02% perovskite solar cell performance. The mechanism of MACl's effect on the formation of a-phase perovskite structure was elucidated using DFT calculation. We believe that our new finding will help researchers to achieve high performance of perovskite solar cells. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24.02</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:19:46Z</infon>
        <location offset="38755" length="5"/>
        <text>24.02</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39025</offset>
      <text> EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURES &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39051</offset>
      <text> Materials Formamidine acetate salt (99%), hydriodic acid (HI, 57 wt% in water), titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate), 2-propanol (anhydrous, 99.5%), chlorobenzene (anhydrous, 99.8%), N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF, anhydrous 99.8%,), and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, &gt; 99.5%) were procured from Sigma-Aldrich and used as received. Methylamine hydrochloride (MACl, 98%) was procured from Acros Organics. Fluorine-doped tin oxide on glass (FTO glass, 7 U sq -1 ) was obtained from Asahi. Ethanol (absolute, 99.9%) was procured from Changshu Yangyuan Chemicals. Diethyl ether (extra pure grade) was procured form Duksan. TiO 2 paste (SC-HT040) was procured from ShareChem. Lead iodide (PbI 2 , 99.999%) was purchased from TCI. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39778</offset>
      <text> Materials Synthesis Formamidinium iodide (FAI) was synthesized as reported elsewhere.  70  Briefly, 25 g formamidine acetate was directly mixed with 50 mL hydriodic acid in a 500 mL round-bottomed flask with vigorous stirring. A light yellow powder was obtained by evaporating solvent at 80 C for 1 h in a vacuum evaporator. The resulting powders were dissolved in ethanol and precipitated using diethyl ether. This procedure was repeated 3 times until white powders were obtained, and the powders were recrystallized from ethanol and diethyl ether in a refrigerator. After recrystallization, the resulting powders were collected and dried at 60 C for 24 h. Single-crystal FAPbI 3 was fabricated as reported previously.  71, 72  Device Fabrication Asahi FTO glass (FTO glass, 7 U sq -1 ) was used as the substrate for the devices. The substrates were cleaned using the RCA-2 (H 2 O 2 -NCl-H 2 O) procedure  73  for 15 min to remove metal ion impurities. The substrates were then cleaned sequentially with acetone, ethanol, and isopropyl alcohol (IPA) in an ultrasonic system for 15 min. To deposit the compact TiO 2 layer, 60 mL of a titanium diisopropoxide bis(acetylacetonate)/ethanol (with 1:10 volume ratio) solution was applied by spraying. Prior to spraying, the substrates were placed on a hot plate and the temperature was increased to 450 C rapidly. After completing the spray pyrolysis step, the substrates were stored at 450 C for 1 h to improve the electrical properties,  74  then slowly cooled to room temperature. On top of the c-TiO 2 layer, a mesoporous TiO 2 (mp-TiO 2 ) layer was deposited by spin-coating. The TiO 2 paste, approximately 50 nm in diameter, was purchased from ShareChem. The paste was dispersed in ethanol/terpineol (78:22 w/w). The FTO/c-TiO 2 substrates prepared with mp-TiO 2 were heated at 500 C on a hot plate for 1 h to remove organic compounds and then slowly cooled to 200 C. To fabricate perovskite solar cells, the perovskite precursor solution was prepared by mixing 1,139 mg mL -1 FAPbI 3 in a mixture of DMF and DMSO in a 4:1 ratio by volume. MACl was added in the range 0$50 mol%. For each sample, 70 mL of the filtered solution was spread over the FTO/c-TiO 2 /mp-TiO 2 substrate at 6,000 rpm for 50 s with 0.1 s ramping. During spin coating, 1 mL diethyl ether was dripped after spinning for 10 s using a pipette. The film was dried on a hot plate at 150 C for 10 min. After cooling the substrate, the perovskite film was spin coated with phenylethylammonium iodide (PEAI) dissolved with IPA (5 mM) at 3,000 rpm. The hole transfer materials were deposited by preparing a spiro-OMe-TAD (Lumtech) in chlorobenzene (90 mg/mL) and mixing with 35.5 mL 4-tert-butylpyridine (TBP), 23 mL Li-bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide (Li-TFSI) (520 mg/mL acetonitrile), and 5 mL tris(2-(1h-pyrazol-1-yl)-4-tert-butylpyridine)-cobalt(III)tris(bis (trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide) (FK209, Lumtech) (180 mg/mL acetonitrile). Finally, a gold counter electrode was deposited on the substrate using a thermal evaporation system. The back and front contacts were formed from 100 nm thick Au films deposited by vapor deposition at a pressure of 10 À6 torr. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>42965</offset>
      <text> Characterization The phases of the perovskite films prepared with different additives were analyzed using X-ray diffractometry (XRD) using a D8 Advance (Bruker) diffractometer equipped with Cu Ka radiation (l = 0.1542 nm). The morphologies of the perovskite films were assessed using a field-emission scanning electron microscope (FE-SEM, S-4800, Hitachi). Steady-state photoluminescence and TRPL measurements were conducted using PicoQuant FluoTime 300 (PicoQuant GmbH, Germany) equipped with a PDL 820 laser pulse driver. A pulsed laser diode (l = 375 nm, pulse FWHM &lt; 70 ps, repetition rate 200 kHz-40 MHz) was used to excite the sample. XPS spectra were collected using a Thermo Fisher Scientific ESCALAB 250XI at a base pressure of 1.0 3 10 À9 torr using a monochromic Al-Ka X-ray source. The solar cells were measured using a solar simulator (McScience, K3000 Lab solar cell I-V measurement system, Class AAA) at 100 mA cm -2 , illumination AM 1.5 G. The light intensity was calibrated using a Si-reference cell certified by NREL before taking measurements. No light soaking was applied before the potential scan. The J-V curves were measured using a reverse scan (from a forward bias [1.2 V] to short circuit [0 V]) and a forward scan (from a forward bias [0 V] to short circuit [1.2 V]). The step voltage was fixed at 100 mV. The cells were masked using a metal mask in order to limit the active cell area to 0.0804 cm 2 . EQE measurements were obtained using a QEX7 system (PV Measurement). The stability test was conducted without encapsulation. The thermal stability test was performed by aging on a hot plate at RT and 40 C, respectively. The performances of the devices were periodically measured under illumination AM 1.5 G after cooling the devices to RT. The photostability test was performed under a maximum power point tracking and continuous light irradiation (AM 1.5G) at 25 C and below 30% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>44883</offset>
      <text> Density Functional Theory Calculation All DFT calculations were performed using the Cambridge Serial Total Energy Package (CASTEP) program.  75, 76  The electronic exchange correlation potential was treated using a generalized gradient approximation with the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof (GGA-PBE) functional.  77  The interactions of the electron-ion cores were described using a norm-conserving pseudopotential.  78  The van der Waals interactions were corrected using the Tkatchenko and Scheffler (TS) method.  79  Spin polarization was considered in all calculations. The electronic wave functions were expanded using the plane wave basis set with the energy cut-off of 700 eV. The self-consistent field calculations were performed using the convergence criterion of 1 3 10 À6 eV/atom. The convergence criteria for the geometry optimization were set to 1 3 10 À5 eV/atom for the maximum energy change, 0.03 eV/A ˚for the maximum force, 0.05 GPa for the maximum stress, and 1 3 10 À3 A ˚for the maximum displacement. The Brillouin zone was sampled using a 1 3 1 3 3 k-point set with the Monkhorst-Pack scheme  80  for geometry optimization. Note that for calculation of projected density of states (PDOS), 2 3 2 3 6 k-point set was used.      Note that the formation energy (ΔEf) of the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure prepared with chloride, cation, or cationic chloride was calculated using the equation (s1), &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>46305</offset>
      <text> SUPPLEMENTAL INFORMATION f system FA Pb I cation Cl E E nE mE lE kE tE  = - - -- - (s1) where, Esystem is the total energy of the chloride, cation, or cationic chloride-incorporated perovskite system. EFA, EPb, EI, Ecation, and ECl are the energies per unit of the reference states, which are the FA, Pb, I2, cation, and Cl, respectively. n, m, l, k, and, t are the number of atoms in the system.  result of (b). The pristine system was taken to be reference for the calculation of the volume shrinkage percent. The lattice parameter was calculated by using the Bragg equation 2 ; 2 sin dn  = , where d is the distance between atomic layers, θ is the diffraction angle, n is the order of reflection, which is an integer (for this case, n is 1), and λ is the wavelength of the radiation (for this case, λ is 1.54056 Å (copper source)). In this study, we calculated the doping formation energy to investigate the formation energy to dope the α-phase perovskite structure with additive. In this calculation, we considered one formation step of α-phase perovskite structure with cationic chloride additive; α-phase perovskite structure incorporated cationic chloride additive before annealing process (pre-annealing step). In the pre-annealing step of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure, the doping formation energy of cationic chloride additive into the perovskite structure (ΔEd) was calculated by using the following equation (s2),  where Ecation Cl doping is the total energy of perovskite system incorporated cationic chloride. Enon-doping is the total energy of the system that does not incorporate the cationic chloride. μA out (μC out) and μA in (μC in) are the chemical potentials of anions (cations), which are deleted from or inserted to the perovskite structure with cationic iodide and cationic chloride. n and m are the number of anions and cations, respectively. In order to investigate the effect of the concentration of cationic chloride additive on the crystallinity of the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure, we have theoretically tested the α-phase perovskite structure, which described the system before (pre-annealing) and after (post-annealing) a thermal annealing, based on the model systems of Figure  s16 . Through these systems, we calculated the formation energy (see Figure  s13 ) and the doping formation energy (see Figure  s18 ). Note that in the preannealing step, the α-phase perovskite is doped with cationic chloride as an additive, and in the postannealing step, the α-phase perovskite is doped with I, which occupies the Cl site through anionic exchange. In Figure  s19 , the doped model systems are described, which are at their most stable states, over the concentration range of 11 % to 44 %. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49065</offset>
      <text> FACl We found that the formation energy decreased as the MACl concentration increased at the preannealing step (Figure  s19 (a)), implying that the performance of materials increased from their increased structural stabilities. But, one can readily expect that there exists a limit of the additive concentration effect to increase the performance since the doping formation energy increases (Figure  s19 (a)). Thus, we examined the formation energy at the post-annealing step, where I was substituted with Cl through the annealing process (Figure  s19(b) ). And, we found that the formation energy was stabilized between 33 % and 44 %, which corresponded to the best performance shown in the experiment (i.e., 40 %).  • Announce a grant/award • Elevate your company's profile Online job board product options listing your vacancy will be on Cell Career Network for 60 days and it will appear alongside Cell Press journal articles and research relevant to your job advertisement on Cell.com Add a featured job banner ad to one of our top rated journals Banners Banners New for 2018: our banners are now responsive! To improve ad visibility, the leaderboard banner will hover with content on desktop and mobile devices &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>50288</offset>
      <text> •Features• SciClick Contextual Link Advertising utilizes a unique search algorithm to match your message in context with the content on cell.com to drive traffic to your specifically chosen URL Customized campaign with campaign optimization manager • Unlimited SciClick Contextual Link Advertising • Unlimited outbound clicks • Monthly updates and edits • Comprehensive analytics Advertising package includes Cell Press research journals Cell Press: the best of the best • 47% of our readers are the lead decision maker in their company or lab • Consistently the highest impact factor in the biology category • Discipline-leading journals in all life science verticals • Increased translational content offerings • Trends and review content provide invaluable insights &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>51081</offset>
      <text> Biophysics • Computational biology 12 issues per year • Genetics, epigenetics, and genomic instability • Cell signaling and communication • Cell cycle and DNA repair • Diagnostics (molecular profiling and pharmacogenomics) • Telomerase and transformation • Apoptosis • Angiogenesis and metastasis • Animal models • Cancer therapy (rational drug design and small-molecule and biologicalmolecule therapeutics) 12 issues per year • Chemical insights into signaling, catalysis, and gene expression • Novel chemical and biological methods for molecular design, synthesis, and analysis • Glycomics • Chemical genetics • Chemistry and biology of natural and unnatural biopolymers • The use of natural and designed molecules as probes of cellular pathways • Drug design • The nature of molecular recognition in biological systems • Novel procedures for the large-scale analysis of genes and proteins • Functional and structural genomics • Molecular basis of evolution 12 issues per year • Molecular and cell biology of microbes • Microbial pathogenesis • Host cellular and immune response to microbes • Immune evasion • Therapeutics • Evolution, epidemiology, and natural history of microbes • Vaccine design, development, and trials • year • Open-access, online-only • High-quality papers across life science spectrum • Focus on shorter, single-point articles, entitled Reports, in addition to longer articles • The primary criterion for both types of formats is new biological insight 12 issues per year • Embryonic stem cells • Pluripotency • Germline stem cells • Tissue-specific stem cells • Stem cell differentiation • Epigenetics • Stem cell genomics and systems biology • Genome reprogramming • Cancer stem cells • Stem cell niches • Stem cell-based disease models • Nuclear transfer technology • Bioengineering • Drug discovery • In vivo imaging of stem cells • Therapeutic applications • Regenerative medicine • Clinical and translational insights • Stem cell research policies, ethical issues, and technical or resource-based innovations 12 issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>53247</offset>
      <text> 12 issues per year • Immune cell development and senescence • Signal transduction • Gene regulation • Innate and adaptive immunity • Cytokines and inflammatory responses • Autoimmunity and tolerance • Infectious disease • Tumor immunology • Vaccine biology • Transplantation biology • Allergy and asthma 24 issues per year • Gene expression and transcriptional and epigenetic regulation • DNA replication, recombination, and repair • RNA processing • Translation • Protein folding, modification, and degradation • Signal transduction • Cell cycle • Cell death • Systems biology 24 issues per year • Developmental neurobiology • Cellular and molecular neuroscience • Synaptic transmission and plasticity • Ion channel structure and function • Behavioral and systems neuroscience • Cognitive neuroscience • Neurological and psychiatric disease • Computational neurobiology 12 issues per year • Atomic resolution analysis • X-ray crystallography • Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy • Computational analyses, simulations, and predictions • Electron microscopy • Neutron scattering • Hydrodynamics • X-ray absorption spectroscopy • Biochemical studies • Biophysical analyses • Fluorescence energy transfer • Design, construction, and analysis of novel protein and RNA structures • Catalytic activities • Medium-to low-resolution structural analysis • Single-molecule analysis • Small-angle X-ray scattering • Emerging methods in structure determination 12 issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54812</offset>
      <text> • Imaging and diagnostics • Stem cell products, manufacturing, and quality control • Ethical, legal, and social issues &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>54939</offset>
      <text> Molecular Therapy -Methods &amp; Clinical Development is an open-access journal publishing top-quality, novel methods, as well as significant improvements to established research techniques in basic, translational, and clinical cell and gene therapy. Topics of interest include gene vector engineering and production, methods for targeted genome editing and engineering, technology development for cell reprogramming, and directed differentiation of pluripotent cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55406</offset>
      <text> Date 28 - 28 Jun-18 12-Jul-18 26-Jul-18 09-Aug-18 23-Aug-18 06-Sep-18 20-Sep-18 04-Oct-18 18-Oct-18 01-Nov-18 15-Nov-18 29-Nov-18 13-Dec-18Ad close / materials due 07-Jun- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55580</offset>
      <text> -18 14-Aug-18 21-Aug-18 28-Aug-18 04-Sep-18 11-Sep-18 18-Sep-18 25-Sep-18 Ad close / materials due 12--18 13-Nov-18 20-Nov-18 27-Nov-18 04-Dec-18 11-Dec-18 18-Dec-18 26-Dec-18 Ad close / materials due 11- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55787</offset>
      <text> Figure s2 .Figure s3 .Figure s4 . s2s3s4 Figure s2. XPS spectra of pristine, MA-10, MA-30, and MA-50 films. (a) N 1s peak region, (b) Cl 2p peak region, (c) Pb 4f peak region, and (d) I 3d peak region. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>55991</offset>
      <text> Figure s5 . s5 Figure s5. XRD peak position of perovskite films around 14˚, which is corresponding to the α-phase perovskite, according to the annealing time. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56154</offset>
      <text> 5 . 5 Figure s6. Cerfitication from the Newport Corp. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56210</offset>
      <text> Figure s10 .Figure s11 .Figure s12 . s10s11s12 Figure s10. The EQE spectra for the MA-40 and pristine devices between 800 nm and 860 nm wavelengths. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56361</offset>
      <text> Figure s14 . s14 Figure s14. PDOS of an α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure (bare) and that including Cl. Note that for the bare system, the p orbital of I is considered except for one I, which occupies the Cl site in the system including the Cl. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>56611</offset>
      <text> Figure s15 .Figure s16 . 11 . s15s1611 Figure s15. Volume of cubo-octahedral site of (a) bare α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure and (b)MA included structure. Note that the volume of cubo-octahedral site is calculated by Connolly surface method.1  The radius of probe atom is 1 Å . Each cubo-octahedral site is denoted by number. Calculated Connolly surfaces of cubo-octahedral site 5 of bare and MA systems are described by blue and pink colors, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57077</offset>
      <text> Figure s18 . s18 Figure s18. Model systems of reference state for calculating the doping formation energy. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57186</offset>
      <text> 13 . 13 Figure s19. (a) Formation energy of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including MACl and doping formation energy of MACl into the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure at the pre-annealing step. (b) Formation energy of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including MAI at the post-annealing step. Note that model systems of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including (a) MACl or (b) MAI are described according to their concentration from 11% to 44%. Red colored region indicates the doped sites of MA cation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>57713</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. SEM Images and Grain Size Distribution of Perovskite Films (A-F) Top view of SEM images of devices prepared with different amounts of MACl: (A) pristine (without addition), (B) MA-10, (C) MA-20, (D) MA-30, (E) MA-40, and (F) MA-50. (G) Grain size distribution of the films as a function of the MACl contents (pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50). Note that for the results of grain size distribution, all grains are measured. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58176</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. XRD Spectra and Photoluminescence Data of Perovskite Films (A) XRD spectra of perovskite films prepared with different amounts: pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50. (B) Reciprocal FWHM obtained from films prepared with different additive concentrations at the diffraction peak 13.9 for the a-phase perovskite. (C) XRD data obtained from perovskite films prepared without MACl before and after annealing at 150 C for 10 min. (D) XRD data obtained from perovskite films prepared with MA-40 before and after annealing at 150 C for 10 min. (E) TRPL decay profiles of the perovskite films prepared with pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50. (F) Steady-state photoluminescence spectra of perovskite films prepared with pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>58986</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Photovoltaic Performance Characteristics (A) Efficiency distribution of perovskite solar cells with different amounts of MACl. (B) Device performance current density-voltage (J-V) curves of perovskite devices with pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50. (C) Comparison of distribution efficiencies for pristine, MA-20, and MA-40 devices. (D) J-V curves of reversed and forward scans for the MA-40 and pristine devices. (E) EQE spectra for the MA-40 and pristine devices. (F) Photocurrent density measured at the maximum power point of a 100 min span. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>59571</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Theoretical Calculation for the Role of MACl Additive on the a-Phase FAPbI 3 Perovskite Structure (A and B) Calculations of the a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure and that prepared with Cl, MA, or MACl. Formation energies (A) and highest-occupied molecular orbitals (HOMOs) (B) of bare a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure and that with Cl, MA, or MACl. Note that the isosurface value of the HOMO was 0.01 e/A ˚3. The red and blue dashed circles indicate p orbital localization on I. (C) Projected density of states (PDOS) of the perovskite system including MA or MACl. Note that for the system including MA, the p orbital of I is considered except for one I, which occupies the Cl site in the system including the MACl. (D) Total volume and cubo-octahedral structure of the bare a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure and that prepared with MA. (E) PDOS of the bare a-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite structure and that prepared with MA. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60528</offset>
      <text> Figure s2 .Figure s3 .Figure s4 . s2s3s4 Figure s2. XPS spectra of pristine, MA-10, MA-30, and MA-50 films. (a) N 1s peak region, (b) Cl 2p peak region, (c) Pb 4f peak region, and (d) I 3d peak region. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60732</offset>
      <text> Figure s5 . s5 Figure s5. XRD peak position of perovskite films around 14˚, which is corresponding to the α-phase perovskite, according to the annealing time. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60895</offset>
      <text> 5 . 5 Figure s6. Cerfitication from the Newport Corp. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>60951</offset>
      <text> Figure s10 .Figure s11 .Figure s12 . 10 . s10s11s1210 Figure s10. The EQE spectra for the MA-40 and pristine devices between 800 nm and 860 nm wavelengths. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61109</offset>
      <text> Figure s14 . s14 Figure s14. PDOS of an α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure (bare) and that including Cl. Note that for the bare system, the p orbital of I is considered except for one I, which occupies the Cl site in the system including the Cl. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61359</offset>
      <text> Figure s15 .Figure s16 . 11 . s15s1611 Figure s15. Volume of cubo-octahedral site of (a) bare α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure and (b)MA included structure. Note that the volume of cubo-octahedral site is calculated by Connolly surface method.1  The radius of probe atom is 1 Å . Each cubo-octahedral site is denoted by number. Calculated Connolly surfaces of cubo-octahedral site 5 of bare and MA systems are described by blue and pink colors, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61825</offset>
      <text> Figure s18 . s18 Figure s18. Model systems of reference state for calculating the doping formation energy. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>61934</offset>
      <text> 13 . 13 Figure s19. (a) Formation energy of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including MACl and doping formation energy of MACl into the α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure at the pre-annealing step. (b) Formation energy of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including MAI at the post-annealing step. Note that model systems of α-phase FAPbI3 perovskite structure including (a) MACl or (b) MAI are described according to their concentration from 11% to 44%. Red colored region indicates the doped sites of MA cation. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>62461</offset>
      <text> 6. UV-absorption spectra analysis Figure s7 . UV-absorption spectra of films prepared with different amounts of the MACl additive. Device performances of perovskite solar cells according to the FACl content. 500 0.8 Voltage (V) (a.u.) 0.4 0.6 Pristine 0.2 FACl 10 mol% FACl 20 mol% FACl 30 mol% FACl 40 mol% FACl 50 mol% Absorbance Voltage (V) Pristine MAI 10 mol% MAI 20 mol% MAI 30 mol% Figure s8. Figure s9. Device performances of perovskite solar cells according to the MAI content 600 700 800 900 Pristine MA-10 MA-20 MA-30 MA-40 MA-50 Wavelength (nm) mol% J sc (mA cm -2 ) V oc (V) 2 ) Pristine 24.90 1.016 FACl 10 mol% 23.46 7.039 FACl 20 mol% 23.97 1.030 FACl 30 mol% 24.36 1.092 FACl 40 mol% 24.34 0.993 FACl 50 mol% 22.52 0.995 0.0 1.0 1.2 0 5 Current Density (mA/cm Density (mA/cm 2 ) mol% J sc (mA cm -2 ) V oc (V) Pristine 24.90 1.016 MAI 10 mol% 23.89 1.032 MAI 20 mol% 23.51 0.999 MAI 30 mol% 23.34 0.974 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 1.2 0 5 MAI 40 mol% MAI 50 mol% MAI 40 mol% 22.94 0.9925 Current MAI 50 mol% 20.67 0.969 FF(%) 76.27 74.62 78.25 76.27 77.59 74.37 FF(%) 76.27 74.5 74.21 74.05 53.49 57.13 Eff. (%) 19.29 18.19 19.32 20.28 18.75 16.66 Eff. (%) 19.29 18.38 17.44 16.83 12.18 11.45 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63669</offset>
      <text> Table s1 . s1 Root-mean-square (RMS) roughness of films fabricated by pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, and MA-40, respectively. MACl Pristine (0%) MA-10 MA-20 MA-30 MA-40 RMS (nm) 64.7 45.8 41.0 33.6 24.7 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>63874</offset>
      <text> Table s2 . s2 Fitted TRPL parameters of perovskite prepared with pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively. No additive 10 mol% 20 mol% 30 mol% 40 mol% 50 mol% τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) MACl 331 68.7 513 227 539 183 686 190 1441 450 1336 326 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64220</offset>
      <text> Table s3 . s3 Device performance of efficiencies, Jsc, Voc, and FF of perovskite devices for MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively. mol% Jsc (mA cm -2 ) Voc(V) FF(%) Eff. 0 24.84 1.027 77.08 19.66 MA-10 24.99 1.034 78.50 20.30 MA-20 25.23 1.083 79.61 21.74 MA-30 25.45 1.101 80.38 22.52 MA-40 25.92 1.130 82.02 24.02 MA-50 25.38 1.123 81.97 23.36 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>64583</offset>
      <text> 6. UV-absorption spectra analysis Figure s7 . UV-absorption spectra of films prepared with different amounts of the MACl additive. Device performances of perovskite solar cells according to the FACl content. 500 0.8 Voltage (V) (a.u.) 0.4 0.6 Pristine 0.2 FACl 10 mol% FACl 20 mol% FACl 30 mol% FACl 40 mol% FACl 50 mol% Absorbance Voltage (V) Pristine MAI 10 mol% MAI 20 mol% MAI 30 mol% Figure s8. Figure s9. Device performances of perovskite solar cells according to the MAI content 600 700 800 900 Pristine MA-10 MA-20 MA-30 MA-40 MA-50 Wavelength (nm) mol% J sc (mA cm -2 ) V oc (V) 2 ) Pristine 24.90 1.016 FACl 10 mol% 23.46 7.039 FACl 20 mol% 23.97 1.030 FACl 30 mol% 24.36 1.092 FACl 40 mol% 24.34 0.993 FACl 50 mol% 22.52 0.995 0.0 1.0 1.2 0 5 Current Density (mA/cm Density (mA/cm 2 ) mol% J sc (mA cm -2 ) V oc (V) Pristine 24.90 1.016 MAI 10 mol% 23.89 1.032 MAI 20 mol% 23.51 0.999 MAI 30 mol% 23.34 0.974 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 1.2 0 5 MAI 40 mol% MAI 50 mol% MAI 40 mol% 22.94 0.9925 Current MAI 50 mol% 20.67 0.969 FF(%) 76.27 74.62 78.25 76.27 77.59 74.37 FF(%) 76.27 74.5 74.21 74.05 53.49 57.13 Eff. (%) 19.29 18.19 19.32 20.28 18.75 16.66 Eff. (%) 19.29 18.38 17.44 16.83 12.18 11.45 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65791</offset>
      <text> Table s1 . s1 Root-mean-square (RMS) roughness of films fabricated by pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, and MA-40, respectively. MACl Pristine (0%) MA-10 MA-20 MA-30 MA-40 RMS (nm) 64.7 45.8 41.0 33.6 24.7 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>65996</offset>
      <text> Table s2 . s2 Fitted TRPL parameters of perovskite prepared with pristine, MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively. No additive 10 mol% 20 mol% 30 mol% 40 mol% 50 mol% τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 τ1 τ2 (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) (ns) MACl 331 68.7 513 227 539 183 686 190 1441 450 1336 326 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66342</offset>
      <text> Table s3 . s3 Device performance of efficiencies, Jsc, Voc, and FF of perovskite devices for MA-10, MA-20, MA-30, MA-40, and MA-50, respectively. mol% Jsc (mA cm -2 ) Voc(V) FF(%) Eff. 0 24.84 1.027 77.08 19.66 MA-10 24.99 1.034 78.50 20.30 MA-20 25.23 1.083 79.61 21.74 MA-30 25.45 1.101 80.38 22.52 MA-40 25.92 1.130 82.02 24.02 MA-50 25.38 1.123 81.97 23.36 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66705</offset>
      <text>			 CellPress Recruitment Media Kit 2018 www.recruitmentads.cell.com &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66775</offset>
      <text>			 CellPress Recruitment Media Kit 2018 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66817</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 2179-2192, September 18, 2019 2181 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66866</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 2179-2192, September 18, 2019 2183 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66915</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 2179-2192, September 18, 2019 2185 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>66964</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 2179-2192, September 18, 2019 2187</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
