<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025049901AEBEFB</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">2</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">2</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 138&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13</offset>
      <text>Supplementary Figure 1| a, b, Molecular representations of flat (a) and corrugated (b) SnO2 (110) surfaces. For the corrugated surface, the angle between the two SnO2 (110) crystallographic facets is 95°, comparable with the angle observed from TEM images of FTO substrates (Fig. 2d). The width of the V-shaped crevice was 6 nm. Sn and O atoms are represented by yellow and red spheres, respectively. Voc (V) Jsc (mA cm -2 ) FF (%) J-V PCE (%) Stabilized PCE (%) Conditions Ref.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>493</offset>
      <text>Supplementary Table   1|   Summary of PL peak position, PLQY, Eg, QFLS, and ΔVoc for the perovskite thin films deposited on different substrates. ΔVoc = (Eg -QFLS)/q, where q is elementary charge.   18|  a, UPS secondary electron cut-off region of bare FTO, control and mixed SAM deposited substrates. b, UPS valence band onset region plotted on a relative logarithmic scale of control and mixed SAM deposited substrates. The x-axis energy scale is with respect to the Fermi energy. Gaussian fit (grey solid line) was used to determine the valence band  4  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1055</offset>
      <text> Substrates A Gaussian fit is used here to maintain consistency with the method used to define the IE of the perovskite.  Statistical analysis of the device performance Yes No Figure  4b  and Supplementary Figure  22  9. Long-term stability analysis &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1306</offset>
      <text> Type of analysis, bias conditions and environmental conditions For instance: illumination type, temperature, atmosphere humidity, encapsulation method, preconditioning temperature &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1488</offset>
      <text> Yes No Figure  4f , Supplementary Figure  26  and Supplementary Figure  28  Low-loss contacts on textured substrates for inverted perovskite solar cells Inverted perovskite solar cells (PSCs) promise enhanced operating stability compared to their normal-structure counterparts  [1] [2] [3]  . To improve efficiency further, it is crucial to combine effective light management with low interfacial losses  4, 5  . Here we develop a conformal self-assembled monolayer (SAM) as the hole-selective contact on lightmanaging textured substrates. Molecular dynamics simulations indicate that cluster formation during phosphonic acid adsorption leads to incomplete SAM coverage. We devise a co-adsorbent strategy that disassembles high-order clusters, thus homogenizing the distribution of phosphonic acid molecules, and thereby minimizing interfacial recombination and improving electronic structures. We report a laboratorymeasured power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 25.3% and a certified quasi-steady-state PCE of 24.8% for inverted PSCs, with a photocurrent approaching 95% of the Shockley-Queisser maximum. An encapsulated device having a PCE of 24.6% at room temperature retains 95% of its peak performance when stressed at 65 °C and 50% relative humidity following more than 1,000 h of maximum power point tracking under 1 sun illumination. This represents one of the most stable PSCs subjected to accelerated ageing: achieved with a PCE surpassing 24%. The engineering of phosphonic acid adsorption on textured substrates offers a promising avenue for efficient and stable PSCs. It is also anticipated to benefit other optoelectronic devices that require light management. Perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have recently attained a certified efficiency of 26.1% (ref. 6); however, the very highest power conversion efficiency (PCE) devices have yet to meet operating stability under accelerated ageing tests  5  . The limited device stability is attributed to the presence of mobile and hygroscopic p-type dopants in hole-transporting layers, which undermine moisture and thermal stability  7  . Inverted PSCs present a solution by utilizing undoped hole-selective contacts  8  . Recent studies have shown PCEs surpassing 25% for inverted PSCs 2 . However, when adhering to the stringent quasi-steady-state (QSS) protocol, their certified efficiency (approximately 24%) requires further improvement  3, 9  . Efforts to improve inverted PSC efficiency have focused on interface passivation  2, 9, 10  . This approach suppresses non-radiative recombination and thus improves fill factors and photovoltages  11  . Nevertheless, higher photocurrents are needed for efficiency gains. In normal-structure PSCs, this has been realized using textured fluorine-doped tin oxides (FTO) as the transparent conductive oxides (TCO)  4, 5  . The pyramidal grains on FTO minimize reflection losses and extend the length of the average optical path  4  . By contrast, inverted PSCs, often built on smooth indium tin oxides (ITOs)  9, 10  , face substantial optical losses due to the lack of light management. The discrepancy is ascribed to differences in transporting materials and deposition techniques. In normal-structure PSCs, inorganic hole-blocking layers are conformally deposited on textured substrates using spray pyrolysis and chemical bath deposition  4, 5  . However, inverted PSCs typically use ultrathin (less than 5 nm) organic hole-selective contacts on substrates  2, 3  , which can be challenging to deposit uniformly using solution processing  12  . Inhomogeneity leads to energy losses and insufficient carrier extraction  13  . Self-assembled monolayers (SAMs), particularly those composed of phosphonic acid molecules with hole-selective tail groups, have shown promise in addressing this issue  14  . Phosphonic acids establish coordinative/covalent bonds with TCOs, enabling sufficient SAM coverage Article on rough surfaces  15  . This could provide a low-loss interface, uniting light management with interface passivation. Indeed, photocurrent improvements have been observed when replacing SAM-modified ITO with FTO substrates in inverted PSCs  16  . Despite their promise, achieving a high-density, closely packed SAM remains challenging, which leads to erratic interfacial properties  17  . For example, Liu and co-workers revealed that phosphonic acids failed to fully cover textured wafers, which affected the performance of tandem solar cells  18  . Even on flat substrates, the formation of SAMs tends to be non-uniform, a problem usually attributed to the limited solubility of phosphonic acids  19  and their insufficient chemical bond formation with metal oxides  20  . Several strategies have been proposed to ensure conformal SAM coverage, such as utilizing more reactive oxide surfaces (for example, nickel oxides) to promote hetero condensation  18  , using thermal evaporation for SAM deposition  21  and designing highly soluble phosphonic acid molecules  19  . However, these methods can be laborious, requiring time-intensive molecule design, synthesis and vacuum-based layer deposition. Additionally, the use of highly reactive oxides could compromise device stability owing to redox reactions with ammonium halides  22  . &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:08:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="2452" length="5"/>
        <text>25.3%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">95</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T03:45:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="2668" length="3"/>
        <text>95%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:23:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="2713" length="5"/>
        <text>65 °C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:24:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="2723" length="3"/>
        <text>50%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:24:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="2765" length="7"/>
        <text>1,000 h</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6741</offset>
      <text> Molecular dynamics simulations We sought to deepen understanding of how phosphonic acids interact with textured TCOs. We began by looking at the case of 2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl)phosphonic acid (2PACz), an organic molecule (Fig.  1a ) capable of forming SAMs on TCOs  14  , and investigated its interactions with FTO. 2PACz has found extensive applications as a hole-selective contact in PSCs in view of its excellent defect passivation and deep highest occupied molecular orbital level  21  . The surface properties of FTO were approximated using tin oxides (SnO 2 ), since commercial FTO has a fluorine-doping level under 0.5% (atomic percentage)  23  . Flat versus corrugated SnO 2 was analysed to understand the effects of surface morphology (Supplementary Fig.  1 ). Molecular dynamics simulations suggest that 2PACz molecules can agglomerate, forming dimers, trimers and tetramers (Fig.  1b  and Supplementary Fig.  2 ). Within the initial 1 nanosecond of simulations, 90% of the final number of clusters has been reached (Fig.  1b ), and dimers were the most prevalent among those clusters (Fig.  1c ). Compared to flat surfaces, textured surfaces led to more clusters (for example, 7 versus 0 for 20 2PACz molecules on 6 nm wide SnO 2 ) (Supplementary Note 1 and Supplementary Figs.  3  and 4 ). The cluster formation is closely linked to the inhomogeneity of SAMs on FTO. For instance, when 162 2PACz molecules are positioned on top of textured SnO 2 surfaces, despite their initial random distribution (Supplementary Video 1), the final equilibrated structures exhibit clear phase segregation (Fig.  1d ), in which almost 85% of the SnO 2 surface remains uncovered by any 2PACz molecules (Supplementary Fig.  5 ). These observations were also verified in a larger system (22 nm width; 1,134 2PACz molecules) (Supplementary Fig.  6 ). Reasoning that a thiol group (-SH) could interact with phosphonic acids and a carboxyl group (-COOH) attached to FTO, we introduced 3-mercaptopropionic acid (3-MPA) (Fig.  1a ) in simulations to break apart 2PACz clusters, particularly on textured substrates. The approach is akin to the co-adsorbent strategy used in dye-sensitized solar cells to reduce dye aggregation on titanium oxides  24  . Similar strategies have been used to improve the quality of hole-selective SAMs  25, 26  . With 3-MPA at a molar ratio of 1:9 with 2PACz, we saw a relative 15% decrease in the number of clusters on textured surfaces (Fig.  1b ), and a slower formation rate (20 ns -1 versus 28 ns -1 ) (Supplementary Fig.  7 ). In particular, the higher order clusters (trimers and tetramers) decreased by 53% (Fig.  1c ). As a result, the mixed system shows less phase segregation (Fig.  1e  and Supplementary Video 2), leading to extended surface coverage (67% versus 15%) by 2PACz molecules (Supplementary Fig.  5 ). Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations (Supplementary Note 2 and Supplementary Fig.  8 ) indicate that the presence of 3-MPA hinders the free movement of individual 2PACz molecules by forming a supramolecular structure (Fig.  1f ). This reduces agglomeration with already formed dimers, suppressing the formation of higher-order clusters (Supplementary Video 3). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed surface binding energies of -3.2 eV and -2.6 eV for 2PACz and 3-MPA, respectively, which are much stronger than the interaction energies of 2PACz clusters (-0.3 to -0.1 eV per molecule). This indicates robust anchoring of 2PACz and 3-MPA molecules on contact with substrate surfaces. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl)phosphonic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:14:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="6895" length="41"/>
        <text>2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl)phosphonic acid</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl)phosphonic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:20:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="6938" length="5"/>
        <text>2PACz</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-mercaptopropionic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:14:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="8719" length="24"/>
        <text>3-mercaptopropionic acid</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">additive_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-mercaptopropionic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:14:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="8744" length="6"/>
        <text>(3-MPA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">3-MPA at a molar ratio of 1:9 with 2PACz</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:15:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="9080" length="41"/>
        <text>3-MPA at a molar ratio of 1:9 with 2PACz,</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10298</offset>
      <text> Characterization of organic contacts We deposited both 2PACz and a mixture of 2PACz:3-MPA on FTO substrates using solution processing, followed by annealing the film at 100 °C and solvent washing (Methods). Micelles were detected in the processing solutions through dynamic light scattering (DLS) (Supplementary Fig.  9 ). However, owing to their limited proportion in the volume distribution compared to 2PACz monomers, film formation primarily resulted from molecular diffusion rather than direct micellar adsorption  27  . The film composition and its interaction with FTO substrates were investigated using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and attenuated total reflectance Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (ATR-FTIR), respectively. For the film consisting solely of 2PACz molecules (the control), the presence of 2PACz was evidenced by the appearance of the phosphine (P) doublet peak (Fig.  2a ) and the characteristic C-N peak and C-C/C-H peak (Supplementary Fig.  10 ) in the XPS spectra  21  . In the case of mixed film, 3-MPA was indicated by the sulfur (S) 2p doublet peak at around 163.8 eV (that is, the thiol group) (Fig.  2a )  28  . From ATR-FTIR, bidentate or tridentate binding was identified as the mode of 2PACz-FTO interactions, given the appearance of the symmetric PO 3 2-stretching (at 996 cm -1 for the control sample)  29, 30  and the disappearance of P-OH vibrations  14  . These also indicated that solvent washing removed unbound molecules  14  . With 3-MPA addition, a redshift of approximately 5 cm -1 was observed for the PO 3 2-vibrational mode, indicating the enhanced surface binding of 2PACz-as confirmed by AIMD simulations (Supplementary Note 3 and Supplementary Figs.  11  and 12 ). ATR-FTIR of the FTO/3-MPA sample (Fig.  2b ) further showed carboxylate-related peaks and a reduction in the intensity of the C=O peak, which correspond to the bidentate chelation of 3-MPA with FTO surfaces  31  . Combining the results from XPS and ATR-FTIR, we reasoned that 3-MPA functioned as a co-adsorbent, modulating the interaction of 2PACz with FTO substrates.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12405</offset>
      <text> Article The resultant SAM uniformity was characterized by Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM). Topography images revealed that, despite varying SAM modifications, the surface morphology of FTO substrates was retained owing to the ultrathin nature of SAMs (Supplementary Fig.  13 ). From the respective contact potential difference (CPD) maps (Fig.  2c ), we recorded surface potential variations on 2PACz-modified surfaces within a range of 120 mV. A Gaussian fit of the single peak in the CPD distribution yielded the full-width half-maximum (FWHM) of 37 mV (Supplementary Fig.  14 ). Introducing 3-MPA enhanced the homogeneity of electronic properties on SAM-modified surfaces, as reflected by a narrower CPD distribution with the FWHM of 22 mV. To directly visualize the distribution of SAMs on FTO substrates, we performed high-angle annular dark-field (HAADF) scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) measurements. Figure  2d  shows cross-sectional HAADF-STEM images of both control and mixed samples. Because of the contrast in the atomic number  2  , SAM was discernible as a dark layer sandwiched between the brighter FTO and protective molybdenum oxide (MoO x ) layers. For the control SAM, we observed thickness variations across the same FTO facet, with certain regions showing thicknesses less than 1 nm. This suggests a low-density coverage and inhomogeneous distribution of 2PACz molecules  32  . The mixed sample exhibited significant improvements in terms of SAM uniformity and coverage; a consistent thickness was recorded for the mixed SAM on the same facet, albeit with variations between 1 and 2 nm across different facets. Correspondingly, mixed SAM-modified FTO substrates exhibited higher hydrophobicity than control SAM-modified counterparts (Supplementary Fig.  15 ). Cyclic voltammetry measurements further determined the areal density of 2PACz in the mixed SAM to be   and mixed (right) SAMs. The colour bar shows the diffraction intensity collected from the GIWAXS detector. q xy and q z represent in-plane and near out-of-plane scattering vectors, respectively. d,e, TOF-SIMS profiles of perovskites on FTO/ control SAM (d) and FTO/mixed SAM (e) substrates measured in negative polarity. Traces of SH -were identified at the perovskite-control SAM interface, possibly owing to contamination of precursor materials. f, Absolute intensity photoluminescence spectra of perovskite films on bare FTO (no SAM) and control and mixed SAMs. g, PLQYs of perovskite films on control and mixed SAMs (five samples for each condition). Statistical distribution represented in box plots (line within the box: mean; box limit: standard deviation). h, UPS and IPES spectra of perovskite films on control and mixed SAMs. Gaussian fit (grey line) was used to determine the conduction and valence bands. i,j, Schematic energy-level diagrams of the perovskite/control SAM (i) and perovskite/mixed SAM bilayer ( j), respectively. Scale bars, 1 µm. IE, ionization energy; HTL, holetransport layer; PVSK, perovskite. 3.9 × 10 13 molecules per cm 2 , a 70% increase from the 2.3 × 10 13 molecules per cm 2 in the control SAM (Supplementary Fig.  16 )  16, 27  . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>15585</offset>
      <text> Characterization of perovskite films To investigate the impact of SAMs on the structural and optoelectronic properties of perovskites, we fabricated triple-cation Cs 0.05 MA 0.10 FA 0.85 PbI 3 perovskite thin films on different FTO/SAM substrates. From scanning electron microscopy (SEM), we observed no notable change in the perovskite surface morphology when 3-MPA was incorporated into the SAM (Fig.  3a, b ). Grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS) measurements showed nearly identical crystal structures for perovskites deposited on both the control and mixed SAMs (Fig.  3c ). Here, the main constituent was photoactive α-phase perovskites, with traces of the 4H hexagonal phase detected at q = 0.82 Å -1 and 0.92 Å -1 as well as PbI 2 at q = 0.90 Å -1 , respectively (Supplementary Fig.  14 )  33  . Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) further confirmed that both 3-MPA and 2PACz molecules, owing to their chemisorption on FTO surfaces, remained localized at the perovskite-FTO interfaces (Fig.  3d, e ). These findings suggest that 3-MPA is not likely to change the perovskite formation process or contribute to the grain boundary or top surface passivation. We conducted photoluminescence characterization by exciting perovskite thin films at a 1 sun equivalent photon flux. We saw an average photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) of 0.13% ± 0.02% for perovskites directly deposited onto FTO substrates, corresponding to a quasi-Fermi level splitting of 1.105 eV (Supplementary Table  1 )  34  . 2PACz can passivate defects on metal oxide surfaces and effectively block electron injection  35  , resulting in an approximately 50-fold increase in the photoluminescence intensity (Fig.  3f ). We noted an average PLQY of 7% ± 2% for the perovskite/2PACz/FTO stacks (Fig.  3g ), corresponding to a quasi-Fermi level splitting of 1.207 eV. The incorporation of 3-MPA further improved the average PLQY to 10% ± 1%. This we ascribed to better SAM coverage rather than 3-MPA passivation, as the thiol group of 3-MPA was embedded within the SAM (Fig.  1f ). We used ultraviolet and inverse photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS and IPES) to determine the work function and transport energy levels of perovskites and SAMs. The secondary electron cutoff in the UPS spectra indicated an increase in the work function from 4.56 to 4.93 eV on depositing the control SAM on the FTO substrate (Supplementary Fig.  18 ). 3-MPA led to an additional work function shift of +100 meV. The ionization energy was 5.51 and 5.64 eV for the control and mixed SAMs, respectively. By contrast, perovskites exhibited similar conduction band minima and valance band maxima on different substrates (Fig.  3h ). The resultant energy-level diagrams of perovskites and SAMs are depicted in Fig.  3i, j . A vacuum level shift of 0.17 eV was recorded between the perovskite and the 2PACz bilayer, which further increased to 0.32 eV for the perovskite/mixed SAM bilayer  36  . A higher vacuum level shift indicates an enlarged built-in field  37  , which in PSCs can lead to enhanced carrier extraction  38  . Meanwhile, the ionization energy offset between the bilayer remained consistent for the control and mixed SAMs (referenced to the Fermi level (E F )). &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Cs0.05MA0.10FA0.85PbI3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:17:34Z</infon>
        <location offset="15749" length="29"/>
        <text>Cs 0.05 MA 0.10 FA 0.85 PbI 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>18860</offset>
      <text> Solar cell efficiency and stability We fabricated PSCs with the following inverted structure: FTO/SAM/ perovskites/3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium (345FAn)/fullerene (C 60 )/bathocuproine (BCP)/Ag (Fig.  4a  and Supplementary Fig.  19 ). 345FAn was selected for interface engineering because of its thermal stability  1  . 2PACz (control) and 2PACz:3-MPA (mixed) were used as the SAMs for   &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:19:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="18955" length="95"/>
        <text>FTO/SAM/ perovskites/3,4,5-trifluoroanilinium (345FAn)/fullerene (C 60 )/bathocuproine (BCP)/Ag</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">2-(9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl)phosphonic acid</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:20:42Z</infon>
        <location offset="19177" length="5"/>
        <text>2PACz</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19246</offset>
      <text> Methods &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19256</offset>
      <text> Molecular dynamics simulations Static DFT calculation and AIMD were performed with the CP2K  40  package utilizing a mixed Gaussian/plane wave (GPW) basis. The PBE exchange-correlation functional  41  , DFT-D3 dispersion corrections  42  and dipole corrections  43  necessary for periodic boundary conditions along the perpendicular direction to the surface were included. Valence electron wave functions were expanded in a double-ζ Gaussian basis set with polarization functions (DZVP)  44  . The energy cutoff for the electron density expansion in the GPW method was 400 Ry. Born-Oppenheimer AIMD simulations were run with an integration time step of 0.5 fs and the system was kept at 300 K using the thermostat of Bussi et al.  45  in a canonical isothermal-isochoric (NVT) ensemble, in which the total number of atoms N, the volume V and the temperature T of the system were held constant. All AIMD simulations were performed at Γ point. Being the most stable surface, the SnO 2 (110) was chosen as the substrate surface. The systems were equilibrated over 5 ps in the NVT ensemble and the remaining 40 ps were used for the production run. To investigate the interactions between the 2PACz and 3-MPA molecules, as well as molecules and the SnO   110 )); E S is the energy of the final configuration of the slab; and E mol is the energy of the final configuration of the isolated molecule. The interaction energies of 2PACz clusters were computed after DFT relaxations of isolated clusters. Dimers, trimers and tetramers were considered. Interaction energies per molecule were calculated as ΔE i = (E tot - nE mol )/n, where E tot is the energy of the final relaxed cluster; n is the number of molecules forming the cluster; and E mol is the energy of a single relaxed molecule assumed isolated. Vibrational power spectra were computed as the Fourier transform of the autocorrelation function of the atomic velocities. Classical molecular dynamics simulations with full atomic resolution were realized with the help of the LAMMPS molecular dynamics simulator  46  . The equations of motion were integrated using the velocity Verlet method  47  , with a 1 fs time step, in which bond stretching was not constrained for any bonds. To maintain isothermal conditions, the deterministic Nosé-Hoover thermostat  48, 49  , with a time constant equal to 0.1 ps, was used. This ensured that thermostating was applied to both translational and rotational degrees of freedom, crucial for the asymmetric 2PACz and 3-MPA molecules. All classical molecular dynamics simulations were realized in the canonical NVT ensemble at T = 300 K comprising a V-shaped SnO 2 (110) model system with dimensions 60 Å × 105 Å × 40 Å. Periodic boundary conditions were used in x and y directions, whereas reflective boundary conditions were used in the z direction. The two considered systems, control and mixed, consisted of a total of 18,498 and 18,714 atoms, respectively, whereas the experimental molar ratio (2PACz:3-MPA = 9:1) was retained in the simulated mixed system. The systems were equilibrated for 1 ns followed by a 10 ns production simulation, during which sampling took place every 500 fs for the calculation of ensemble averages. A snapshot of the system was taken every 1,000 fs for visualization purposes. The calculation of the number distributions of formed 2PACz clusters was performed through an in-house code using a threshold distance of 8 Å among the centre of masses of adjacent 2PACz molecules, in accordance with the nearest neighbour shell of the corresponding radial distribution function as clustering criterion. To accurately capture the interactions of SnO 2 , the thoroughly validated classical force field developed by Bandura et al.  50  was used. The all-atom OPLS force field was utilized for 3-MPA, wherein the corresponding interaction parameters were obtained with the help of the LigParGen server  51  . For 2PACz, containing the phosphonic functional group, the specially designed force field developed by Meltzer et al.  52  based on the generalized Amber force field  53  was used. The van der Waals and electrostatic non-bonded interactions were calculated using a real-space cutoff radius of 10 Å and 8 Å, respectively, whereas the particle-particle-particle-mesh scheme  54  with an accuracy of 0.0001 (kcal mol -1 ) Å -1 was used for the consideration of long-range electrostatic interactions. Because the SnO 2 force field uses a Buckingham potential for the van der Waals interactions, its combination with the Lennard-Jones potential used for the compounds was realized by fitting the Buckingham parameters of SnO 2 to a suitable set of Lennard-Jones parameters  55  and geometric mixing rules were applied for all dissimilar non-bonded interactions. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24048</offset>
      <text> Materials All materials were used as received without further purification. Organic halide salts, including methylammonium iodide (MAI), formamidinium iodide (FAI) and methylammonium chloride (MACl), were purchased from Great Cell Solar. Caesium iodide (CsI), 3-mercaptopropionic acid (3-MPA), 3,4,5-trifluoroaniline (98%) and guanidinium thiocyanate (GuaSCN) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. 3,4,5-Trifluoroaniline was converted to its ammonium form following the published procedure. 2PACz, lead iodide (PbI 2 , 99.99%) and BCP were purchased from TCI. Anhydrous solvents, including N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF, 99.8%), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, 99.9%), 2-propanol (IPA, 99.5%), chloroform (CF, 99.8%) and anisole (99.7%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. The C 60 was purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. ITO and FTO (TEC 10) substrates were purchased from Thin Film Devices and Ossila, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>24966</offset>
      <text> Perovskite film fabrication First, 1.5 M Cs 0.05 MA 0.1 FA 0.85 PbI 3 perovskite precursor was fully dissolved in mixed solvents of DMF and DMSO (4:1, v/v) with the molar ratio for FAI/MAI/CsI of 0.85:0.1:0.05. Then, 10 mg ml -1 MACl and 8 mg ml  -1  GuaSCN were added to the solution to improve the film morphology. The precursor solution was filtered through a 0.22 µm polytetrafluoroethylene membrane before use. A portion of 60 µl of perovskite solution was deposited on the substrate and spun cast at 1,000 rpm for 10 s, followed by 6,000 rpm for 30 s. A 150 µl portion of anisole was dropped onto the substrate during the last 5 s of spinning, resulting in the formation of dark brown films that were then annealed on a hot plate at 100 °C for ITO and 120 °C for FTO, for 20 min. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25759</offset>
      <text> Device fabrication FTO glasses were sequentially sonicated in aqueous detergent, deionized water, acetone and IPA each for 10 min. After drying with nitrogen, the substrates were exposed to UV-ozone treatment for 15 min to remove organic contaminants and then transferred into a nitrogen-filled glovebox maintaining less than 0.1 ppm of O 2 and H 2 O. Then, 100 µl of 2PACz or a mixture of 2PACz:3-MPA (in a molar ratio of either 9:1 in characterization and device fabrication, or 8:2 in XPS measurements) in anhydrous ethanol (1 mM) solution was uniformly spread on the substrates and allowed to rest for 15 s, followed by spinning of the films at 3,000 rpm for 30 s. The films were then annealed at 100 °C for 10 min and washed by dropping 500 µl ethanol during the film spinning at 3,000 rpm. Perovskite solution was deposited on the SAM-modified substrate as detailed above. A 200 µl portion of 345FAn solution (1 mg ml -1 ) in CF with an additional 3% of IPA was then drop cast within 2-3 s on the perovskite film spinning at 4,000 rpm (that is, dynamic spinning) and annealed at 100 °C for 5 min. Both control and mixed SAM films were then transferred to the thermal evaporator (Angstrom Engineering). The C 60 (30 nm) and BCP (7 nm) were deposited sequentially with a rate of 0.3 Å s -1 and 0.5 Å s -1 , respectively, at a pressure of approximately 2 × 10 -6 mbar. Finally, Ag contact (140 nm) was deposited on top of BCP through a shadow mask with the desired aperture area. For the stability testing, ALD-SnO 2 was used as the barrier layer. The deposition of ALD-SnO 2 was carried out in the PICOSUN R-200 Advanced ALD system. H 2 O and TDMASn were used as oxygen and tin precursors. Precursor and substrate temperature were set to 75 °C and 85 °C, respectively. The carrier gas used was 90 sccm N 2 . Pulse and purge times for H 2 O were 1 s and 5 s, and 1.6 s and 5 s for TDMASn. The total deposition cycle was 120, corresponding to 20 nm of SnO 2 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27733</offset>
      <text> Solar cell characterization The current-voltage (I-V) characteristics of solar cells were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under the illumination of a solar simulator (Newport, Class AAA) at a light intensity of 100 mW cm -2 , as checked using a calibrated reference solar cell (Newport). The stabilized PCE was measured by setting the bias voltage to the V MPP and then tracing the current density. The V MPP was determined from the reverse I-V curve. The active area was determined by the aperture shade mask (0.049 cm 2 ) placed in front of the solar cell to avoid overestimation of the photocurrent density. EQE spectra were recorded with a commercial system (Arkeo-Ariadne, Cicci Research) based on a 300 W xenon light source and a holographic grating monochromator (Cornerstone, Newport). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>28541</offset>
      <text> Stability tests of solar cells Devices were placed in a homemade stability tracking station. The illumination source was a white-light LED with intensity calibrated to match the 1 sun condition. For the ISOS-L-3 ageing protocol (65 or 85 °C; 50% relative humidity; MPP)  56  , the device chamber was left open in a room with 50 ± 10% humidity and the solar cell was mounted on a metal plate kept at 65 °C by a heating element. A thermal couple attached to the metal plate was used to monitor and provide feedback control to the heating element to ensure temperature consistency. MPP was tracked using a home-built MATLAB-based MPP tracking system using a 'perturb and observe' method. The MPP was updated every 1,000 min. Encapsulation was done by capping the device with a glass slide, using UV adhesive (Lumtec LT-U001) as a sealant. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-27T09:22:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="28745" length="8"/>
        <text>ISOS-L-3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29382</offset>
      <text> XPS measurements XPS measurements were performed with a Thermo Scientific K-Alpha system with 180° double-focusing, hemispherical analyser. The system is equipped with a 128-channel detector and monochromatic small-spot XPS. An AlKα source (1,486.6 eV) was used for excitation and a pass energy of 50 eV was used for XPS acquisition. Samples were mounted on a metal specimen holder. All data were analysed with CasaXPS and Thermo Avantage software. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29835</offset>
      <text> KPFM measurements KPFM measurements were performed using an Asylum Research Cypher S atomic force microscope (Oxford Instruments) with an ASYELEC.01-R2 Ti-Ir coated cantilever (Asylum Research). Scans were performed over 2 µm at 512 pixels and 0.5 Hz using a two-pass method in which the first pass is a tapping mode topography scan and the second is in KPFM mode with a tip potential of 3 V and a surface clearance of 5 nm. Cantilever calibration was performed using the Thermal method from the Asylum Research GetReal database. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30368</offset>
      <text> HAADF-TEM measurements HAADF-TEM images were acquired at an aberration-corrected FEI Titan Cubed Themis G2 operated at 300 kV equipped with an XFEG gun and Bruker Super-X EDS detectors. The SAM samples had a structure of glass/FTO/SAM/MoO x (50 nm), in which the MoO x layer was deposited through thermal evaporation with a low rate of 0.1 Å s -1 at a pressure below 2 × 10 -4 Pa. The cross-sectional samples were prepared by using a focused ion-beam system (Helios G4 UX). Another protective layer of carbon was thermally evaporated before ion-beam cutting and etching. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>30943</offset>
      <text> Cyclic voltammetry measurements Cyclic voltammetry measurements were conducted using a three-electrode configuration with a potentiostat (PGSTAT204, Autolab). The working electrodes were prepared using a spin-coating method on an FTO electrode. The exposed area of the working electrode to the electrolyte measured 8 mm × 21.4 mm. A platinum plate and an Ag/AgCl electrode (in a 3.0 M KCl solution) were used as the counter and reference electrodes, respectively. The measurements were performed in an Ar-saturated solution of 1,2-dichlorobenzene (o-DCB) with 0.1 M tetrabutylammonium hexafluorophosphate (TBA + PF 6 -) serving as the supporting electrolyte. All potentials were referenced against the ferrocene redox couple, serving as an internal standard. The effective coverage of the self-assembled monolayers on the FTO surface was measured by the slope of a linear dependency of the oxidative peak intensity against the scan rate, as follows: i n F RTN AΓ v = 4 * p,o 2 2 A where i p,o is the oxidative peak current, v is the voltage scan rate, n is the number of electrons transferred, F is the Faraday constant (96,485 C mol -1 ), R is the universal gas constant (8.314 J K -1 mol -1 ), T is the temperature, N A is the Avogadro constant, A is the electrode area and Γ* is the areal density. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32249</offset>
      <text> UPS and IPES measurements UPS measurements were taken with an Excitech H Lyman-α photon source (10.2 eV) with a nitrogen-filled beam path coupled with a PHI 5600 UHV and analyser system. A sample bias of -5 V was applied and a pass energy of 5.85 eV was used for UPS acquisition. IPES measurements were performed in the Bremsstrahlung isochromatic mode with electron kinetic energies below 5 eV and an electron gun emission current of 2 µA was used to minimize sample damage. A Kimball Physics ELG-2 electron gun with a BaO cathode was used to generate the electron beam. Emitted photons were collected with a bandpass photon detector consisting of an optical bandpass filter (254 nm, Semrock) and a photomultiplier tube (R585, Hamamatsu Photonics). Samples were held at a -20 V bias during all IPES measurements and the UHV chamber was completely dark. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33107</offset>
      <text> Other characterizations Particle size distributions in solutions were determined by the DLS technique using a Malvern Zetasizer Nano ZS. Contact angles were measured using VCA-Optima XE. The image was taken with a CCD camera within 1 s after water droplet. GIWAXS measurements were performed at the CMS beamline, NSLS II. The monochromatic X-ray with an energy of 13.5 keV was shone on the samples at different grazing incident angles of 1°, 0.5° and 0.08° with an exposure time of 10 s. A Pilatus 800K detector was placed 259 mm away from the sample to capture the two-dimensional diffraction pattern. Absolute intensity photoluminescence spectra were measured using an integrating sphere, and Andor Kymera 193i spectrograph, and a 660 nm continuous-wave laser set at 1 sun equivalent photon flux (1.1 µm beam FWHM, 632 µW); photoluminescence was collected at normal incidence using a 0.1 numerical aperture, 110-µm-diameter optical fibre. TOF-SIMS was conducted on the IONTOF M6 instrument with a Bi 3+ (30 keV) primary ion beam for analysis and a Cs cluster gun (2 keV) for sputtering. Data were acquired in positive mode with an analysis area of 49 × 49 µm 2 centred and a raster area of 200 × 200 µm  2  . IR spectra were obtained in the attenuated total reflectance mode using a Fourier-transform IR spectrometer (Thermo Scientific iS50). Samples were prepared on the FTO substrate and scanned in the spectral range of 4,000 to 550 cm -1 with a minimum number of 500 scans and a resolution of 4 cm -1 . The triangular apodization function was used to improve the signal-to-noise ratio. High-resolution SEM images were obtained using the Hitachi S5200 microscope with an accelerating voltage of 1.5 kV. A low accelerating voltage and a low beam current were deployed to reduce surface damage of perovskite films under electron beam bombardment. The diffuse and specular light reflected from the substrate surface was measured using a Cary 5000 UV-Vis-NIR double-beam spectrophotometer in diffuse reflectance mode. Pure BaSO 4 was used for the baseline collection. Figure4band Supplementary Figure22 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35223</offset>
      <text> So Min Park 1 , 2 , 10 , 1210 Mingyang Wei 3,10 , Nikolaos Lempesis 4,10 , Wenjin Yu 5 , Tareq Hossain 6 , Lorenzo Agosta 4 , Virginia Carnevali 4 , Harindi R. Atapattu 6 , Peter Serles 7 , Felix T. Eickemeyer 3 , Heejong Shin 1 , Maral Vafaie 2 , Deokjae Choi 1 , Kasra Darabi 8 , Eui Dae Jung 2 , Yi Yang 1 , Da Bin Kim 2 , Shaik M. Zakeeruddin 3 , Bin Chen 1 , Aram Amassian 8 , Tobin Filleter 7 , Mercouri G. Kanatzidis 1 , Kenneth R. Graham 6 , Lixin Xiao 5 , Ursula Rothlisberger 4 , Michael Grätzel 3 ✉ &amp; Edward H. Sargent 1,2,9 ✉ &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35768</offset>
      <text> Fig. 1 | 1 Fig. 1 | Molecular dynamics simulations of phosphonic acid adsorption with and without molecular additives. a, Chemical structures of the phosphonic acid 2PACz and the bifunctional compound 3-MPA. b, Total number of 2PACz clusters formed over a set period, in the absence (without, control) and presence (with, mixed) of 3-MPA. c, Types of 2PACz clusters formed at equilibrium. d,e, Top views of equilibrated molecular representations of control (d) and mixed (e) systems. 2PACz and 3-MPA (where applicable) are shown in pink and blue, respectively; Sn and O atoms, shown in the background, are depicted in yellow and red, respectively. f, Successive steps along an AIMD trajectory showcasing the role of 3-MPA as a co-adsorbent. Large, encircled areas are magnifications of small ones. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>36568</offset>
      <text> Fig. 2 | 2 Fig. 2 | Homogeneity of self-assembled monolayers formed on FTO substrates. a, XPS P 2p (left) and S 2p (right) spectra for the control and mixed samples. The peaks were fitted using one S 2p or P 2p doublet with a 2:1 peak area ratio. b, 2PACz (left) and 3-MPA (right) transmission FTIR spectra, compared with ATR-FTIR spectra for the SAM-coated (left) and 3-MPA-coated (right) FTO substrates. The FTIR peaks identified at 947 and 1,021 cm -1 for 2PACz powders correspond to the symmetric and asymmetric (as) stretching of P-OH, respectively. Cz, carbazole. c, KPFM images of control (left) and mixed (right) SAM-coated FTO substrates. d, Cross-sectional HAADF-STEM images of control (top) and mixed (bottom) SAMs sandwiched between MoO x and FTO. Scale bars, 500 nm (c); 100 nm (d, left); 20 nm (d, right). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37390</offset>
      <text> Photon ux (s -1 m -2 nm -1) Control Mixed &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37434</offset>
      <text> Fig. 3 | 3 Fig. 3 | Materials properties of perovskite films on different FTO/SAMsubstrates. a,b, Top-view SEM images of perovskite films deposited on control (a) and mixed (b) SAMs. c, GIWAXS images for perovskite films on control (left) and mixed (right) SAMs. The colour bar shows the diffraction intensity collected from the GIWAXS detector. q xy and q z represent in-plane and near out-of-plane scattering vectors, respectively. d,e, TOF-SIMS profiles of perovskites on FTO/ control SAM (d) and FTO/mixed SAM (e) substrates measured in negative polarity. Traces of SH -were identified at the perovskite-control SAM interface, possibly owing to contamination of precursor materials. f, Absolute intensity &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38145</offset>
      <text> Fig. 4 | 4 Fig. 4 | Photovoltaic performance of perovskite solar cells. a, Schematic illustration of the device architecture with textured FTO substrate. b, Solar cell parameters for the control (16 devices) and mixed (32 devices) SAM devices. Statistical distribution represented in box-and-whisker plots (line within box: median; box limit: standard deviation; whiskers: 1.5 × outliers). c, EQE and integrated J sc (grey dashed line) curves of the mixed SAM device. d, QSS J-V curve of one representative mixed SAM device certified at Newport. Inset: PV parameters of the device. e, Certified performance of inverted PSCs measured under the QSS condition. f, MPP tracking of the encapsulated mixed SAM device at heat sink temperature of 65 °C with a relative humidity (RH) of approximately 50% under 1 sun illumination. The device configuration is FTO/SAM/perovskite/ 345FAn/C 60 /ALD-SnO 2 /Ag, with a PCE of 24.6% at room temperature. ALD, atomiclayer deposition; FF, fill factor. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>39134</offset>
      <text> Supplementary Table3|Summary of reported device operating stability based on ISOS-L-3 protocols. RT = room temperature. Light source Identity of the independent certification laboratory T Environm ent PCE @RT Yes Newport PCE @high-T Lifetime Ref. that confirmed the photovoltaic performance No White LED Provide in Supplementary Information 65°C A copy of any certificate(s) ~50% RH 24.6% No Yes Supplementary Figure 21 23.1% (65°C) T95 = 1075 h This work N.A. 65°C ~85% RH 25.0% 23.35% (65°C) T82 = 500 h P. Shi, Nature (2023) 13 1.1607 White LED 85°C 25.44 ~50% RH 81.48 N.A. 21.1% 24.05% 19.9% (85°C) QSS (NREL) T85 = 1560 h Q. Jiang, Nature (2022) 6 S. M. Park, Science (2023) 5 1.1505 White LED 1.1687 Metal-halide lamp 65°C 85°C 24.90 ~50% RH 83.46 22.89 84.55 ~65% RH N.A. 23.1% N.A. 17.4% 23.91% N.A. 22.62% ~16.5% (85°C) QSS (NREL) T92 = 500 h QSS (NREL) T85 = 4000 h H. Chen, Nat. Photonics H. Chen, Nat. Photonics (2022) 7 (2022) 7 S. Chen, Sci. Adv (2021) 8 X. Zhao, Science (2022) 14 1.1429 Xenon lamp 85°C 23.84 ~50% RH 82.0 N.A. 20.1% 22.34% ~14.2% (85°C) QSS (Newport) T95 = 1200 h X. Zheng, Nat. Energy (2020) 9 Y-H. Lin, Science (2020) 15 1.203 Plasma lamp 65°C 25.02 ~60% RH 82.73 24.90% 21.1% 24.71% ~19.5% (65°C) MPP (NPVM) T96.8 = 1200 h W.Peng, Science (2023) 10 S. Yang, Science (2019) 16 1.171 25.33 82.60 24.50% 24.25% MPP (NPVM) X. Wu, Adv. Mater. (2023) 11 1.19 24.45 84.2 24.5% 24.1% MPP (JET) F. Li, Nat. Photonics (2023) 12 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>40604</offset>
      <text> MPA on SnO 2(110). In all the scenarios, an in-plane SnO 2 (110) simulation cell of 22.690 Å × 27.756 Å with 45 Å of vacuum between the slab repetitions was used. AIMD was also used to estimate the interaction energy of 2PACz and 3-MPA with the SnO 2 (110) surface. The final AIMD configurations were relaxed with DFT to extract the interaction energies of the molecules. Binding energies were calculated as ΔE b = E tot - E S - E mol , where E tot is the energy of the final relaxed configuration (molecule on SnO 2 ( 2 substrate, five scenarios were simulated: (1) a single molecule (2PCAz or 3-MPA) on SnO 2 (110); (2) one 2PACz and one 3-MPA concurrently on SnO 2 (110); (3) two 2PACz and one 3-MPA on SnO 2 (110); (4) four 2PACz and one 3-MPA on SnO 2 (110); and (5) six 2PACz and one 3-</text>
    </passage>
    <relation id="R1">
      <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
      <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
      <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:53Z</infon>
      <node refid="14" role=""/>
      <node refid="2" role=""/>
      <node refid="3" role=""/>
      <node refid="4" role=""/>
      <node refid="5" role=""/>
      <node refid="10" role=""/>
    </relation>
  </document>
</collection>
