<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025023348IEGIIG</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 7&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>11</offset>
      <text>The 2D Halide Perovskite Rulebook: How the Spacer Influences Everything from the Structure to Optoelectronic Device Efficiency&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>138</offset>
      <text>Two-dimensional (2D)  halide perovskites have emerged as outstanding semiconducting materials thanks to their superior stability and structural diversity. However, the ever-growing field of optoelectronic device research using 2D perovskites requires systematic understanding of the effects of the spacer on the structure, properties, and device performance. So far, many studies are based on trial-and-error tests of random spacers with limited ability to predict the resulting structure of these synthetic experiments, hindering the discovery of novel 2D materials to be incorporated into high-performance devices. In this review, we provide guidelines on successfully choosing spacers and incorporating them into crystalline materials and optoelectronic devices. We first provide a summary of various synthetic methods to act as a tutorial for groups interested in pursuing synthesis of novel 2D perovskites. Second, we provide our insights on what kind of spacer cations can stabilize 2D perovskites followed by an extensive review of the spacer cations, which have been shown to stabilize 2D perovskites with an emphasis on the effects of the spacer on the structure and optical properties. Next, we provide a similar explanation for the methods used to fabricate films and their desired properties. Like the synthesis section, we will then focus on various spacers that have been used in devices and how they influence the film structure and device performance. With a comprehensive understanding of these effects, a rational selection of novel spacers can be made, accelerating this already exciting field.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1752</offset>
      <text>INTRODUCTION Halide perovskites are rock-star semiconducting materials which have emerged in the past decade because of their extraordinary physical properties such as high mobility, long carrier lifetime and low trap density despite the presence of excessive impurities, structural defects, disorders and compositional variations.  1, 2  They have outperformed many rival materials from other classes of compounds in a wide variety of optoelectronic applications such as solar cells,  3, 4  light emitting diodes (LEDs),  5, 6  field effect transistors (FETs),  7, 8  lasers,  9, 10  and detectors (e.g., photodetectors, X-ray and γ-ray detectors).  [11] [12] [13]  The most extensively studied perovskites are three-dimensional (3D) halide perovskites with the general formula AMX 3 [A = Cs + , CH 3 NH 3 + (MA), or HC-(NH 2 ) 2 + (FA); M = Ge 2+ , Sn 2+ , Pb  2+  ; X= Cl -, Br -, I -]. The 3D structure with six-coordinated octahedra connected by corner-sharing creates a favorable electronic band structure with broad conduction and valence bands that facilitates the charge transport.  14  Larger organic cations cannot incorporate into the 3D structure, so lower-dimensional structures form instead. A common structure type is that of two-dimensional (2D) halide perovskites, which can be imagined as "cleaving" the 3D structure along a crystallographic plane to form sheets, adding halide ions to satisfy the surface metal coordination sites and with the large cations inserted between the inorganic layers as spacers. The cleaving can be along the ⟨100⟩-, ⟨110⟩-, and ⟨111⟩-planes of the 3D structure, giving rise to ⟨100⟩-, ⟨110⟩-, and ⟨111⟩-oriented 2D perovskites. These sheets stack to form the bulk crystalline materials.  15  This type of dimensional reduction, where the covalently bonded 3D metal-anion (M-X) framework is terminated by chargebalancing counterions in one or more directions, is common in solid-state chemistry (Figure  1a ),  16, 17  This is different from the morphological dimensional reduction, where the framework itself stays the same but the crystallite size changes to the point where the system exhibits size-dependent properties at the nanoscale. For example, morphological changes for CsPbBr 3 result in 3D nanocubes, 2D nanoplates and 1D nanowires, but all these are still 3D materials in the solid-state definition since they all have the same framework (Figure  1b ). The 2D perovskites exhibit excellent structural diversity, and their properties can be tuned by the layer thickness, the cage cation and the spacer cation.  18, 19  They can be seen as naturally formed quantum wells; as the layer becomes thinner, the bandgap increases in defined steps since the structure becomes more quantum confined perpendicular to the stacking direction. The cage A-site cation can affect not only the metal-halide-metal (M-X-M) bond angles, like in 3D perovskites, but also the metal-halide (M-X) bond length, both of which can modulate the overlap of the metal and halide orbitals, thus altering the bandgap in a smaller degree than the layer-number.  20, 21  The properties of the 2D perovskites can also be tuned by the spacer cations: (1)  They can affect the distortion of each octahedron (deviation from the perfect octahedron) as well as tilting of the M-X-M bond angles. (2) The exciton binding energy (E b ) of the 2D perovskite (quantum well) structures can be tuned by the dielectric constant of the spacer cation (barrier),  15  higher dielectric constant of the spacer can lead to less dielectric mismatch between the organic and inorganic layer, thus reducing the E b . (3) The stability of the materials can be improved as well by controlling the hydrophobic cation as a "raincoat" layer.  22  When fabricating films and optoelectronic devices from 2D perovskites, even more factors must be considered. (i) Film morphology, (ii) crystallinity, and (ii) the orientation of the layers regarding the substrate are also influenced by the composition. Furthermore, the actual film composition is complex, containing other 2D perovskite phases with different layer thickness than the one targeted.  23  The distribution of layer-number is influenced by the spacing cation and by the film deposition method. Understanding how the structures may affect properties is essential for applying these materials in optoelectronic devices. However, so far most research on 2D perovskites is based on trial-and-error tests by picking the spacers at random to incorporate into devices. There is no commonly understood correlation between the chosen spacer Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review and the resulting structure or properties for the specific application. With the rapid growth of the field, different aspects of 2D halide perovskites have been reviewed such as the history and general introduction to the material family,  18, 19, 24  the electronic structures and consequences of quantum and dielectric confinement,  15, 25  the photophysical properties,  26, 27  and advances in optoelectronic devices such as solar cells.  28  So far, there have been a large number of spacer cations incorporated into 2D perovskites, but the structural design rules on how to choose the spacer cations are still ill-defined. In this review, we focus on the spacer cations that have been systematically studied for the group 14 (mainly Pb and Sn) halide perovskites, from single crystal synthesis to thin film fabrication to illuminate how they affect the properties and applications. We outline the many spacers that have been used in synthesis of crystals as well as in films and devices. We start with a guide to synthesize single crystals, to characterize the crystal structures and optical properties, all essential for the proper understanding of structure-property relationship and device performance. Then we discuss the structural design rules which determine if a given organic spacer will form a 2D perovskite or another nonperovskite phase from our experiences and lessons. We then provide a summary of different types of spacer cations that have been studied, categorized by charge (+1 vs +2) and functional group. Following that, we review the films made from these materials. Like the single crystal section, we begin with a guide to making films, starting with the different desired film properties and how to analyze them and following with the different methods to fabricate them. This is followed by a summary of the different structures incorporated into films and devices, categorized by the perovskite film architecture (2D vs mixed dimensionality vs heterostructures) with emphasis on how the resulting properties of the films relate to the spacer used. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">CsPbBr 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T19:08:13Z</infon>
        <location offset="3980" length="8"/>
        <text>CsPbBr 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8489</offset>
      <text> OVERVIEW OF THE SYNTHETIC ASPECTS There are several synthetic approaches that have proven effective in the synthesis and crystallization of pure compounds of the 2D halide perovskites. These are classified based on the solvent and approach used and are described below. 2.1. Synthetic Methods 2.1.1. Solution Synthesis Using Hydrohalic Acid. Most of the 2D halide perovskites are prepared by solution synthesis in a hydrohalic acid.  [29] [30] [31] [32]  This method is particularly efficient for synthesizing the multilayered 2D perovskites.  [32] [33] [34]  The hydrohalic acid (HX = HI, HBr and HCl) functions as solvent as well as the halide source and thus must match the type of halide (X) in the desired perovskite. The metal source, spacer (or spacer salt), and A-site cation salt are dissolved under heating and stirring so that everything becomes ionized. After a clear solution is obtained, it can be cooled down to room temperature to get the desired crystal. Since there is a large excess amount of halide from HX in the solution, the perovskite with the same halide as the HX will be obtained no matter the anions in the metal source and cation salts. For example, to get lead iodide perovskites, one can use PbO, PbCl 2 , PbBr 2 , PbI 2 , Pb(NO) 2 , or Pb(CH 3 COO) 2 (as long as they are soluble in HI), and from our experience the choice of salt makes no difference. The layer-number can be controlled by the amount of the spacer cation added. However, using the ratio of starting materials based on the stoichiometry of the targeted composition does not necessarily lead to that composition in the crystals. The general principle is that compounds with a greater organic component (e.g., thinner layers with lower layer-number) are less soluble in HX and will crystallize more readily than more soluble (e.g., higher layernumber) compounds. The layer-number can by tuned by the ratio between the spacer and Pb sources, which is determined by the solubility of the n = 1 compound. If the spacer cation is very soluble in HX, for example, propylammonium (PA), a stoichiometric ratio may be needed to obtain the desired layernumber [PA:MA:Pb 2+ = 2:2:3 for (PA) 2 (MA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 )].  35  For less soluble spacer cations such as butylammonium (BA), if a stoichiometric ratio was added, lower layer-number phases would be obtained instead since they contain more organic part which is much less soluble in HX. Therefore, less than the stoichiometric ratio (70% or 50%) for the spacer should be added to obtain the desired layer-number [BA:MA:Pb 2+ = 1.4:1:2 for (BA) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 ) and BA:MA:Pb 2+ = 1:2:3 for (BA) 2 (MA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 )].  32  For other spacer cations, this ratio needs to be optimized based on their solubility. Another note is that the solution needs to be close to saturation to get the desired layer-number. The solubility of MAPbI 3 is 0.6 M in boiling HI, so the concentration of Pb 2+ in solution should be close to 0.6 M because the compound whose solubility is close to the concentration of ions in solution will precipitate out first. If the solution is too diluted, the lower layer-number compounds would precipitate out since they are generally less soluble.  36  Sometimes, reducing agent such as hypophosphorous acid (H 3 PO 2 ) need to be added to the solution to stabilize the ions, especially during the synthesis of Sn 2+ perovskites. Since Sn 2+ can be easily oxidized to Sn 4+ , the addition of H 3 PO 2 is the key to the successful synthesis. Even during the synthesis of lead iodide perovskites, absence of H 3 PO 2 can cause the formation of I 3 -in air, which can lead to a dark brown solution and no precipitate formation. Even though H 3 PO 2 is added to many commercial sources of aqueous HI as stabilizer, external H 3 PO 2 is still necessary especially when the HI is nonstabilized. Usually 1/5 of the volume of HI is enough for H 3 PO 2 , and it is worth noting that hypophosphite may also form for some metals when large excess of H 3 PÒis used.  37  Sometimes for iodide perovskites, if the hot solution is cooled down directly to room temperature (RT), a light-yellow hydrate phase will be obtained instead of the desired perovskite phase. In these cases, the step-cooling method can be used to get the 2D phase.  [38] [39] [40]  After all the starting materials are dissolved under stirring and boiling, one can first lower the temperature of the solution to 125 °C, which is right below the boiling point of HI (127 °C), so that the solution is hot, and the light-yellow phase can remain soluble. At the same time, the solution is very concentrated, so the desired 2D phase can still precipitate out. Once the first few crystals start to precipitate out, they can serve as seeds for further crystal growth. Gradually lowering the temperature to RT would not result in precipitation of any second phase. There are also limitations of this method, for example, as mentioned above, sometimes light-yellow hydrate phases form during the precipitation. Even though some of these phases can be avoided by the step-cooling method, for those that are too insoluble in HX, other solvent should be used (see below). Besides, to grow high-quality, large crystals, it may take relatively long time. It is also worth noting that some spacer cations can react with HI, which will be discussed in detail in section 2.2.6. 2.1.2. Solution Synthesis Using Organic Solvents. The 2D halide perovskites can also be synthesized using organic solvent,  41, 42  such as N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), and γ-butyrolactone (GBL),  43, 44  as well as mixtures of the solvents of above. These polar solvents can dissolve most organic and inorganic salts and may be suitable for the cations that are insoluble in HI (those with large organic cations, for example, Table  3c ). These solvents do not provide excess halide like HX; thus, salts with the same halide as the desired perovskites must be used, or an external halide source such as small amount of HX or NaX must be added. Usually a stoichiometric ratio of the starting materials is dissolved, but this cannot guarantee that the product is a single phase and has the same stoichiometry as the ingredients added; thus, it is necessary to identify the phase with powder or single-crystal X-ray diffraction (PXRD or SC-XRD). This is different from the deposition of thin film where all the ingredients must precipitate in some form on the film (see below), while during the solution synthesis of single crystal, some ions may remain soluble in the solution. For some of the 3D halide perovskites such as MAPbI 3 , their solubility in the organic solvent decreases with increasing temperature; thus, the crystal can precipitate out by the temperature-rising method.  43, 45  However, this method requires a systematic study of each compound's solubility with temperature, which may vary from spacer to spacer. Another way is to keep the solution temperature constant and let the solvent evaporate slowly, which can also result in a large single crystal.  46  Sometimes, additives such as H 3 PO 2 or formic acid are used to accelerate the crystallization, but additives should be picked carefully without introducing other component to the system.  47  However, so far, there is no systematic study on how to synthesize multilayer 2D perovskites using organic solvents. To achieve a single phase, the type of solvent (including ratio of mixed solvents), concentration, and additives need to be optimized and further studies are required. 2.1.3. Antisolvent (Vapor Diffusion) Method. Sometimes, the solubility reduction upon change in temperature or solvent evaporation is not significant enough for the crystal to precipitate. In these cases, slowly adding an antisolvent can accelerate the precipitation process.  [48] [49] [50] [51]  Like solution synthesis using an organic solvent, a stoichiometric ratio of starting materials is dissolved in a small vial with a "good solvent" (e.g., DMF and DMSO). Then the small vial (with the cap open) is put into another larger vial with a "poor solvent," which acts as the antisolvent (e.g., ethyl ether and dichloromethane). As the "poor solvent" slowly diffuses into the "good solvent" in the small vial, the solubility of the perovskite phase decreases and crystals can precipitate out.  48  So far, this vapor diffusion method is also limited to the synthesis of n = 1 for 2D perovskites, especially for the cations with bulky organic parts that cannot be dissolved in HI (Table  3e -g, Figure  6a ).  [49] [50] [51]  Sometimes, the solvent has such a strong interaction with the starting materials that the solvate phase (metal-solvent complex) forms instead of the 2D perovskite phase. 2.1.4. Solvothermal Synthesis. Solvothermal method has been used to synthesize 3D and lower-dimensional structures.  [52] [53] [54] [55] [56]  The solvent can be either hydrohalic acid (HX) or organic solvent, or even a mixture of "poor solvent" (e.g., ethanol or acetonitrile) and HX. The solution is usually sealed in an autoclave or Pyrex tube. Interestingly, by changing the reaction conditions such as temperature or time, different morphologies of 3D perovskites can be obtained.  57  Sometimes, even different phases can be achieved when varying the conditions.  [54] [55] [56]  Recently, this method has been used to synthesize 2D perovskites  [58] [59] [60]  as well as nanocrystals.  61  However, there is no report of using it to synthesize multilayer bulk 2D perovskites. 2.1.5. Solid-State Grinding Method/Ball-Milling. To completely get rid of the effects of the solvent, the solid-state grinding method can be utilized. This is first done for the 3D halide perovskites, by grinding a stoichiometric ratio of the starting materials with a mortar and pestle, followed by annealing to get the desired phase.  62, 63  This method can also be used to synthesize the 2D perovskites,  39, 64  especially those that cannot be synthesized in solution (spacers too soluble or insoluble). Stoichiometric ratios of the starting materials are grinded until the metal source has been completely reacted. Examination of the as-grinded powder by PXRD should show no existence of the metal source, but the perovskite peaks have low intensity, suggesting poor crystallinity. Annealing of the powder results in a great improvement of the crystallinity. Ballmilling method can also achieve similar results without annealing.  65, 66  The advantage of this method is that it has no limitation of the spacer solubility as long as it can form 2D perovskites Thus, it is a good way to check whether a spacer can form a 2D perovskite (if the solution synthesis does not work). So far, 2D perovskites with more n &gt; 3 have not been synthesized this way.  39, 64  Another note is that this method cannot yield highquality single crystals to resolve the structure by SCXRD, but it is possible to do Rietveld refinement on high-resolution PRXD to solve the structure. Generally, for the solution method, the product is determined by the solubility of the compound and the concentration of the solution. The species whose solubility limit is closest to the solution concentration precipitates out first. We do need to worry about second phases such as the solvate phase. Even though this problem can be overcome by the solid-state grinding method, this method does have its own limitations such as crystallinity. The organic or antisolvent methods work better for spacer cations with medium to poor solubility in HX. Therefore, all the methods can compensate each other to get the crystals we want. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20135</offset>
      <text> Rules of Picking Spacer Cations for 2D Perovskites With the above synthetic methods of 2D perovskites in mind, we now discuss some factors that need to be considered when choosing a spacer cation to stabilize a 2D structure. Even though we cannot predict the structure of the product with 100% certainty, there are some general rules that can help choose a successful spacer. 2.2.1. Charge. To date, most of the 2D perovskites incorporate +1 and +2 cations, with the general formula of A′ 2 A n-1 M n X 3n+1 (A′ is +1) or A′A n-1 M n X 3n+1 (A′ is +2). Cations with +3 and +4 charges are unlikely to achieve charge balance in 2D perovskites. Therefore, they usually template low-dimensional structures instead. It is worth noting that when calculating the charge of a cation, one should count the number of nitrogen atoms (N) that can be protonated, instead of the total N number. For example, pyrrole cannot be protonated since lone pair of electrons on N are a part of the aromaticity. However, pyridine can be protonated because the N electrons are not involved in the aromaticity.  40  In imidazole, only one N can be protonated for the same reason.  67, 68  In other cases, the number of protonated N is determined by the reaction environment (pH) and pK a of the molecule. In these cases, researchers should carefully examine the protonation situation by infrared (IR) spectroscopy and nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR). 2.2.2. Shape. The shape of the spacer cation should be considered in two aspects, the amino head and the organic tail. The amino head must be the right size to fit in the inorganic pocket, this is why the primary ammonium cations are the most favorable for 2D perovskites, followed by secondary, then tertiary and quaternary ammonium cations (RNH 3 + &gt; R 2 NH 2 + &gt; R 3 NH + &gt; R 4 N + ). If bulky groups are substituted on the N, the 2D structure may be destabilized.  69  The shape of the head amino group can influence the penetration depth (Figure  4b ), defined by the distance between the N atom of the amino group and the plane for terminal halides. When it is bulky (e.g., R 4 N + ), the head cannot penetrate into the inorganic pocket and the penetration depth is negative (above the plane), thus exhibiting weaker interaction with the inorganic layer and resulting in less tilted structure (discussed in detail below). The shape of the organic tail can be linear, branched or cyclic (both aliphatic and aromatic). Linear spacer cations are the most flexible, and usually they can form 2D perovskites.  [70] [71] [72]  For branched cations, the bulky tail increases the steric hindrance and may not form the interdigitating structure for these 1+ cations. If the spacer cation is cyclic, the ring has less freedom to move, especially for the aromatic ring, where all the atoms on the ring must stay on the same plane, further increasing the steric hindrance of the cation.  50, 73  2.2.3. Size. To form 2D perovskites, the spacer cannot be too big or too small. Billing et al. has reported the n = 1 structures for linear cations with up to 18 carbons.  [70] [71] [72]  The smallest monoammnonium spacer reported that can template a 2D n = 1 structure is methylhydrazinium, though it is not sure whether it can form multilayer structures. Ethylammonium can serve as spacer for bromide perovskite  59  as well as A-site cations inside the perovskite cage.  30, 74, 75  For linear diammonium cations, the shortest cation that can form ⟨100⟩-oriented 2D structure for iodide and bromide perovskites is 1,4butanediammonium.  39, 76, 77  For bromide compounds, the use of 1,3-propanediammonium forms 6 × 6 ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite and ethylenediammonium cation template 1D structure.  76  For chloride perovskite, 1,3-propanediammonium does form a 2D structure.  78  For cyclic spacers, Billing et al. has studied the monoammonium cations with different ring sizes from three to eight carbons and found that three-to six-member ring monoammonium cations can form 2D structures, while seven-and eight-member rings only form 1D structures.  79, 80  If the diameter of the ring is close to or larger than the width of the MX 6 octahedron (6.3 Å), it cannot fit into the 2D structure. For the same reason, C 60 derivatives cannot template 2D perovskite structure. Besides, if a cyclic spacer has too many rings, the tail may be too big to stabilize 2D perovskite structure. 2.2.4. Solubility. For solution synthesis, the solubility of the cation also needs to be considered to choose the right solvent. With HX as the solvent, generally bulkier spacers with more carbon atoms are less soluble. For aromatic spacers, the position of functional group (ortho, meta and para) can affect the solubility, for example, meta &gt; ortho &gt; para. To get single crystals, organic solvents may be a better choice for those less soluble cations. If a spacer cation is very soluble (e.g., propylammonium cation), using an organic solvent may not result in crystal precipitation, thus using HX is preferable. But for the solid-state grinding method, there is no limit for the solubility of the spacer since no solvent is involved. 2.2.5. Hydrogen Bonding. Hydrogen bonding plays a big role in stabilizing the 2D perovskites, for example, ⟨110⟩oriented 2D perovskites.  [81] [82] [83]  On the basis of the length of the carbon chain, different hydrogen bonds can form, resulting in different structures (⟨100⟩-vs ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites). Hydrogen bonding is also important when the cation has heteroatoms, and it may change the configuration of the cation and even displacement of the unit cell (see below in the heteroatom section).  84, 85  2.2.6. Spacer Cation Cannot React with the Solvent. Though seemingly obvious, this can also easily be forgotten. For example, primary amines can react with acetone to form imines. Therefore, acetone cannot be used as solvent for synthesis of halide perovskites. Many functional groups can react with HX, such as double bonds,  86  triple bonds,  87  -OH,  88  -Br, -Cl, and ether, especially under heating conditions. Thus, nonreactive solvents or milder conditions (low temperature)  82, 87  should be used when incorporating spacers with these functional groups. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26391</offset>
      <text> STRUCTURAL CASE STUDIES USING DIFFERENT SPACER CATIONS The 2D perovskites can be categorized structurally into ⟨100⟩oriented, ⟨110⟩-oriented, and ⟨111⟩-oriented structures by the crystallographic planes of the 3D parent structure where the large spacer cations separate the octahedra. Among those, the ⟨100⟩-oriented 2D perovskites are most common and extensively studied. The ⟨100⟩-oriented 2D perovskites can be further divided into the Ruddlesden-Popper (RP)  32  phase, Dion-Jacobson (DJ)  89  phase and alternating cations in the interlayer space (ACI) phase,  90  with general formulas of A′ 2 A n-1 M n X 3n+1 , A′A n-1 M n X 3n+1 and A′A n M n X 3n+1 , respectively (Figure  2 ). The RP phases incorporate +1 cations, which   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27153</offset>
      <text> Chemical Reviews usually interdigitate between the layers and enforce the inorganic layer to be staggered by half a unit cell (0.5, 0.5 displacement in the in-plane direction, not necessarily the a and b direction of the unit cell). The DJ phases feature compact +2 cations which generally leads to an eclipsed stacking with the inorganic layer exactly on top of each other (0, 0 displacement). For the ACI phases (0, 0.5 displacement), the inorganic layers are eclipsed looking from the a direction, but staggered from the b direction. The A site cation exists not only inside the cuboctahedral cage but also between the layers alternating with another cation. So far, only the guanidinium cation can template this type of structure. Though the structural templating effects of spacer cations have been reviewed previously,  19, 91, 92  hundreds of new structures have been reported since 2016. In this review, some of those structures will be revisited and new knowledge will be built up on those results based on recently reported structures. In the following part, we will discuss the structures of the most systematically studied main group 2D halide perovskites based on the spacer cations (the structural design rule of transition metal 2D halide perovskites may be slightly different and beyond the scope of this review). The spacer cations are categorized by charge, for example, monoammonium and diammonium cations. Under each category, examples of published structures will be discussed and compared to focus on the key factors of the spacers in influencing the structure of 2D halide perovskites. The following part can be seen as a series of case studies expanding upon the structural design rules on how to choose the spacer cation as discussed above. 3.1. Monoammonium Cations 3.1.1. Linear Cations. Linear carbon chain cations are one of the first spacer types explored in 2D perovskites.  [93] [94] [95]  These perovskites were mainly studied for their optoelectronic properties because of their naturally formed quantum well structure. In 1994, Mitzi et al.  96  reported the homologous series of (C 4 N 9 NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Sn n I 3n+1 (n = 1-5) and their electronic properties, setting the foundation of 2D halide perovskites as promising semiconductor materials. Subsequently, many n = 1 structures were reported by Mitzi et   (m = 4-18) where m represents the carbon-chain length (Table  1 ).  [70] [71] [72]  They also reported that for m = 3 (propylammonium), a nonperovskite 2D structure formed.  97  There seems to be little restriction on the maximum length of the carbon-chain that can form the 2D structure, though there is likely a limit where the cation can still be templated by the inorganic layer instead of being totally disordered like in the liquid phase. Most 2D perovskites exhibit a series of phase transitions upon temperature change.  [70] [71] [72] 98  The temperature of the phase transition increases with the chain length. From low to high temperature, the structure changes from a low symmetry phase to a high symmetry phase. Often the low-temperature phase transition is from the movement of the spacer cation, and the high-temperature phase transition usually involves increase of the Pb-I-Pb bond angles to closer to 180°, accompanied by a change to a darker color of the crystal, indicating a narrowing of the bandgap. When the M-X-M angle is closer to 180°, the Pb s-and I p-orbitals have better overlap, thus leading to a smaller bandgap, explaining the color change for the phase stabilized at high temperatures. Sometimes the phase transition is even accompanied by a change in the stacking of the inorganic layer, from staggered to eclipsed [unit cell displacement from (0.5, 0.5) to (0, 0)]. The thicker layered 2D perovskites have not been extensively explored until the recent demonstration of using them as absorbers for highly efficient solar cell devices, which will be discussed in the device part below.  99, 100  In 2016, Stoumpos et al. reported the single-crystal structures and properties of (C 4 N 9 NH 3 ) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 1-4).  32  Using the HI solution synthesis as discussed above, they obtained pure phase crystals of n = 1-4, as confirmed by PXRD. The structures solved and refined by SCXRD exhibit a unit cell displacement of (0.5, 0.5), resembling the oxide perovskite phases with staggered octahedra layers. Therefore, borrowing from the oxide perovskite nomenclature, they are classified as Ruddlesden-Popper (RP) type. Expanding this series to higher layer-number than n = 4 can be challenging. In 2017, the series was expanded to n = 5  33  and to n = 6 and 7  34  in 2019 (Figure  3a ), which is the highest layer-number resolved by SCXRD to date. Thermodynamic calorimetry measurements show that the enthalpy of formation (ΔH f ) for members above n = 5 is positive (Figure  3d ).  34  This value can change the Gibbs free energy of formation (ΔG) from negative to positive, suggesting that the formation of phase-pure n = 6 and 7 is thermodynamically unfavorable. For n &gt; 7, the phases may even be thermodynamically unstable and, so far, attempts to synthesize them resulted in mixed phases, likely 3D MAPbI 3 and higher-n phases.  34  It is also possible that the 2D phases intergrow within a 3D matrix. Further exploration of the n &gt; 7 phase is still ongoing, and these may be termed "quasi-2D perovskites". The optical properties of the homologous members of this series are shown in Figure  3b  and c . There are two slopes in the absorption spectra, a low-energy excitonic part and a highenergy continuum part. The bandgap is extracted by extrapolating the high-energy slope to the imaginary axis parallel to the x axis where the absorption edge is interrupted by the excitonic peak. The bandgaps decrease with increasing layer thickness, showing reduced quantum and dielectric confinement effects. The excitonic feature in the absorption spectra becomes less obvious for n = 5 and above. With greater layer thickness, the change in the bandgap is diminishingly smaller tending asymptotically to that of the n= ∞ member, that is, 3D MAPbI 3 , but there is still ∼0.15 eV difference between the bandgap of n = 7 and 3D MAPbI 3 . The theoretical band structure calculations show that all the compounds in this series are direct bandgap semiconductors, with a dispersive valence band (VB) and conduction band (CB) in the layer directions and flat bands along the stacking direction, which is typical for 2D materials. Besides the extensively studied spacer butylammonium cation, other spacers such as propylammonium, pentylammonium, and hexylammonium cations have been demonstrated for the multilayer 2D structures (Table  1 ).  35, 36, 101  For propylammonium, even though crystals of the n = 1 2D structure could not form, as also seen by Billing et al.,  97  crystals for the 2D structure with n = 3 and 4 were successfully synthesized (Figure  3e ).  35  There is another homologous series with general formula of (C 3 H 7 NH 3 ) 2m+4 (MA) m-2 Pb 2m+1 I 7m+4 (m = 2, 3, 4). With a combination of corner-sharing and facesharing octahedra, they are called "step-like" structures and have a strong perovskites character, however, because of this they are not fully proper perovskites (Figure  3f ).  35  This suggests that when the cation is relatively small (e.g., propylammonium), the spacer itself may not be efficacious to template the 2D structure. When the A-site cation is involved to support the cage, the multilayer 2D structure can be stabilized. For the step-like structures, even though the connection is 2D, they exhibit a 1D electronic band structure because the charge transport through the face-sharing octahedra is almost forbidden.  35  This shows the importance of maintaining the corner-sharing structure for the excellent optoelectronic properties. For the longer carbon-chain pentylammonium and hexylammonium cations (Table  1d , 1e),  36, 101  they adopt similar 2D RP structures with lower symmetry space group at room temperature. This is because, as the carbon-chain length increases, the phase transition temperature from monoclinic to orthorhombic space group increases. The structure still does go to the orthorhombic space group at higher temperature.  36, 101  The bandgaps are not significantly influenced by the cation for a given layer thickness n, suggesting that the optical properties are mainly determined by n, as expected for the quantum well structure. But the bandgap does vary for the n = 1 structures, because of the larger difference in Pb-I-Pb angles across difference cations, as discussed previously,  18, 62, 102  showing that the spacer cation can also fine-tune the properties. The smallest monoammonium cation that can form the 2D n = 1 structure for iodide perovskites is methylhydrazinium (Table  1g ).  103  Although it has two N atoms, only the middle one is protonated in the synthetic conditions reported. Despite the small size, it can still form the iodide n = 1 2D structure because of the strong hydrogen bonding effect, and the octahedra are fairly undistorted with average Pb-I-Pb angles of 175.1°. The closest interlayer distance is 2.99 Å and it shows a reduced bandgap of 2.2 eV compared to other n = 1 perovskites. But it is not clear whether the spacer can form multilayered 2D perovskites or not. More interestingly, the same cation can also form 3D perovskite structures for bromide and chlorides, with methylhydrazinium as A-site cation.  104, 105  Even though the structures are distorted at room temperature, they both go through phase transitions to more proper perovskite phases at higher temperature. The bromide analogues were mainly explored for their ferroelectric properties, with (C 4 N 9 NH 3 ) 2 (A)Pb 2 Br 7 (A = Cs + , MA, and FA). All three compounds adopt the noncentrosymmetric Cmc2 1 space group at room temperature and exhibit a phase transition to the centrosymmetric space groups at high temperature, where the ferroelectric behavior disappears.  [106] [107] [108]  The shortest linear monoammonium cation that forms 2D bromide perovskite is ethylammonium, even though the same cation can also fit into the perovskite cage as A-site cation (discussed in section 3.3).  59  3.1.2. Cyclic Cations. Another type of aliphatic spacer is cyclic cations, which is a good model system to study the effect of ring size on the structure. Billing et al. reported a systematic study on different ring sizes from three to eight carbons, with the primary amino groups directly attached to the ring (Table  2 ).  79, 80  They found that for cyclic ammonium cations with three to six carbons, 2D perovskite phases can form. The structures with the smaller rings (three and four carbons) show more significant out-of-plane tilt and smaller Pb-X-Pb angles, since they are more distorted to accommodate the small spacer cations. For the cations with seven and eight-member rings, 1D structures form.  79, 80  This suggests there is a limit on the ring size that can template 2D perovskites. If the ring is too big, lower-dimensional structures will form to accommodate the spacer cation. More interestingly, for small ring members (three and four), the inorganic layers adopt the eclipsed stacking pattern, while for large ring members (five and six), the layers are staggered to better accommodate the bulky groups.  80  This suggests that the spacer cation can not only cause distortion of Pb-X-Pb bonds but also affect the stacking of the inorganic layers. 3.1.3. Aromatic Cations. Aromatic cations were one of the first spacers explored for multilayer 2D perovskites,  111  and they have been widely studied since then. The aromatic rings are believed to be beneficial for charge transport, however, if aromatics such as phenyl groups are involved, they tend be disordered in the crystal structure frustrating efforts to crystallographically refine the structures. Therefore, the bond lengths and bond angles are usually modeled with restraints   3b ), for example, it incorporates two sheets of organic spacers between the inorganic layers. Within each sheet, the aromatic rings are parallel because of π-π stacking, while between the sheets, the rings adopt a face-toedge (herringbone) configuration (Figure  4a ). Beyond ring size, Mitzi and co-workers systematically studied the influence of the number of rings fused together (benzene and naphthalene) and carbon-chain length (methyl and ethyl) attached to the ring on the perovskite structure (Table  3a d).  73  When comparing these structures to a variety of alreadyreported structures, they found that the penetration depth (Figure  4b ), defined by the distance between the N atom of the primary amino group and the plane for terminal halides, has a large influence on the Pb-X-Pb angles and thus the optical properties. The Pb-X-Pb bond angle decreases with increasing penetration depth in the range from -0.7 Å (above the plane) to 0.4 Å (below the plane) and then increases in the range from 0.4 to 0.9 Å (Figure  4c ). This is because the tilt of the PbX 6 octahedra (Pb-X-Pb bond angle) is mainly decided by the interaction (e.g., hydrogen bonding) between the cation and inorganic layer. When the amino group is way above the plane (negative penetration depth), it has very weak interaction with the halogen atoms, so the octahedra are not tilted (Pb-X-Pb bond angle close to 180°). When the penetration depth is positive, the amino group sinks into the octahedra pocket, and the distances between the N and halogen atoms (both terminal and bridging) decrease. Thus, the interaction between those atoms is stronger and the octahedra have larger tilts (Pb-X-Pb bond angle smaller than 180°). When the penetration depth is around 0.4 Å, the N atom has largest interaction with all the halogen atoms, so the Pb-X-Pb bond angle is smallest. As the penetration depth further increases, the distance increases again (especially for the terminal halogens) and so does the Pb-X-Pb bond angle. This shows the great influence of hydrogen bonding on the structure as mentioned above. Increasing the number of rings provides further tunability of the structure and property. Passarelli et al. used spacers with naphthalene, pyrene, or perylene as the aromatic component of the spacer bonded to an ethyl, propyl, or butyl linkers and synthesized the n = 1 2D compounds (Table 3e-g). When the intramolecular hydrogen bonding between the O of the linker and the N pulls the amino head further away from the inorganic layer, the distance between primary N and I atoms is larger, resulting in weaker interaction with the inorganic layer and thus a smaller bandgap.  50   The complexity of the aromatic cations provides a tunability of the molecular orbitals of the spacer, which can match with the band structure of the inorganic layer to improve the charge transport. The highest occupied molecular orbitals (HOMO) and lowest unoccupied molecular orbitals (LUMO) of the organic spacers get closer to the valence band maximum (VBM) and conduction band minimum (CBM) of the inorganic layer, which may improve the charge transport between them (Figure  4d ). More interestingly, the out-ofplane conductivity increases with the number of the aromatic rings, suggesting better charge transport in the stacking direction (Figure  4e ). 3.1.4. Cations with Heteroatoms. Heteroatoms (O, F, Cl, Br, and I) in the spacers play important roles in templating the perovskite structures through hydrogen bonding and halogen-halogen interactions (Table  4 ), and their effects are mainly studied for the n = 1 structures, as those discussed below. After substituting the ethylammonium spacer with a hydroxyl group to form HO(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + (Table  4a ), the intermolecular hydrogen bonding NH 3 + •••OH stabilizes the cation in the cis conformation.  88, 118  The structure also features a short I•••I distance of 4.279(2) Å thanks to the compact conformation of the cation and the almost eclipsed octahedra stacking [(0.1, 0.1) unit cell displacement], both because of the hydrogen bonding.  118  The chlorine-and bromine-substituted cations, Cl(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + and Br(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + (Table  4b ,c), also experience hydrogen bonding between the amino group and the halogen atom, which results in the amino groups no longer in the pocket of the inorganic layer, giving a negative penetration depth (discussed above) of -0.39 Å and -0.44 Å for Cl and Br, respectively (Figure  5a ).  119  As a result, the hydrogen bonding between the amino group and the I atoms becomes negligible, leading to untilted octahedra (Pb-I-Pb bond angle close to 180°). This results in a better overlap of the Pb s-and I p-orbitals, thus giving smaller bandgaps than n = 1 structures with tilted octahedra. The iodine-substituted cation, I(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + (Table  4d ), shows a different structure. Because of the strong interaction between the iodine atom of the organic cation and the axial iodine atom of the octahedron, the C-N bond is perpendicular to the inorganic layer and the amino group penetrates into the octahedra pocket (penetration depth +0.44 Å). Thus, the amino group has strong interaction with iodine atoms of the octahedra, resulting in heavily tilted structure and larger bandgap than the Cl and Br-substituted ones.  119  More interestingly, the structures with Cl(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + and Br-(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + have (0.1, 0.5) unit cell displacement, while those with HO(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + and I(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + show (0.1, 0.1) displacement, showing that besides the (0, 0) and (0.5, 0.5) displacement, there are many possibilities in between, especially when heteroatoms and hydrogen bonding are involved. The fluorine-substituted one, F(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + (Table  4e ), exhibits similar structure as the Cl(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + and Br-(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + , with a cis conformation for the cation and The Pb analogue of 4-FPEA also adopts a parallel configuration for the cation (Figure  5b ),  22, 121  which is believed to be beneficial for the out-of-plane charge transport.  122  The in-plane transport of (4-FPEA) 2 PbI 4 is not as good as (PEA) 2 PbI 4 , because the Pb-I-Pb angle of (4-FPEA) 2 PbI 4 (151.69°) is smaller than (PEA) 2 PbI 4 (153.30°). 2D perovskite solar cells incorporating the 4-FPEA cation show higher power conversion efficiency than those with PEA, a point which will be discussed further in the device section below. More importantly, the photovoltaic devices exhibit better stability performance thanks to the hydrophobicity of 4-FPEA. 122 The fully fluorine-substituted cation, perfluorophenethylammonium (F5-PEA) (Table  4k ), was also explored. Interestingly, Mitzi et al. found that (F5-PEA) 2 SnI 4 could allow intercalation of benzene molecules between the layer, and perfluoroaryl molecules can also intercalate into (PEA) 2 SnI 4 .  123  Recently, the (F5-PEA) 2 PbI 4 was revisited because of its high hydrophobicity, thus improving the stability of the corresponding devices.  124  Mitzi and co-workers also explored the effects of substituting different halogens in the meta position (Table  4l ,m).  125  As the size of the halogen increases, so does the interlayer distance between the two planes of terminal iodine atoms to accommodate the bulky spacer cation. While A similar effect of halogen substitution on the para position for the Pb system was also studied by Tremblay et al.  84     85  BZA and 4-FBZA cations adopt a face-to-edge configuration, while 4-ClBZA and 4-BrBZA are tilted (Figure  5c ) because of the stronger halogen-halogen interaction between the halogen atom in the cation and the iodine atom in the octahedra. More interestingly, the 4-IBZA cation adopts face-to-edge configuration again because of the strong halogen-halogen interaction between the iodine atoms in the spacer and the octahedra. The closest I•••I distance is 3.931 Å, smaller than the sum of the van der Waals radii of 3.96 Å.  84  Therefore, the strength of the halogen interaction follows the trend I &gt; Br &gt; Cl ≫ F. The unit cell displacements are (0.1, 0.3), (0.2, 0.2), (0.2, 0.2), and (0.45, 0.45) for 4-FBZA, 4-ClBZA, 4-BrBZA, and 4-IBZA, respectively, suggesting that the halogen interaction plays an important role in affecting the unit cell displacement. However, the lack of multilayer structures suggests that more studies are needed to understand the role of heteroatoms in n &gt; 1. 3.1.5. Cations Involving Thiophene. Although the thiophene is a heterocyclic group, we separated the discussion from the above section of "Cations with heteroatoms" since it represents a special case because of the interactions between the electronic structure of the thiophene rings and that of the inorganic perovskite network. Cations involving thiophene moieties are another important class of aromatic spacers because the HOMO-LUMO gap of the molecule can be engineered relative to the bandgap of the inorganic layer. Thus, they can form either Type I or Type II quantum wells, where in Type I alignment, the low-energy electrons and holes are localized on the same component (both on the inorganic layer or both on the organic layer), and in Type II alignment, the electrons and holes are on different components (the inorganic layer and the spacer), as shown in Figure  6c .  126  This idea was first proposed by Mitzi et al. in 1999,  127  and they mainly focused on oligothiophene spacers with two amino groups on both ends, which will be discussed below. This idea has also been explored by Dou and co-workers using oligothiophene monoammonium cations.  51  The four cations listed in Figure  6a  have different HOMO-LUMO gap alignments compared to the inorganic layer. For cation i, the LUMO of the organic cation is higher than the CBM of the inorganic layer, and the HOMO is lower than VBM. The electrons and holes are localized on the CBM and VBM, respectively, and the bandgap is determined by the VBM-CBM gap of the inorganic layer. The photoluminescence property is similar to other n = 1 perovskites discussed above, with the PL emission peak at 526 nm (Figure  6b(i) ). The LUMO and HOMO of the organic cation ii are higher than the CBM and VBM of the inorganic layer, respectively, so the electrons are localized in the CBM of the inorganic part, while the holes are in the HOMO of the organic part, corresponding to the Type II quantum well structure (Figure  6c (ii)), which results in PL quenching. Cation iii is similar to cation ii except that the LUMO and HOMO are lower than the CBM and VBM, respectively, so the PL is also quenched (Figure  6c (iii)). For cation iv, the LUMO is lower than CBM, and the HOMO is higher than VBM, so the charge transport process is enabled and the electrons and holes are localized on the spacers. Only PL from the cation is observed, which has a longer lifetime than structure with cation i. This shows the powerful tunability of band alignment in 2D perovskites. Besides, cation ii has also been shown to improve the performance and stability of Sn perovskite-based field effect transistors (FET), thanks to the hydrophobic and bulky spacer cation. A multilayered 2D iodide perovskite using 2-thiophenemethylammonium has also enabled solar cell devices to achieve a PCE of over 15%, after adding extra methylammonium chloride, which will be discussed in more detail in the device section.  128  3.1.6. All Inorganic 2D Perovskites. Unlike the structures discussed above with organic spacer cations separating the octahedral layers, for the all-inorganic 2D perovskites, Cs 2 SnI 2 Cl 2  129  and Cs 2 PbI 2 Cl 2 ,  130  the two halides are ordered in the layers by the size mismatch. Instead of distributing randomly, the small halide (Cl) is in the bridging position while the large halide (I) takes the terminal sites. These unique ordered phases are favored thermodynamically and are distinct members of the Ruddlesden-Popper family, with the inorganic layer staggered by half an octahedron and the Cs + cations taking the inorganic pocket. The interlayer spacing is quite short because of the small size of the Cs + . The materials exhibit higher bandgaps than all-iodide 2D perovskites, but they are electronic structures are equally attractive because of their direct band gaps and broad valence and conduction bands. The organic cation MA can form similar structure in (MA) 2 Pb(SCN) 2 I 2 .  131  3.1.7. Guanidinium Cations. The alternating cations in the interlayer space (ACI) phase is rare and was first reported by Kanatzidis and co-workers.  90  The A-site cation, MA, is not only inside the perovskite cage but also between the inorganic layers, alternating with another larger spacer cation, guanidinium (GA). Viewing from the a direction (Figure  2c ), the inorganic layers are eclipsed and from the b direction, they are staggered by half an octahedron, so the unit cell displacement is (0, 0.5). Because of the small size of the GA cation, the interlayer distance is small. There may be some interaction across the layer in the stacking direction, so the bandgaps of this series are smaller than the RP phase of the same layer-number. The n = 1 phase, (GA)(MA)PbI 4 , has MA between the inorganic layers even though there is no cuboctahedral cage, that is different from (GA) 2 MI 4 (M = Sn 2+ or Pb 2+ ),  [132] [133] [134]  which form ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite. This is not surprising because the GA cation is small enough to fit in the pocket of the ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite. Similar structures also form when Cs + is between the layer and alternating with GA for bromide and iodide perovskites.  135  The GA cation has strong hydrogen bonding with the neighboring Br atoms, so octahedra are tilted and the Pb-Br-Pb angles are much smaller than 180°. The bandgap is still smaller than the corresponding RP phase [(BA) 2 PbBr 4 ] because of the small interlayer distance. Combining GA with formamidinium (FA), which is slightly larger than MA, a ⟨210⟩-oriented 2D perovskite forms.  136  The crystals are red with a relatively broad PL emission. A similar structure can also form with FA and thiourea.  137  3.2. Diammonium Cations 3.2.1. Linear Cations. Diammonium cations have been less explored as spacers for 2D perovskites than the monoammonium cations. These are essentially ditopic ligands because they are capable of forming electrostatic interaction at two separate sites of their molecule. For linear cations that have a positive charge at each end, the ethylenediammonium cation is too small to template the 2D structure. The 1,3propanediammonium cation stabilizes a ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite using bromide  76  and ⟨100⟩-oriented 2D perovskite using chloride.  78  The iodide structure with 1,3-propanediammonium cation has not been published, and it is likely that it cannot form 2D structure. Billing and co-workers studied diammonium cations of different carbon-chain lengths NH 3 (CH 2 ) m NH 3 2+ (m = 4, 7, 8, 10, 12) (Table  5 ) and found that the diammonium cations with even carbon-chain lengths formed n = 1 2D perovskites while those with odd carbon chain lengths (m = 7) formed a 1D structure.  71  Li et al. synthesized (NH 3 C m H 2m NH 3 )(MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (m = 4-9, n = 1-4) with both solution method and solid-state grinding method (Table  5b -f).  39  They found that the multilayer 2D perovskites can form when a step-cooling solution method is utilized for cations with both odd and even number carbon-chain lengths. However, this solution method does not apply to diammonium cations with short carbonchain (m = 4 and 6) since the cations are too soluble in HI. The solid-state grinding method can be used to solve this problem, achieving n = 3 for all the carbon-chain members (m = 4-9). The optical properties of 2D perovskites incorporating diammonium cations are similar to those with monoammonium cations. The PL emission peaks shift to lower energy as the interlayer distance decreases, so there may be some interaction in the stacking direction leading to lower bandgaps. The films with diammonium cations show better stability performance than those with monoammonium cations, since the weakest interaction between the layers changed from van der Waals interaction in the monoammonium cations to the electrostatic interaction between the amino group and the inorganic layer. Other linear diammonium cations explored include (CH 3 ) 3 NCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 2+ and 2-methylpentane-1,5-diammonium (Table  5i , j). The tertiary N with three methyl groups i s b u l k y , s o i t c a n f o r m 2 D p e r o v s k i t e ((CH 3 ) 3 NCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 )SnI 4 .  138  More interestingly, the inorganic layers are almost stacking exactly on top of each other, resembling the Dion-Jacobson phase. For 2-methylpentane-1,5-diammonium, it forms a 2D n = 1 structure for bromide and chloride perovskites and a 1D structure with face-sharing octahedra for the iodide compound.  78  Interestingly, when MA is incorporated into the compound, it can stabilize the n = 2 2D structure for the iodide perovskite, similar to the case of propylammonium discussed earlier when the 2D structure cannot form by the spacer itself but requires the A-site cation to be stabilized.  139  3.2.2. Cyclic Cations. Cyclic diammonium cations have more strict size limits for the rings since the spacers are more compact. Billing and co-workers. reported the n = 1 structure of (1,4-bis(ammoniomethyl)cyclohexane)PbI 4 (Table  6a ).  143  The Pb-I bonds are mainly tilted in-plane and barely tilted out-of-plane, and the unit cell displacement is (0.1, 0.1), close to that of the DJ phase. Not all cyclic cations involving a benzene ring can form a 2D structure. The p-phenylenediammonium cation stabilizes 1D and nonoctahedral structures for iodide  144  and chloride,  145  respectively (Table  6c ). While the m-phenylenediammonium cation (Table  6b ) stabilizes a 2D n = 1 structure for chloride, with eclipsed inorganic layers indicating this structure is a DJ phase.  145  If one of the amino groups becomes bulkier, for example, the N,Ndimethyl-p-phenylenediammonium cation (Table  6d ), it stabilizes isostructural 2D n = 1 structures for all three h a l i d e s . 1 4 5 , 1 4 6 T h i s is s i mi l a r t o th e c a s e of (CH 3 ) 3 NCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 2+ discussed above (Table  5i ), where the primary amino spacer cannot stabilize the 2D structure, but the quaternary amino spacer can. The penetration depths for the primary and tertiary N groups are 1.11 and -0.57 Å, respectively. The primary amino group can penetrate into the inorganic layer pocket, while the bulky tertiary amino group has a negative penetration depth, depending on the level of steric hindrance. The 1,5-naphthalene diammonium cation (Table  6e ) can also form the eclipsed DJ phase, and the octahedra are mainly tilted in-plane and barely tilted out-ofplane.  77  However, diammonium cations such as benzidinium  147  and 4,4′-bipyridinium  148  tend to form 1D structures. Heterocyclic diammonium cations such as 2,2′-biimidazolium  67  and benzodiimidazolium  149  can also form 2D perovskites (Table  6f , g). As discussed above, only two of the four N can be protonated. More interestingly, the M-I-M bond angles are close to 180°. The 2,2′-biimidazolium cations adopt a parallel configuration, and they are tilted with respect to the inorganic layer. So, the octahedra are staggered, with unit cell displacement of (0.1, 0.5).  67  1,4-dimethylpiperazinium cations stabilize the 2D n = 1 structure for bromide and 1D structure for iodide (Table  6h ).  150  All the 2D structures discussed in this part have relatively small interlayer d-spacing because of the compact spacers. 3.2.3. (Aminomethyl)piperidinium Cations. Some of the diammonium cations discussed above form the n = 1 Dion-Jacobson phase with inorganic layers stacked exactly on top of each other, but none have been incorporated into multilayered n &gt; 1 structures. In 2018, Mao et al. first reported multilayer structures of 2D halide DJ perovskites (xAMP)-(MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (AMP = (aminomethyl)piperidinium, x = 3 or 4, n = 1-4) (Table  6  i, j).  89  The dications are less symmetrical than most spacers discussed in the session above, with one primary N and another N on the piperidine ring. The position of the functional group has a profound influence on the structure and properties of the resulting 2D perovskite structure. Since the inorganic layers are stacked exactly on top of each other with no lateral shift, the distance between adjacent layers defined by the planes of terminal iodine atoms can simply be measured by the closest I•••I distance. Both series exhibit short interlayer distance of ∼4 Å, with the 3AMP series showing a slightly smaller distance (Figure  7a ) than the 4AMP one (Figure  7b ). The 3AMP cation shows weak interaction with the terminal iodine atoms (Figure  7a ), which exhibits a small effect on the in-plane Pb-I-Pb angle since the terminal iodine atom does not contribute to the in-plane distortion directly. While 4AMP seems to interact in a stronger fashion where the hydrogen bonding with bridging iodine atoms causes amplified in-plane distortion but negligible outof-plane distortion (Figure  7b ). To distinguish these two effects, the Pb-I-Pb angles can be further classified into two categories, the equatorial Pb-I-Pb angle parallel to the inorganic plane, and the axial Pb-I-Pb angle perpendicular to the plane (Figure  7a ). For both series, all the axial Pb-I-Pb bond angles are close to 180°, so the bond angle difference mainly comes from the equatorial ones. The equatorial Pb-I-Pb angles are much smaller in the 4AMP series than in the 3AMP series with a similar trend for the average angles. The inorganic layers are more distorted in the 4AMP series, leading to higher bandgaps than those for the 3AMP series (Figure  7e, f ). The optical properties of the DJ series present some differences from those in the RP series. For the same homologous member (e.g., n = 3), the PL emission peaks of the AMP compounds are at lower energy than those of the butylammonium (BA) compounds (Figure  7e ). As mentioned above, the Pb-I-Pb angle can affect the bandgap when the other structural parameters are the same (e.g., layer-number, interlayer distance and Pb-I bond lengths). For n = 3, even though the 4AMP compound shows the smallest average Pb-I-Pb bond angle (as well as smallest equatorial Pb-I-Pb bond angle), its bandgap is still smaller than the that of the BA compound, which suggests that the Pb-I-Pb angle is not the only factor that can influence the bandgap. It has been suggested that the interlayer spacing can also affect the bandgap especially when the closest interlayer distance is equal to or shorter than the sum of van der Waals radii of iodide atoms. In that case there may be significant I•••I interactions in the stacking direction and broaden electronic band widths thus reducing the 2D confinement and the narrowing bandgap.  40  Since the interlayer distance is much shorter for 4AMP (4.1 Å) than BA (7.1 Å), it shows lower bandgap despite the smaller average Pb-I-Pb angles. Electronic band structure calculations also show the I•••I interaction participates in antibonding that destabilizes the VBM, leading to reduced bandgap compared to the RP phase.  89  While between 3AMP and 4AMP, the interlayer distance is similar (∼4 Å) so the Pb-I-Pb angle still plays the role. The 3AMP series with larger average Pb-I-Pb angle (as well as larger equatorial Pb-I-Pb angle) shows lower bandgap. Fabrication of solar cell devices using the n = 4 compounds results in a PCE of 7.32% for (3AMP)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 , which is higher than (4AMP)-(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13. In this context, it is illustrative to compare the n = 7 structure of (4AMP)(MA) 6 Pb 7 I 22 , which is highest layer thickness perovskite to be crystallographically characterized, with the RP structure of (BA) 2 (MA) 6 Pb 7 I 22 .  151  Even though for n = 3 the 4AMP structure is more distorted (smaller Pb-I-Pb angle) than the BA one, in n = 7 the difference becomes smaller. The equatorial Pb-I-Pb angle is still smaller for the 4AMP compound (160.8°) than the BA one (163.7°). Since the contribution of the axial Pb-I-Pb angle becomes more significant in n = 7 (six axial Pb-I-Pb angles), and 4AMP has large axial Pb-I-Pb angle close to 180°, the average Pb-I-Pb angle is larger for the 4AMP (169.2°) than the BA (165.1°) compound. More interestingly, the distortion of individual octahedron quantified by the bong angle variance (BAV) and distortion index (DI), is much larger in the BA compound. For the AMP n = 7 compound, the inorganic layer closest to the AMP cation is most distorted, and "absorbs" most of the strain. For the BA compound, the central layer is most distorted, and the strain cannot be relieved in the individual layer, leading to the overall more distorted structure. Therefore, the AMP n = 7 compound shows a lower bandgap than BA owing to its less distorted structure and smaller interlayer distance. The bandgaps of the AMP compounds can be further tuned by FA alloying targeting the perovskite cages.  152  It is wellknown that in 3D perovskites, FAPbI The same strategy of A cation alloying also applies to the bromide perovskites. Because of the similarity of 3AMP and 4AMP cations, both the spacer and the A-site cations can be a l l o y e d t o g e n e r a t e t h e s e r i e s ( 3 A M -P) a (4AMP) 1-a (FA) b (MA) 1-b Pb 2 Br 7 . Similar to the iodide series, the average Pb-Br-Pb angles are closer to 180°with more 3AMP and FA and increasing ratio of 4AMP and MA decreases the angles. Since all compounds exhibit similar interlayer distance, the Pb-Br-Pb angles play the major role in determining the bandgaps. The compound with larger Pb-Br-Pb angle shows lower bandgap, which can be tuned from 2.66 to 2.82 eV.  153  3.2.4. (Aminomethyl)pyridinium Cations. The aromatic analogues of the (aminomethyl)piperidinium cations, x-(aminomethyl)pyridinium (AMPY, x = 3 or 4) (Table  6k ,l) have been explored by Li et al.  40  Compared to the aliphatic xAMP cations, the aromatic xAMPY cations have larger rigidity since all the atoms on the aromatic ring must stay on the same plane. These cations also have some delocalization of charge on the aromatic ring as well as a smaller dielectric mismatch between the inorganic and organic layer owing to the increased dielectric constant of xAMPY. These factors affect the strength of the electrostatic interaction between the inorganic and organic layers, influencing stacking of the inorganic layer and the Pb-I-Pb bond angle, thus changing the optical properties. The 3AMPY cation is less symmetric than the 4AMPY, and since the aromatic ring cannot bend, the inorganic layers are slightly offset, with a unit cell displacement of (0.25, 0.25). Even though the 3AMPY compounds exhibit smaller interlayer distance, their closest I•••I distance (Figure  7c ) is still larger than the 4AMPY series (Figure  7d ) because of the slightly staggered octahedra. Because of the resonance of the aromatic ring, the ortho and para (2 and 4) positions are activated, bearing more partial positive charges. Then the partial positive charge is brought to the primary NH 3 + group through the inductive effect of the carbon in the aminomethyl group (CH 2 NH 3 + ). So, the 4AMPY cation exhibits a stronger electrostatic interaction with the inorganic layer, with the 4AMPY compounds showing smaller NH 3 + •••I distance than the 3AMPY compounds. For 4AMPY, the hydrogen bonding between the N-H of the pyridinium ring and the bridging iodine atom of the octahedra makes the octahedra mainly distorted in-plane and barely distorted out-of-plane (Figure  7d ). For 3AMPY, the N-H of the pyridinium ring is loosely hydrogen-bonded to the terminal iodine atom, resulting in slight distortion in the perovskite layer both in-plane and outof-plane (Figure  7c ). The 4AMPY series exhibits axial Pb-I-Pb angles close to 180°, but smaller equatorial Pb-I-Pb angles than the 3AMPY series (Figure  7c, d ). Overall, the average Pb-I-Pb angles are smaller for the 4AMPY series, leading to wider bandgaps than the 3AMPY series. Looking at the optical absorption spectra of the aromatic AMPY and aliphatic AMP compounds (Figure  7f ), there are two slopes for all, and the bandgap is extracted from the highenergy slope before it is interrupted by the exciton peak. The high-energy bandgap slope is almost the same, the low-energy slope varies because of the existence of the exciton peak. The exciton binding energy E b can be roughly estimated by subtracting energy of the exciton peak relative to the bandgap, resulting in smaller E b in the aromatic AMPY series than the aliphatic AMP series. As mentioned previously, the 2D perovskites can be seen as naturally formed quantum well structure, with the organic spacer as the barrier and the inorganic layer as the well. the E b of 2D perovskites can be estimated by the equation, = ε ε ( ) E E 4 b b D 2 3 w b , where ε w and ε b are the dielectric constants of the well and barrier, respectively, and E b 3D is the exciton binding energy of the corresponding 3D perovskite. Since the organic spacer (barrier) usually has smaller dielectric constant than the inorganic layer (well), the exciton binding energy of 2D perovskite is higher than that of the 3D one. This makes sense because of the quantum and dielectric confinement effects when the dimension is reduced from 3D to 2D. For 2D perovskites with different spacer cations (for the same n value), since the aromatic spacers (AMPY) exhibits larger dielectric constant than the aliphatic ones (AMP) as the barrier, they are expected to have smaller dielectric mismatch between the organic and inorganic layers and reduced dielectric confinement in the quantum well structure.  154  So, one can expect the electron-hole pairs to be more easily separated and carriers collected by the electron/ hole transport layers in photovoltaic devices, which is supported by the efficiencies of the solar cell devices. The J sc and thus the PCE of the devices based on (3AMPY)-(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 is 50% higher than those of (3AMP)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 (see below in the device part). Interestingly, during synthesis, using the same aromatic cations but changing the starting ratio of Pb: xAMPY, new 3D nonperovskitic structures (perovsktoids) form with a combination of corner-sharing and edgesharing octahedra.  38  The 2AMPY cation can also be incorporated into lead iodide structures to form either a 1D structure that incorporates crystalline H 2 O in the lattice or 2D structures that preclude H 2 O, and these structures are interconvertible below 90 °C.  155, 156  This cation forms 2D perovskites for bromide and chloride compounds as well with a unit cell displacement of (0.2, 0.2), similar to that of the 3AMPY compounds.  156  The bromide compounds with x-AMPY (x = 3 or 4) cations form 0D and 1D structures with 3AMPY and 4AMPY, respectively.  157  3.2.5. Diammonium Cations Involving Thiophene. As mentioned above in the monoammonium cation section, Mitzi et al. first proposed the idea of exploring band alignment in the materials using cations with oligothiophene derivatives.  127  In 1999, they described the lead bromide perovskites structure of the n = 1 single crystal with a heavily conjugated quaterthiophene derivative (AE4T, Figure  8e (iv)) (Figure  8a ).  127  The cations adopt the herringbone configuration and have significant optical absorption and emission by themselves. They also fabricated the thin film of the perovskites with all three halides (X = Cl, Br, I). The absorption spectra of three thin films resemble those of the corresponding halide salts with an additional exciton peak from the inorganic lead halide octahedra (Figure  8b ). For X = Cl, the exciton peak is at higher energy than the organic absorption feature (Figure  8b (i)). For X = Br, the two energy peaks overlap (Figure  8b (ii)), and for X = I, the exciton absorption is at lower energy than the organic absorption feature (Figure  8b (iii)). The PL spectrum of the chloride perovskite is similar to that of the chloride salt of the oligothiophene organic cation, while the PL spectrum of the iodide perovskite is significantly quenched. This suggests that the chloride perovskite likely forms internal Type I heterojunction (Figure  6c (iv)) with the HOMO and LUMO level of the organic molecule representing the lowest energy states for both electrons and holes, so the carriers recombine in the chromophore radiatively. The conduction band is composed of the lead p-orbital and the valence band consists of the lead s-and halide p-orbitals. Changing the halogen from X = Cl to X = I increases the energy of the valence band maximum while maintaining the conduction band energy (Figure  8c ). This leads to a Type II quantum well for the bromide and iodide structures, with the electrons are localized in the CBM of the inorganic part and the holes in the HOMO of the organic part (Figure  6c (ii)). Charge separation inhibits overlap of the electron and hole wave functions and therefore decreases the possibility of radiative recombination. This is confirmed by DFT calculations (Figure  8c ).  126  Liu et al. has also evaluated the band alignment of different oligothiophene spacer cations for bromide perovskites, from one thiophene to five thiophene rings (Figure  8e(i)-(v) ).  126  Using the spacer with one thiophene ring leads to a 2D perovskite structure that adopts Type I alignment, while those with two and more thiophene rings lead to 2D perovskites with Type II quantum well structures (Figure  8d ). The rigidity and unique configuration of the AE4T cation also stabilizes the so-called metal deficient perovskites (AE4T)M 2/3 □ 1/3 X 4 (M = Bi 3+ and Sb 3+ , □ = vacancy)  158  and the iodide 2D double perovskite (AE4-T) 2 AgBiI 8 .  159  However, diammonium cations containing thiophene rings and flexible linear chain (Figure  8e (vi)) form 1D structures of (NH 3 RNH 3 )BiI 5 .  127   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>73342</offset>
      <text> Varying the A-site Cations So far, we have discussed how the spacer cations can influence the properties of 2D perovskites, most of which have incorporated MA as the A-site cation. The size of the A-site cation which occupies the perovskite cage is limited by the  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>73609</offset>
      <text> Goldschmidt tolerance factor = + [ + ] t r r r r ( )/ 2( ) A X M X , where r A , r M , and r X are the effective radii of A + , M 2+ , and X - ions, respectively.  160, 161  When the t value is between 0.8 and 1, the perovskite phases are favored. For cations with t larger than 1 or smaller than 0.8, they usually form nonperovskite phases.  162  For M = Pb 2+ and X = I -, the t values of Cs + and FA are near the lower and upper limits of the ideal range, respectively, so perovskite structures of CsPbI 3 and FAPbI 3 are metastable at room temperature. When M = Sn 2+ , the t values for Cs + and FA + are well within this range, so CsSnI 3 and FASnI 3 form stable perovskite structures.  62  However, in 2D perovskites (e.g., (A′) 2 (A) n-1 M n X 3n+1 ), the range of the tolerance factor can actually be extended so that spacer cations larger than MA can be stabilized.  75, 163  For example, (BA) 2 (FA)Pb 2 I 7 and (BA) 2 (FA)Pb 2 Br 7 are stable at room temperature (Table  7a ).  101, 107  Incorporating the isopropylammonium (IPA) cation in the tin iodide system forms a 1D structure at room temperature. But during the synthesis at high temperature, a red phase is observed, and characterizing the aliquots reveals a 2D structure (IPA) 2 (IPA)Sn 2 I 7 with the IPA cations taking the positions both between the inorganic layer (A′ site) and inside the perovskite cage (A site) (Table  7e ).  164  Upon cooling to room temperature, this phase transforms back to the 1D phase within five minutes. Mao et al. reported the structures of (EA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 X 10 (EA = ethylammonium, X = Br and Cl), which are both stable at room temperature (Table  7c ). Similar to (IPA) 2 (IPA)Sn 2 I 7 , the EA cation takes both the A and A′ site (Figure  9a ).  75  To accommodate the large cation, the octahedra are highly distorted, with elongated Pb-X bonds and X-Pb-X angles deviated from 90°(Figure  9b ). The PL spectra of the compounds are broad, covering the whole visible light range, making them white-light emitters at room temperature. EA cannot template the iodide structure "(EA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 " by itself, but it can serve as A-site cation when a larger spacer cation (such as butylamine (BA)) is employed, forming (BA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 .  30, 74  Its bandgap is the highest among the n = 3 structures because of the elongation of the Pb-I bond length and distortion of the octahedra. Mixing EA with MA for the A-site results in a continuous shift of optical properties.  74  Adding more EA to the structure causes the bandgap and PL peak to shift to higher energy and the PL intensity to quench. (BA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 is also reported to show antiferroelectricity  30  and sensitive X-ray detection.  166  Fu et al.  163  extended of Goldschmidt tolerance factor concept to 2D perovskites using hexylammonium (HA) as the spacer and formamidinium (FA), dimethylammonium (DMA), guanidinium (GA), and acetamidinium (AA) as A-site cations. The structure of (HA) 2 (GA)Pb 2 I 7 was characterized by singlecrystal X-ray diffraction and compared to that of (HA) 2 (MA)-Pb 2 I 7 (Table  7d ). The perovskite cage is expanded, and the tensile strain of the cage is compensated by the compressed spacer layer. The PL intensity and lifetime of (HA) 2 (GA)Pb 2 I 7 are significantly reduced compared to (HA) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 because of increased phonon-mediated nonradiative decay caused by exciton-phonon interaction. Li et al. reported the detailed evolution of structural and optoelectronic properties of (BA) 2 (A)Pb 2 I 7 (A = MA, FA, DMA, GA) (Figure  9d-g ).  21  As the size of A-site cation increases (MA &lt; FA &lt; DMA &lt; GA), the Pb-I bonds are elongated, which reduces the orbital overlap of the Pb s-and I p-orbitals, thus increasing the bandgap (Figure  9h ). A 2D color map of how the bandgap changes with Pb-I bond length is built by DFT calculations, showing that the bandgaps increase with increasing Pb-I bond lengths (Figure  9c ). It has been reported that the Pb-I-Pb bond angles can affect when the other structural parameters are the same. However, in this series, the Pb-I bond length plays the major role and the effect of Pb-I-Pb bond angle is secondary since the angles are similar. Raman spectra suggest that the lattice becomes softer and more anharmonic with larger A-site cations. These structural changes with enlarged A cations result in significant decreases in PL intensity and PL lifetime, consistent with a more pronounced nonradiative decay (Figure  9i ). So far, three factors have been proved experimentally to tune the bandgap of 2D perovskites for a specific layer-number: (i) metal-halidemetal (M-X-M) bond angle, (ii) interlayer distance and (iii) metal-halide (M-X) bond length. M-X-M bond angles close to 180°and small M-X bond lengths lead to more overlap of metal s-and halide p-orbitals, while close interlayer d-spacing results in weak halide interaction in the stacking direction, both reducing the bandgap. Hautzinger et al. reported similar trend for 2D nanoplates (HA) 2 (A)Pb 2 I 7 (A = Cs + , MA, FA, DMA, EA, GA, and AA).  165  The peak positions for both the absorption and PL spectra show a clear parabolic trend versus the size of the Asite cation, with MA and FA near the bottom (Figure  9j ). It is worth mentioning that the trend of the bulk and colloidal systems is slightly different, since the octahedra in the nanoplates have more freedom to tilt due to the finite size of the crystals and the strain introduced by the large A-site cation can be easily mitigated to the ligand. In contrast, for the bulk materials, the strain is accumulated in the inorganic lattice since the octahedra repeat infinitely in the stacking direction. The size dependence of the absorption peak for the 2D perovskite nanoplates follows the same trend as for that of the 3D bulk perovskites APbI 3 (A = Cs + , MA and FA) in that E g/Cs+ &gt; E g/MA &gt; E g/FA , which suggests in this region, the tilt of octahedra (Pb-I-Pb bond angle) is the main factor in determining the bandgap. On the other hand, for the 2D bulk perovskites, E g/MA &lt; E g/FA &lt; E g/GA , suggesting that the Pb-I bond elongation plays the major role. The size of the A-site cation is indicative of the chemical pressure inside the cage. Recent reports have shown that upon external pressure, the Pb-I bond length decreases and the optical bandgap also reduces (Figure  9j ).  [167] [168] [169]  However, there is no mechanism for stretching the Pb-I bond length by applying "negative" physical pressure. Incorporating large Asite cations can expand the perovskite cage as a form of negative chemical pressure, which results in the increase of the optical bandgap, in contrast to the bandgap decrease caused by physical pressure (Figure  9j ). This also leads to a decrease in PL quantum yield (PLQY) and lifetime, both of which are detrimental to solar cell performance. These results suggest that A-site cation alloying is not responsible for the improved photovoltaic performance, instead the passivation of grain boundary from the large A-site cations could be more likely.  165  The A-site cation is therefore a powerful tool for tuning the properties of 2D perovskites. More importantly, there is a longstanding debate on how the A-site cation may influence the properties of perovskites  [170] [171] [172] [173]  such as carrier dynamics,  171, 173  local ferroelectric domains,  170, 172  Rashba splitting,  174  and localization of conduction and valence band edges in spatially separated regions.  170  However, agreement still has not been reached and very few studies have been done on 2D perovskites. Increased choices of A-site cations for 2D perovskites with different dipole moments provide useful model systems to study the effect of A-site cation on the properties. This can help us with future designs of more optimal materials for specific optoelectronic applications. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>81517</offset>
      <text> ⟨110⟩-Oriented 2D Perovskites The less-explored ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites can incorporate +1 or +2 cations, adopting the general formula of A′AMX 4 (A and A′ are +1) or BMX 4 (B is +2) (Figure  10a, b ). For A′AMX 4 , the A and A′ cations can be the same or different. The A cation occupies the octahedral pocket while the A′ cation sits between the layers (Figure  10a ). For BMX 4 , the +2 cation connects the adjacent layers by electrostatic interaction. The ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites were first reported by Mitzi et al., using iodoformamidinium (IFO)  175  as the A′ cation and MA as the A cation (Table  8a ). Multilayered structures (IFO) 2 (MA) m Sn m I 3m+2 (m = 2-4) were synthesized, which remains the only example of multilayered ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites, but only the crystal structure for (IFO) 2 (MA) 2 Sn 2 I 8 (m = 2) was reported (Figure  10a ). ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite can also form for the Pb analogue, (IFO)(MA)PbI 4 , but so far, only the structure of one-layer is reported.  176  Lightfoot and co-workers have found that similar structures can be templated with GA as the A cation and imidazolium (ImH) (Table  8b ) and 1,2,4triazolium (TzH) (Table  8d ) as the A′ cation for lead bromide  177  perovskites and 1-methylimidazolium (Table  8c ) for tin iodide perovskites.  178  Combining TzH and ImH, a rare 3 × 3 ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite can form.  179  Because of the existence of multiple N atoms in the cation, inter-cation hydrogen bonding influences the structure. More interestingly, a 3D tin iodide structure can be stabilized with GA and TzH both inside the cuboctahedral cage.  178  The octahedra are highly distorted to accommodate the large cation. In the previously mentioned examples, the smaller cation occupies the octahedral pocket with the larger cation between the layers, but the 2-hydroxyethylammonium (Table  8e ) cation takes the position inside the pocket with the smaller FA between the layers. This because of the strong hydrogen bonding between 2-hydroxyethylammonium and the inorganic layer.  180  GA forms similar structures of (GA) 2 MI 4 (M = Pb 2+ and Sn 2+ ), where it takes both A and A′ site,  [132] [133] [134]  so does acetamidinium.  179  However, with a combination of GA and FA, a 2 × 3 ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskite forms (Table  8g ).  136  A similar structure can also form for thiourea and FA (Table  8h ).  137  Besides the most common 2 × 2 ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites, other configurations can also be stabilized depending on where the corrugation occurs. These are named "n × m" ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites (Figure  10c ) such as the 2 × 3 structure discussed above, with two octahedra on the one side of the roof and three on the other side. Most of the structures are symmetric, such as 2 × 2, 3 × 3, 4 × 4 and 6 × 6 ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites (Figure  10c ). Most of these structures form because of unique hydrogen bonding, such as 4-nitrophenylethylammonium (Table  8i ), which forms 3 × 3 ⟨110⟩-oriented lead iodide perovskites. The isostructural bromide perovskite can form but not chloride.  182  ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites BMX 4 can form using linear or cyclic diammonium cations as well. For example, 1,3propanediammonium cation forms the 6 × 6 ⟨110⟩-oriented lead bromide perovskite (Table  8j ),  76  and 1,5-pentanediammonium cation can form the 4 × 4 ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskite with tin and iodide (Table  8k ).  183     5i ), forms ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites with tin and iodide,  138  probably because the hydrogen bonding is not as strong as secondary and ternary N-H. Longer diammonium cations with ether groups such as 2,2-(ethylenedioxy)bis(ethylammonium) can form 2 × 2 ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites for bromide and iodide, but not chloride (Table  8l ).  82  It is difficult to form ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites with all three halides since the Pb-X bond length is halide-dependent, meaning the tolerance of each Pb-X framework to the same cation is different. However, because of its unique shape and size, the cyclic diammonium cation 3-aminopyrrolidinium can form ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites for all three halides (Table  8p ).  181  The ring lies parallel to the stacking direction for the bromide and chloride structures but perpendicular to the stacking direction for the iodide structure which requires more space inside the octahedra pocket and leads to more distorted inorganic layers. Other cyclic diammonium cations such as piperazinium  150  (Table  8q ) and 1-ethylpiperazinium  69  (Table  8r ) can form 2 × 2 ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites for chloride and bromide, respectively. For imidazolium derivatives (Table 8su), only one N atom on then ring can be protonated, and when that N atom shows on the different positions of the ring, different structures can form.  68, 184, 185  Many of the compounds discussed above exhibit broad PL emission, and the PL spectra for some of these compounds covers the whole visible light range, making them white-light emitters at room temperature. The white-light emission mechanism is associated with self-trapped excitons (STE), which are a series of traps states below the bandgap in highly distorted structures.  81, 82  Even though the essence of STE is still under exploration, they are generally believed to be caused by an exciton-phonon (lattice) interaction similar to polarons, not permanent chemical defects.  186  The perovskite lattice is very soft, so when the exciton interacts with the deformable lattice, local distortion can be created, like a hard ball dropping on a soft net and causing a potential minimum. When the ball (exciton) is removed, the net (lattice) returns to its original states. This is different from a ball dropping on a net with holes (defects), where the ball prefers to fall into where the hole is. Researchers have tried to correlate the STE with structural characters such as bond length distortion, bond angle variance and out-of-plane distortion.  83, 187  Most of the ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites are more distorted than the ⟨100⟩-oriented perovskites; however, it is rare to find a system where ⟨110⟩oriented perovskites can be formed by all three halides and emit white-light at room temperature. As discussed above, 3aminopyrrolidinium is an exception and can form ⟨110⟩oriented perovskites for all three halides, which provides a perfect platform to compare the mechanism. Li et al. performed temperature-dependent PL measurement on these three compounds and found that as the temperature cooled down, the STE peak becomes observable.  181  Though the position of the free exciton (FE) peak varies for three halides, the positions of the STE peaks are similar. As shown in Figure  10d , at room temperature, the carriers have enough thermal energy to cross the barrier from FE to STE, so all three compounds emit white light at room temperature. As the temperature cools down, the thermal energy is insufficient for the carriers to cross the barrier. This happens for the iodide compound first at the highest temperature, so the FE peak starts to show up first. On the other hand, the barrier from STE to FE is smallest for the iodide compound, so it is possible for the carrier to detrap back to FE states. But for the chloride compound, the barrier to detrap is largest once the carriers are trapped, so it is unlikely for them to detrap. So, the chloride compounds exhibit broad emission even at low temperature. Overall, the trend for trapping follows E trap, I &gt; E trap,Br &gt; E trap,Cl while the trend of detrapping is the opposite. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(ethylenedioxy)bis(ethylammonium)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T19:12:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="85160" length="33"/>
        <text>(ethylenedioxy)bis(ethylammonium)</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>89191</offset>
      <text> ⟨111⟩-Oriented 2D Perovskites ⟨111⟩-oriented 2D perovskites usually incorporate +3 metals since cleaving the parent 3D structure selectively eliminates some metal sites, changing the charge of the inorganic lattice. These perovskites can be regarded as a class of defect perovskites A 3 M 2 □X 9 (M = Bi 3+ , Sb 3+ and As 3+ ; □ is vacancy), where the metal takes 2/3 occupancy of the M site in the A 3 M 3 X 9 perovskite formula. The structure can be seen as removing one layer of octahedra in the ⟨111⟩ direction for every three layers (Figure  11 ). For the iodide perovskites, when the A cation is small, such as ammonium,  189, 190  potassium,  191  or rubidium,  192, 193  ⟨111⟩-oriented 2D perovskite structures can form. While for large A cations like methyl-ammonium  194, 195  and guanidinium,  196  a 0D structure with a dimer of face-sharing octahedra forms. For Cs + , it forms 0D structure with Bi 3+191 and ⟨111⟩-oriented 2D structure with Sb 3+ .  197  Interestingly, when mixed with chloride, the 0D structure of Cs 3 Bi 2 I 9 can expand to 2D Cs 3 Bi 2 I 6 Cl 3 ,  198  with the small chloride taking the bridging site and large iodide occupying the terminal site. More interestingly, even when a small fraction of I (9%) is replaced by Cl, the structure can change from 1D (Cs 3 Bi 2 Cl 9 ) to 2D Cs 3 Bi 2 Cl 8.16 I 0.84 ,  199  showing the powerful range that this strategy works. Thanks to the relatively low bandgap and large density, some of the compounds are explored for optoelectronic applications such as solar cells and 200 α-particle 201 and X-ray detection.  202  Generally, we expect the 2D structures to show better performance than the 0D ones. Solis-Ibarra and co-workers expand the single layer ⟨111⟩oriented 2D perovskites to multilayered perovskites by incorporating +2 metal to form A 4 M II M III 2 X 12 .  203  These compounds can also be seen as expansion of 2D layered double perovskites. The octahedra with the M II are in the middle layer and those with the M III are on the edge (Figure  11 ). So far, there are seven synthesized and structurally characterized compounds (Cs   [203] [204] [205]  and more are predicted by DFT calculations.  205, 206  4. OVERVIEW OF THIN FILM AND DEVICE FABRICATION The ascendance of 2D perovskites in the field of photovoltaics in the past five years was surprisingly rapid, and the main reasons for this have been their significantly greater chemical stability, facile tendency to form films from solutions, strong tendency for perpendicular orientation of the 2D perovskite layers relative to the substrate and comparable ability to perform as great solar cell materials compared to the 3D MAPbI 3 . However, even as the success in solar cell devices and light emitting diodes has been undisputed, there has been confusion and controversy in understanding the true nature of the films and the difference between nominal composition and the actual phase distribution in the films. In this section, we review the various methods, characterizations and current understanding of films made from 2D as well as 2D/3D perovskite mixtures. There are different methods used to make thin films of these materials which will influence the properties and the ultimate performance of the device. To understand the relationship between the perovskite layer and device performance, it is important to look at the perovskite layer in the context of the overall device architecture, which varies depending on the device. In solar cells, the overall device architecture consists of an electrode, a hole-transport layer (HTL) which allows holes through but not electrons, the absorbing perovskite layer, an electron-transport layer (ETL) which allows electrons through but not holes, and another electrode.  207  These layers can either be stacked with in the order substrate/electrode/HTL/perovskite/ETL/electrode (pi-n architecture, Figure  12a ) or substrate/electrode/ETL/ perovskite/HTL/electrode (n-i-p architecture, Figure  12b ). The HTL and ETL are chosen based on the energy levels of the perovskite layer. The conduction band minimum (CBM) of the ETL is ideally just below the CBM of the perovskite layer to allow electrons in the CBM of the perovskite to easily transfer to the CBM of the ETL. Likewise, the valence band In solar cells, the power conversion efficiency (PCE)  208  is the factor of merit, defined as the power produced by the solar cell divided by the power put into the cell via sunlight. The PCE can be determined through the simple formula PCE = V OC × J SC × FF where V OC is the open-circuit voltage, J SC is the short-circuit current density, and FF is the fill factor. Each of these parameters is affected differently by the properties of the materials used in the device. The potential maximum V OC is determined by the difference in the electron and hole quasi-Fermi levels.  209  However, other factors like carrier recombination from defects in the perovskite layer or at the interface reduce the V OC from the ideal. The J SC is dependent on the ability of the perovskite absorbing layer to absorb light and transfer the carriers to the HTL and ETL. Finally, the FF is primarily dependent on the interfaces between the perovskite layer and the ETL and HTL layers. If the physical contact of the layers or the electronic alignment between the layers is poor, the FF will suffer. With these parameters in mind, we begin by discussing the desired properties that films need to maximize each of these values. These can be thought of as the "rules" to making lowdimensional perovskite films which can succeed in devices. Proper measurements of these properties will be discussed along with the rules, as has been outline elsewhere.  210  After this, we outline the methods used to make the perovskite films and how each method can be used to access the desired properties. Then, we discuss the different cations used in devices with different dimensionalities to relate the effects of the spacer on the different properties of these films and devices, outlining what has been learned so far about the correlation between spacer and device performance from a film and device perspective. One of the well-known advantages of employing low-dimensional structures in perovskite films is the remarkable increase in chemical stability. 3D MAPbI 3 devices suffer significantly from their proclivity to react with moisture to form PbI 2 , MA, and HI as byproducts. This process is enhanced by the high polarity of the organic cation MA which can easily be separated from the inorganic framework.  211, 212  Along with this, degradation from light and heat as well as considerable ion migration in the 3D structures degrade the devices in real conditions.  213  While these processes can be mitigated by encapsulation and barriers,  214  producing intrinsically stable materials in films is preferred to reduce processing and production costs. All these factors should be considered when discussing the stability of perovskite films and devices. The presence of bulky more hydrophobic cations increases the overall hydrophobicity of the film. Additionally, the confinement of ion migration in two dimensions for the 2D structures give rise to an overall higher stability. Measuring film stability under light, humidity, or heat stress can be accomplished easily via X-ray diffraction (XRD) by observing the growth of the PbI 2 phase as the film decomposes.  99  Devices can be measured over time by simply taking the currentvoltage scan after different periods of time under different conditions. However, there is still a need for a consistent manner to test device stability. For instance, humidity varies greatly from location to location, which leads to drastically different responses to humidity depending on the weather. Humidity testing must be done in a controlled environment to make sure that fluctuations in humidity outside are not a factor. Furthermore, testing for light and heat should be regularly performed as well. Only by considering all these factors in a systematic manner can different methods and materials be compared. In fact, recently a consensus statement was issued, suggesting a systematic means to report device efficiency based on the International Summit on Organic Photovoltaic Stability (ISOS) protocols.  215  4.1.2. Crystallinity. It is important to consider crystallinity when evaluating a film's ability to transport carriers. Crystallinity is based on the crystallites in the film, where a crystallite is a repeating unit of a chemical structure. Crystallinity is commonly measured using XRD by finding the full-width at half-maximum (fwhm) of the peaks in the pattern. With decreasing crystallite size, the fwhm will increase; however, other factors such as strain, stacking faults, and instrumental broadening can also influence the fwhm, so this is not a perfect method to approximate crystallite size but can be used as a general guide to the relative size of the crystallites when comparing films. 4.1.3. Morphology. Like the crystallinity, morphology is important when considering charge carrier transport. The morphology of a film is its internal and external structure based on the grain size and shape. In the perovskite literature, the term "grain" is loosely defined as a region on a film separated by a change in the topography of the film such as a crack. This is commonly quantified by scanning-electron microscopy (SEM)  216  or atomic-force microscopy (AFM). However, smaller cracks often exist within these grains, making the exact definition of "grain" difficult. Here, we define grain as the smallest unit able to be seen by SEM or AFM. It should be acknowledged that the techniques used to define grains often only use images from the surface of the film, giving an incomplete picture of the film morphology. Cross-sectional SEM can elucidate the full morphology of the film, showing how deep the grains grow, which is important when considering electron transport for devices. Related to the grains, the roughness of the films should be considered when discussing morphology. When the roughness is large, the presence of pin holes, defined as areas where there is no film coverage, become a possibility, leading to poor device performance. 4.1.4. Orientation. Achieving the correct orientation of a 2D perovskite film on the substrate is crucial for the success of device performance. This is the main difference concerning film deposition between 2D and 3D perovskites where in the latter crystalline grain orientation is much less of a critical issue. For 2D materials, the layers all orient in the same direction within each grain making the grains anisotropic. The orientation of the grains themselves thus leads to a distinct orientation of the layers with regard to the substrate, commonly defined as the "texture" of the film. A highly textured film could have grains with layers all parallel to the substrate or all perpendicular to the substrate while an untextured film has grains with layers oriented at all angles regarding the substrate. This is important because of the highly anisotropic nature of the 2D perovskites, which experience both quantum and dielectric confinement perpendicular to the layers. Because of these confinement effects, the charges cannot go from one layer to another, resulting in several orders of magnitude difference in conductivity measured perpendicular and parallel to the layers.  35  For devices such as solar cells, carriers must be able to separate and reach the top and bottom of the film to create current, shown in Figure  13a . If the layers are parallel to the substrate, the charges can only recombine, and no current is produced (Figure  13b ). On the other hand, devices like transistors require charge to run parallel to the substrate and may benefit from the perovskite layers being parallel to substrate. XRD can be used to roughly define the orientation of the films. Characteristic peaks below 2θ = 14°( for diffractometers with a Cu source) are indicative of grains with the 2D layers parallel to the substrate. On the other hand, characteristic peaks at ∼14°and ∼28°(for lead-iodide based structures) are from the repeating unit of one octahedra in line with the layers and seen when the layers are perpendicular to the substrate. A better technique to measure orientation is grazing-incidence wide-angle scattering (GIWAXS). Here, the X-rays irradiate the sample at a very low angle, resulting in complete reflection from the film. The scattering is measured with a 2D detector.  217, 218  The same peaks that would appear in a 1D XRD pattern and peaks that would not normally be seen due to the orientation of the 2D layers are seen in the 2D GIWAXS pattern.  23  The d-spacing of the various crystallographic planes will determine the position of the peaks along the radial axis q. Then, depending on the orientation of the crystallographic hkl planes in the chemical structure with relation to the substrate, the spot wills appear at a certain points along the azimuthal angle χ. The orientation of the perovskite layers will affect the orientation of all crystallographic planes, leading to distinct patterns depending on the orientation of the layers. If the orientation is random, the spots will be spread out along all χ, leading to rings. Comparing simulated GIWAXS patterns to experimental data allows the orientations in the film to be determined. 4.1.5. Composition. The chemical makeup of the film has become more and more relevant to low-dimensional perovskite films because of the phase inhomogeneity of the films. Generally, mixtures of different n values are seen within the films, with high-n phases first crystallizing at the surface followed by low-n phases on the bottom of the film, leading to the multiple quantum well film structure in Figure  13c .  220  Along with 2D lead halide perovskite films, this mechanism has also been seen in 2D tin halide perovskite films with a large variety of n values,  221  meaning that this mechanism is generalizable to a variety of systems. Thus, one should always systematically study the composition of a novel film. Several techniques have been used to identify the composition. XRD can give evidence of the film composition by the characteristic low-angle peaks below 2θ = 14°. As discussed above, the layers are generally oriented perpendicular to the substrate, so the X-ray can only detect the two characteristic peaks at ∼14°and 28°, which is unhelpful to elucidate the composition. In fact, the diffraction patterns for oriented MAPbI 3 and perpendicularly oriented 2D perovskites with most spacers and n values are nearly identical. Sometimes, low-angle peaks can be seen in films which can allow for phase identification by matching the experimental data to a pattern simulated from a structure solved via single-crystal XRD. If the single-crystal has not been solved for, having a harmonic pattern of low-angle peaks does imply the presence of a 2D phase, though not conclusively. Alternatively, high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) can sometimes be used to detect different phases in the film visually, though this technique cannot measure the bulk film. A simple way to show the different phases that exist is static absorption spectroscopy measurements, which show the positions of the excitonic peaks, which can be correlated to the expected positions for different phases based on the bandgap of single crystals though it cannot always be assumed that these peaks must be correlated to n = 1, 2, 3, etc. To make such a conclusion, phase-pure materials must be made and measured to determine the location of the peaks in the spectrum, usually in the form of crystals, as phase purity when n &gt; 2 is difficult to achieve in films.  222  Then, the peaks of the phase-pure materials and the peaks in the film can be correlated, though, even then, the presence of other phases with similar band gaps cannot be totally ruled out. Photoluminescence (PL) can also be used to identify different phases, as different quantum well thicknesses for different n values give discrete PL emission energies. The surface of the films (at the film/air interface) often gives a low-energy emission indicative of n &gt; 7 while the bottom (at the film/ substrate interface) gives higher-energy emissions of n = 1-4, depending on the film composition and processing. This is illustrated by the depth-dependent PL of the film seen in Figure  13d .  219  However, the excitons are quickly transferred to higher n phases, reducing PL from the low-n values. Transientabsorption (TA) spectroscopy can be used to better track these different phases, as it tracks the excitons as they transfer from phase to phase, making it one of the most effective ways to observe film composition.  223  No matter which method is used, to conclusively identify the composition in the film, the properties of the phase-pure materials must be known. While certain properties such as bandgap are fairly consistent for the same layer thickness using different spacers, notable exceptions do exist.  89  This also applies to diffraction-and scattering-based analysis, which require simulations based on single-crystal XRD to match data in the films to the proper phase. Thus, we emphasize the need for crystallographic understanding before positing chemistry-based explanations for device performance. 4.1.6. Interactions between Phases. Films with multiple phases have been shown to be particularly advantageous for LEDs, as the carriers are able to transfer quickly from low-n to high-n phases in a sort of "energy funnel," allowing for the carriers to travel easily through the film.  224  This is shown schematically in Figure  17a  and has also been described as a multiple quantum well structure (MQW). Understanding how these phases interact in the films has become increasingly important in optimizing both LEDs and solar cells. TA spectroscopy and time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) also give indications as to how quickly carriers will transfer from phase-to-phase. These processes have not been fully elucidated yet, as the composition in films with n &gt; 3 is highly complex, making systematic studies of the interactions between different phases difficult to achieve. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T11:51:31Z</infon>
        <location offset="93158" length="5"/>
        <text>n-i-p</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>107583</offset>
      <text> Thin Film Deposition Methods Next, we discuss the methods that have been developed to fabricate the films with desired properties as illustrated above. While these are the most common methods, there are many more methods used for fabrication of 3D devices which may be utilized for 2D devices as well in the future.  225  Further details on each of these methods have been reviewed previously.  226  4.2.1. One-Step. The simplest method to fabricate films is a one-step deposition, shown in Figure  14a . To spin-coat a thin film of perovskite, the components of the structure are dissolved in a solvent, generally an organic solvent such as γbutyrolactone (GBL), N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF) or dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO). While GBL cannot coordinate strongly with the perovskite in solution, DMF and DMSO can, which affects the kinetics of the crystallization of the film. These solvents have also been shown to create 1D solvated intermediates, which can lead to an undesired needle-like morphology.  220, [227] [228] [229]  In particular, DMSO has been shown to strongly coordinate to PbI 2 and slow down crystallization.  230  One can either directly dissolve the phase-pure crystals synthesized using the methods above or dissolve the individual components, PbI 2 , the A-site cation halide, and the spacer halide. Dissolution can be completed in minutes to hours depending on the concentration, composition, and temperature of the solution. Once dissolved, the solution is injected onto the substrate which is sitting on the spin-coater. If needed, the solution can also be filtered before injection. Spinning then commences, often for 30 to 60 s at a rate of thousands of rpm. Depending on composition and concentration, crystallization may commence on the spin-coater, leading to a color change from clear to colored for most materials.  100  After this, it is commonplace to anneal the film to remove residual solvent and complete crystallization. However, another method, the gas-pump method, involves removing solvent in a vacuum chamber immediately after deposition.  231  Even for the relatively simple one-step method, there are already many different parameters to consider: perovskite composition, solvent choice, dissolution time, concentration, spin time, spin rate, annealing time, and annealing temperature, among others, making transparency in reporting these parameters key to reproducibility. This process can be further optimized by using additives to the precursor solution before spin-coating, such as ammonium salts and hydrohalic acids,  232  but choosing the proper additive is highly dependent on the processing and composition of the film. 4.2.2. Hotcasting. Like the one-step method, hotcasting (Figure  14b ) involves depositing a solution of perovskite precursor directly onto the substrate. However, in this case, the substrate is hot enough to accelerate crystallization during spin-coating. This process has been shown to give large grain size for MAPbI 3  233  and was adopted to 2D (BA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 to give films with the layers highly perpendicular to the substrate,  234  giving highly efficient devices. The drawback to this technique is that the films are often not homogeneous, giving thinner regions in the center of the films. It is also difficult to reproduce given that the process must happen very quickly using a hot substrate, allowing for a greater amount of human error than room-temperature spin coating. However, further optimization and automation could prove to improve homogeneity and remove human error, making this a relevant lab-scale process for evaluating new materials and techniques. 4.2.3. Antisolvent. One commonly used technique is the so-called antisolvent method, shown in Figure  14c .  230  In this method, the perovskite precursor solution contains a polar solvent such as DMSO that is able to coordinate with lead iodide in solution. Generally, a mixture of DMF or GBL and DMSO is used. As mentioned above for one-step method, DMSO is known to coordinate with PbI 2 , which is essential for this method. This solution is then deposited on a substrate for spin coating. During spinning, an antisolvent is deposited onto the center of the film, rapidly removing the solvent and leaving a pinhole-free film composed of a solvated intermediate. Several antisolvents can be used, as long as they do not dissolve the perovskite phase. Commonly used antisolvents include toluene, chlorobenzene, and diethyl ether. The choice of antisolvent strongly affects the crystallization process; for example, chlorobenzene has been shown to lead directly to MAPbI 3 without the intermediate phase produced with other antisolvents.  235  Furthermore, the timing of this step is very important and varies depending on the specific conditions being used. However, in general, dropping of the antisolvent too early leads to the antisolvent being washed away with the precursor solution, and dropping too late into the process leads to large pinholes, presumably from the prolonged growth of the solvate intermediates. Annealing then converts this to a dense and uniform perovskite film, advantageous for device applications. This process has been reviewed in detail recently by Ghosh et al.  236  4.2.4. Dry Methods. In addition to methods that rely on a solvent, other methods have been developed as well. Being able to avoid toxic solvents has been of interest to the perovskite community, leading to developments of new methods to make 3D MAPbI 3 without solvent such as thermal evaporation,  237  gas-solid crystallization,  238  and chemical vapor deposition (CVD).  239  Some of these methods have also been applied to 2D perovskites, though to a lesser extent. Thermal deposition has been achieved using a single source apparatus to deposit ( B A ) 2 ( M A ) 3 P b 4 I 1 3 2 4 0 a n d m i x e d d i m e n s i o n a l "(BA) 2 Cs n-1 Pb n Br 3n+1 ,"  241  and CVD has been used to form CsPbX 3 (X = Cl, Br, I) nanoplatelets.  242  However, few further studies have been done using these methods to form molecularly 2D perovskite films. 4.2.5. Additives. Any of the mentioned fabrication methods can be modified and likely improved by the use of additives to the precursor solution. The use of additives in 3D and 2D perovskites has been reviewed extensively elsewhere.  28, 243, 244  For both 2D and 3D perovskites, additives can lead to grain boundary passivation, interface modification, and improved morphology, crystallinity, and stabilization, among other effects. In 2D perovskites, the effect of additives on orientation and n phase distribution are also highly important. Common additives include salts with cations such as ammonium (NH 4 + ), FA + , MA + , Cs + , or other metal and ammonium cations. The anions include Cl -, I -, Br -, and thiocyanate (SCN -), which have been shown to improve orientation and crystallinity for certain systems.  128, [245] [246] [247]  However, it should be noted that synergistic effects of multiple additives may be needed to take advantage of these effects.  245  Interestingly, these additives may improve the orientation by suppressing the formation of solvate intermediates.  248  Finding the correct additive or additives for each system and fabrication process is crucial to maximizing efficiency. In the case of addtives certain caveats need to be kept in mind. Additives are in fact reagents added into the precursor solutions or post film deposition and as a consequence they can engage in reactions with the perovskite and potentially generate in situ certain amounts of second phases. Elucidating and understanding these extra phases and their effects on film properties is a challenging task and today it has received very little attention, as the emphasis has been to just observe performance increases regardless of how they occur. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>115442</offset>
      <text> THIN FILM CASE STUDIES USING DIFFERENT PEROVSKITE LAYER ARCHITECTURES AND SPACER CATIONS Now that the desired properties of the 2D perovskite films and the methods used to fabricate them have been discussed, we turn our attention to the different low-dimensional perovskite layer architectures in the films. Here, we are defining film architecture as it relates only to the orientation of the perovskite layer [Pb n I 3n+1 ], not to be confused with the entire device architecture, which includes many other layers such as the electrodes, ETL, or HTL. This section is separated into the three primary architectures used for reduced dimensional perovskites films: 2D films based on stoichiometries for n &lt; 8, mixed dimensionality films where multiple phases with different dimensionalities are all present throughout the film, and heterostructures in which a low-dimensional perovskite layer is selectively deposited on an already-existing 3D perovskite. These three architectures are illustrated in Figure  15 . For each of these three architectures, many different organic cations have been used as spacers, from the most common BA and PEA to complex spacers such as guaninium  249  and many more,  [250] [251] [252] [253] [254] [255] [256] [257] [258] [259]  though the structures produced by many of these cations have not been resolved crystallographically, making correlations between structural properties and film properties difficult. Here, we outline several examples of different spacers used in different architectures and relate what is known about the phases that are stabilized by these spacers to the film properties and device performance. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>117100</offset>
      <text> 2D Films We begin with a discussion of what we call "2D films," designated as films in which the targeted stoichiometry (based on the precursor solution) gives an n value less than 8. We have chosen this value because the highest n value studied with single crystal X-ray crystallography has been n = 7.  34, 151  Because the crystalline phases in the film deposit quickly depending on the deposition method, the final material in the film is highly unlikely to be phase pure especially when the targeted n is greater than 2, as multiple phases with different n values will crystallize under kinetic control during film formation. Because of the multitude of conditions used in a wide variety of laboratories, the phase composition of the films can vary from indeed being a single phase containing only one homologous member to containing several homologous members. This is why it is critical for researchers to report as broad a characterization of these films as possible. For simplicity, we will define the composition of the films by the nominal stoichiometry that is used in the precursor solution to make the film. Here, we outline some examples of spacers used in 2D films and devices along with the methods used to make the films and highlight the spacers' unique influence on film properties and device efficiency. Tables  9  and 10  summarize a selected list of monoammonium and diammonium spacers, respectively, that have been used in solar cells with relevant device parameters. 5.1.1. 2D Phases with Monoammonium Cations. 5.1.1.1. Alkylammonium Cations. The BA spacer was the first alkylammonium spacer used in a 2D perovskite solar cell  100  and has also been utilized in LEDs.  [260] [261] [262]  Table  9a  shows a couple examples of early 2D devices using BA as the spacer in solar cells, including with tin as the metal.  64  Mixtures of tin and lead have also been used in solar cells. One report shows a PCE of 5.96% (with large hysteresis) using (BA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 3 SnI 13 . Interestingly, GIWAXS analysis shows a narrower texture with increasing tin concentration, implying that films using 2D tin perovskites have a greater degree of preferred orientation compared to their lead equivalents.  263  While BA remains one of the most commonly used spacers in film and device studies, other alkylammonium spacers derived from BA have been used to improve upon the original BA spacer. When choosing a new alkylammonium spacer for highefficiency devices, three of the more common derivations of the BA spacer have been considered, outlined in Figure  16 . (1)  A smaller carbon-chain length can be utilized to potentially give a narrower interlayer spacing, leading to a larger inorganic volume ratio in the film, which increases light absorption in solar cells.  35  (2) Conversely, increasing spacer length has shown some improvements in solar cell stability.  36  (3) Conjugated spacers or spacers with heteroatom substitutions can have a higher dielectric constant which is thought to facilitate charge transport across layers.  264  One short spacer is isobutylammonium (IBA), which is isomeric to BA, but with a more compact branched structure. We have recently characterized crystals using the IBA spacer along with the longer isoamylammonium spacer up to n = 4.  265  Solar cell efficiencies for each are in Table  9b  and c . Because of its more compact shape, IBA allows for a smaller interlayer spacing and increased inorganic volume ratio, and its bulky shape leads to larger Pb-I-Pb angles, lowering the bandgap, making it a good possibility for solar cells. In fact, solar cells made from hotcasting (IBA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 films gave a champion efficiency of 10.63% using a C 60 electron transport layer (ETL). In this study, the IBA-based device was compared to a device using the same architecture and method with the BA spacer which led to a lower efficiency of 5.38%.  266  However, because of the hysteresis from using the C 60 layer at the bottom of the device, these values are inflated. Despite this, the results imply that the use of a small spacer leads to increased device efficiency. Further analysis of n = 4 films shows that the phase distribution and charge transfer process is also affected when using IBA instead of BA as the spacer.  223  As mentioned above, multiple phases with different n values exist in these films to form energy funnels. This allows for charge transfer from the wide-bandgap low-n phases to the narrowbandgap high-n phases, as shown in Figure  17a . The TA data in Figure  17b  show that the high-n phases, indicated by the peak at ∼760 nm, are much more apparent in the IBA-based film than the BA-based film. Because the quantum confinement in high-n phases decreases, this would lead to lower exciton binding energy and higher carrier mobility with greater charge extraction in devices, possibly explaining the higher efficiencies for IBA-based devices. Furthermore, the authors showed that the rate of charge transfer was faster for the IBA-based films which had shorter interlayer spacings, implying that the shorter spacers allowed for more efficient charge transfer. One carbon shorter than BA, propylammonium (PA) has been used as a short spacer in solar cells (Table  9d ). We have published the structures for three 2D "step-like" structures with the general formula (PA) 2m+4 (MA) m-2 Pb 2m+1 I 7m+4 (m = 2, 3, 4) Table  9 . continued and two 2D RP structures with the general formula (PA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 3, 4).  35  Notably, RP "n = 1," "2," and "5" were unable to form with a traditional synthesis, though it has been suggested that certain conditions allow "n = 1" to form in films.  267  Hotcasting with solvent engineering has been primarily used when studying films with PA. Solvent engineering involves simply tuning the solvent mixture with two or more solvents, in this case DMF and DMSO. Using either DMF or DMF:DMSO mixed solvents has given highly oriented films for n = 3,  35  4,  268  and "5" 269 films, particularly with the solvent mixture. TA spectroscopy has also detected a high degree of 3D character in the PA films when compared to the BA equivalents, implying that shorter spacers favor phase distributions with high-n phases, as was the case with the IBA spacer above.  268  Despite this advantage, it is unclear if the parasitic "step-like" structures are present in these films or if  such structures are common among short spacers, which would be problematic for device performance. Devices have been fabricated using the same methods with the stoichiometry for n = 3,  35  4,  271  and "5."  269  The latter "n = 5" case gave a PCE of about 10%, nearly equivalent to the PCE achieved under the same conditions but with (BA) 2 (MA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 .  33, 272  Compared to (BA) 2 (MA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 made with the same method, the efficiencies are nearly equivalent, though the J SC is much higher for "(PA) 2 (MA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 " and the FF is higher for (BA) 2 (MA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 , suggesting that, while PA allows for more  current, possibly due to more light absorption, the interface is not as ideal as when using BA. While shorter spacers have potential for greater light absorption since inorganic component of the 2D perovskite is mainly responsible for light absorption, longer spacers may still be beneficial in terms of stability. Films made from the longer pentylammonium and hexylammonium cations have shown improved stability under heat, light, and ambient conditions compared to MAPbI 3 films.  36  Contact angle measurements with water droplets in Figure  17c  clearly show increased hydrophobicity of the films with increasing spacer length. The stability was tested on films with the stoichiometry for n = 4, and both films made from the hotcasting and onestep methods were analyzed. Several conditions were tested as well: 100 °C with 50% relative humidity, ambient light with 50% relative humidity, 1 sun illumination with 50% relative humidity, no light with 50% relative humidity, encapsulated at 100 °C, and encapsulated with 1 sun illumination. In general, the pentylammonium spacer provided the greatest stability for each deposition method and each condition tested. Except for films kept at 100 °C with 50% relative humidity, the stability trend for all conditions is pentylammonium &gt; butylammonium &gt; hexylammonium. For the films under heat and humidity, the trend is pentylammonium &gt; hexylammonium &gt; butylammonium. In either case, the stability is not directly correlated to the spacer length, meaning that the spacer length does not directly affect the stability. Other factors such as final film composition, orientation, and thickness must also be considered, highlighting the complexity of correlating spacer to stability. Films using tin as the metal have also been fabricated with the longer spacers octylammonium and dodecyl-ammonium, showing that shorter chains lead to perpendicular layer orientation for the tin system.  273  The other strategy used to increase efficiency involves alkylammonium spacers with higher dielectric constants (Table  9e -g). For example, conjugated spacers may lead to better charge transport from layer to layer. BA is a completely saturated carbon chain with only single C-C bonds, but replacing the C-C tail with a double or triple bond results in 3-buten-1-ammonium (BEA) or 3-butyn-1-ammonium (BYA), respectively. This gives a series of three cations with similar lengths and different degrees of conjugation, which were incorporated into films and devices via hotcasting using the stoichiometry for n = 4.  270  Shown in Figure  17d , BEA gave the highest efficiency of 16.1% primarily from increased J SC attributed both to the reduced tunneling barrier for conjugated spacers and the more crystalline films leading to lower leakage and fewer defects. Using the 2-(methylthio)ethylammonium spacer has also led to potential for cross-layer interactions via sulfur atoms in the interlayer spacer, as suggested by DFT calculations, yielding a remarkable efficiency of over 18% for a stoichiometrically "n = 5" film.  274  Further studies on single crystals of all these materials will help to understand these processes by isolating a single phase and ruling out other variables present only in films. 5.1.1.2. Aromatic Cations. Like the conjugated BEA and BYA spacers discussed above, aromatic spacers are commonly used to attempt to reduce dielectric confinement to improve efficiencies. Phenylethylammonium (PEA) was the first spacer used in a 2D halide perovskite solar cell  99  and LED.  275  Solar cells using this cation have benefitted from the addition of salts with the ammonium cation NH 4 + (Table  9h ). Using ammonium thiocyanate (NH 4 SCN) gives devices using the stoichiometry for "(PEA) 2 (MA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 " with efficiencies over 11%, though 2 mol equiv of NH 4 SCN are needed to achieve this efficiency.  246  By using a combination of NH 4 SCN and ammonium chloride (NH 4 Cl), an even higher efficiency of 14.1% is achieved with only 0.2 equiv of total ammonium additives using the same composition and device architecture.  276  LEDs have benefitted from the naturally formed multiple quantum well structure in both lead  224  and tin-based perovskites.  277  The thickest layer for any aromatic spacer characterized by SCXRD is n = 3.  99, 128  Thus, the chemical understanding of these spacers is lagging behind that of the alkylamines. Bulky spacers such as the recently reported 1-naphthalenem e t h y l a m m o n i u m ( N p M A ) a n d 9 -a n t h r a c e n emethylammonium (AnMA)  278  show potential for improved solar cell performance (Table  9 (j,k)).  279  The presence of low-n phases is strongly suggested in "n = 4" films using the NpMA spacer. HRTEM shows lines of atoms indicative of plates oriented perpendicularly to the substrate, and TA spectroscopy shows bleaches with the energy characteristic of low-n phases. Furthermore, XRD of n = 1 and n = 2 films shows low angle peaks with harmonicity. However, separate DFT studies have shown that, compared to those using phenylmethylammonium, n = 1 RP phases using 1-naphthalenemethylammonium have a higher formation energy, implying that the bulkier the spacer, the less stable the RP phases.  280  While the naphthalene spacer still appears to form well-defined quantum wells, the bulkier AnMA spacer shows greater 3D character via TA spectroscopy, and the n = 1 film does not clearly show harmonic peaks. Because the naphthalene spacer can more readily stabilize multiple quantum wells, it delivers a higher performance. Furthermore, bleach formation time of the 3D phase is more rapid when using the NpMA than it is for the AnMA spacer (6.56 ps vs 10.17 ps), further showing the advantage of the distinctly defined multiple quantum well structure when using NpMA. Additionally, the NpMA spacer has shown great use in LEDs with "n &lt; 3" films, which shown a quantum well structure despite the low n value.  281, 282  Characterization of larger n values for such bulky spacers will help to determine which spacers have the potential to stabilize 2D phases in the films and which do not. Dielectric confinement can be potentially further modulated by using spacers substituted with heteroatoms (Table  9 (l-n)); Figure  16 ). Devices made with the precursor stoichiometry for "n = 5" using 4-fluorophenylethylammonium (4FPEA) have shown improved efficiencies compared to using the unsubstituted PEA.  122, 283  In particular, a one-step method with an ammonium thiocyanate (NH 4 SCN) additive gave an impressive efficiency of 17.34%.  264  These devices seemed to benefit from a change in phase distribution. Looking at the TA data in Figure  18a , compared to PEA-based films, the 4FPEA-based films have stronger MAPbI 3 and n = 2 bleaches. The enhanced MAPbI 3 bleach is reminiscent of the films made with short spacers and could help charge transfer. Additionally, as shown in Figure  18b , DFT calculations suggest that the fluorinated spacers have substantially higher dipole moments which is backed up by Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) which shows an increase of surface potential from 91.28 mV for PEAbased films to 224.36 mV for 4FPEA-based films. This could allow for greater carrier mobility. In fact, the electron mobility remained unchanged, the hole mobility increased by an order of magnitude, giving credence to this hypothesis. Solid state mixtures using the spacers PEA and perfluorophenethylammonium (F5-PEA) have been incorporated into films using a one-step method with no additives and have shown to give the greatest efficiency and stability when a 1:1 ratio of these phase is used, as shown in Figure  18c .  124  The texture (defined as the degree to which the grains in the film are oriented in the same direction) lessens with increasing 4FPEA (i.e., the orientation of the grains goes from perpendicular to random) while the morphology becomes less favorable for increasing PEA, leading to an optimum film structure when a 1:1 ratio is used. Thus, using fluorine-substituted spacers affects phase distribution, dipole moment (and thus exciton binding energy and carrier mobility), chemical stability, orientation, and morphology, which demonstrates the complexity of the effects of changing the spacer. Other substituted spacers can also be considered such as methoxyphenyletheylammonium  283  (Table  9m ) or other halogenated spacers. Earlier, we discussed how the halogen atoms on the cation and the MX 6 inorganic framework can interact to change the unit cell displacement and cation configuration. However, as mentioned above, the spacers also play a key role in film-specific properties. For example, spacers using the larger bromine (4-bromophenylethylammonium, 4BrPEA) and chlorine (4-chlorophenylethylammonium, 4ClPEA) atoms instead of fluorine leads to differences in the orientation of the films, with the films using 4BrPEA and 4ClPEA giving some grains oriented parallel to the substrate.  284  This films also show lower electron mobility compared to those with 4FPEA, reducing device performance. Heteroatoms can also substitute for one of the carbon atoms in the conjugated ring, such as the case for the sulfurcontaining thiophenes (Table  9o -q). In the previous synthesis section, we discussed the ability of the thiophene spacers to form Type II quantum wells. Here, we discuss their effects on film composition and device performance. Thiophenemethylammonium (2TMA) has been used as a spacer, giving (2TMA) 2 (MA) 2 Pb 3 I 10 , which was solved crystallographically and incorporated into a solar cell.  128  This material was deposited using the antisolvent method, which leads to rapid crystallization. Remarkably, by adding additional MACl, the orientation of the layers is still highly perpendicular to the substrate despite the rapid crystallization during the antisolvent method. Understanding whether this effect is because of the extra Cl -, the crystallization rate, or the spacer itself would be very helpful to develop alternative methods for crystalline and oriented films. Either way, a PCE of 15.42% was achieved and remains one of the highest efficiencies for an RP n = 3 solar cell. Later, a "(2TMA) 2 (FA) 4 Pb 5 I 16 " solar cell using a 4-(trifluoromethyl)benzylammonium iodide additive in a isopropanol antisolvent yielded a remarkable efficiency over 1 9%.  2 8 5  Anot her thiophene spacer, thiopheneethylammonium  286  was also used to achieve a similar PCE with n = 3 stoichiometry using the hot-casting method with a carefully chosen solvent mixture of 4:1 DMF:toluene and an 8 vol% HI additive.  287  In this study, the phase compositions using different solvent mixtures were analyzed. While all conditions saw bleaches for the n = 2 and n = 3 phases present, the N,N-dimethylacetamide (DMAc):toluene solvent mixture (with and without HI) was the only one to show a bleach for MAPbI 3 and had more phases with n &gt; 3 present in the film when compared to films made with a DMAc:DMSO solvent mixture. Furthermore, the bleaching time constants when using DMAc:toluene were shorter than the other mixtures. Once again, the phase distribution plays a pivotal role in the charge carrier dynamics for the films, even when the same spacer is used. In this case, all films had low-n phases, but the film with faster charge transfer (and better solar cell efficiency) had both 2D and 3D character. Meanwhile, the DMAc:DMSO mixture here had mostly 2D character. Along with this, we discussed the 9-anthracenemethylammonium (AnMA) spacer above which gave films with mainly 3D character, resulting in slower charge transfer than films made with the 1-naphthalenemethylammonium (NpMA) spacer, which had both 2D and 3D phases.  279  Thus, this phase distribution appears to be a common denominator for high-performance devices. 5.1.1.3. Alternating Cations in the Interlayer Space Phases. Guanidinium (GA) has been the only cation studied in films composed of the ACI phase (Table  9r ). The first device using (GA)(MA) 3 Pb 3 I 10 gave an efficiency of 7.26% with the antisolvent method and the FTO/PEDOT:PSS/ (GA)(MA) 3 Pb 3 I 10 /PCBM/Al architecture.  90  However, by simply using a new architecture -FTO/c-TiO 2 /(GA)-(MA) 3 Pb 3 I 10 /Spiro-OMeTAD/Au-the efficiency nearly doubled, and the addition of an MACl additive allowed the efficiency to exceed 18% when accounting for hysteresis.  288  Other methods such as hotcasting and the one-step method have only seen efficiencies at about 13-14% for each.  289  Like other small spacers, GA can also stabilize other structures such as the ⟨110⟩-oriented (GA) 2 PbI 4 phase  132  which may affect the film formation mechanism. TA spectroscopy has also shown that multiple phases, likely n = 1, 2, and 3 and 3D phases are present in these films and act as energy funnels as in other 2D perovskite films.  289  5.1.2. 2D Phases with Diammonium Cations. 5.1.2.1. Alkyldiammonium Cations. Diammonium cations are attractive because they can coordinate to both layers, removing the van der Waals gap. By coordinating to both layers, these structures are more robust, potentially improving thermal stability.  39  An early report used several cations in devices using the n = 1 materials,  291  which was followed by incorporation of multilayered structures in films and devices. Multilayered structures are known only for the longer cations with at least four carbons.  39  While short cations such as propyldiammonium (PdA)  271, 292  have been used in films and have shown high efficiencies of over 14% in solar cell devices (Table  10a ), it is not clear if these are truly "2D films," as there is no proof that PdA can stabilize 2D iodide perovskites. If PdA cannot form such a structure, it may play a different role in the final film such as a passivator as interfaces. Only with full characterization can we understand this. Even so, the devices show very high efficiency and stability, with the hotcasted "(PdA)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 " device showing great stability in ambient conditions, heat, light, and humidity. The crystal structures for several alkyldiammonium structures were discussed in the synthesis part of this report. The n = 3 crystals were also made into films using a one-step method with an HI additive to test their stability in future device applications.  39  A different study also fabricated films using an "n = 5" stoichiometry with several of these spacers using a one-step method with an ionic liquid solvent.  293  Interestingly, the two methods and n values result in different textures for the films, which is quantified by the GIWAXS images in Figure  19 . For the n = 3 films, GIWAXS reveals that a greater degree of texture (i.e., more grains aligned in the same direction) is found when using longer cations. In fact, while the films from butyldiammonium (BdA) and hexyldiammonium (HdA) show almost no preferred orientation as indicated by the rings in the GIWAXS patterns, the films from octyldiammonium (OdA) and nonyldiammonium (NdA) are highly oriented with the layers perpendicular to the substrate as indicated by the sharp peaks. It should be mentioned that NdA-based films do have some grains orientated with the layers parallel to the substrate, but no rings are seen in the GIWAXS pattern. This indicates that the 2D layers in the grains are either oriented parallel or perpendicular to the substrate with none oriented at other diagonal angles to the substrate Contrarily, the "n = 5" films showed sharp Bragg peaks in the GIWAXS patterns for all alkydiammonium cations from three (PdA) to six (HdA) carbons in length when using a one-step method with an ionic liquid solvent. Additionally, the PdA-based film was thge most textured, while the HdA-based film was the least, indicating that these trends are dependent on the n value and deposition method. Additionally, TA spectroscopy of the "n = 5" films was also measured and revealed that the PdA and BdA films showed no presence on low-n phases while the pentyldiammonium (PedA) and HdA films did, indicating that longer chains lead to more low-n character in the films, which matches our earlier discussions comparing short monoammonium cations such as PA to longer cations such as BA. Alkyldiammonium-based films were also shown to have increased stability to light, heat, and humidity compared to MAPbI 3 . For the n = 3 films, the OdA-based film had the highest stability of all the alkyldiammonium-based films, with BdA and HdA having the poorest stability. Furthermore, the OdA-based film was even more stable in light than the BAbased film, both n = 3 stoichiometrically and prepared under the same conditions, showing the great stability of these materials. For the "n = 5" films, a similar trend was seen, the longest spacer (HdA) showing the greatest thermal stability. However, when incorporated into solar cells (Table  10b -d), the PedA spacer led to greater thermal stability, showing the complexity of stability in devices. The thermal stability for the BdA-based films has been further enhanced by using Cs + instead of MA as the A-site cations.  294  Of the "n = 5" films, the short BdA spacer gave the greatest efficiency of 16.38%, likely because of a complexity of factors such as perpendicular orientation, low trap state density, and less surface defects. We also note that the BdA spacer has been used to form lead-free (BdA)(FA) 2 Sn 3 I 10 which has been characterized crystallographically and been incorporated into devices to enhance both PCE and stability.  295  5.1.2.2. Cyclic Diammonium Cations. These cations are attractive for use in solar cells because some of them can form Dion-Jacobson 2D halide perovskites, and they can lead to very close terminal I-I bonds and relatively low bandgaps. Initial average efficiencies for devices based on (xAMP)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 (AMP = (aminomethyl)piperidinium, x = 3 or 4) were only 6.74% and 4.24% for x = 3 and 4, respectively (Table  10f ,g).  89  This was done using the antisolvent method with a small amount of HI added, which is shown to give more perpendicular orientation in films. As mentioned above, using a mixture of FA and MA as the A-site cation leads to lower bandgaps by increasing bond angle. Additionally, the trap density has decreased with the addition of the FA cation.  152  To further tune the properties of these materials, the conjugated spacers 3AMPY and 4AMPY can be studied, which benefit from both small spacer size and larger dielectric constant. Using the same methods and architecture as for 3AMP-and 4AMP-based devices, the efficiencies for (xAMPY)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 (AMP = (aminomethyl)pyridinium, x = 3 or 4) are 9.20% and 5.69%, respectively (Table  10h ,i). It is interesting to note that, regarding PCE, 3AMPY &gt; 3AMP &gt; 4AMPY &gt; 4AMP, indicating that substitution position, and thus spacer size, influences the device efficiency more than conjugation in this case. It seems likely that this trend is a result of better crystallinity and orientation for 3AMPY film, as well as different optical properties of the crystals, since the 3AMPY crystals show lower bandgaps and smaller interlayer distances than the 4AMPY ones. The use of 4AMP to form Dion-Jacobson phases, though without SCXRD characterization, has also seen success in improving tin-based device stability.  296, 297  Devices have also been made using other spacers whose final structures have yet to be characterized crystallographically (Table  10 (j,k)). The 4-(aminoethyl)pyridinium (4AEP) spacer is slightly longer than the 4AMPY spacer, but has given an efficiency of 11.68% for a device with "n = 5" when using a one-step method with NH 4 SCN as an additive, as has been done for other aromatic spacers.  298  It should be noted that the authors characterized this as though AEP was a monoammonium cation, leading to an excessive of (4AEP)I 2 in the precursor solution. This nice efficiency is attributed to the 4AEP spacer's proclivity to coordination with PbI 2 cations, evidenced by Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Another perovskite using the phenylenedimethanammonium (PDMA) spacer and FA as the A-site cation, "(PDMA)(FA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 ," gives an efficiency of 6.52% using a one-step method with no additives. These devices primarily suffer from a low V OC , which may be a result of poor film morphology seen by SEM.  299   &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">C60</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T19:08:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="120809" length="4"/>
        <text>C 60</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">phenethylammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T11:52:17Z</infon>
        <location offset="127574" length="19"/>
        <text>Phenylethylammonium</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4-bromophenylethylammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:16:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="132845" length="26"/>
        <text>4-bromophenylethylammonium</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4-bromophenylethylammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:16:01Z</infon>
        <location offset="132873" length="6"/>
        <text>4BrPEA</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">4-chlorophenylethylammonium</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:15:59Z</infon>
        <location offset="132895" length="27"/>
        <text>4-chlorophenylethylammonium</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>144558</offset>
      <text> Mixed Dimensionality and Composite Films While the 2D films benefit from additional stability and have seen efficiencies over 17%, they still lag behind the record 25.2% efficiency for 3D devices. Therefore, so-called "mixed dimensionality"  28  films have been fabricated which have largely 3D character but incorporate small quantities of spacers which stabilize lower-dimensionality structures. These films take advantage of the superior optical properties of the 3D structures to achieve high efficiency while also taking advantage of the improved stability of the lower-dimensional films. Most of the films use spacers which stabilize 2D structures such as BA or PEA, but an unrealistic stoichiometry with a very high n value such as n = 50. As mentioned before, the highest n value to be characterized using SCXRD has been n = 7, which was only formed by very precise stochiometric control with slow crystallization. Even using these scrupulous techniques, crystals of n = 9 were unable to be grown phase pure, though they still formed as plates which indicates some form of 2D character. However, this could mean that the crystals are mostly 3D with 2D phases grown in, that they are 2D with very high n values, or that they are composed of  very unlikely to form, but instead combinations of phases including the 3D phase, are likely to grow together. In fact, there have been no substantiated claims of phases where n &gt; 7 in films or in crystals. Thus, we emphasize that films made from a precursor stoichiometry with n &gt; 7 must be treated differently than either 2D or 3D films. In the case of these mixed dimensionality films, several scenarios are possible. For example, mixtures of 2D phases (n ≤ 7) and 3D phases may be present. If so, TA spectroscopy can be used to show which phases are present by matching absorption peaks in the film to those of pure crystals. However, the spacing cations can also move to grain boundaries or interfaces instead of forming 2D phases. Here, no 2D phases will be seen in the TA data, nor will the XRD peaks shift, as the present phase remains 3D. While it is still unclear what phases make up these films, we discuss what has been understood about the composition of these films so far, with a summary of different phase distributions in the films shown in Figure  20 , which will be discussed further in this section. For ease of understanding, we continue providing the so-called n values to give an intuitive estimate of the quantity of spacer in the film. Tables 11-14 list the spacers used in these mixed dimensionality films organized by dimensionality: 2D/3D with monoammonium spacers, 2D/ 3D with diammonium spacers, 1D/3D, and unknown dimensionality, respectively. 5.2.1. Mixed Phases with Monoammonium Cations. 5.2.1.1. Alkylammonium Cations. As with the 2D films, mixed dimensionality films can be made with alkylammonium spacers such as BA. An early report incorporates BA into a (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.91 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 film using hotcasting and an  HI/HBr additive, resulting in both improved efficiency and stability (Table  11a ).  300  In this report, instead of targeting a specific stoichiometry for some high n value, the authors substituted the A-site cations for an equal molar amount of BA to give films of "BA x (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 1-x Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 " (x = 0.05, 0.09). This results in approximate n values of 22.2 for x = 0.09 and 40 for x = 0.05, but the precursor solution has an excess of PbX 2 compared to these n values based on the stoichiometry used in the precursor solution. It is unclear what effect, if any, preparing a precursor in this way has on the film. Either way, the x = 0.09 film gives an impressive average efficiency of 15.5% ± 1.1% with 80% of the efficiency maintained at 1005 h in ambient conditions, an improvement over the 3D (Cs 0.17 FA 0.83 ) 0.91 Pb(I 0.6 Br 0.4 ) 3 device which had an average efficiency of 15.1% ± 1.0% and 80% efficiency at 693 h. Furthermore, reducing the BA content by setting x = 0.05 gives a film more compositionally like the 3D film, with an even higher efficiency of 18.1 ± 1.5% and a champion efficiency of 20.6%. 2D-XRD analysis shows that increasing the quantity of BA gives new peaks likely from 2D phases with an unknown n value. These peaks are highly oriented, as seen in 2D films. SEM analysis further shows plates clearly perpendicular to the substrate, a good indication that a mixture of 2D and 3D phases exist. Further analysis on the films shows that the PL is slightly blue-shifted for the x = 0.09 film when compared to the pure 3D film, suggesting some form of reduced dimensionality. The shorter propylammonium (PA) cation has also been used in mixed-dimensionality devices with the stoichiometry for "(PA) 2 (Cs 0.05 FA 0.79 MA 0.16 ) 40 Pb 41 (I 0.84 Br 0.16 ) 124 " ("n = 41") using the antisolvent method (Table  11b ).  305  In this case, XRD shows no low-angle peaks, but the (110) peak appears to shift to lower 2θ, indicative of unit cell expansion. The authors concluded that a new phase is present but did not determine the identity of this phase. This paper was published only days before a paper characterizing several phases using the PA cation,  35  which may be present in these films. Furthermore, while the presence of PA increased the values of the CBM and VBM, the bandgap showed negligible changes. The allylammonium (ALA) cation is the same length as the PA cation but is conjugated, with a double bond between the two terminal carbon atoms (Table  11c ). Films with the stoichiometry "(ALA) 2 (MA) 9 Pb 10 I 31 " ("n = 10") were fabricated using the antisolvent method and compared to films with the same stoichiometry using BA and PEA spacers. UV-vis spectroscopy showed sharp peaks corresponding to phases with n = 3-5 for all films, but the peaks were not nearly as sharp for the ALA-based films as for the BA-and PEA-based films. Furthermore, TA spectroscopy showed almost no signs of low-n phases for ALA-based films, but low-n phases were readily apparent when using BA and PEA. The differences in these multiple quantum well structures can be seen in Figure  20a . All these data suggest that the ALA spacer favors phases with high-n values, hindering the formation of low-n values in films, similar to the PA system which shows great 3D character in the EQE spectrum even for n = 3 films.  35  The ALA-based films also showed long diffusion lengths of 633 ± 14 nm for electrons and 507 ± 11 nm for holes. In comparison, electron diffusion lengths when using BA and PEA were 224 ± 2 nm and 442 ± 22 nm, respectively, and hole diffusion lengths were 76 ± 1 nm using BA and 266 ± 13 nm using PEA. This leads to improvements in solar cell performance, with ALA giving the highest PCE of 14.4% compared to PEA (12.1%) and BA (11.5%) using the same conditions. Adding Cs + and FA into the precursor solution allows for an even greater PCE of 16.5%. While it is unclear whether the conjugation or the small size of the ALA spacer plays a bigger role in the quantum well distribution, clearly the preference for high-n values is valuable for solar cell performance in this case. However, this seems contrary to the discussion of multiple quantum well distribution discussed for 9-anthracenemethylammonium (AnMA) which suffered from its lack of 2D character.  279  The difference may be that the ALA-based films consist of only 3D phases while the AnMA-based films were mostly 3D phases, though this is mere speculation and other factors such as orientation and crystallinity need to be considered as well. Clearly, the charge transfer mechanisms are very complex and must be better understood to know exactly what composition and where the phases should be located to yield the best device. Particularly, the ideal scenario for mixed dimensionality devices will need to be distinguished from that of the 2D devices. ALA has also been used for tin-based devices, with "n = 9" giving efficiencies up to 9.48%.  306  Another cation, cyclohexane methylammonium (CMA), has been incorporated into a mixed dimensionality film with the stoichiometry for "(CMA) 2 (MA) 8 Pb 9 I 28 " ("n = 9") to create a "reversed-graded" film (Table  11d ).  302  In this film, the low-n phases are located at the surface of the film and the high-n phases at the bottom by the substrate, the opposite of the other films we have described. While no crystallographic characterization has been done, strong evidence for 2D phases is provided by the XRD of a stoichiometric "n = 1" film which shows a set of peaks with equal 2θ spacing starting from a lowangle value, a common characteristic of 2D phases. Furthermore, the UV-vis and PL data show several highenergy peaks which suggests phases with different n values. The reverse-graded structure of this film is evidence by TA data taken from the front and the back of the film, shown in Figure  20a . When excited from the surface, the films exhibit bleaches corresponding to energies expected for n = 2, 3, and 4 along with a strong low-energy bleach associated with a high-n bleach. When excited from the back, two low-energy high-n bleaches dominated with little or no low-n-associated bleaches present, indicating that the back of the film has greater high-n character than the surface. This implies that the charges will transfer from the surface to the bottom of the film. This also has important implications for the stability of devices made from these films, as the more water-resistant 2D phase is contained at the surface of the film, which is most likely to react with humidity in the air. In fact, negligible PCE was lost even after 4600 h (70 days) in 40-70% relative humidity. 5.2.1.2. Aromatic Cations. Another early example of mixed dimensionality films used the PEA cation.  307  This and other aromatic cations used in these types of films are listed in Table  11e -h.  257, 308, 309  Films were made based on stoichiometries for 2D structures "(PEA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 with n ranging from 1 to 60. Films with n &lt; 10 were fabricated from a one-step deposition while films with n ≥ 10 were made using the antisolvent method, giving efficiencies from 9.22% for n = 6 to an impressive 18.40% for n = 60. These efficiencies are on par with that for BA without the need for secondary A-site cations. Furthermore, n = 60 devices retained 74% of their efficiency over 2 weeks in humidity compared to MAPbI 3 , which retained only 4%. When looking at the different n values studied here, it is apparent that there is a trade-off between efficiency (high n) and stability (low n). To study the composition of these films, the films were scraped off the substrate to collect a powder which was measured by XRD. Interestingly, low-angle peaks are seen from n = 1 to "n = 60." While the exact composition is unknown, clearly these phases are some reduced dimensional structures present in the film far from the n values based on the precursor solution. Furthermore, absorption spectra show increasing bumps for low-n films which correspond to low-n phases, as expected. Along with this, a low-energy tail corresponding the MAPbI 3 forms for the higher-n films, indicating the presence of 3D structure. Along with the lead iodide series, lead bromide perovskites hold potential to be used in solar cells, particularly for the top cell of a tandem cell because of their wide bandgaps. Three aromatic phenylalkylammonium spacers with various alkylammonium tail lengths were incorporated into nominally "n = 50" films: benzylammonium (BZA), phenylethylammonium (PEA) and phenylpropylammonium (PPA).  309  The mixed dimensionality films showed an enlarged unit cell via XRD, which the authors suggest is from the incorporation of the spacers. While the bandgaps of the films do not change, high-energy peaks in the absorption spectra were attributed to low-n phases. While this does suggest mixed dimensionality, the exact composition of the films remains unclear. That being said, solar cells made with these films show decent efficiencies of 9.5%, 8.6%, and 7.1% for BZA, PEA, and PPA, respectively. In fact, the BZAbased film has a higher efficiency than that of the 3D film (8.9%). All devices have very high V OC , with PEA giving a V OC of 1.45 V. Furthermore, the 2D/3D devices are more stable in air, retaining 80% PCE under 1 sun illumination, 90 °C, and 50% humidity compared to 3D devices which had lost nearly all efficiency over the same period in the same conditions. Tin-based devices have benefitted greatly by the incorporation of mixed-dimensional architectures (Table  11j ). One of the earliest reports uses phenylethylammonium (PEA) as the spacer in "(PEA) 2 (FA) 8 Sn 9 I 22 " mixed-dimensionality solar cell devices to achieve an efficiency of 5.94%.  310  Remarkably, very little loss of efficiency is seen in the devices after 100 h in the glovebox compared to the 3D devices which completely short in ∼70 h. This was further improved by Shao, et. al to give an efficiency over 9% for stoichiometrically "n = 25" devices also using the PEA spacer.  311  5.2.1.3. Other Cations. The heavily fluorinated cation 3-(nonafluoro-tert-butyloxy)propylammonium (A43) has been shown to form the RP structures (A43) 2 PbI 4 and (A43) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 , confirming that they can stabilize multilayered 2D structures which may be present in films (Table  11i ). This study analyzed both mixed dimensionality films and heterostructures with this cation, the latter of which will be discussed further below. In the mixed dimensionality films, no noticeable change in the XRD was noticed, though a slight peak around 550 nm was seen in the absorption, implying a 2D structure was present. By using a micro-PL setup to only analyze the very surface of the film, the same 2D phase was found, which did not appear when the bulk was measured. This implies that the 2D phase formed only at the surface and not through the entire film, possibly suggesting another reversegraded architecture. The same group later reported that other similar fluorinated cations could stabilize RP n = 1 structures and make water-repellent films, with longer alkyl chains and removal of the ester group showing the largest water droplet contact angle.  312  5.2.2. Mixed Phases with Diammonium Cations. 5.2.2.1. Cyclic Diammonium Cations. The use of diammo-  Recently, the use of 3-aminomethylpiperidinium (3AMP) incorporated into the 3D (MA) 0.5 (FA) 0.5 Pb 0.5 Sn 0.5 I 3 gave an impressive efficiency over 20% and a very low bandgap of 1.27 eV, which can be useful in tandem solar cells.  314  One study uses the previously mentioned phenylenedimethanammonium (PDMA) cation as a spacer in films with the stoichiometry for "n = 10."  315  A film made with the precursor stoichiometry for "n = 1" does show a low-dimensional phase with a high-energy PL emission, though no crystallographic characterization has been done to prove what phase this is.  316  Devices made with this cation showed a nice PCE of 15.6% and improved stability in light and humidity when compared to standard MAPbI 3based devices. 5.2.2.2. ⟨110⟩ Phases. Beyond the ⟨100⟩ phases commonly discussed, cations which stabilize the ⟨110⟩ phase can be used in mixed dimensionality films (Table  12f ). However, it is rare to stabilize multilayered ⟨110⟩ phases, with only one known example,  175  meaning that mixtures of these phases with a 3D phase should be treating differently. This is exemplified by a study of mixed dimensionality films using the cation (ethylenedioxy)bis(ethylammonium) (EDBE), known to stabilize a ⟨110⟩ phase.  82, 303  In this study, mixed dimensional films were made with the stoichiometry "(EDBEP-bI 4 ) x (MAPbI 3 ) 1-x " (x = 0.01, 0.03, and 0.05), where the x values correspond to "n = 90", "30", and "13," respectively. However, for all these films, the XRD shows Bragg peaks only for the (EDBE)PbI 4 and 3D phases, with no evidence for higher layer-numbers, as expected based on the challenges to make higher layer-numbers synthetically of the ⟨110⟩ phase family. The optical absorption spectra show only a single highenergy peak corresponding to (EDBE)PbI 4 , as opposed to the previous examples which showed multiple peaks for several n values. Further evidence is provided by TA spectroscopy, where only the 3D phases show bleaches in the spectra, ruling out the possibility of a multiple quantum well structure (Figure  20b ). These films gave champion efficiencies of 21.06% for x = 0.03 ("n = 30") with remarkable stability, retaining 90% of the efficiency after 1000 h in 65% humidity. 5.2.2.3. 1D Structures. Some cations do not stabilize 2D perovskite structures but instead stabilize 1D structures. One such example is with the dication benzyldiammonium (BDA) (Table  13a ). While this cation is 2+ with an aromatic ring similar to the 3AMPY and 4AMPY cations, it instead stabilizes the (BDA)PbI 4 structure consisting of 1D chains of lead iodide octahedra connected at the edges as discussed earlier in the crystal structure part.  304  This spacer was incorporated into films with the stoichiometry "(BDA)(MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 " ("n = 1-4"). We previously described materials with such low n values as 2D films, but here represents a new case to be considered. When attempting to synthesize crystals of "n = 1-4," only the 1D (BDA)PbI 4 •2H 2 O and 3D MAPbI 3 formed, suggesting that higher layer-numbers could not be stabilized. While no water was used in the film fabrication process, there was still evidence of a 1D phase in the film. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) of the films showed that the films were made of the 3D phase with the 1D phase incorporated in it, not necessarily with 2D phases, as shown in Figure  20c . Thus, the n values used in the paper were only nominal, and this is a 1D/3D mixed dimensionality film. Interestingly, the absorption spectra still show multiple peaks as expected from multiple n phases. In fact, it appears from the TEM that 2D sheets of MAPbI 3 do exist in the film. However, based on the aforementioned results, this should not be treated the same way as for traditional 2D perovskites. For 2D perovskites, the quantum confinement is caused by the spacing cations. Here, the 1D quantum wires themselves separate the 2D layers, creating quantum wells which are not based on an extended 2D perovskite structure. These films also result in nice efficiencies of over 14% and improved stability with encapsulation under humidity, illumination, and heating. Another reported 1D/3D mixed dimensional film incorporates the fluorinated 2,2,2-trifluoroethylammonium (FEA) spacer (Table  13b ).  317  In the case discussed above, the FEA spacers stabilizes a 1D face-sharing structure. In this case, the stoichiometry was much closer to that of MAPbI 3 , meaning the phases present are not obvious, as the XRD patterns show peaks associated with structures other than MAPbI 3 . Either way, significant disadvantageous morphological changes such as pin holes were seen with as low as 8% FEA incorporation. However, with only 3% incorporation, a PCE of 18% was achieved, an improvement over 15.7% for MAPbI 3 . Improvements in V OC , J SC , and FF all contribute to this. Furthermore, the device with 3% FEA maintained 92% PCE after 4 months in ambient humidity, which is about 50-80% throughout the year in Lausanne, Switzerland where the study was performed. 5.2.2.4. Incorporation into 3D Structures. Very short cations such as guanidinium (GA), ethylammonium (EA), and dimethylammonium (DMA) have been used in mixed dimensional films for solar cells as well (Table  14a-c ). While incorporating these spacers into perovskite devices has given outstanding efficiencies of 21.12%,  318  13.91%,  319  and 15.02%,  308  respectively, these spacers have potential to  incorporate as an A-site cation in 2D and 3D structures, as discussed earlier for the 2D (BA) 2 (A)Pb 2 I 7 or (BA) 2 (A) 2 Pb 3 I 10 crystals. It has also been suggested that each of these cations can be incorporated into a 3D structure as a solid solution with MA, FA, or Cs + as the primary A-site cation.  268, 320  So far, we have discussed GA as a spacer in ACI perovskites. However, there is substantial evidence that, when the concentration of GA is low enough, the ACI phases are not stabilized, but instead the GA incorporates into the 3D perovskite structure as an A-site cation.  321  In fact, GA has already been used as an A-site cation in a 2D structure (mentioned in the previous section).  1 6 3  In the (GA) x (MA) 1-x PbI 3 system, no low angle peaks, indicative of 2D phases, are seen up to x = 25%, and the (2 0 2) 3D   perovskite peak shifts to lower 2θ, indicative of the expected unit cell expansion by the large GA cation. Further studies of mechanically synthesized powders and films using both GA/ MA and GA/FA mixtures shows similar results and are backed by solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR), which shows that the GA cations rapidly rotate, as is common with the A-site cation.  322  Recently, single crystal structures of (GA) x (MA) 1-x PbI 3 have proven that GA can be incorporated into a structure with up to x = 5.6%.  323  Similar results are seen when attempting to incorporate DMA into MAPbBr 3 . 324 5.2.2.5. No Incorporation. While many ammonium cations can incorporate into the perovskite structure, it should be acknowledged than not all seem to do so (Table  14d ). A fluorinated cation, 2,2,3,3,3-pentafluoropropyl ammonium (5F-PA), has been shown to give increased device stability and carrier lifetime.  325  However, it does not show any low angle peaks in the XRD nor a shift or any high-energy peaks in the bandgap or PL. In fact, TA spectroscopy confirms that no high-energy peaks corresponding to a low-dimensional phase exist, suggesting that 5F-PA does not template low-dimensional structures but has other functions in the device, such as a grain boundary or surface passivator. Other cations are listed in Table 14(e,f) which have been used in solar cell devices but whose role is the film has not been conclusively determined. Tin-based devices have also benefitted from adding spacers that do not incorporate into the structure (Table  14 (g-j)). The complex aromatic spacers x-fluoro-phenylethylammonium (xFPEA; x = 2,3,4) have given efficiencies over 10% by improving the crystallinity, though no evidence that 2D structures form was seen, implying that the cation formed at the grain boundary instead.  326  Another highly conjugated cation, 3-phenyl-2-propen-1-ammonium (PPeA) has also given an impressive efficiency of 9.6% and 7.08% for a large-scale solar cell device.  327  Additionally, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) shows that, when compared to a film using PEA as an addition, PPeA leads to less formation of Sn 4+ , indicating a lower propensity of the film to oxidize. In fact, when stored in an N 2 environment, the PPeA-modified device retained 92% PCE after 60 days while the 3D device retains only 12%. Additionally, the PPeA-modified device maintained 60% PCE after 10 h in 60% relative humidity and 60% PCE after 1000 h at 100 °C, compared to the 3D device which retains 0% and 20% PCE for each condition, respectively. Even more impressively, the PPeA-modified device shows selfhealing behavior after exposure to heat or light. Once back under N 2 atmosphere with no heat, the devices regained a substantial percent of the relative PCE. This effect was seen with PEA-and BA-modified films as well, but to a lesser extent. The 3D films did not show this effect, suggesting that bulkyamine modification is the key to the self-healing behavior in these tin-based devices.    &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Stability test embeded here</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T19:13:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="155776" length="2792"/>
        <text>Along with the lead iodide series, lead bromide perovskites hold potential to be used in solar cells, particularly for the top cell of a tandem cell because of their wide bandgaps. Three aromatic phenylalkylammonium spacers with various alkylammonium tail lengths were incorporated into nominally "n = 50" films: benzylammonium (BZA), phenylethylammonium (PEA) and phenylpropylammonium (PPA).  309  The mixed dimensionality films showed an enlarged unit cell via XRD, which the authors suggest is from the incorporation of the spacers. While the bandgaps of the films do not change, high-energy peaks in the absorption spectra were attributed to low-n phases. While this does suggest mixed dimensionality, the exact composition of the films remains unclear. That being said, solar cells made with these films show decent efficiencies of 9.5%, 8.6%, and 7.1% for BZA, PEA, and PPA, respectively. In fact, the BZAbased film has a higher efficiency than that of the 3D film (8.9%). All devices have very high V OC , with PEA giving a V OC of 1.45 V. Furthermore, the 2D/3D devices are more stable in air, retaining 80% PCE under 1 sun illumination, 90 °C, and 50% humidity compared to 3D devices which had lost nearly all efficiency over the same period in the same conditions. Tin-based devices have benefitted greatly by the incorporation of mixed-dimensional architectures (Table  11j ). One of the earliest reports uses phenylethylammonium (PEA) as the spacer in "(PEA) 2 (FA) 8 Sn 9 I 22 " mixed-dimensionality solar cell devices to achieve an efficiency of 5.94%.  310  Remarkably, very little loss of efficiency is seen in the devices after 100 h in the glovebox compared to the 3D devices which completely short in ∼70 h. This was further improved by Shao, et. al to give an efficiency over 9% for stoichiometrically "n = 25" devices also using the PEA spacer.  311  5.2.1.3. Other Cations. The heavily fluorinated cation 3-(nonafluoro-tert-butyloxy)propylammonium (A43) has been shown to form the RP structures (A43) 2 PbI 4 and (A43) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 , confirming that they can stabilize multilayered 2D structures which may be present in films (Table  11i ). This study analyzed both mixed dimensionality films and heterostructures with this cation, the latter of which will be discussed further below. In the mixed dimensionality films, no noticeable change in the XRD was noticed, though a slight peak around 550 nm was seen in the absorption, implying a 2D structure was present. By using a micro-PL setup to only analyze the very surface of the film, the same 2D phase was found, which did not appear when the bulk was measured. This implies that the 2D phase formed only at the surface and not through the entire film, possibly suggesting another reversegraded architecture. The sa</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">passivating_molecule</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">(ethylenedioxy)bis(ethylammonium)</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T19:12:27Z</infon>
        <location offset="160703" length="11"/>
        <text>(EDBE)PbI 4</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T05:16:22Z</infon>
        <location offset="161097" length="3"/>
        <text>90%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">1000</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T11:44:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="161125" length="6"/>
        <text>1000 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">65</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-09T11:44:44Z</infon>
        <location offset="161135" length="3"/>
        <text>65%</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T01:33:35Z</infon>
        <node refid="10" role=""/>
        <node refid="11" role=""/>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>168308</offset>
      <text> Heterostructures Another way to utilize both the high efficiency advantages of 3D films and the long stability of low-dimensional films is to create a heterostructure architecture, in which a thin layer of low-dimensional perovskite sits on the surface of a 3D film. This can be done by a very simple process. First, a 3D film is deposited with a predetermined method and composition, generally using an excess of lead halide. Then, an ammonium (or sulfonium) halide salt is dissolved in an antisolvent (generally isopropanol, IPA) and deposited on the 3D film with the one-step method followed by annealing. This second step forms the low-dimensional film in situ by reacting with the lead-halide-rich 3D film underneath, effectively removing the excess lead halide.  328  Alternatively, the film can be dipped in the same antisolvent mixture to form the capping layer.  329  Thus, the bulk of the film has the same properties as a 3D film while the surface is capped with a layer of moisture-repellant low-dimensional perovskite, improving efficiency while keeping stability. Tables 15-17 list spacers used in heterostructure films based on dimensionality, as was done for mixed dimensionality devices, specifically: 2D/3D, 1D/3D, and unknown dimensionality. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>169571</offset>
      <text> 2D Structures. The first study of a mixed phase perovskite heterostructure architecture used BAI and PEAI to form 2D perovskites on top of MAPbI 3 (Table  15a ).  330  In this study, no excess PbX 2 was used. Instead, the composition of the antisolvent mixture had both MAI and either BAI or PEAI. For the BAI-treated film, this led to XRD peaks corresponding to (BA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 on the surface. GIWAXS analysis showed that this phase oriented parallel to the substrate, potentially hindering charge transport. Compared to the 3D control device, the J SC of the BAI-modified device did decrease from 19.82 mA/cm 2 to 16.56 mA/cm 2 . However, an increase of the V OC from 0.99 to 1.08 V was also seen, which was attributed to reduced charge recombination. These trends were also consistent for the PEAI-modified film, but the FF was also increased from 70% for the 3D device to 73% for the PEAImodified device, leading to an increase in PCE from 13.61% to 14.94%. The effects of the aromatic PEA spacer will be discussed further below in the aromatics section. 5.3.1.1. Alkylammonium Cations. Another of the first spacers to be used in a heterostructure film was the small cyclopropylammonium (CA) cation (Table  15b ).  328  In this study, CA in IPA was deposited onto a "MAPbI x Cl 3-x " film where the concentration of CA in the IPA was varied from 5 mg/mL to 30 mg/mL. The overall properties of the film remained the same, though for the 20 and 30 mg/mL samples, a small peak corresponding to the previously characterized 79 n = 1 RP phase (CA) 2 PbI 4 was seen. For the other phases, the amount formed was too small to be seen using their diffractometer. Devices made with the concentration at 5 or 10 mg/mL showed little difference compared to the 3D control device, giving efficiencies around 13%. This indicates that the 2D capping layer has little effects on the device properties when using the CA cation. However, with increasing CA concentration, the J sc and FF decrease, particularly for the former, as the 2D capping layer hinders the charge transfer at the interface. Stability was improved, with the 10 mg/mL device maintaining 54% of its PCE after 220 h in 63% humidity, while the control device completely shorted before 60 h. With a wide variety of spacers to choose from, one simple question is: What effect, if any, does the spacer length have on device performance of a heterostructure film? Furthermore, will too long of a spacer have a deleterious effect on charge extraction by functioning as a barrier at the surface of the film? Three straight-chain alkyammonium spacers -BA (four carbons long), octylammonium (OA, eight carbons long), and dodecylammonium (DA, 12 carbons long)were chosen to investigate this effect by depositing the alkylammonium iodide on the surface of a (MA) 0.05 (FA) 0.95 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 film (Table  15c ).  331  Each of these spacers has been shown to form RP n = 1 phases.  [70] [71] [72]  The presence of low-n phases can be seen by both a small shoulder at higher energy (560 nm) in the absorption spectra corresponding to some low-n structure such as n = 2 as well as low-q diffraction spots in GIWAXS patterns, which shows low-n structures oriented parallel to the substrate. Both features are strongest for the longest spacer DA. These films also benefited from surface passivation, clear from TRPL which shown increased carrier lifetimes for the treated films, especially OAI and DAI. Furthermore, for HTL-free devices, the V OC is highly dependent on the spacer used. Without any spacer, the V OC is low at about 0.5 V, but adding BAI, OAI, and DAI raise it to about 0.7, 0.85, and 0.9 V, respectively, showing a clear trend for increasing V OC with increased spacer length (Figure  21a ), indicating that surface passivation is improved with longer spacers. Notably, the J SC is not strongly affected, indicating that the 2D passivating layer does not hinder charge transfer even with the very long DA cations. Furthermore, when an HTL layer is employed in the device architectures (Figure  21b ), the V OC is higher for all the devices, but the same trend is seen with the DA cations leading to the highest V OC of 1.13 V follow by OAI (1.12 V), BAI (1.11 V) and no spacer (1.09 V). In this case, J SC and FF are not affected significantly, leading to devices with similar efficiencies, though OAI has the highest efficiency. However, the stabilities for the devices vary greatly. After 100 h in 85% relative humidity, the DAI-treated film retained 90% PCE with the overall stability trend DAI &gt; OAI &gt; BAI &gt; 3D, with the nontreated 3D film maintain only 60% PCE. The best heat stability was also when DA was used, with 80% of the PCE maintained at 65 °C after 100 h, as shown in Figure  21c . The general trend for heat stability was DAI &gt; OAI &gt; BAI = 3D, with the BAI-treated and nontreated 3D films only maintaining 40% of the starting PCE. 5.3.1.2. Aromatic Cations. Heterostructures using the PEA cation have been used to improve efficiencies and stabilities of lead-based and tin based devices,  332  similar to the alkylammonium spacers discussed above.  330, 333  As previously mentioned in the first study of heterostructure devices, the PEA spacer was shown to improve the PCE by increasing V OC and FF.  330  Another study elaborates on this phenomenon.  333  XRD and UV-vis spectroscopy confirm formation of 2D (PEA) 2 PbI 4 on a Cs 0.05 (MA) 0.16 (FA) 0.79 Pb(I 0.83 Br 0.17 ) 3 film (Table  15d ). To evaluate the effects of the capping layer on the electronic structure of the film, Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) was used to assess the work function of the films by detecting the surface potential difference. Maps of the surface potential distribution were made for both the control 3D film and the heterostructure film. For the 3D film, a lower average potential was measured when compared to the heterostructure film, corresponding to a deeper Fermi level. Furthermore, there were much greater variations in the potential distribution for the 3D film, indicating that the 2D capping layer effectively lowered the potential of the film and made it more homogeneous. This has important implications for devices because the V OC is dependent on the Fermi levels of the different layers. In fact, this lowering of the surface potential for the heterostructure film led to a better alignment with the HTL (Spiro-OMeTAD), increasing the V OC from 1.05 to 1.11 V. Furthermore, devices benefitted from an increased carrier lifetime from lower recombination rates, also improving V OC . Additionally, if the capping layer was not too thick, the current was still able to be extracted, evidenced by the unaffected J SC . Finally, the stability of these devices was also improved. After 1000 h in 60% relative humidity, devices retained 90% of the PCE. Furthermore, heating the devices at 60 °C for 100 h showed improved thermal stability of the heterostructure device, with 75% of the PCE retained. While the effects of efficiency are like that of the heterostructure devices using alkylammonium spacers, the stability using PEA as a spacer does seem to be greater. Several other aromatic spacers derived from phenylalkylammonium cations have been used to form capping layers as well. These include 4-tert-butyl-benzylammonium (tBBA), 334 phenylformamidinium (PFA),  335  phenyltrimethylammonium (PTA), 5F-PEA,  336  and 4-vinylbenzylammonium (VBA) (Table  15e -i).  337  The tBBA spacer was shown to give no low-angle peaks by XRD though XPS confirmed presence of extra carbon molecules on the surface of the film, indicative of the intercalation of tBBA on the surface.  334  The authors suggest that the material formed on the surface was amorphous, leading to the lack of low-angle peaks. Like PEA, addition of tBBA leads to better carrier extraction at the surface of the film, fewer surface defects, and higher stability when compared to the 3D control film, though tBBA has an even greater effect than PEA. This leads to highly efficient devices with a PCE of 23.4%, higher than that of the 3D device (20.1%) and of the PEA-modified device (22.7%). The stability also is greatly enhanced, with over 90% PCE maintained after 1300 h in ∼60% relative humidity, compared to 86% maintained PCE for the PEA-modified device with the same film composition in the same conditions. The previously mentioned F5-PEA spacer leads to greatly increased hydrophobicity of the film.  336  In fact, contact angle measurements with water droplets loading for 3 s increase from 38.4°for the 3D film to 95.8°for the F5-PEA-modified film. This is reflected in device stability measurements under very high relative humidity (&gt;90%). The F5-PEA-modified film retains over 60% PCE after 70 h while the PEA-modified film retains less than 20%. As has been reported earlier, thiophene-derived spacers have led to highly efficient solar cells using the pure 2D and mixed dimensionality architectures.  128  Additionally, a series of these spacers was also employed in heterostructure devices, including the 2-thiophenemethylammonium (2TMA) spacer discussed along with 3-thiophenemethylammonium (3TMA) and 2-thiopheneethylammonium (2TEA) (Table  15j ).  338  Interestingly, the temporal stability of these devices was greatly dependent on the spacer. As shown in Figure  22b , for devices using 2TMA and 3TMA, there was substantial increase in device stability under illumination in an inert atmosphere when compared to the 3D control device. However, the device modified with 2TEA showed nearly 90% PCE was maintained after 1000 h. Even more remarkable, the PCE did not simply drop over time but began to increase over the first 400 h before slowly dropping again. To understand how this was happening, PL spectra were taken of the surface of the films over time in light to understand how the 2D/3D interface evolved (Figure  22a ). For the films with 2TMA and 3-TMA, the high-energy emissions corresponding to low-n phases slowly decreased in intensity while low-energy emissions associated with 3D or 3Dlike phases slowly increased. Meanwhile, the films with 2-TEA showed only the high-energy peaks, with only a small peak with an emission similar to that of a RP n = 2 phase growing in. The schematic in Figure  22c  illustrates the mechanism that leads to this. For 2TMA and 3TMA, the interface reacts over time to form less-stable high-n phases which can then degrade, but the 2TEA spacer retains its structure. While it is not clear why some cations lead to more robust low-n phases, this is an important step to understanding the correlation between spacer and device stability for heterostructure films. 5.3.1.3. Other Cations. As mentioned above in the mixed dimensionality section, the heavily fluorinated 3-(nonafluorotert-butyloxy)propylammonium (A43) spacer (Table  11i ) stabilizes RP n = 1 and n = 2 structures.  313  This study uses this spacer for both mixed dimensionality devices, discussed earlier, as well as heterostructure devices (Table  15k ). Treating a 3D Cs 0.1 (MA) 0.13 (FA) 0.74 PbI 2.48 Br 0.39 film with the A43 iodide salt shows new peaks in the XRD corresponding to the (A43) 2 PbI 4 phase, confirming their presence in heterostructure films. Two PL peaks, possibly corresponding to n = 1 and n = 2 phases, are seen as well which were not visible for the mixed dimensionality film. Notably, because the same cation was used for both mixed dimensionality and heterostructure films, it is interesting to note that the photovoltaic performance of each was similar for V OC , J SC , FF, and PCE. Likewise, the waterrepelling capabilities were both drastically improved, though the heterostructure film had a greater water drop contact angle of 98.4°compared to 83.8°for the mixed dimensionality film. 5.3.2. 1D Structures. Beyond 2D/3D heterojunctions, 1D/3D heterojunctions can also be formed (Table  16 ). Using the small thiazolium (TA) cation, a 1D structure with facesharing octahedra can be formed (Figure  23a ).  339  This spacer was then used to modify a 3D (MA) 0.9 (FA) 0.1 PbI 3 film to form the 1D structure on the surface. This is confirmed by XRD which shows the presence of the low-angle peak corresponding to the pattern for the crystallographically confirmed 1D structure. Despite its very large bandgap, the 1D structure shows no effects on the optical properties of the film. Like the 2D/3D heterostructures above, this structure shows increased carrier lifetime, improved V OC , and enhanced device stability. In fact, these devices maintained 84% PCE after 500 h at 70 °C and 70% PCE after 500 h with 70% relative humidity, shown in Figure  23b . Another recently reported 1D/3D heterostructure uses the nonammonium spacer trimethylsulfonium, denoted as (CH 3 ) 3 S + .  340  This spacer forms a 1D structure also with facesharing octahedra, which can be employed as a capping layer on a 3D film to yield increased film stability. 5.3.3. No Incorporation. As previously mentioned, some bulky spacers may not be able to easily stabilize RP phases. (Table  17 ) The 1-naphthalenemethylammonium (NpMA) spacer has been shown to barely react with a 3D film and mainly leave a thin layer of NpMAI on the surface.  280  The previously mentioned fluorine-substituted alkylammonium cation 2,2,3,3,3-pentafluoropropylammonium (5F-PA) has also been implemented in these types of devices, with no evidence of RP phases.  341  The authors report that even when casting a 1 M solution of the spacer in IPA on top of 3D films, no low-angle peaks are seen nor are there any peaks in the UV-vis spectra to suggest that low-dimensional phases are  present. Thus, it is likely that this cation functions as a surface passivator, possible at the grain boundaries, instead of forming low-dimensional structures. This is in agreement with the previously mentioned study,  325  which showed that the 5F-PA cation does not form low-dimensional structures in mixed dimensionality films. Either way, similar benefits to the heterostructure devices such as increased PL lifetime and enhance moisture stability, are seen, implying that these benefits are not dependent on the presence of low-dimensional structures. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>183792</offset>
      <text> CONCLUDING REMARKS AND FURTHER DIRECTIONS Studies on 2D halide perovskites in the past few years have led to a remarkable degree of understanding of the excellent properties and potential applications of these materials. Because of a seemingly endless plethora of spacers to choose from, being able to choose the correct spacer for the desired application will further propel this field. While many spacers have already been explored, the library of the known structures needs to be expanded to achieve a full understanding of 2D halide perovskites from structure-property relationships to stability and performance in devices.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>184423</offset>
      <text> Choice of Spacer Cations Rationally choosing new spacer cations which have the right characteristics to stabilize 2D compounds is the key to successful synthesis of new structures. The structural design rules we have outlined can be used to target spacers that will likely stabilize 2D perovskites, where factors such as the charge, shape, size, and heteroatoms need to be considered. The amino head should be able to anchor in the inorganic layer pocket, while the organic tail cannot be too bulky or too small. Heteroatoms on the spacer cations such as O, F, Cl, Br can influence the formation of hydrogen bonding thus the stacking or even structure type (e.g., ⟨100⟩ vs ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites). More complicated cations, especially those with heavily conjugated rings, may interact electronically with the inorganic layers to yield new properties. This allows for a large diversity of structures which have tunable dimensionalities and electronic structures. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>185402</offset>
      <text> Structure-Property Relationships When new spacer cations are incorporated into perovskites, the resultant structures need to be characterized by single-crystal X-ray diffraction even if they are 2D perovskites similar to already known structures. Because of the unusual softness and flexibility of these frameworks, even subtle distortions from one structure to the next could be behind the observed differences in physical properties. We now know that the M-X-M bond angle is a major determinant in the electronic structure with angles close to 180°giving narrower bandgaps more ideal for solar cell applications.  62, 102, 342  Besides, the interlayer distance and metal-halide (M-X) bond length can also influence the bandgap. Other factors such the spacer length, which may affect light harvesting  35  and device efficiency  36  have also been shown to be very important. Additionally, having crystallographic evidence of multilayered structures is critical to discern what 2D phases can exist in the final film. On the one hand, only knowing that the n = 1 compound can be stabilized is not proof that other homologous phases with higher layer-numbers may exist; on the other hand, the absence of 2D n = 1 phase does not necessarily mean the multilayer phases cannot exist, like in the case of propylammonium cation. Since the resultant film usually has mixture of different phases, to compare the optical properties of those phases with the properties of single crystals, each phase should be made phase pure and fully characterized structurally and optically. Though, with very high n values, this becomes more challenging. That being said, structures up to n = 7 have been verified with SCXRD, and they may be present in films,  34, 151  though this has not been confirmed. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>187188</offset>
      <text> Film and Device Fabrications With this chemical understanding, the focus can then be turned to depositing films and optoelectronic devices. Even then, however, the effects of the spacer on the film properties are complex and must be studied in depth to gain a fundamental understanding of the effects of the spacers on the film performance and in the final device. Because the crystallization process during film deposition is relatively fast compared to crystallization from a synthesis solution, it cannot be assumed that the same kinetics will apply to both systems. While kinetics and thermodynamic processes often align, if there are competing processes, the kinetic processes could prevail in the fast crystallization during spin coating. For other film deposition methods, thermodynamic processes may prevail instead. This casts doubt on the composition of the films. More importantly, many powders and crystals are made from acid solutions, not the organic solvents generally used for films which may complicate the crystallization. Because the mechanisms are different, the resulting compositions are unlikely to be the same for films and powders. Therefore, the effects of spacer selection on film composition are difficult to control or predict, especially considering that films are highly affected by processing conditions. Thus, we can expect that each film architecture (2D, mixed dimensionality, and heterostructures) will be affected by spacers differently. Looking at factors such as stability, crystallinity, morphology, orientation, composition, and the interaction between phases in the film helps to discern the effects of the spacer. For example, systematically studying alkyldiammonium spacers revealed opposite trends when using an ionic solvent with onestep spin coating  293  versus an organic solvent with hotcasting.  39  Nevertheless, we expect the proper conditions and processes can be found for the deposition of films with targeted single phase compositions for many organic spacers. Recently, researchers have reported the phase-pure films of (BA) 2 (MA) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 (n = 1-5) using molten salt butylamine acetate instead of butylamine iodide in the precursor.  343  It will be interesting to see if this strategy works for other spacers as well. On the other hand, it does not always mean that the presence of mixed phases in the films is undesirable or detrimental to device performance. One of the most important effects seen in recent years is the spacer's effect on composition of the mixed-phase films, allowing energy funnels from low-n to high-n phases in high performing devices.  224  With greater mixtures of 2D and 3D character, charge transfer rates from phase to phase increase, and efficiencies can improve.  223  Knowing the right combination of phases and how to control the phase distribution and understanding the charge transfer processes are keys to increasing device efficiency. Looking into the f uture, some key challenges need to be addressed to take us to the next level of the field: rational design of perovskite structures for desired applications, not only for solar cells but also all kinds of optoelectronic devices, especially those that are hard to achieved in 3D perovskites, such as the all-perovskite heterostructures.  344   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>190492</offset>
      <text> Using Theory to Help Develop New 2D Perovskite Structures When choosing a new spacer, theory can also help pick the spacer by modeling the factors such as charge, shape and size of the cations. Machine learning has been used to find new 3D halide perovskites,  345  for 2D perovskites, it is more complicated because of the structural diversity and many factors that need to be considered. A recent paper builds a database of 2D halide perovskites with 180 different cations and 515 compounds. Machine learning is used to extract the relationships between the structures and bandgaps.  346  Since this review cannot cover all of those compounds, it will be useful to check the database for more information on reported 2D perovskites. Another paper shows automated synthesis using inverse temperature crystallization can be used to rapidly test many different cations with n = 1 to improve machine learning techniques,  347  though this technology for 2D perovskites is still in its infancy. Therefore, the structural design rules still need to be considered to narrow down the number of cations that need to be modeled instead of picking random cations. After the cations are chosen, proper synthesis conditions need to be found to achieve the targeted phases using the theory-selected cations. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>191790</offset>
      <text> Synthesis of Pure Single Crystals From synthesis and structural characterization aspects, synthesis methods need to be improved to obtain pure phases of 2D perovskites, especially for the multilayer structures. So far, the most effective way to synthesize multilayer 2D perovskite is using a solution method with hydrohalic acid. Other solution methods using organic solvents and antisolvents have lagged and need to be further optimized to give crystals of multilayer 2D n &gt; 1 perovskites. Further development and understanding of these synthetic methods will help expand the library of spacer cations that can be incorporated into structures and devices. 6.6. Exploring the Layer-Number Limit 2D perovskites with very high layer thickness n need to be explored to gain insights on what phases, mixed or pure, can be stabilized when the thermodynamic limits of layer thickness are reached or passed. This will help to bridge the gap between pure 2D and 3D perovskites. So far, the highest layer-number that has been crystallographically characterized is n = 7. What structures are stabilized beyond that layer-number is unknown. When n &gt; 7, crystallography becomes insufficient to fully characterize these phases. This is because the unit cell dimensions become very large and intergrowth of different phases reduces the crystallinity. There is tremendous imbalance in electron density between the very heavy atom in the inorganic slabs and the very light atoms in the organic spacers causing weak Bragg scattering of the long-range order in the stacking direction. Other microscopic and spectroscopic techniques are needed to supplement or possibly replace crystallographic means to characterize these phases. For example, high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) can be used to take images at the molecular level. Spectroscopic techniques can be used to find emission and absorption peaks between those of n = 7 and 3D peaks. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>193737</offset>
      <text> Characterizing the Photophysical Properties As we gain more knowledge on the chemistry and precise structures of 2D perovskites, it aids understanding of their physical properties using different spectroscopic techniques.  348  So far, the vast majority of the spectroscopic studies are on well-explored 3D perovskites. There are many interesting phenomena such as self-trapped excitons, charge and energy transfer in different layer-numbers, exciton-exciton annihilation, etc. that need to be further explored in 2D perovskites. Furthermore, even though the complex makeup of the films has made spectroscopic characterization a challenge, significant progress in the charge transfer mechanisms and their effects on device performance has been made. The multiple quantum well structure has been shown to allow for efficient charge transfer from low-n phases to high-n phases, allowing for improved efficiencies in LEDs and solar cells. While it has been established that the presence of 2D and 3D phases together is advantageous for charge transfer, more studies are needed to understand the optimal composition in films for charge transfer. Is it best to have phases where n is at least 3 or 4 or are the n = 1 and 2 phases also necessary? Does the location of the phases within the film matter? What are the effects of the spacer on charge transfer between phases with different n values? We expect that addressing these questions will expedite film optimization and device performance. In particular, there is a dearth of charge transfer studies in the recently popularized heterostructure films which have shown great promise in terms of efficiency and stability. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>195407</offset>
      <text> Understanding the Structural Role of the Organic Cation and the Film Formation Mechanism For film and device fabrication, more emphasis should be put on the structural effects of new spacers beyond the improvement of device performance. They can serve as spacers for 2D perovskites (2D films), ligands on the grain boundaries (mixed dimensionality films), or capping ligands on the surface (heterostructure films). So far, many studies on film and device fabrication focus on a new specific spacer and present how it improves device efficiency but there is a lack of understanding of why a spacer changes properties such as film texture and phase distribution. Several studies of the film formation mechanism have recently come to light through the use of techniques such as in situ GIWAXS or PL during spincoating and annealing. These techniques can help to understand how the spacers affect the final film and they should be applied systematically to multiple materials and methods. It is imperative to understand which parts of the mechanisms that have been uncovered are generalizable and which are spacer-specific. From a mechanistic standpoint it is also important to understand the intermediate phases and how they may influence the film formation process. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>196673</offset>
      <text> Improving the Device Stability Besides device efficiencies, improving the stability is also an essential step toward the commercialization of the materials. Understanding the degradation mechanism is important to improve the stability. The use of a standard stability test protocols as the recently suggested  215  is needed to compare the results from different laboratories. It has become very clear that the interfaces are key to the stability, and understanding how the spacer affects these interfaces is also important. For the heterostructure perovskite film architectures, this is especially important, as the lower-dimensional phases only exist at the interfaces. Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Structures for ⟨100⟩-oriented 2D perovskites. (a) Ruddlesden-Popper phase with staggered layer stacking. (b) Dion-Jacobson phase with eclipsed layer stacking. (c) Alternating cations in the interlayer phase with staggered layer stacking along the b-and eclipsed along the a-axis. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>197654</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (a) Crystal structure of (PEA) 2 PbI 4 . (b) Definition of penetration depth of the ammonium group. (c) Summary of M-X-M bond angle dependence on the organic cation penetration depth. (d) Energy levels of typical n = 1 perovskites (gray) ((BA) 2 PbI 4 ) as compared to the energy levels of the conjugated organic ammonium iodide salts. (e) Out-of-plane electrical conductivity for different n = 1 perovskites. Panel c reprinted with permission from ref 73. Copyright 2017 American Chemical Society. Panels d and e reprinted with permission from ref 50. Copyright 2018 American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>198274</offset>
      <text> untilted octahedra. However, when more than one fluorine atoms are substituted, as in F 2 CHCH 2 F no longer exists. 60  Instead the amino head penetrates inside the inorganic pocket (positive penetration depth) and has a stronger interaction with the iodine atoms of the octahedra, thus the Pb-I-Pb angles are much smaller than those for F(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 + . So, (FCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 )PbBr 4 shows the smallest bandgap among these three compounds. When more F atoms are substituted the interlayer distance also increases from (FCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 )PbBr 4 to (F 2 CHCH 2 NH 3 )PbBr 4 and (F 3 CCH 2 NH 3 )PbBr 4 because of the different cation conformations and increasing steric hindrance. Besides the aliphatic cations, heteroatoms in aromatic rings can also change the spacer configuration and even the layer stacking motif. In 2001, Mitzi et al. reported the (x-FPEA) 2 SnI 4 (FPEA = fluorophenylethylammonium, x = 2, 3, 4) series with fluorine substitution in the meta, ortho, and para positions (Table 4h-j). 120 While the cations of 2-FPEA and 3-FPEA adopt face-to-edge configuration, the 4-FPEA spacers stack parallel to each other. For 3-FPEA and 4-FPEA cations, the closest fluorine-fluorine distance is 3.015 and 3.511 Å, respectively, while the van der Waals radius of fluorine is 1.47 Å, suggesting strong F•••F interaction for 3-FPEA and weaker interaction for 4-FPEA. For 2-FPEA, the closest F•••F distance is 6.117 Å, while the closest I•••F distance is 3.781 Å, which is near to the sum of the van der Waals radii (3.45 Å), indicating a strong interaction between the fluorine atom and the inorganic layer. The unit cell displacements are (0.1, 0.5), (0.4, 0.5), and (0.15, 0.15) for 2-FPEA, 3-FPEA, and 4-FPEA, respectively. (2-FPEA) 2 SnI 4 shows the highest bandgap among this series, because of the largest tilt of inorganic layer (smallest Sn-I-Sn angle) caused by the strong interaction between the fluorine atom and the octahedra. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>200245</offset>
      <text> Figure 5 . 5 Figure 5. Crystal structures of (a) (Br(CH 2 ) 2 NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 , (b) (4-FPEA) 2 PbI 4 (with parallel cation configuration), and (c) (4-BrPMA) 2 PbI 4 (with tilted cation configuration). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>200447</offset>
      <text> (2-FPEA) 2 SnI 4 and (2-ClPEA) 2 SnI 4 only tilt in-plane but barely tilt out-ofplane, (2-BrPEA) 2 SnI 4 tilts both in-plane and out-of-plane. The Sn-I-Sn angle is smallest for (2-BrPEA) 2 SnI 4 , leading to the highest bandgap among this series. Unlike in (2-FPEA) 2 SnI 4 , 2-BrPEA adopts a parallel configuration, with a closest C•••C distance of 3.80 Å. This strong interaction between the aromatic rings helps stabilize the parallel cation configuration. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>200916</offset>
      <text> and Schmitt et al. (Table 4n-j) 85 using 4-XBZA (X = F, Cl and Br, BZA = benzylammonium) as spacers. (BZA) 2 PbI 4 and (4-FBZA) 2 PbI 4 adopt the centrosymmetric space groups of Pbca and P2 1 /n, respectively, while (4-ClBZA) 2 PbI 4 and (4-BrBZA) 2 PbI 4 adopt the noncentrosymmetric space group of P2 1 . This is confirmed by the second-harmonic generation (SHG) measurement, which show that (BZA) 2 PbI 4 and (4-FBZA) 2 PbI 4 only exhibit a surface SHG signal while (4-ClBZA) 2 PbI 4 and (4-BrBZA) 2 PbI 4 show both surface and bulk SHG signals two orders higher than (BZA)PbI 4 and (4-FBZA) 2 PbI 4 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>201523</offset>
      <text> Figure 6 . 6 Figure 6. (a) Cations with conjugated groups and different HOMO-LUMO levels. (b) PL spectra of n = 1 iodide perovskites with cations from panel a. (c) Energy level alignment for the organic layer (red line) and inorganic layer (dark blue line) within 2D perovskites. (i) and (iv) are examples of Type I quantum wells, while (ii) and (iii) are Type II. Reprinted with permission from ref 51. Copyright 2019 Nature Publishing Group. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>201969</offset>
      <text> 3 has larger Pb-I-Pb angle and thus smaller bandgap than MAPbI 3 . So mixing FA with MA in the A site can further reduce the bandgap. Taking (3AMP)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 for example, alloying 25% FA ((3AMP)-(MA 0.75 FA 0.25 ) 3 Pb 4 I 13 ) increases the Pb-I-Pb angle from 168°to 173.8°and reduces the bandgap by 0.1 eV. The average PCE of the solar cell devices also increases from 7.02% for (3AMP)(MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 to 11.24% for (3AMP)-(MA 0.75 FA 0.25 ) 3 Pb 4 I 13 . &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>202437</offset>
      <text> Figure 8 . 8 Figure 8. (a) Crystal structure of (AE4T)PbBr 4 . (b) Absorption spectra for (AE4T)PbX 4 films, X = Cl (i), Br (ii), and I (iii). The peak from the inorganic part is marked with an arrow. (c) Frontier energy levels of the organic and inorganic components at the Γ point for the series of (AE4T)PbX 4 (X = Cl, Br, I). (d) Frontier energy levels at the Γ point for the series with different number of thiophene rings shown in e (i)-(v). (e) Oligothiophene-based organic molecules with different ring number n (i)-(v) and carbon-chain (vi). Panel b reprinted with permission from ref 127. Copyright 1999 American Chemical Society. Panels a and c-e reprinted with permission from ref 126. Copyright 2018 American Physical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>203181</offset>
      <text> Figure 9 . 9 Figure 9. (a) Crystal structure of (EA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 Br 10 from side view. (b) Crystal structure of (EA) 2 (EA) 2 Pb 3 Br 10 emphasizing the perovskite cage. (c) 2D color map of computed electronic bandgap energies (E g ) for different values of equatorial (d Pb -I eq ) and internal axial (d Pb -I ax-int ) distances, setting d Pb -I ax-ext to 3.1 Å, overlaid by the experimental bond lengths extracted from single crystal structures of (d) (BA) 2 (MA)Pb 2 I 7 (MA), (e) (BA) 2 (FA)Pb 2 I 7 (FA), (f) (BA) 2 (DMA)Pb 2 I 7 (DMA) and (g) (BA) 2 (GA)Pb 2 I 7 (GA). (h) Absorption spectra and (i) PL spectra for compounds in panels d-g. (j) Dependence of optical bandgap energy on the A site cation size for the 3D perovskite (left axis, red line) and 2D perovskites (right axis, blue line). The pressure data points for 3D perovskites show the effect of applied physical pressure on the perovskite cage, resulting in a decrease in bandgap. This is opposite to the increased bandgap for 2D perovskites of the large A-site cation with increased chemical pressure. Panels c-i reprinted with permission from ref 21. Copyright American Chemical Society. Panel j reprinted with permission from ref 165. Copyright American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>204430</offset>
      <text> Figure 10 . 10 Figure 10. ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites. Crystal structures of (a) (IFO)(MA)SnI 4 and (b) (3APr)PbBr 4 as examples of A′AMX 4 (A and A′ are +1) and BMX 4 (B is +2), respectively. (c) Schematic representation of different structure type of n × m ⟨110⟩-oriented 2D perovskites. (d) Schematic comparison of self-trapping mechanism for (3APr)PbX 4 (X = I, Br, Cl). Panel d reproduced with permission from ref 181. Copyright American Chemical Society 2019. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>204913</offset>
      <text> Figure 11 . 11 Figure 11. Crystal structure of α-Cs 3 Sb 2 Cl 9 and Cs 4 CuSb 2 Cl 12 . Reprinted with permission from ref 203. Copyright 2017 American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>205086</offset>
      <text> 4. 1 . 1 Desired Film Attributes 4.1.1. Stability. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>205139</offset>
      <text> Figure 12 . 12 Figure 12. (a) Simple n-i-p device architecture. (b) Simple p-i-n device architecture, as known as the "inverted architecture." (c) Energy levels of the different layers in a solar cell device are ideally set up to allow for the electron to travel to the electron transport layer (ETL) then the cathode and for the hole to travel to the hole transport layer (HTL) then the anode. The ETL also blocks holes while the HTL blocks electrons. The paths for the electrons (blue) and holes (red) are shown both in the energy diagram and in a schematic of a device in panel d, using an n-i-p architecture as an example. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>205768</offset>
      <text> Figure 13 . 13 Figure 13. (a) Schematic showing the 2D perovskite layers oriented perpendicular to the substrate. The blue electron and orange hole are able to travel to the anode and cathode, respectively. (b) Layers here are oriented parallel to the substrate, meaning that the electron and hole are unable to reach the electrodes, leading them to recombine. (c) Schematic showing a common phase distribution. The 3D or 3D-like phase (black) is at the top of the substrate while the 2D layers (green) are closer to the substrate. (d) Depth-dependent photoluminescence (PL) confirms the phase distribution shown in (c). Panel d reprinted with permission from ref 219. Copyright 2020 American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>206481</offset>
      <text> Figure 14 . 14 Figure 14. Schematics of three commonly used film fabrication methods: (a) the one-step method, (b) hotcasting, and (c) the antisolvent method. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>206642</offset>
      <text> Figure 15 . 15 Figure 15. Depictions of the three types of dimensionality architectures used in films: (a) 2D films, (b) mixed dimensionality films, specifically mixed 2D and 3D phases, and (c) heterostructures, specifically a 2D/3D heterostructure. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>206894</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrenesulfonate; PCBM = [6,6]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester; PTAA = poly[bis(4-phenyl)(2,4,6-trimethylphenyl)amine; spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; Bphen = bathophenanthroline; BCP = bathocuproine; PEI = polyethylenimine b OS = one-step spin coating; HC = hotcasting; AS = antisolvent method; PA = postannealing method; 254 SA = solvent annealing; Additives are listed second to the technique: TEP = trielthylphosphine; MACl = methylammonium chloride. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide; GBL = γ-butyrolactone; DMAc = N,Ndimethylacetamide; MAAc = methylammonium acetate; Tol = toluene. d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>207671</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate; PCBM =[6,6]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester; spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine. b OS = one-step spin coating; HC = hotcasting; AS = antisolvent method SA = solvent annealing; DC = drop-casting; Additives are listed second to the technique: HI = hydriodic acid. c DMF = N,Ndimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide; GBL = γ-butyrolactone; MAAc = methylammonium acetate. d Device parameters based on champion devices. e Mesoscopic device architecture was used in which the absorber layer was within a porous scaffold of (TiO 2 /ZrO 2 /C). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>208367</offset>
      <text> Figure 16 . 16 Figure 16. Many spacers are based on the commonly used BA and PEA spacers. Alkylammonium cations can be made shorter than BA to achieve greater light absorption or longer to achieve greater stability. They can also be conjugated or substituted to improve charge transfer between layers. For aromatic spacers derived from PEA, hydrogen substitution has been shown to lead to a higher dipole moment. Ring substitution has led to a different quantum well structure (Type II). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>208857</offset>
      <text> Figure 17 . 17 Figure 17. (a) Phase distribution can lead to satisfactory charge extraction if the charges are able to travel to a high-n phase with less quantum confinement. This mechanism has been described as "energy funnels" or a multiple quantum well (MQW) structure, and is demonstrated by the TA data in panel b, which shows measurements on hotcasted (BA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 ("n-BA perovskite") and (IBA) 2 (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 ("iso-BA perovskite"). For the BA-based film, bleaches associated with n = 3, 4, and 5 are present. For the IBA-based film, a bleach associated with a high-n ("3D") phase is seen which grows in after the low-n bleaches diminish in intensity, demonstrated charge transfer. (c) Contact angle measurements of water droplets on n = 3 films with different alkylammonium spacers (C4 = butylammonium, C5 = pentylammonium, C6 = hexylammonium), showing the increased hydrophobicity of the films with longer spacers. (d) J-V curves for solar cells with n = 4 perovskites using different spacers: BA (only C-C single bonds), BEA (one C=C double bond), and BYA (one CC triple bond). Panel b reprinted with permission from ref 223. Copyright 2018 Royal Society of Chemistry. Panel c reprinted with permission from ref 36. Copyright 2019 American Chemical Society. Panel d reprinted with permission from ref 270. Copyright American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>210229</offset>
      <text> Figure 18 . 18 Figure 18. (a) TA data for stoichiometrically "n = 5" films using PEA and 4FPEA spacers. Incorporation of 4FPEA spacer into the 2D structure leads to a low-energy bleach associated with high-n phases. (b) Dipole moments of 4FPEA and PEA spacers derived from DFT calculations. (c) Normalized PCE for solar cells using different solid state mixtures of (5F-PEA) x (PEA) 1-x (MA) 3 Pb 4 I 13 under 45% relative humidity. Panels a and b reprinted with permission from ref 264. Copyright 2019 Wiley-VCH. Panel c reprinted with permission from ref 124. Copyright 2019 American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>210835</offset>
      <text> Figure 19 . 19 Figure 19. GIWAXS images of 2D perovskite films with dialkylammonium spacers. Using an ionic liquid solvent with a one-step method (top), the texture becomes narrower for shorter spacers. However, using an HI additive in DMF with a one-step method (bottom), the trend is the opposite, with the longest spacers giving the narrowest texture. Top reprinted with permission from ref 293. Copyright 2019 Wiley-VCH. Bottom reprinted with permission from ref 39. Copyright 2018 American Chemical Society. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>211350</offset>
      <text> Figure 20 . 20 Figure 20. Different distributions of phases in mixed dimensionality films. (a) Multiple quantum wells occur when there are 2D and 3D phases both present in the film. This distribution is generally graded with the 2D phases at the substrate, as shown by the TA data to the right under "Graded.: However, a reverse-graded phase distribution can exist where the 2D phases at the surface, demonstrated by TA data with excitation at the front and back of the film. (b) When using the EDBE spacer, a ⟨110⟩-oriented phase is stabilized, leading to a two-component mixture of (EDBE)PbI 4 and MAPbI 3 . UV-vis data shows a peak below 500 nm associated with the 2D phase and a shoulder associated with the 3D phase. TA data only shows the 3D phases and PbI 2 , unlike the multiple phases with the multiple quantum well structure. (c) When the spacer can stabilize a 1D structure, a mixture of the 1D phase and the 3D phase can exist. HRTEM shows 1D quantum wires dispersed in a 3D matrix. Part of panel a reprinted with permission from ref 301 (Copyright 2018 American Chemical Society) and ref 302 (Copyright 2019 Wiley-VCH). Part of panel b reprinted with permission from ref 303. Copyright 2018 Wiley-VCH. Part of panel c reprinted with permission from ref 304. Copyright 2019 Royal Society of Chemistry. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>212670</offset>
      <text> a PCBM =[6,6]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester;PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrenesulfonate; spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine. b HC = hotcasting; AS = antisolvent method; Additives are listed second to the technique: HI = hydriodic acid; HBr = hydrobromic acid. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide; GBL = γ-butyrolactone. d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>213167</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate; PCBM = [6,6]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester; spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine. b OS = one-step spin coating; AS = antisolvent method; Additives are listed second to the technique: MASCN = methylammonium thiocyanate. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide. d Device parameters based on champion devices. nium cations in mixed dimensionality films has yet to be fully explored, though a few examples are listed in Table 12a-e. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>213767</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrenesulfonate; Spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine. b AS = antisolvent method. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide. d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>214083</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrenesulfonate; Spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine. b OS = one-step spin coating; AS = antisolvent method; Additives are listed second to the technique: HCl = hydrochloric acid; HI = hydriodic acid; c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide. d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>214519</offset>
      <text> a PEDOT:PSS = poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate; PCBM = [6,6]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester; Spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; BCP = bathocuproine; DM = N2,N2′,N7,N7′-tetrakis(9,9-dimethyl-9Hfluoren-2-yl)N2,N2′,N7,N7′-tetrakis(4-methoxyphenyl)-9,9′-spirobi[fluorene]2,2′,7,7′-tetraamine b The first step refers to the deposition of the 3D layer. The second steps refers to the spin-coating the ammonium spacer onto the 3D layer to react and form a low-dimensional surface layer. OS = one-step spin coating; AS = antisolvent method; Dip = Dip-coating. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide; GBL = γbutyrolactone; CB = chlorobenzene; IPA = isopropanol. d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>215339</offset>
      <text> Figure 21 . 21 Figure 21. (a) J-V curves of HTM-free solar cells made from 2D/3D heterostructures using alkylammonium cations with different lengths, leading to different V OC values. (b) Same devices as panel a but with an HTM layer give a similar trend. (c) Stability of the devices in panel b at 100 °C where the normalized PCE is tracked. Reprinted with permission from ref 331. Copyright 2019 Wiley VCH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>215751</offset>
      <text> Figure 22 . 22 Figure 22. (a) Photoluminescence (PL) spectra over time when exposed to light. (b) Normalized PCE of 2D/3D heterostructure devices using thiophene spacers over time under continuous light. (c) Schematic showing the degradation of the 2D/3D interface for 2-TMA and 3-TMA versus no degradation for 2-TEA. Reprinted with permission from ref 338. Copyright 2020 Royal Society of Chemistry. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>216154</offset>
      <text> Table 16 . 16 List of Selected Solar Cells Using a 1D/3D Heterostructure a Spiro-OMeTAD = 2,2′,7,7′-Tetrakis[N,N-di(4-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene; b The first step refers to the deposition of the 3D layer. The second steps refers to the spin-coating the ammonium spacer onto the 3D layer to react and form a low-dimensional surface layer. OS = one-step spin coating; AS = antisolvent method; GP = gas-pump method. c DMF = N,N-dimethylformamide; DMSO = dimethyl sulfoxide; IPA = isopropanol d Device parameters based on champion devices. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>216713</offset>
      <text> Figure 23 . 23 Figure 23. (a) Cross-section SEM of a 1D/3D heterostructure solar cell using the TA spacer. The 1D TA-based crystal structure is shown to the right of the SEM (b) Stability of the TA-based device in (a) over time under 70 °C (left) and 70% relative humidity (right). Reprinted with permission from ref 339. Copyright American Chemical Society.Table 17. List of Selected Solar Cells Using Heterostructures in Which the Cation May Not Form a Low-Dimensionality Phase &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217196</offset>
      <text> Table 1 . 1 Structures Reported for Linear Monoammonium Cations a a All A-site cations in the tables are MA unless otherwise noted. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217330</offset>
      <text> al. and Billing et al., which will be heavily reviewed in this paper. Billing et al. reported the structures and phase transitions of (C m H 2m+1 NH 3 ) 2 PbI 4 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217493</offset>
      <text> Table 2 . 2 Structures Reported for Cyclic Monoammonium Cations &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217559</offset>
      <text> Table 3 . 3 Structures Reported for Aromatic Monoammonium Cations a GBL = γ-butyrolactone, DCM = dichloromethane. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217676</offset>
      <text> within each cation, the relative configuration between adjacent spacers can still be determined by refinement since it gives the most stable (lowest energy) structure. Taking the commonly studied (PEA) 2 PbI 4 (PEA = phenyl- ethylammonium, Table &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>217924</offset>
      <text> Table 4 . 4 Structures Reported for Cations with Heteroatoms Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>218106</offset>
      <text> Table 5 . 5 Structures Reported for Linear Diammonium CationsStructures were determined by PXRD and space group was not reported in the reference. Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review a https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>218376</offset>
      <text> Table 6 . 6 Structures Reported for Cyclic Diammonium Cations Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>218559</offset>
      <text> Table 7 . 7 Structures Reported Incorporating A-site Cations larger than MA a All tables above (Tables1-6) include structures with MA as A-site cation. Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review a https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>218834</offset>
      <text> Table 8 . 8 Cations That Can Form ⟨110⟩-Oriented 2D PerovskitesSingle-crystal structure was shown in the reference, but space group was not reported. Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review * https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219111</offset>
      <text> When one of the N atoms has methyl groups connected to it, such as the CH 3 NH 2 CH 2 CH 2 NH 3 2+81 and (CH 3 ) 2 NHCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 2+83 (Table 8m , n) cations, they can also form 2 × 2 ⟨110⟩-oriented perovskites. Interestingly, the cation with quaternary N, (CH 3 ) 3 NCH 2 CH 2 NH 3 2+ (Table &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219413</offset>
      <text> 4 CuSb 2 Cl 12 , Cs 4 MnSb 2 Cl 12 , Rb 4 CuSb 2 Cl 12 , Rb 4 MnSb 2 Cl 12 , Cs 4 CdSb 2 Cl 12 , Cs 4 MnBi 2 Cl 12 , and Cs 4 CdBi 2 Cl 12 ), &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219557</offset>
      <text> Table 9 . 9 List of Selected Solar Cells Using Monoammonium Spacers in 2D Films with n &lt; 8 Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219690</offset>
      <text> Table 10 . 10 List of Selected Solar Cells Using Diammonium Spacers in 2D Films with n &lt; 8 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219783</offset>
      <text> Table 11 . 11 List of Selected Solar Cells Using Monoammonium Spacers in 2D/3D Mixed Dimensionality Films &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219891</offset>
      <text> Table 12 . 12 List of Selected Solar Cells Using Diammonium Spacers in 2D/3D Mixed Dimensionality Films &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>219997</offset>
      <text> Table 13 . 13 List of Selected Solar Cells Using 1D/3D Mixed Dimensionality Films &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>220081</offset>
      <text> Table 14 . 14 List of Selected Solar Cells Using Spacers in Which the Dimensionality of the Final Film Is Uncertain &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>220199</offset>
      <text> Table 15 . 15 List of Selected Solar Cells Using a 2D/3D Heterostructure Chemical Reviews pubs.acs.org/CR Review &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>220314</offset>
      <text> Table 15 . continued 15 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>220340</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c01006 Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 2230-2291</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
