<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025040283CEEFFD</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 92&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Banners &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>21</offset>
      <text> Banners New for 2018: our banners are now responsive! To improve ad visibility, the leaderboard banner will hover with content on desktop and mobile devices As screens gradually permeate each aspect of our lives, banner advertising generates awareness for your brand or product in the moment your targeted customer is in their "science zone". Readers come to Cell.com, individual journal homepages, and the Elsevier online platform, ScienceDirect, to read and research the latest great science. Choose from standard banners, flash banners, and rich media. Geo-target your markets. Select regional targets to push specific examples and messaging. Cater to international customers with distinct messaging! &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>727</offset>
      <text> Electronic Table of Contents (eToC) &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>765</offset>
      <text> Email Targeting Broadcast your message in the audience's inbox through our electronic Tables of Contents (eToCs). Recipients are all opt-in subscribers, so emails are all fully permission based. Opportunities are available for all primary Cell Press research journals and are delivered the day before each journal's cover date. Two sponsored message slots are available: • Top: 728 x 90 (before the Table of Contents) • Middle: 336 x 280 (within the body) Campaign Subscribers Average&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1255</offset>
      <text>Cell Career Network Cell Career Network is the premier web platform for your recruiting efforts and events. Our highly-qualified audience uses Cell Career Network to keep tabs on industry trends and meetings, and for career advancement such as job openings and funding opportunities. • Promote an upcoming course, conference, or event With a job listing your vacancy will be on Cell Career Network for 60 days and it will appear alongside Cell Press journal articles and research relevant to your job advertisement on Cell.com Add a featured job banner ad to one of our top rated journals &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1847</offset>
      <text> Standard banner • Acceptable formats: .gif and/or .jpeg • Animations should run for less than three rotations or 30 seconds • All ads with a white background must include a colored border • All available ad sizes &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2070</offset>
      <text> Flash banner • Animations should run for less than three rotations or 30 seconds • All ads with a white background must include a colored border • Flash ads should use Click-Tag. When submitting rich media, an alternate .gif is required • 336 x 280 pixels • 728 x 90 pixels &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>2356</offset>
      <text> Specifications It's contextual, with a Phd (SciClick) Discover a comprehensive marketing solution. Our readers turn to Cell Press for landmark discoveries and a host of fascinating article formats, including our highly popular Previews, Minireviews, and Reviews. Generate maximum awareness through Marketplace Recommendations. Rather than guessing where your messaging should land, our Marketplace Recommendations tool uses SciClick software to read every article in real time and match it to product notes that you've supplied. This ensures that every reader is being shown your relevant product lines at every juncture of their research. Marketplace Recommendations with Cell Press offers an unrivaled opportunity to drive readers directly to your applications and products relevant to their work. • Drive highly qualified traffic to your website from a robust content-rich environment • Deliver a focused and targeted message alongside first-rate, peer-reviewed content  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>3336</offset>
      <text> Relevance and impact factor At Cell Press, we understand that impact factor is just one measure of journal performance, and you can find additional metrics at: cell.com/impact 26 issues per year • Molecular biology (transcription, RNAi splicing, RNA editing, DNA replication and repair, protein synthesis and editing, protein modification and degradation, and chromatin) • Cell biology (cell cycle, subcellular organization, protein and membrane transport, protein folding and stability, and signal transduction) • Systems biology • Stem cells • Human disease (infectious diseases including HIV and other viruses, cancer, and human disease genes) • Developmental biology (differentiation and morphogenesis, organogenesis, sex determination, stem cell biology, apostosis, and embryology in all model organisms including plants, mice, fish, flies, chicks, and worms) • Genetics and genomics (bacterial regulation, fly and worm genetics, and eukaryotic genomics) • Proteomics • Cancer research • Immunology (T cell selection, lymphocytes and immunoglobulins, and somatic hypermutation) • Neuroscience (learning and memory, neuronal guidance and connections, and synaptic transmission) • Structural biology • Microbiology • Virology • Physiology (receptors, hormone action, obesity, and lifespan) • Evolution       • &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4685</offset>
      <text> 9.025 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4707</offset>
      <text> 3.656 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4729</offset>
      <text> 8.827 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4751</offset>
      <text> 7.338 12 issues per year  I N T E R N A T I O N A L S O C I E T Y F O R S T E M C E L L R E S E A R C H &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>4857</offset>
      <text> Molecular Therapy family of journals Cell Press is delighted to announce our partnership with the American Society of Gene and Cell Therapy to publish the Molecular Therapy family of journals. Commencing January 2017, this premier collection of journals in the exciting areas of molecular and cellular therapeutics is published alongside the high-quality, cutting-edge research that you've come to expect from Cell Press journals. www.cell.com/molecular-therapy-family/home Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5347</offset>
      <text> 6.688 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5369</offset>
      <text> 2.610 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5391</offset>
      <text> 6.392 Impact Factor &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5413</offset>
      <text> 12 issues per year Molecular Therapy is the leading international journal for research on the development of molecular and cellular therapeutics to correct genetic and acquired diseases, including, but not limited to, research on gene transfer and editing, vector development and design, stem cell manipulation, vaccine development, pre-clinical target validation, safety/efficacy studies, and clinical trials.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5827</offset>
      <text> issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>5845</offset>
      <text> issues per year Molecular Therapy -Nucleic Acids publishes research targeted to the advances in nucleic acidbased therapeutics to treat and/ or correct genetic and acquired disease. Subject areas include development of therapeutics based on nucleic acids and their derivatives, vector development and design for the delivery of RNA-based therapeutics, and applications of gene-modifying agents. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6242</offset>
      <text> issues per year Molecular Therapy -Oncolytics is an international, open-access journal focusing on the development and clinical testing of viral, cellular, and other biological therapies targeting cancer. While providing a unique forum for work in the burgeoning fields of oncolytic virotherapy, as well as T cell-and stem cell-based therapies, the journal will consider all top-quality research that employs innovative molecular and cellular approaches that target cancer cells for destruction.  &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6741</offset>
      <text> Society partner journals &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6768</offset>
      <text> Online rates &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>6783</offset>
      <text> Print advertisements sizes Our high-impact-factor journals offer you a wide range of affordable advertising options across the broad spectrum of life sciences. Print advertisement specifications   4 ) 23(  5 ) 23(  6 ) 24(  1 ) 24(  2 ) 24(  3 ) 24(  4 ) 24(  5 ) 24(  6 ) Issue Date 10-Jan-18 14-Feb-18 Volume(Issue) 24(  1 ) 24(  2 ) 24(  3 ) 24(  4 ) 24(  5 ) 24(  6 ) 24(  7 ) 24(  8 ) 24(  9 ) 24(  10 ) 24(  11 ) 24(  12 ) 24(  13    4 ) 25(  5 ) 25(  6 ) 25(  7 ) 25(  8 ) 25(  9 ) 25(  10 ) 25(  11 ) 25(  12 ) 25(  13     4 ) 25(  5 ) 25(  6 ) 25(  7 ) 25(  8 ) 25(  9 ) 25 (10)  25 (11)  25 (12)   Issue Date 18-Jan-18 Dates and deadlines: review journals     Table  S3 . The photovoltaic parameters of BSO based PSCs processed and aged at 40% RH for 0 and 24hours.    S4 . The parameter of BaSnO3 (40% RH) &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">BaSnO3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:52:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="7585" length="6"/>
        <text>BaSnO3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7602</offset>
      <text> Article &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>7612</offset>
      <text> Impact of Electrode Materials on Process Environmental Stability of Efficient Perovskite Solar Cells We employ a mesoporous BaSnO 3 electron transport layer to satisfy both solar-cell performance and stability as an alternative to conventional Li-doped TiO 2 . Both BaSnO 3 and Li-doped TiO 2 show considerable power conversion efficiency exceeding 21% and 20%, respectively, under 10% relative humidity. However, in 40% relative humidity, PSCs using Li-doped TiO 2 are dramatically deteriorated within 24 h while PSCs with BaSnO 3 exhibit excellent processing stability.  &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="2">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">BaSnO3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:52:51Z</infon>
        <location offset="7737" length="7"/>
        <text>BaSnO 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="3">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Li-doped TiO2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:53:09Z</infon>
        <location offset="7857" length="14"/>
        <text>Li-doped TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="4">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">BaSnO3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:53:19Z</infon>
        <location offset="7879" length="7"/>
        <text>BaSnO 3</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="5">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">Li-doped TiO2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:53:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="7891" length="14"/>
        <text>Li-doped TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="6">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:54:03Z</infon>
        <location offset="7962" length="3"/>
        <text>21%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="7">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">20</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:53:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="7970" length="4"/>
        <text>20%,</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>8187</offset>
      <text> INTRODUCTION Organometal-halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have received considerable attention because of their low-cost fabrication process and remarkable power conversion efficiency (PCE), recently exceeding 22%.  1  Most highly efficient PSCs utilize a bilayered device architecture of a mesoporous scaffold, which is infiltrated by a formamidinium (FA)-cation-based perovskite and an overlayer of the perovskite.  2  Mesoporous (mp) TiO 2 has been commonly used for high-surface-area electrodes, but it exhibits low electron mobility ($1 cm 2 V À1 s À1 ).  3, 4  Therefore, the use of substitutional dopants such as Li salt has been necessary for facilitating electron injection and transport in the mesoporous TiO 2 .  5, 6  A number of problems with PSCs should be resolved before expanding from a lab scale to actual mass production, including homogeneity over a large area and the throughput and yield of the process with quality and the stability of large-area devices. One further major issue is the processing stability of the perovskites, which are sensitive to atmospheric conditions with uncontrolled humidity. With respect to processing costs, it is not ideal to establish a 100% nitrogen environment or a dry air atmosphere with less than 10% relative humidity (RH) for a mass production line. On the other hand, humidity higher than 40%$50% should be avoided for the perfect conversion of the precursors into the perovskite film. Thus, high processing stability of all of the incorporated materials is essential for practical fabrication under a broad window of humidity (with an upper limit of 40%$50%). Efforts to address the aforementioned limitations include incorporating 2D perovskites into 3D perovskites or introducing an inorganic cation (such as Cs or Rb) into the perovskites.  [7] [8] [9] [10]  To protect the perovskite layer from the ingress of moisture, the perovskite film can be covered with a hydrophobic polymer layer.  11  For better stability, the use of hole transport materials (HTMs) without a hygroscopic dopant such as lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide (Li-TFSi) has also been explored.  12  Finally, device stability against humidity has been obtained by applying encapsulation.  13  Nevertheless, all the layers of the device during the fabrication and aging process in a practical mass production line could be exposed to ambient humid air before encapsulation of the device. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>10626</offset>
      <text> Context &amp; Scale For the aforementioned reasons, many researchers have conducted research to enhance the stability of the perovskite layer and the hole transport layer (HTL) against humidity.  14, 15  However, to date, little research has been performed on the humidity stability of the metal-oxide layer of the device. As explained, facile doping of Li salt into mesoporous TiO 2 could lead to improved electron conductance, but the stability issue has still not been addressed. Furthermore, high reactivity of the intercalated Li ions with any moisture may produce undesirable byproducts such as Li 2 O and LiOH, which can degrade device performance.  16, 17  Therefore, in finding an alternative to Li-doped mp-TiO 2 , the development of an electron transport layer (ETL) that exhibits better mobility and superior moisture stability in humid air is also critical for attaining processing stability during practical mass production. BaSnO 3 (BSO) is an n-type semiconductor that is induced by oxygen vacancies in the lattice with a wide band gap of 3.1 eV. It has high mobility because the conduction band (CB) minimum originating from the Sn 5s-O 2p orbital interaction gives rise to a large CB dispersion and thus a low effective mass. Recently, our group and Seok reported a highly efficient and stable planar PSC with a device configuration of a fluorine-doped SnO 2 (FTO)/thin layer of nanoparticle La-BaSnO 3 (NP-BSO)/MAPbI 3 / polytriarylamine polymer (PTAA)/Au.  18  This planar PSC based on a BSO-MAPbI 3 heterojunction showed excellent device performance of 21% and better photostability compared to that obtained with the use of a thin layer of its TiO 2 counterpart. However, thus far, there have been no reports on employing BSO nanoparticles in a mesoporous scaffold or in a heterojunction with FA-based mixed perovskites. In this work, we propose a strategy for improving the process stability by incorporating a BSO mesoporous layer into a state-of-the-art PSC architecture of a bilayered device, including FA-based mixed perovskites. From the resultant device, we achieved stabilized efficiency of 21.7% (reverse scan: 22%) with a certified efficiency of 21.3%, which is the highest efficiency among non-TiO 2 -based PSCs. The mp-BSObased device exhibited excellent processing stability during the fabrication and aging processes under a broad window of humidity in a range up to $40% RH. In contrast, the device using Li-doped mp-TiO 2 showed relatively poor stability under a similar humid atmosphere. Furthermore, the mp-BSO-based PSCs exhibited good long-term stability under dark and light illumination for 500 h. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="8">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:54:00Z</infon>
        <location offset="12801" length="4"/>
        <text>21.3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>13266</offset>
      <text> RESULTS AND DISCUSSION BSO may be the best candidate as an ETL for commercializing PSCs because it has excellent conductivity with no additional process compared to its TiO 2 counterpart. But, a previous report shows the TiO 2 /BSO-based PSCs have a large hysteresis in current-voltage (J-V) curves.  18  Surprisingly, during the optimization process, we found that the introduction of SnO 2 nanoparticle layer onto the spray-deposited TiO 2 reduces the hysteresis in J-V curves (Figure  S1 ). For this reason, we employed a TiO 2 /SnO 2 bilayer as a blocking layer for mp-BSO-based PSCs. To maximize the device performance of mp-BSO-based PSCs, we adopted a state-of-the-art PSC architecture consisting of an FTO/ blocking layer (bl-TiO 2 and SnO 2 bilayer)/mesoporous layer/FA-based mixed perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au (Figure  1A ). For fabricating best-performing devices, all processes were carried out under optimum condition, i.e., 10% RH. From a cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) image (Figure  1A ), all the layers are discernible; the mesoporous BSO layer is deposited with a thickness of 140 nm, and a uniform perovskite layer on top of BSO is fabricated with a thickness of 450 nm by using our solvent engineering technique. From this resultant device, we obtained a reverse PCE of 22% with a stabilized PCE of 21.7% (Figure  1B ) and a certified average PCE of 21.3% (Figure  S2 ). As displayed in Figure  S3 , hysteresis behavior is clearly observed but is considerably suppressed in the mesoporous scaffold based on FA-based mixed perovskites, as compared to a previous study using La-doped BSO/MAPbI 3 planar PSCs.  18  A histogram of the solar-cell PCEs for 43 cells is shown in Figure  1C  and Table  S1 . Surprisingly, over 30 cells have a PCE of more than 21% (an average PCE of 21.45% G 0.61%), which is comparable to that of Li-doped mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs (hereafter, denoted as mp-TiO 2 ) (20.74% G 0.58%) (Figure  1C ). In addition to a highly efficient performance, practical processing stability in a production line is required until the device is encapsulated since moisture cannot be perfectly excluded in the processing environment, in contrast with the inert atmosphere of a laboratory (e.g., a glove box filled with nitrogen or dry air). We investigated the processing stability of an mp-BSO-based device fabricated and aged under controlled humidity (i.e., low humidity [$10% RH] and high humidity [$40% RH]). For comparison, we also prepared an mp-TiO 2 -based device under the same conditions. It should be noted that it is usually difficult to prepare a high-quality perovskite film with a dense and uniform morphology under humidity higher than 40% RH. Thus, we adjusted the humidity up to 40% RH. As shown in Figure  S4 , at 10% RH, we could not detect any degradation in either device even after 1 week, and the performance was enhanced from 19.4% and 19.2% to 20.1% and 21.3% for the mp-TiO 2 -based PSC and mp-BSO-based PSC, respectively, owing to the aging effect. However, at 40% RH, we found a significant difference in the device stability between mp-BSO and mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs. Figure  2A  shows the evolution of the average photovoltaic parameters over 24 h for non-encapsulated mp-BSO-and mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs aged at controlled 40% RH. Surprisingly, the mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs show serious degradation at 40% RH in the early stage of the first 3 h because of abrupt decreases in the fill factor (FF) and open circuit voltage (V OC ), and their performance diminishes to approximately 50% of the initial efficiency over 24 h (Figure  2A ). Conversely, the mp-BSO-based PSCs exhibit good stability at 40% RH for 24 h. The FF and short circuit current (J SC ) values stay constant for the first 3 h, while the V OC increases slightly because of the aging effect (similar to the result at 10% RH), resulting in an improvement in the PCE (Figure  2A ). Even after 24 h, only a slight decrease in the PCE is observed for the mp-BSO-based devices. For detailed information, a histogram of PCEs (Figure  S5 ), and full photovoltaic parameters (Tables  S2  and S3 ) for mp-BSO-and mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs processed and aged at 40% RH for 0 and 24 h are further shown. Consequently, it can be concluded that the mp-BSO is an ideal candidate for the ETL in a highly efficient PSC with good processing stability. To elucidate the degradation pathway by the humidity effect on both PSCs, an electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) analysis was performed at a V OC under 1 sun illumination. Figure  2B  presents the Nyquist plots of mp-TiO 2 -and mp-BSObased PSCs at different humidity conditions. The Nyquist plots show a typical semicircle in a frequency range of 0.1 Hz to 100 kHz. The semicircle in the high-frequency region is caused by the selective contact or the interface of this contact and is related to the series resistance (R series ).  19  For a BSO-based PSC, the R series is negligibly affected by humidity, while the diameter of the semicircle for the mp-TiO 2 -based PSC in high-frequency regions increases significantly at higher humidity (40% RH), i.e., the increase in R series , which reduces the FF and thus decreases the PCE of the device. This is in agreement with R series trends extracted from the J-V curves. This increase in the R series can be attributed to the reduced electrical property of Li doped mp-TiO 2 film because all layers in the PSCs are identical except for the n-type mesoporous layer. Because the measured electron concentration for BSO and TiO 2 film also is the same (Figure  S6 ), the reduced electrical property may be ascribed to low mobility of TiO 2 film. Furthermore, the dark J-V curves show a clear difference between mp-BSO-and mp-TiO 2 -based devices, depending on humidity (Figure  2C ). The dark current of mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs is significantly reduced at high humidity ($40% RH) compared to mp-BSO-based PSC, although at low humidity ($10%), they exhibit similar dark J-V curves. In general, the reduction of dark current has a positive effect on devices, suggesting a decrease in defects and hence a reduction of recombination. However, an abnormally greater reduction of dark current may be due to a large drop in electrical properties of the ETL or the ETL/perovskite interface, i.e., an increase in the resistance of the ETL or the ETL/perovskite interface, which increases the R series , as shown in EIS analysis.  19  We further performed transient photocurrent (TPC) and photovoltage (TPV) analysis for devices aged at 40% RH (Figures  2D  and S7 ). It is observed that the mp-BSO-based PSC shows faster decay in TPC and slower decay in TPV than that of the mp-TiO 2 -based PSC, respectively. Additionally, the time-resolved photoluminescence (TR-PL) result exhibits that the BSO/perovskite sample has a faster charge transfer compared to TiO 2 /perovskite (Figure  S8 ). Based on these results, we can conclude that mp-BSO-based PSCs fabricated and aged at 40 % RH have superior charge extraction capability than mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs fabricated and aged at 40% RH. Therefore, it can be assumed that a high-humidity condition can inhibit electron transport or transfer at the interface between oxide particles or at the interface between the perovskite and the ETL, thereby increasing the resistance of the ETL, which in turn can significantly decrease the FF and PCE of the device with mp-TiO 2 -treated Li salt. To reveal the exact reason for the increase in the resistance of the device, various analyses for mesoporous films under different humidity conditions were performed. First, we carried out X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) (Figures  3A  and S9 ). Figure  3A  displays XPS O 1s spectra of BSO and mp-TiO 2 films with different humidity conditions. The spectra of the BSO films are almost identical regardless of the humidity, indicating that BSO is almost unaffected by humidity, whereas the spectra of the TiO 2 film show clear differences at different humidity conditions. A peak deconvolution process shows that the O 1s spectrum of the samples consists of two peaks at 529.4 and 531.4 eV. The peak with low binding energy is generally associated with the contribution of O 2 À ions in the anatase anionic network, while that with higher binding energy is attributed to the oxygen atoms in the OH species and/or the adsorbed oxygen species on the surface.  20, 21  At a high-humidity condition ($40% RH), the shoulder peak at 531.4 eV is diminished compared with the TiO 2 film at a low-humidity condition, indicating a decrease in the OH species on TiO 2 . Generally, the reduction of OH species may originate from the formation of a new oxide layer (e.g., oxide shell) on the surface of TiO 2 nanoparticles. To support this speculation, we performed a Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy analysis (Figure  3B ). Comparing the FTIR spectra of pristine TiO 2 and Li-doped TiO 2 , we found that Li doping inevitably produces lithium oxide (e.g., 625 and 716 cm À1 ; Li-O stretching) on TiO 2 films regardless of the humidity level.  22  Interestingly, the peaks for 625 and 716 cm À1 become stronger at higher humidity, although the peak at 832 cm À1 (Ti-O-Ti stretching) becomes weaker. This indicates that the moisture can accelerate the formation of lithium oxides in TiO 2 . As reported, some types of lithium compounds are critically sensitive to moisture in the air. Water can easily penetrate crystal structures or porous films and react with lithium in the lattice or surface, which can produce Li 2 O.  16  Furthermore, we directly confirmed the formation of an oxide layer on TiO 2 nanoparticles via high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM). Figures  3C  and 3D  compare HR-TEM images of Li-doped TiO 2 nanoparticles prepared under different humidity (10% or 40% RH). At low humidity (10% RH), the surface of the TiO 2 nanoparticles is smooth. Although we detected Li-O stretching on TiO 2 under low humidity through an FTIR analysis, we could not directly observe a noticeable layer on the TiO 2 surface in the TEM image. This can imply that Li x O can be partially or very thinly formed at a low-humidity condition. However, at high humidity (40% RH), we distinctly observed a non-uniform thin amorphous layer (&lt;5 nm) on the surface of the TiO 2 nanoparticles. Therefore, it can be concluded that the formation of a lithium oxide layer on the surface of TiO 2 nanoparticles is one of the key factors responsible for deterioration of the device under high humidity.  Along with outstanding device performance, the durability of PSCs is another major factor for the commercialization of PSCs. We therefore investigated the long-term stability of BSO-based PSCs under dark storage, as well as under continuous illumination. First, devices were tested without any encapsulation in an ambient environment (25 C and $25% humidity). Figure  5A  shows a normalized PCE of the non-encapsulated FTO/ BSO/perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au device as a function of storage time. The resulting device exhibits substantially excellent storage stability for 500 h, retaining almost 100% of the original PCE. Second, we performed a light stability test using two representative HTMs, i.e., Spiro-OMeTAD and PTAA, in a nitrogen-filled chamber at a constant temperature of $25 C under AM 1.5 G illumination using a xenon lamp. Figure  5B  displays the normalized PCE of the encapsulated FTO/BSO/(FAPbI 3 ) 0.93 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.07 (FAMA)/ Spiro-OMeTAD/Au device as a function of testing time under constant air mass (AM) 1.5 G illumination. The PCE of the BSO-based PSC degrades to 67% of its original value within the first 50 h, followed by retention over the next 450 h. Figure  5C  shows the normalized PCE of the encapsulated FTO/BSO/FAMA/PTAA/Au device as a function of testing time under constant AM 1.5 G illumination. The BSO-based PSCs using PTAA exhibit excellent photostability under light illumination, including UV without a drop in the PCE over 500 h, showing superior light stability to a Spiro-OMeTAD-based device. Based on these results, including successful elimination of the problems originating from the TiO 2 ETL, the n-type BSO ETL is a good candidate as an ETL for PSC commercialization. In conclusion, through systematic analyses, we demonstrated that a BSO ETL is an excellent alternative to TiO 2 for commercialization of PSCs. With the state-of-the-art PSC using mp-BSO ETL, we achieved a certified efficiency of 21.3% (reverse scan: 22%; and forward scan: 20.6%) with a stabilized efficiency of 21.7%. These values are comparable to those of the top-performing PSCs based on Li-doped TiO 2 and are the highest efficiencies among non-TiO 2 -based PSCs. By establishing a humid environment similar to that of an actual production line (i.e., high humidity over 40%), we have verified that the BSO ETL would be beneficial to the actual process because of its superior resistance to moisture relative to TiO 2 ETL. In addition, we confirmed that the mp-BSO-based PSCs exhibit superior long-term stability in a humid environment (25%-30% RH) and under light illumination, including UV. We believe that the introduction of mesoscopic BSO will enable a wide processing window in an actual production line, where it is difficult to remove moisture or control humidity, and it can move us a step closer to PSC commercialization. &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="9">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">TitaniumDioxide</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T09:54:15Z</infon>
        <location offset="13436" length="5"/>
        <text>TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="10">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:08:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="13977" length="107"/>
        <text>FTO/ blocking layer (bl-TiO 2 and SnO 2 bilayer)/mesoporous layer/FA-based mixed perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="11">
        <infon key="type">treated_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">21.3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:23:02Z</infon>
        <location offset="14655" length="5"/>
        <text>21.3%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="12">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSL</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:27:08Z</infon>
        <location offset="15637" length="25"/>
        <text>under controlled humidity</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="13">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">40</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:26:21Z</infon>
        <location offset="16299" length="3"/>
        <text>40%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="14">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:27:24Z</infon>
        <location offset="16373" length="6"/>
        <text>mp-BSO</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="15">
        <infon key="type">control_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:27:30Z</infon>
        <location offset="16384" length="8"/>
        <text>mp-TiO 2</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="16">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_cont</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">50</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:21:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="16813" length="3"/>
        <text>50%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="17">
        <infon key="type">electron_transport_layer</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">24</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:28:35Z</infon>
        <location offset="16848" length="4"/>
        <text>24 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="18">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">90</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:21:39Z</infon>
        <location offset="17201" length="15"/>
        <text>slight decrease</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="19">
        <infon key="type">treatment_element</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:37:18Z</infon>
        <location offset="23990" length="9"/>
        <text>BSO-based</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="20">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSD</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:35:37Z</infon>
        <location offset="24005" length="18"/>
        <text>under dark storage</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="21">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:36:49Z</infon>
        <location offset="24147" length="4"/>
        <text>25 C</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="22">
        <infon key="type">humidity</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:36:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="24157" length="3"/>
        <text>25%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="23">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:36:28Z</infon>
        <location offset="24231" length="35"/>
        <text>FTO/ BSO/perovskite/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="24">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">500</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:37:04Z</infon>
        <location offset="24381" length="5"/>
        <text>500 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="25">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">100</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:21:48Z</infon>
        <location offset="24405" length="4"/>
        <text>100%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="26">
        <infon key="type">stability_type</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">ISOSLT</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T09:55:36Z</infon>
        <location offset="24454" length="20"/>
        <text>light stability test</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="27">
        <infon key="type">temperature</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">25</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:37:41Z</infon>
        <location offset="24594" length="2"/>
        <text>25</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="28">
        <infon key="type">control_pce</infon>
        <infon key="identifier"></infon>
        <infon key="annotator">kvences@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-20T21:16:25Z</infon>
        <location offset="24608" length="5"/>
        <text>1.5 G</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="29">
        <infon key="type">structure_pin_nip</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">NIP</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-01-14T10:37:55Z</infon>
        <location offset="24707" length="64"/>
        <text>FTO/BSO/(FAPbI 3 ) 0.93 (MAPbBr 3 ) 0.07 (FAMA)/ Spiro-OMeTAD/Au</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="30">
        <infon key="type">efficiency_tret</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">67</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-13T04:21:56Z</infon>
        <location offset="24899" length="3"/>
        <text>67%</text>
      </annotation>
      <annotation id="31">
        <infon key="type">time</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">450</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-12T17:32:54Z</infon>
        <location offset="24984" length="5"/>
        <text>450 h</text>
      </annotation>
      <relation id="R1">
        <infon key="type">test_1</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:58Z</infon>
        <node refid="12" role=""/>
        <node refid="14" role=""/>
        <node refid="15" role=""/>
        <node refid="13" role=""/>
        <node refid="16" role=""/>
        <node refid="17" role=""/>
        <node refid="18" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R2">
        <infon key="type">test_2</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">kvences@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:58Z</infon>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
        <node refid="20" role=""/>
        <node refid="21" role=""/>
        <node refid="22" role=""/>
        <node refid="24" role=""/>
        <node refid="25" role=""/>
        <node refid="28" role=""/>
      </relation>
      <relation id="R3">
        <infon key="type">test_3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jlnomura@ucsd.edu</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-17T03:49:58Z</infon>
        <node refid="26" role=""/>
        <node refid="27" role=""/>
        <node refid="30" role=""/>
        <node refid="31" role=""/>
        <node refid="19" role=""/>
      </relation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26672</offset>
      <text> EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURES Full experimental procedures are provided in the Supplemental Information.     Table  S3 . The photovoltaic parameters of BSO based PSCs processed and aged at 40% RH for 0 and 24hours.    S4 . The parameter of BaSnO3 (40% RH) • Announce a grant/award • Elevate your company's profile Online job board product options &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27019</offset>
      <text> •Features• SciClick Contextual Link Advertising utilizes a unique search algorithm to match your message in context with the content on cell.com to drive traffic to your specifically chosen URL Customized campaign with campaign optimization manager • Unlimited SciClick Contextual Link Advertising • Unlimited outbound clicks • Monthly updates and edits • Comprehensive analytics Advertising package includes Cell Press research journals Cell Press: the best of the best • 47% of our readers are the lead decision maker in their company or lab • Consistently the highest impact factor in the biology category • Discipline-leading journals in all life science verticals • Increased translational content offerings • Trends and review content provide invaluable insights &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27812</offset>
      <text> Biophysics • Computational biology 12 issues per year • Genetics, epigenetics, and genomic instability • Cell signaling and communication • Cell cycle and DNA repair • Diagnostics (molecular profiling and pharmacogenomics) • Telomerase and transformation • Apoptosis • Angiogenesis and metastasis • Animal models • Cancer therapy (rational drug design and small-molecule and biologicalmolecule therapeutics) 12 issues per year • Chemical insights into signaling, catalysis, and gene expression • Novel chemical and biological methods for molecular design, synthesis, and analysis • Glycomics • Chemical genetics • Chemistry and biology of natural and unnatural biopolymers • The use of natural and designed molecules as probes of cellular pathways • Drug design • The nature of molecular recognition in biological systems • Novel procedures for the large-scale analysis of genes and proteins • Functional and structural genomics • Molecular basis of evolution 12 issues per year • Molecular and cell biology of microbes • Microbial pathogenesis • Host cellular and immune response to microbes • Immune evasion • Therapeutics • Evolution, epidemiology, and natural history of microbes • Vaccine design, development, and trials • year • Open-access, online-only • High-quality papers across life science spectrum • Focus on shorter, single-point articles, entitled Reports, in addition to longer articles • The primary criterion for both types of formats is new biological insight 12 issues per year • Embryonic stem cells • Pluripotency • Germline stem cells • Tissue-specific stem cells • Stem cell differentiation • Epigenetics • Stem cell genomics and systems biology • Genome reprogramming • Cancer stem cells • Stem cell niches • Stem cell-based disease models • Nuclear transfer technology • Bioengineering • Drug discovery • In vivo imaging of stem cells • Therapeutic applications • Regenerative medicine • Clinical and translational insights • Stem cell research policies, ethical issues, and technical or resource-based innovations 12 issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>29978</offset>
      <text> 12 issues per year • Immune cell development and senescence • Signal transduction • Gene regulation • Innate and adaptive immunity • Cytokines and inflammatory responses • Autoimmunity and tolerance • Infectious disease • Tumor immunology • Vaccine biology • Transplantation biology • Allergy and asthma 24 issues per year • Gene expression and transcriptional and epigenetic regulation • DNA replication, recombination, and repair • RNA processing • Translation • Protein folding, modification, and degradation • Signal transduction • Cell cycle • Cell death • Systems biology 24 issues per year • Developmental neurobiology • Cellular and molecular neuroscience • Synaptic transmission and plasticity • Ion channel structure and function • Behavioral and systems neuroscience • Cognitive neuroscience • Neurological and psychiatric disease • Computational neurobiology www.recruitmentads.cell.com CellPress Recruitment Media Kit 2018 11 12 issues per year • Atomic resolution analysis • X-ray crystallography • Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy • Computational analyses, simulations, and predictions • Electron microscopy • Neutron scattering • Hydrodynamics • X-ray absorption spectroscopy • Biochemical studies • Biophysical analyses • Fluorescence energy transfer • Design, construction, and analysis of novel protein and RNA structures • Catalytic activities • Medium-to low-resolution structural analysis • Single-molecule analysis • Small-angle X-ray scattering • Emerging methods in structure determination 12 issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31611</offset>
      <text> • Imaging and diagnostics • Stem cell products, manufacturing, and quality control • Ethical, legal, and social issues &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>31738</offset>
      <text> Molecular Therapy -Methods &amp; Clinical Development is an open-access journal publishing top-quality, novel methods, as well as significant improvements to established research techniques in basic, translational, and clinical cell and gene therapy. Topics of interest include gene vector engineering and production, methods for targeted genome editing and engineering, technology development for cell reprogramming, and directed differentiation of pluripotent cells. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32205</offset>
      <text> -18 14-Aug-18 21-Aug-18 28-Aug-18 04-Sep-18 11-Sep-18 18-Sep-18 25-Sep-18 Ad close / materials due 12- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32310</offset>
      <text> -18 13-Nov-18 20-Nov-18 27-Nov-18 04-Dec-18 11-Dec-18 18-Dec-18 26-Dec-18 Ad close / materials due 11- &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32415</offset>
      <text> Figure S1 . S1 Figure S1. (a) SEM images for bl-TiO2, bl-TiO2/SnO2, and (b) bl-TiO2/SnO2/mp-BSO and J-V curves for BSO based devices with and without SnO2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32573</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 . S2 Figure S2. Certification result of our PSC. Certification of BSO-based PSC tested at an independent and accredited PV testing lab (Newport). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32731</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. Hysteresis of BSO based PSC. Reverse and Forward J-V curves of BSO-based PSC tested at an independent and accredited PV testing lab (Newport). Inset shows photovoltaic parameters of mp-BSO based PSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>32959</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 .Figure S5 . S4S5 Figure S4. Process stability of BSO and TiO2 based PSCs. J-V curves of Li-doped TiO2-and BSObased PSCs fabricated and aged at 10% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33123</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 .Figure S7 . S6S7 Figure S6. Mott-Schottky plots for BSO and TiO2 films. Both TiO2 and BSO films show positive slope, indicating that both BSO and TiO2 have n-type property. Both films have identical slope, which means that their carrier density is almost same. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33397</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. TR-PL spectra for glass/perovskite, glass/Li:TiO2/perovskite and glass/BSO/perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>33518</offset>
      <text> Organometal-halide perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have emerged as very promising next-generation solar cells owing to their low fabrication cost and remarkable power conversion efficiency (PCE) of more than 24%. With improving the PCE, stability issues have been raised for commercialization. Recently, much effort has been made to enhance the stability of the perovskite layer and the hole transporting layer, which has successfully improved the durability of the device. However, little research has been done on the humidity stability of the metaloxide layer, especially conventional Li-doped TiO 2 . This issue is very important because moisture cannot be perfectly excluded in an actual production line. Herein, we provide deeper understanding of the degradation mechanism for Li-doped TiO 2based PSC under a humid environment and propose a new metal-oxide (BaSnO 3 ) ETL to improve both device performance and processing stability under a humid environment. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34483</offset>
      <text> Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Device Structure and Performance of BSO-Based PSCs (A) Device structure and the corresponding cross-sectional SEM image of a BSO-based PSC. (B) J-V curve of top-performing BSO-based PSC measured in Newport. The inset shows the stabilized PCE for top-performing BSO-based PSC. (C) Histogram for PCEs of BSO and TiO 2 : Li-based PSCs processed at 10% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>34861</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. Process Stability of BSO-and TiO 2 -Based PSCs (A) Evolution of average photovoltaic parameters with standard deviation, power conversion efficiency (PCE), short circuit current (J SC ), fill factor (FF), and open circuit voltage (V OC ), over 24 h at 40% RH. We compare the behavior of mp-BSO-and Li-doped mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs that are nonencapsulated. The errror bars indicate standard deviation of the PCEs measured from 16 devices for each condition. (B) Impedance spectra of Li-doped TiO 2 -and BSO-based PSCs fabricated and aged at 10% RH and 40% RH. (C) Dark J-V curves of Li-doped TiO 2 -and BSO-based PSCs fabricated and aged at 10% RH and 40% RH. Inset shows log(abs(J)) versus V curves. (D) Transient photocurrent decay curves for mp-BSO and Li doped mp-TiO 2 -based PSCs aged at 40% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35685</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. Surface Characteristic of Pure TiO 2 and Li-Doped TiO 2 (A) XPS spectra of Li-doped TiO 2 and BSO films at 10% and 40% RH. (B) FTIR spectra of TiO 2 and Li-doped TiO 2 film at 10% and 40% RH. (C and D) HR-TEM images of Li-doped TiO 2 nanoparticle at (C) 10% RH and (D) 40% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>35987</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 4 Figure4shows a schematic illustration of electron transport in typical bilayered devices employing mp-TiO 2 and mp-BSO as an ETL. As mentioned above, moisture in the air can induce Li x O on the TiO 2 surface by reacting with Li ions, regardless of the humidity level. In a low-humidity environment (Figure4A), even if Li x O is partially or very thinly formed on the TiO 2 surface, it does not have a significant effect on electron transport, thus maintaining excellent device performance. However, a high-humidity condition can promote the formation of Li x O on the TiO 2 surface, which can operate as a barrier layer for electron transport in TiO 2 (Figure4B). Such suppression of electron transport increases the resistance of the TiO 2 ETL, thereby deteriorating the device performance. Even with no additional doping of Li, BSO nanoparticles have intrinsic properties of high electron conductance and good chemical stability against moisture. Therefore, we could realize a highly efficient and stable PSC fabricated under a broad window of humidity (up to $40% RH) by incorporating BSO nanoparticles as an ETL in a typical bilayered architecture comprising an FA-based mixed perovskite and a mesoporous scaffold. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37220</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. Electron Transport Mechanism of Pure TiO 2 , Li-Doped TiO 2 , and BSO-based PSCs Schematic illustration of electron transport in pure TiO 2 , Li-doped TiO 2 -, and BSO-based ETL. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37424</offset>
      <text> Figure S1 . S1 Figure S1. (a) SEM images for bl-TiO2, bl-TiO2/SnO2, and (b) bl-TiO2/SnO2/mp-BSO and J-V curves for BSO based devices with and without SnO2. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37582</offset>
      <text> Figure S2 . S2 Figure S2. Certification result of our PSC. Certification of BSO-based PSC tested at an independent and accredited PV testing lab (Newport). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37740</offset>
      <text> Figure S3 . S3 Figure S3. Hysteresis of BSO based PSC. Reverse and Forward J-V curves of BSO-based PSC tested at an independent and accredited PV testing lab (Newport). Inset shows photovoltaic parameters of mp-BSO based PSC. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>37968</offset>
      <text> Figure S4 .Figure S5 . S4S5 Figure S4. Process stability of BSO and TiO2 based PSCs. J-V curves of Li-doped TiO2-and BSObased PSCs fabricated and aged at 10% RH. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38132</offset>
      <text> Figure S6 .Figure S7 . S6S7 Figure S6. Mott-Schottky plots for BSO and TiO2 films. Both TiO2 and BSO films show positive slope, indicating that both BSO and TiO2 have n-type property. Both films have identical slope, which means that their carrier density is almost same. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38406</offset>
      <text> Figure S8 . S8 Figure S8. TR-PL spectra for glass/perovskite, glass/Li:TiO2/perovskite and glass/BSO/perovskite films. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>38527</offset>
      <text> Cell Press is proud to publish 8 journals on behalf of learned societies, including the American Society of Human Genetics, the American Society of Gene and Cell Therapy, the Biophysical Society, and the International Society of Stem Cell Research as well as partner institutions such as the Institute of Plant Physiology and Ecology, the Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and the Chinese Society of Plant Biology. Society partner journals Cell Press research journals Impact Factor 4.945 NEW IN 2016 NEW IN 2017 NEW IN 2018 12 issues per year Life sciences • Cancer • Cell biology • Development • Immunology • Metabolism • Organic chemistry • Microbiology • Inorganic chemistry Physical sciences • Physical chemistry • Chemistry • Materials science • Energy • Nanoscience • Material science • Catalysis • Physics • Chemical biology • Polymer science • Analytical chemistry Environmental sciences Impact Factor • Supramolecular chemistry • Theoretical chemistry • Climate science • Atmospheric science • Computational chemistry • Ecology and evolution • Green chemistry • Hydrology • Energy and environmental chemistry • Solid earth science • Atmospheric chemistry • Food chemistry www.recruitmentads.cell.com CellPress Recruitment Media Kit 2018 13 Chem publishes work from across the chemical sciences and at the interfaces between chemistry and other disciplines. Chem showcases how fundamental studies in chemistry and its sub-disciplines may help in finding potential solutions to the global challenges of tomorrow. Joule is a home for outstanding and insightful research, analysis and ideas addressing a key global challenge: the need for more sustainable energy. Joule is a distinctive and forward-looking journal, bridging disciplines and scales of energy research, which connects all who are researching and analyzing the challenges -scientific, technical, economic, policy and social -of providing sustainable energy solutions.. • Batteries and supercapacitors • Biofuels and biotechnology • Carbon capture and storage • Energy access, security, and behavior • Energy grids and networks • Energy-harvesting devices • Energy policy and economics • Fuel cells and electrocatalysis • Geothermal energy • Hydrogen storage and energy • Materials for energy systems • Nuclear power • Solar energy • Techno-economic analysis and life-cycle assessment • Transportation fuels • Wave energy, wind energy, and hydroelectricity 12 issues per year &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>41112</offset>
      <text> Bonus Distribution means your advertisement will have broad visibility at key meetings and conferences throughout 2018. Cell Press journals will have extensive presence at many Keystone Symposia, Cell Symposia, LabLinks meetings, and additional society and annual meetings worldwide. Print rates Calendar American Journal of Human Genetics (AJHG) Volume(Issue) 102(1) 102(2) 102(3) 102(4) 102(5) 102(6) 103(1) 103(2) 103(3) 103(4) Rate 103(5) 103(6) Issue Date 04-Jan-18 01-Feb-18 01-Mar-18 05-Apr-18 03-May-18 07-Jun-18 05-Jul-18 02-Aug-18 06-Sep-18 Full 04-Oct-18 Half 01-Nov-18 Quarter 06-Dec-18 Ad close / materials due 14-Dec-17 11-Jan-18 08-Feb-18 15-Mar-18 12-Apr-18 17-May-18 14-Jun-18 12-Jul-18 16-Aug-18 Page 13-Sep-18 Page 11-Oct-18 Page 15-Nov-18 Cell Society and Annual Meetings Biophysical Journal (BPJ) $3,500 $2,400 $1,350 Neuron, AJHG, Biophysical Journal and Molecular Therapy Volume(Issue) 114(1) 114(2) 114(3) 114(4) 114(5) Conference/Meeting Name Issue Date 9-Jan-18 23-Jan-18 6-Feb-18 27-Feb-18 13-Mar-18 114(6) 27-Mar-18 114(7) Start Date 114(8) 10-Apr-18 24-Apr-18 $1,600 114(10) End Date Location 114(9) 8-May-18 22-May-18 $900 114(11) 5-Jun-18 114(12) $600 19-Jun-18 Cancer Cell, Cell Host &amp; Microbe, Cell Metabolism, Cell Stem Cell, Chemistry &amp; Biology, Society for Laboratory Automation and Screening 03-Feb-18 Ad close / materials due 19-Dec-17 02-Jan-18 16-Jan-18 06-Feb-18 20-Feb-18 06-Mar-18 20-Mar-18 03-Apr-18 Current Biology, Developmental Cell, Immunity, Molecular Cell, Structure and all Trends Journals 07-Feb-18 San Diego, CA, USA $1,200 $850 17-Apr-18 01-May-18 15-May-18 Colour 4 Colour Biophysical Society 17-Feb-18 Volume(Issue) 115(1) 115(2) 115(3) 115(4) 115(5) 115(6) 115(7) 115(8) 115(9) 115(10) 115(11) 21-Feb-18 San Francisco, CA, USA $540 29-May-18 115(12) Issue Date 3-Jul-18 17-Jul-18 7-Aug-18 21-Aug-18 4-Sep-18 18-Sep-18 2-Oct-18 16-Oct-18 6-Nov-18 20-Nov-18 4-Dec-18 18-Dec-18 Spot Colour American Association for Cancer Research 14-Apr-18 18-Apr-18 Chicago, IL, USA Ad close / materials due 12-Jun-18 26-Jun-18 17-Jul-18 31-Jul-18 14-Aug-18 28-Aug-18 11-Sep-18 25-Sep-18 16-Oct-18 30-Oct-18 13-Nov-18 27-Nov-18 American Society for Chemistry -Spring Cancer Cell (CCELL) 18-Mar-18 $500 22-Mar-18 New Orleans, LA, USA $250 Repeat discount American Association of Immunologists Volume(Issue) 33(1) 33(2) 33(3) 33(4) 33(5) 33(6) 34(1) 04-May-18 34(2) 15% 08-May-18 Austin, TX, USA 34(3) 34(4) 34(5) 34(6) American Society for Gene and Cell Therapy Issue Date 08-Jan-18 12-Feb-18 12-Mar-18 Ad close / materials due 15-Dec-17 22-Jan-18 19-Feb-18 09-Apr-18 19-Mar-18 14-May-18 23-Apr-18 11-Jun-18 21-May-18 16-May-18 09-Jul-18 13-Aug-18 18-Jun-18 23-Jul-18 10-Sep-18 19-May-18 Chicago, IL, USA 08-Oct-18 12-Nov-18 20-Aug-18 17-Sep-18 22-Oct-18 10-Dec-18 19-Nov-18 American Society for Microbiology 07-Jun-18 11-Jun-18 Atlanta, GA, USA International Society for Stem Cell Research Cell (CELL) Volume(Issue) 172(1 and 2) 172(3) 172(4) 172(5) 172(6) 173(1) 173(2) 20-Jun-18 173(3) 23-Jun-18 Melbourne, Australia 173(4) 173(5) 173(6) 173(7) Federation of European Neuroscience Societies Issue Date 11-Jan-18 25-Jan-18 08-Feb-18 22-Feb-18 08-Mar-18 22-Mar-18 05-Apr-18 07-Jul-18 19-Apr-18 11-Jul-18 03-May-18 17-May-18 31-May-18 14-Jun-18 Berlin, Germany American Society for Chemistry -Fall Ad close / materials due 21-Dec-17 04-Jan-18 18-Jan-18 01-Feb-18 15-Feb-18 01-Mar-18 15-Mar-18 19-Aug-18 29-Mar-18 23-Aug-18 Boston, MA, USA 12-Apr-18 26-Apr-18 10-May-18 24-May-18 NIH -Fall Research Festival Volume(Issue) 174(1) 174(2) Issue Date 28-Jun-18 12-Jul-18 174(3) 26-Jul-18 Sep-18 175(2) 09-Aug-18 23-Aug-18 06-Sep-18 20-Sep-18 04-Oct-18 174(4) 174(5) 174(6) 175(1) Sep-18 175(4) 18-Oct-18 175(3) 01-Nov-18 15-Nov-18 29-Nov-18 13-Dec-18 175(5) 175(6) 175(7) Bethesda, MD, USA American Society of Human Genetics Ad close / materials due 07-Jun-18 21-Jun-18 05-Jul-18 19-Jul-18 02-Aug-18 16-Aug-18 30-Aug-18 17-Oct-18 13-Sep-18 21-Oct-18 San Diego, CA, USA 27-Sep-18 11-Oct-18 25-Oct-18 08-Nov-18 22-Nov-18 Society for Neuroscience Cell Host &amp; Microbe (CHOM) 12-Nov-18 16-Nov-18 San Diego, CA, USA Materials Research Society -Fall Volume(Issue) 23(1) 23(2) 23(3) 23( 25-Nov-18 30-Nov-18 Boston, MA, USA American Society for Cell Biology 08-Dec-18 12-Dec-18 San Diego, CA, USA Cell Symposia Conference/Meeting Name Start Date End Date Location Trim Size Cell-Weizmann Institute of Science Symposium: Next Gen Immunology Live/"Safe" Area 11-Feb-18 14-Feb-18 Rehovot, Israel Bleed Full Page Multifaceted Mitochondria 8.375" x 10.875" 7.5" x 10" 04-Jun-18 8.625" x 11.125" 06-Jun-18 San Diego, CA, USA Translational Immunometabolism (212 mm x 276 mm) (190 mm x 254 mm) 24-Jun-18 26-Jun-18 Basel, Switzerland (219 mm x 282 mm) Double Page Spread The TCGA Legacy: Multi-omic Studies in Cancer 16.75" x 10.875" 15" x 10" 27-Sep-18 17.25" x 11.125" 29-Sep-18 Washington, DC, USA Aging and Metabolism (425 mm x 276 mm) (381 mm x 254 mm) 23-Sep-18 25-Sep-18 Sitges, Spain (438 mm x 282 mm) 1/2 Page Horizontal Cell-NERF Symposium: Engineering the Brain: Recent Developments in 7" x 4.5" 30-Sep-18 02-Oct-18 Leuven, Belgium Neurotechnologies (178 mm x 114 mm) 1/2 Page Vertical Translation of Pluripotent Stem Cells to the Clinic: Challenges and Opportunities 3.25" x 9.25" 04-Dec-18 04-Dec-18 Los Angeles, CA, USA RNA Biology (82 mm x 235 mm) TBD TBD TBD 1/4 Page 3.25" x 4.5" Cell Press LabLinks (82 mm x 114 mm) Conference/Meeting Name Date Location Translational Neuroscience Feb-18 Cambridge, MA, USA Systems Immunology Sep-18 San Francisco, CA, USA Microbiomes in Humans and Plants TBD Ghent, Belgium Overcoming Drug Resistance in Cancer TBD TBD Physical Sciences TBD TBD Metastasis TBD New York, NY, USA Chemical and Biological Innovations for Energy, Health, and Sanitation in the TBD Berkeley, CA, USA Developing World • File Format: PDF version 1.3; Acrobat Distiller 4.0 compatible • Color: CMYK and grayscale only • All fonts must be embedded and subset • Image resolution: 300 dpi minimum for color or grayscale images; 500 dpi minimum for combination color and grayscale images; 1,000 dpi minimum for monochrome bitmap (line art) images • All bitmapped or rasterized images should be saved as TIFF format rather than EPS • Do not use color management (i.e., no ICC profiling, SWOP, or RBG color) • DO NOT INCLUDE: OPI information, transparencies, PEG/GIF/copydot elements &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>47548</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . The parameters of the mp-BSO based perovskite solar cells S1 Voc(V) Jsc(mA/cm 2 ) FF(%) Efficiency(%) 1 1.13 24.1 80 21.8 2 1.13 23.7 77.5 20.9 3 1.14 23.8 78.6 21.2 4 1.14 24.1 73.6 20.2 5 1.13 24 79.5 21.5 6 1.13 24 80.6 21.8 7 1.11 24.2 82 22 8 1.11 24.3 81.3 21.9 9 1.12 24.5 79.1 21.6 1.1 24.1 75.5 20.2 1.12 24.6 79.4 22 1.13 24.3 79.3 21.8 1.12 23.9 79 21.3 1.12 24 77.5 21 1.13 24.2 78.9 21.7 1.14 23.9 79.2 21.7 1.14 23.8 80.4 21.9 1.14 23.9 79.3 21.8 1.14 24.4 78.8 22.1 1.14 24.1 78 21.6 1.15 23.9 79.4 21.8 1.14 23.9 78.5 21.5 1.13 24.1 75.8 20.8 1.13 24.2 77.5 21.1 1.13 24 74.6 20.4 1.13 23.9 75 20.2 1.12 24 74.1 20.1 1.13 24.2 75.8 20.9 1.11 23.5 80.6 21 1.1 23.3 80.7 20.8 1.11 23.7 80 21 1.12 24.3 79.4 21.8 1.12 24.1 78.4 21.3 1.12 24.7 78.6 21.7 1.12 24 81.4 21.8 1.12 24.6 79.7 21.9 1.12 24.2 80.5 21.8 1.12 24.3 80 21.8 1.12 24.6 80 22 1.13 24.8 79.6 22.3 1.13 24.1 80.6 21.9 1.13 24.1 81.7 22.2 1.13 24.4 80.7 22.4 Average 1.13 ± 0.01 24.11 ± 0.31 78.84 ± 2.07 21.45 ± 0.61 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>48562</offset>
      <text> Table S1 . The parameters of the mp-BSO based perovskite solar cells S1 Voc(V) Jsc(mA/cm 2 ) FF(%) Efficiency(%) 1 1.13 24.1 80 21.8 2 1.13 23.7 77.5 20.9 3 1.14 23.8 78.6 21.2 4 1.14 24.1 73.6 20.2 5 1.13 24 79.5 21.5 6 1.13 24 80.6 21.8 7 1.11 24.2 82 22 8 1.11 24.3 81.3 21.9 9 1.12 24.5 79.1 21.6 1.1 24.1 75.5 20.2 1.12 24.6 79.4 22 1.13 24.3 79.3 21.8 1.12 23.9 79 21.3 1.12 24 77.5 21 1.13 24.2 78.9 21.7 1.14 23.9 79.2 21.7 1.14 23.8 80.4 21.9 1.14 23.9 79.3 21.8 1.14 24.4 78.8 22.1 1.14 24.1 78 21.6 1.15 23.9 79.4 21.8 1.14 23.9 78.5 21.5 1.13 24.1 75.8 20.8 1.13 24.2 77.5 21.1 1.13 24 74.6 20.4 1.13 23.9 75 20.2 1.12 24 74.1 20.1 1.13 24.2 75.8 20.9 1.11 23.5 80.6 21 1.1 23.3 80.7 20.8 1.11 23.7 80 21 1.12 24.3 79.4 21.8 1.12 24.1 78.4 21.3 1.12 24.7 78.6 21.7 1.12 24 81.4 21.8 1.12 24.6 79.7 21.9 1.12 24.2 80.5 21.8 1.12 24.3 80 21.8 1.12 24.6 80 22 1.13 24.8 79.6 22.3 1.13 24.1 80.6 21.9 1.13 24.1 81.7 22.2 1.13 24.4 80.7 22.4 Average 1.13 ± 0.01 24.11 ± 0.31 78.84 ± 2.07 21.45 ± 0.61 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49576</offset>
      <text>			 CellPress Recruitment Media Kit 2018 www.recruitmentads.cell.com &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49646</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 1977-1985, August 21, 2019 ª 2019 Elsevier Inc. 1977 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49714</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 1977 -1985 , August 21, 2019  1979    &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49766</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 1977 -1985 , August 21, 2019   &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49811</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 1977 -1985 , August 21, 2019  1981    &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>49863</offset>
      <text>			 Joule 3, 1977 -1985 , August 21, 2019  1983</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
