<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection>
  <source/>
  <date/>
  <key/>
  <document>
    <id>250108025037119BDDACE</id>
    <infon key="tt_curatable">no</infon>
    <infon key="tt_version">1</infon>
    <infon key="tt_round">1</infon>
    <passage>
      <offset>0</offset>
      <text>Paper #: 76&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>12</offset>
      <text>Suppressed Halide Ion Migration in 2D Lead Halide Perovskites&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>74</offset>
      <text>Two-dimensional (2D) lead halide perovskites represent an emerging class of materials given their tunable optoelectronic properties and long-term stability in perovskite solar cells. In order to assess the halide ion mobility, we have tracked the changes in the bromide and iodide composition in physically paired 2D lead halide perovskite films of different layer numbers (n = 10-1). These low-dimensional perovskites suppressed halide ion migration as a result of their intercalated spacer ligands and their strong van der Waals interactions. The rate constants for halide exchange of low dimensionality perovskites follow the Arrhenius relationship with thermal activation energy ranging from 58 kJ/mol (n = 10) to 72 kJ/mol (n = 1). The suppression of halide ion mobility (and diffusion coefficient) with modulating perovskite layer number (n) provides further insight into the role of 2D perovskites in improving the performance of photovoltaic devices.&#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>1033</offset>
      <text>A s an alternative to three-dimensional (3D) ABX 3 lead halide perovskites, two-dimensional (2D), e.g., the Ruddlesden-Popper phase, perovskites have drawn attention in stabilizing solar cells.  [1] [2] [3] [4] [5]  The tunable layer number (n) in the 2D perovskites with R 2 A n-1 B n X 3n+1 (R: intercalating cation) provides flexibility in tailoring optoelectronic properties such as tunable bandgap energy, exciton binding energy, and emission wavelength across the entire visible.  3, [6] [7] [8] [9] [10]  Furthermore, as a result of the intercalated organic spacer ligands, 2D and 2D/3D heterostructure perovskite solar cells also exhibit suppressed halide ion migration and enhanced long-term device stabilities against moisture and heat under operating conditions.  [11] [12] [13] [14] [15] [16] [17]  Halide ion mobility in lead halide perovskites that arise from soft, ionic crystalline lattices remains a topic of recent debate since it directly affects the perovskite device performances.  [18] [19] [20] [21]  Specifically, the mixed halide perovskite films undergo halide phase segregations under continuous light irradiation, and the original mixed halide composition is restored upon stopping the illumination.  [22] [23] [24]  Several mechanistic models have been proposed to explain the intriguing, reversible photoinduced phase segregation and dark recovery, including polaron-induced lattice strain,  25  two-state thermodynamic model,  26  and defect-driven halide ion movement.  22, [27] [28] [29]  In a recent study, we have shown that the halide ion mobility under light irradiation originates from hole trapping at the iodide site, and there is a threshold for energy of photo-excitation that is needed to overcome the entropy of mixing.  22, 30, 31  The increase in stability, despite the trade-off of lower efficiency, has fueled the utilization of 2D lead halide perovskites in solar cells and optoelectronic devices.  32  However, the halide ion mobility in two-dimensional metal halide perovskites has been less studied as compared to 3D perovskites. Temperature-dependent conductivity measurements have provided some insight of halide ion movement in low-dimensional perovskites. An activation energy of 41 ± 7 meV was estimated for the electronic conduction in the dark and under illumination.  28, 33  The complex interplay between ionic and electronic conductivity dictated by different temperature regimes is still under discussion. In a previous study we have demonstrated a solid-state halide ion exchange in the paired 3D MAPbBr 3 /MAPbI 3 films by tracking absorption changes with time.  34  Upon being subjected to thermal activation, mechanically clamped films undergo the halide ion exchange across the interface. Strong temperaturedependent halide ion mobility (and diffusion coefficient) in these 3D systems follows the Arrhenius relationship with a thermal activation energy of 51 kJ/mol.  22, 34  A fundamental question that arises is how the dimensionality (n) affects the halide ion mobility within these 2D perovskites. In order to obtain a better understanding of halide ion mobility in low-dimensional perovskites, we have now probed halide ion movement in the 2D layered lead halide perovskites (n = 10-1). The halide ion mobility dependence on the perovskite layer number (n) can provide fundamental insight into designing perovskite devices with more desired properties. Halide Ion Homogenization in Paired 2D Halide Perovskite Films. One of the convenient ways to monitor halide ion mobility is to monitor the halide compositional changes through absorption and emission spectra.  [22] [23] [24] 26, 34, 35  Since the bandgap of mixed halide perovskite films shifts linearly with the ratio of halides (e.g., Br:I in MAPbBr x I 3-x ), we can monitor the changes in the onset of the absorption peak.  30, 36  In order to investigate the effect of dimensionality (n) of 2D layered perovskite on the halide ion mobility, 2D lead halide perovskite films with tunable layer numbers (n = 10-1) were prepared using the experimental procedure reported previously (see the Supporting Information).  1, 2, 6  Stable 2D lead halide perovskite films with tunable layer numbers of n = 10, 6, 3-2, and 1 were obtained by varying the cation ratio of methylammonium:phenylethylammonium (MA:PEA) of 80:20, 66:33, 33:66, and 0:100, respectively. The corresponding layer number (n) of 2D lead halide (bromide and iodide) perovskite films was assigned based on the exciton absorption peak position.  3, 6, 8, 9, [37] [38] [39]  The absorption spectra of 2D lead bromide and lead iodide perovskite films of different n values are presented in the Supporting Information. It is worth noting that 2D layered perovskite films (n&lt;6) have a propensity for formation of mixed phases with different n values due to the similar formation enthalpy of 2D layers (-50 ∼ -80 kJ/mol for the layer number of n = 1-5), as can be seen from Figure  S2 .  37  We probed the exchange of halide ions between 2D lead bromide and lead iodide films by pairing the two films with direct physical contact. The glass slides of different 2D perovskite films with the same layer number (n) but with different halides (viz., bromide on one slide and iodide on the other slide) were clamped together with binder clips. The physically paired films were placed on the temperaturecontrolled hot plate in the range of 23-140 °C. The clamped films were maintained at a constant temperature to induce migration of bromide and iodide across the two films. All halide ion exchange experiments were carried out ≤140 °C to avoid thermal-induced destabilization of the perovskites.  40  The absorption spectra of paired films (and separated film) were recorded periodically until the films are fully homogenized (i.e., the films attained halide equilibrium). Figures  1A  and 1B  show the absorption spectra of 2D lead halide (bromide and iodide) perovskite films with n = 10 and n = 1 before (spectra a and b) and after annealing (spectra a′ and b′) at 140 °C, respectively. For the films with n = 10, both excitonic absorption peaks were observed at 510 nm and at 735 nm corresponding to 2D lead bromide and lead iodide perovskites (Figure  1A ). The absorption characteristics of 2D perovskite films with n = 10 closely resemble those of the corresponding 3D perovskite films. When physically paired films of these two perovskites are subjected to thermal treatment for a period of 60 min, we induce migration of Br and I from one side to the other until both films are homogenized. Insets of Figure  1A  and Figure  S1  confirmed visual color changes of the films from greenish yellow (lead bromide) and from dark brown (lead iodide) to similar light brown (mixed halide composition) following homogenization. This observation is confirmed from the single characteristic peak at 615 nm in both films (spectra a′ and b′ in Figure  1 ). Similar absorption changes were observed for paired films with the single-layer 2D lead bromide and lead iodide perovskite films. The initial absorption maximum peaks at 405 nm for 2D lead bromide and at 515 nm for 2D lead iodide perovskites merged to produce a single absorption peak at 435 nm following homogenization at 140 °C (Figure  1B ). We also extended these thermally induced exchange of halides in 2D perovskites with n = 6, 3-2, and 1, respectively (Figures  S2  and 1B ). The thermally-activated halide ion movement across the interface of 2D lead halide films with the layer number of n can be described by eq 1.  + → - + - + - + ( Interestingly, all of the 2D perovskite films were fully homogenized at 140 °C within 60-120 min. To track the kinetics of halide ion exchange between bromide and iodide 2D perovskite films, absorption spectra were recorded at intermediate times. The representative spectra for 2D perovskite films with n = 10 and n = 1 are shown in Figures  2A  and 2B . With increasing annealing time, the absorption spectra show significant changes with the appearance of a new absorption band at 610 nm for 2D perovskite films with n = 10 (Figure  2A ) and 430 nm for perovskite films with n = 1 (Figure  2B ). The appearance of the new band confirms the formation of mixed halide composition as the films are homogenized. The changes in the absorption during the homogenization process are better visualized through difference absorption (ΔA) spectra. By subtracting the absorption spectrum (t = 0 min) from the spectra recorded at different times, we can observe the change in absorbance that occurs during the course of homogenization (Figure  2C  and D ). These spectra further highlight the disappearance of bromide and iodide 2D perovskite and appearance of a new band corresponding to the mixed halide formation. These spectral evolutions also point out that the time required for homogenization (or mixing of Br and I) for 2D perovskites with n = 1 is greater than n = 10. Activation Energy of Halide Exchange in 2D Perovskites. The mixing of halide ion (or homogenization) is an entropically-driven process as the mixed halide phase is thermodynamically more favorable.  26  The halide ion homogenization experiments (as described in Figure  2 ) were repeated with paired films with n = 10, 6, and 1 at different temperatures. The absorption changes at 495 nm with time at different temperatures (140-23 °C) show an increased rate of bromide disappearance from the 2D lead bromide perovskite (n = 10) film (Figure  3A ). The individual absorption (and difference absorption) spectra corresponding to these kinetic traces with n = 10 are shown in Figure  S3 . At room temperature (23 °C), we notice negligible change in absorption. However, the rate of homogenization of the two paired halide film increased with increasing temperature. Since the absorption shifted to shorter wavelengths upon mixing of iodide with bromide, we were able to track the change in the bandgap of the materials. As shown earlier,  30, 36  the bandgap of the mixed halide film directly correlates with the Br:I ratio. Figure  3B  shows the kinetic traces of rate of change in iodide (in 2D lead iodide perovskite film) as monitored from the shift in the bandgap with time. The bandgap was measured from the Tauc plots (Figure  S4 ) using the absorption spectra recorded at different temperatures (140-23 °C). The bandgap of pure 2D lead iodide film (∼1.6 eV) shifts to 1.9 eV as the film undergoes homogenization and attains mixed halide composition. The halide composition of mixed halide films after homogenization was further confirmed by energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS) elemental analyses and mappings. Both 2D lead bromide and lead iodide films following homogenization at 140 °C for 1 h show homogeneous elemental distributions of Pb, Br, and I across the films along with equimolar ratio of Br:I = 1:1 (Figure  S5 ). These changes in absorption and EDS mapping confirmed the bidirectional movement of bromide and iodide in paired films and the rate of exchange of halide ions being dependent on the temperature. The pseudo-first-order rate constants (k, s -1 ) were determined from fitting all the traces shown in Figures  3A  and 3B  (absorption and Tauc plots) with monoexponential fits. The apparent rate constants for halide ion exchange in the films of n = 10 increased by 2 orders of magnitude from 1.75 × 10 -5 to 1.09 × 10 -3 s -1 (from absorption plots) and from 1.85 × 10 -5 to 1.15 × 10 -3 s -1 (from Tauc plots) upon increasing the annealing temperature from 60 to 140 °C. The temperature-dependent halide ion exchange rate constants were then analyzed using Arrhenius relationships (eq 2). = - + k E RT A ln( ) / ln( ) a (2) From the linear dependence of ln(k) versus 1/T (Figure  3C ), we determined an activation energy (E a ) for halide ion exchange to be 57.8 ± 2.4 kJ/mol (from change in absorption at 495 nm, Figure  3A ) and 59.5 ± 2.8 kJ/mol (from Tauc analysis, Figure  3B ), respectively. Similarity between these activation energy values further validates our analysis of tracking halide ion homogenization by monitoring the optical changes either in 2D lead bromide or 2D lead iodide in the paired films. We repeated the above temperature-dependent homogenization rate constant measurements for other 2D perovskite films (n = 6 and 1). The individual absorption spectra along with corresponding difference absorption spectra during homogenization were recorded for n = 6 (Figure  S6A-H ) and for n = 1 (Figures  2B, 2D  and S7A-F ). The absorption  changes in the paired 2D lead halide films with n = 6 (at 488 nm) and n = 1 (at 403 nm) as a function of annealing time at different temperatures (140-60 °C) and associated kinetic fits are shown in Figure  S8 . The Arrhenius plots (ln(k) versus 1/ T) of these two 2D perovskite films with n = 6 and 1 are compared with that of n = 10 in Figure  4A . The activation energy for halide exchange determined from these plots was 66.9 ± 0.6 kJ/mol (n = 6) and 71.5 ± 2.0 kJ/ mol (n = 1). It is evident that the activation energy increases with decreasing n value of the 2D perovskites. The activation energy as a function of the perovskite layer number (n), plotted in Figure  4B , shows a marked increase in the activation energy when the n value decreases from 10 to 1. Since 2D perovskites with n = 10 resemble that of bulk perovskite (n = ∞), we only see a small change in E a . The increased activation energy with the decreasing layer number of 2D perovskite (n &lt; 10) shows the increased thermal barrier for the halide ion mobility in 2D perovskites as compared to their 3D counterparts. As one would expect, the intercalation of the bulky phenylethylammonium cation in 2D layered perovskite architectures hinders the halide ion mobility. During halide exchanges, the bromide and iodide halide ions diffuse in opposite directions. The bromide ions diffuse into iodide side, while the iodide ions move into the bromide side until the two physically paired films equilibrate with a nearly 50:50 Br:I composition. A simplified version of Fick's second law is employed to calculate the apparent diffusion coefficient (eq 3). The parameters evaluated from the halide exchange lifetime are listed in Table 1 τ = d l / 2 diffusion ( 3 ) where d is defined as the effective diffusion coefficient, l is defined as the diffusion length (average film thickness), and τ diffusion is defined as average lifetime of halide exchange. The diffusion length (l) corresponds to the distance between two centers of paired 2D lead halide films as there is only one directional movement for each halide ion diffusion (vice versa). The average film thickness of the films between n = 10 and n = 1 was determined to be 97 ± 15 nm from crosssectional SEM image analyses by averaging out the thickness of four films (Figure  S9 ). For the calculation of the diffusion coefficient, we employed a value of l = ∼100 nm. The diffusion coefficients summarized in Table  1  show that the 2D perovskite layer number (n) dictates the halide ion mobility. The diffusion coefficient values measured in the temperature range of 60-140 °C were in the range of 10 -15 -10 -13 cm 2 s -1 (Table  1 ). The film of n = 1 generally has a lower diffusion coefficient as compared to the film of n = 6 or n = 10 at the same temperature due to the increased fraction of organic layers suppressing halide ion movement. The observed values are consistent with the previous reports measured using absorption and emission spectroscopy.  34, 41  This suppressed halide ion mobility in 2D perovskites explains the improved stability one observes in perovskite solar cells with the introduction of a small amount of 2D perovskites.  16, 42  The apparent diffusion coefficient values for all perovskite films (n = 1, 6, 10) increased by 2 orders of magnitude with increasing the temperature from 60 °C to 140 °C. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations have shown that halide ion movement is facilitated by vacancy-mediated halide transport.  28, 33  The 2D lead halide perovskites which have higher halide vacancy formation energy (5.46 eV) than that of conventional 3D MAPbI 3 perovskites (3.44 eV) also contribute to the overall lower halide ion mobility.  28  During the halide ion homogenization discussed in the experiments above, we expect the halide ion diffusion to be affected by diffusion length, crystallinity of films, crystallographic grain boundary, and number of halide ion vacancy sites.  35  The crystallographic domain size and shape of the 2D lead halide perovskite films (between n = 10 and n = 1) employed in this study remain unchanged after homogenization (Figure  S10 ). The halide ion diffusion across the films is driven by thermal activation of vacancy-mediated halide ion movement. Scheme 1 compares the halide ion migrations (and exchange) across the interface of the paired 2D lead bromide and lead iodide perovskite films with different dimensionalities of n = 10 and 1. The halide ion mobility in the 2D architecture is reduced through the introduction of the organic cation between different layers within the film. The intercalated organic spacer ligands, thus, effectively suppress the halide ion mobility across the films, resulting in long-term stability of lowdimensional perovskite films. Similar stabilization aspects of 2D have been observed in the long-term operation of solar cells.  16, 28, 33  The comparison of halide mobility in the present study offers direct evidence for the suppressed mobility of halides in 2D perovskites. Table  1 . Halide Ion Diffusion Parameters for the 2D Perovskite Films with n = 10, 6, and 1 a temp (°C) for n = 10 lifetime, min (diffusion coeff, cm 2 s -1 ) for n = 6 lifetime, min (diffusion coeff, cm 2 s -1 ) or n = 1 lifetime, min (diffusion coeff, cm The diffusion coefficients are shown within parentheses. In summary, a simple approach of pairing two dissimilar 2D perovskite films provides a means of tracking the halide ion movement. The halide ion movement can be tracked by recording the absorption spectra of the physically paired 2D lead halide perovskite films with different dimensionality of n = 10-1. The temperature-and layer-number-dependence of halide ion mobility sheds light on the overall stability of 2D lead halide films. Efforts are underway to elucidate the reversible photoinduced halide phase segregation and dark recovery in the 2D lead halide perovskites.  &#13;</text>
      <annotation id="1">
        <infon key="type">perovskite_composition</infon>
        <infon key="identifier">MAPbBr 3</infon>
        <infon key="annotator">jillnomura1211@gmail.com</infon>
        <infon key="updated_at">2025-02-16T03:18:26Z</infon>
        <location offset="3594" length="8"/>
        <text>MAPbBr 3</text>
      </annotation>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19541</offset>
      <text> S1 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19546</offset>
      <text> Supporting Information &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19571</offset>
      <text> Suppressed Halide Ion Migration in 2D Lead Halide Perovskites Junsang Cho 1 , Jeffrey T. DuBose 1,2 , An Ngoc Thien Le 3 , Prashant V. Kamat Corresponding Author: pkamat@nd.edu &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19750</offset>
      <text> S2 &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>19755</offset>
      <text> Experimental Section Materials. Phenylethylammonium bromide (PEABr, Greatcell Solar), Phenylethylammonium bromide (PEAI, Greatcell Solar), methylammonium bromide (MABr, Greatcell Solar), methyl ammonium iodide (MAI, Greatcell Solar), lead bromide (PbBr 2 , 99.99%, Sigma-aldrich), lead iodide (PbI 2 , 99.99% with 10 mesh bead, Alfa-Aesar), dimethylformamide (DMF, anhydrous 99.8%, Sigma-Aldrich), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, anhydrous 99.9%, Sigma-Aldrich), chlorobenzene (anhydrous 99.8%, Sigma-Aldrich), fluorine-doped tin oxide conducting glass (FTO, Pilkinton glass). All chemicals were used as received without additional purification. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>20397</offset>
      <text> 2D Lead Halide Perovskite Films with different dimensionality (n). The preparation of 2D lead halide (bromide and iodide) perovskite films with tunable layer numbers of n = 10-1 follows the previously reported method in the literature.  [1] [2] [3]  FTO-coated glasses (2.5 cm × 2.5 cm) were used as a substrate to make 2D layered perovskite films. The FTO substrates were cleaned with soapy water and sonicated in an ethanol bath for 20 min. After that, the substrates were rinsed additionally with excess isopropanaol and dried with air-stream at ambient conditions. To remove any organic residues, the FTO substrates were further treated with plasma for 10 minutes. The FTO substrates were then immediately transferred to a N 2 -filled glovebox for the deposition of lead halide films. The 2D perovskite films were prepared in the glove box (&lt; 10 ppm H 2 O). The 2D lead bromide and iodide perovskite films were made through the same procedures except for the halide (X = Br and I) precursors employed for the synthesis. The mixed precursor solutions containing MAX, PEAX, and PbX 2 with a stoichiometric amount was used to control the dimensionality (n). The ratio of MAX:PEAX were systematically varied such as MA:PEA = 80:20 (n = 10), 66:33 (n = 6), 33:66 (n = 3-2), and 0:100 (n = 1), respectively. The mixed solutions dissolved in DMF:DMSO mixture with a 4:1 volumetric ratio were vigorously stirred for 1 hr at room temperature. The precursor solutions were then syringe-filtered through a 0.2 μm PTFE membrane filter. The 2D lead halide perovskite films were acquired through static spin-casting of 50 μL of 0.6 M PbX 2 precursor solution followed by spin-coating at 4000 rpm for 25 s with an acceleration of 1200 rpm. A 0.5 mL of chlorobenzene was rapidly injected as antisolvent after 10 seconds. After spin-casting process was completed, the perovskite films were transferred to using a hot plate and annealed at 100 °C for 5 minutes. The films were cooled down and stored inside of the glovebox until use. Halide Ion Homogenization Experiments. The 2D lead halide (bromide and iodide) perovskite films with different layer number of n = 10-1 were physically paired each other, clamped with binder clips, and then transferred to a pre-heated hot plate with different homogenization temperature (140-23 °C). Care was taken to keep the annealing temperature of the paired 2D lead halide perovskite films at constant temperature. The clamped films were then placed on a &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>22884</offset>
      <text> S3 brass plate for direct-heating of the paired films. The temperature of the brass plate was monitored and controlled by adjusting the temperature of the hotplate. The clamped (or separated) films were periodically monitored during homogenization process. The completion of homogenization was visually inspected based upon the change of film colors and confirmed by spectroscopic measurements. Steady State Absorption Measurements. UV-Vis absorption spectra were obtained using a Varian Cary 50 bio spectrophotometer in the wavelength of 450-800 nm for 2D lead halide perovskite films with n = 10 and 350-700 nm for 2D lead halide perovskite films with n = 1. The difference absorption spectra were acquired by subtracting the absorption spectrum at 0 min (as a reference) from the absorption spectra acquired at different annealing (or homogenization) time. Tauc Plot Analysis in conjunction with Estimation of Bandgap energy. The absorption spectra were converted to Tauc plots using the equation of (αhν) 2 versus hν for the directlyallowed transitions materials. The straight line was fitted and extrapolated from the curvature onto X-axis to estimate the bandgap energy (E g ) of the perovskites during the course of homogenization at different temperature with time. Halide ion compositions were further analyzed based upon the bandgap energy of mixed lead iodide perovskite films with n = 10 determined from the Tauc plots (equations 1 and 2). The estimated bandgap energy (E g ) is determined to be 1.62 eV for pure 2D lead iodide film with n = 10, 2.24 eV for pure 2D lead bromide film with n = 10, and 1.93 eV for mixed 2D halide film with n = 10 (Br:I = 50:50). A simple Vegard's law with a linear interpolation is applied to approximate the halide composition. I composition (%) = [(2.24 -E g (mixed iodide film))/(0.62)] x 100 equation (1) Br composition (%) = 100 -I composition (%) equation (  2 ) Characterizations. Top-down view, cross-sectional SEM imaging, and EDS spectra were acquired using a Magellan 400 digital field emission scanning electron microscope operated with a beam voltage of 5 kV.      Figure 1 . 1 Figure 1. Absorption spectra of the two separated 2D lead halide (X = Br and I) perovskite films with different layer numbers of (A) n = 10 and (B) n = 1 before (a,b) and after (a′,b′) homogenization at 140 °C. The paired 2D lead bromide and lead iodide perovskite films were clamped together and thermally treated at 140 °C. Insets of A and B show the digital photographs taken for separated 2D lead bromide and lead iodide films before (a,b) and after homogenization (a′,b′). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25513</offset>
      <text> Figure 2 . 2 Figure 2. (A, B) Absorption spectra of the paired 2D lead halide (bromide/iodide) perovskite films with (A) n = 10 and (B) n = 1, recorded at 140 °C as a function of homogenization time (a-e). (C, D) Corresponding difference absorption spectra in panels A and B, wherein 0 min spectrum (a) served as a reference. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>25842</offset>
      <text> Figure 3 . 3 Figure 3. (A) Changes in the absorption of the excitonic peak at 495 nm observed in 2D lead bromide perovskite film (n = 10) from difference absorption spectra at different temperatures of (a) 140 °C, (b) 105 °C, (c) 80 °C, (d) 60 °C, and (e) 23 °C during the homogenization process. (B) Temporal evolution of bandgap energy of mixed 2D lead iodide films (n = 10) estimated from Tauc plots. (C) Arrhenius plot of natural log of the rate constants versus inverse of temperature obtained from panels A and B, respectively. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26383</offset>
      <text> Figure 4 . 4 Figure 4. (A) Arrhenius plots of ln(k) versus 1/T obtained from the 2D lead halide perovskite films with different dimensionality of n = 10 (a), 6 (b), and 1 (c), respectively. (B) Activation energy obtained from panel A versus number of layers (n). The activation energy of 51 kJ/mol was used for n = ∞ according to a previous report by Elmelund et al. 30  The error bars in panel A are derived from two different measurements. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26829</offset>
      <text> Scheme 1 . 1 Scheme 1. Schematic Illustration of Halide Ion Movement Across the Interface of the Paired 2D Lead Halide Films with n = 10 and 1 a &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>26976</offset>
      <text> Figure S10 . S10 Figure S10. Top-down view SEM images before (A,C,E,G; left) and after (B,D,F,Hl right) homogenization at 140 °C for 2 hr with the 2D lead halide perovskite film of (A,B) X = Br (n = 10), (C,D) X = I (n =10), (E,F) X= Br (n = 1), and (G,H) X = I (n = 1). &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27250</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.0c00124 ACS Materials Lett. 2020, 2, 565-570 Downloaded via UNIV OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO on November 8, 2024 at 06:44:17 (UTC).See https://pubs.acs.org/sharingguidelines for options on how to legitimately share published articles. &#13;</text>
    </passage>
    <passage>
      <offset>27530</offset>
      <text>			 https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.0c00124 ACS Materials Lett. 2020, 2, 565-570</text>
    </passage>
  </document>
</collection>
