<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
				<funder ref="#_YjXm6FM">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_HQJvWMH">
					<orgName type="full">Ontario Research Fund</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_v8JMUpZ #_cHbbeg2">
					<orgName type="full">Ontario Research Fund-Research Excellence Round 7)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">-Ministry of Research and Innovation</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_8fQexMP">
					<orgName type="full">US Department of the Navy, Office of Naval</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_FTCT46E">
					<orgName type="full">National Science Fund of China</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_Ezns4Du">
					<orgName type="full">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST) Office of Sponsored Research</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">OSR</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_gBYH7zm">
					<orgName type="full">US Department of Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Canadian Foundation for Innovation and the Natural Science and Engineering Council of Canada (NSERC)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_3jEkhtJ #_BaCyPP7">
					<orgName type="full">National Key Research Program</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2022-04-07">7 April 2022</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><roleName>Prof</roleName><forename type="middle">Edward</forename><surname>Sargent</surname></persName>
							<email>ted.sargent@utoronto.ca</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Prof</roleName><forename type="first">Zhijun</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Edward S. Rogers</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M5S 3G4</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>Ontario</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Physical Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Tech University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>201210</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Kentucky</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>40506</postCode>
									<settlement>Lexington</settlement>
									<region>Kentucky</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 Engineering Drive 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>117585</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>5 King&apos;s College Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>M5S 3G8</postCode>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<region>ON</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">KAUST Solar Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Materials Science and Engineering Program (MSE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Physical Sciences and Engineering Division (PSE)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Thuwal</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SA">Saudi Arabia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2022-04-07">7 April 2022</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">2B0A70E315D59DAD22A6543C74EA93E9</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41566-022-00985-1</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: 13 July 2021; Accepted: 21 February 2022;</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Thicknesses were chosen to reflect our device architecture Bandgap: The bandgaps of SnO2 and NiOx were taken from 5 and 6 respectively. The bandgaps of 3D and 2D perovskites were taken from our photo-electron spectroscopy results (Table <ref type="table">S1</ref> and<ref type="table">S2</ref> respectively).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Electron affinity:</head><p>The electron affinities of SnO2 and NiOx were taken from 5 and 6 respectively. The electron affinities of different 2D perovskite species were taken from our photo-electron spectroscopy results (Table <ref type="table">S2</ref>). For 3D perovskite, we used the same value used in similar simulations in 1 , referenced from 7 which is almost identical to the value derived from photo-electron measurements (Table <ref type="table">S1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dielectric permittivity:</head><p>The dielectric permittivity of SnO2, 3D perovskite and NiOx were taken from 8-10 respectively. 2D perovskite was taken to be the same as 3D perovskite due to a lack reliable literature. The same assumption was made when simulating solar cells in 1 , and a similar value for 2D perovskite was used in SCAPS simulations in 18  .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conduction/valence band effective density of states:</head><p>The effective density of states for the conduction and valence bands (NC and NV respectively) were calculated using standard equations:</p><p>where k is Boltzmann's constant, T is temperature and h is Planck's constant. The effective masses of electrons and holes (𝑚 𝑒 * and 𝑚 ℎ * respectively) were found in the literature. For SnO2, the value for electrons was taken from 11 and for holes it was assumed to be the same as the absorber, an assumption used previously in 19 . For perovskite, values from 12 were used. For NiOx, values from 13 were used. For 2D materials these equations are no longer valid. However, previous SCAPS nature research | solar cells reporting summary</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S1 | Summary of PSC efficiency/stability</head><p>A comparison of device efficiency and stability from many high-profile perovskite solar cell papers from 2019 onwards. This summary demonstrates that the majority of high performing NIP PSCs use a 2D/3D heterostructure. It also showcases the stability advantages of PIN solar cells. In this work we sought to use both of these for excellent stability and efficiency. All references can be found in Table <ref type="table">7</ref>.   <ref type="table">S1</ref> | Calculated band alignment values from a linear fitting of Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">S2a</ref> (semi-log plot) and Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">S2b</ref> (linear plot). These values were combined with the optical bandgap found from TA spectra to calculate the band alignment of &lt;n&gt; = 1,2,3 and 4 films.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text 1 | Reduced performance of the standard 2D treatment in PIN</head><p>As mentioned in the main manuscript, it has been reported that standard 2D treatments do not produce improved performance in PIN devices as they do in NIP. We confirmed this ourselves by fabricating PIN (NiOx/3D-perovskite/2D/C60/ALD-SnO2/Ag) and NIP (SnO2/3D-perovskite/2D/Spiro-OMeTAD/Au) devices. The resultant current-voltage (J-V) curves (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">S3</ref>) show improved open circuit voltage (VOC) for both architectures, indicating well-passivated surfaces. <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2</ref> Despite both devices using the same 5 mg/mL PEAI in isopropanol (IPA) surface treatment, the inverted devices have reduced short circuit current (JSC) and fill factor (FF), indicating a transport barrier within the cell. Reducing the concentration of PEAI does curtail losses; but the treatment does not dramatically improve performance compared to controls as it does for NIP solar cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S4</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S3</head><p>| J-V curves from PIN and NIP devices using a 5 mg mL -1 L PEAI 2D treatment. The NIP device is improved by the treatment, the PIN device is significantly inhibited, with losses in current and fill factor. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text 2 | Simulations of 2D/3D heterojunctions in PIN</head><p>Using the band alignment calculated from quasi-2D films, we simulated inverted devices with 10 nm n = 1, 2, 3 or 4 2D interlayers in SCAPS-1D (Fig. <ref type="figure">S5a</ref>). <ref type="bibr">3</ref> When we assumed that passivated surfaces see a reduction in defect denstity, <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">4</ref> we found that devices with a n = 1 interlayer suffered from significant losses to JSC and FF, devices with n = 2 suffered losses to FF, and devices utilising n &gt; 2 were improved compared to controls. We also found that efficiency is dependent on interlayer thickness with thinner layers demonstrating improved FF (Fig. <ref type="figure">S5b</ref>), this may explain the reasonable performance of 1 mg mL -1 2D treated devices (higher VOC but slightly lower FF and JSC than controls). A comprehensive breakdown of the simulation parameters and justification for their use is found below.  <ref type="table">2</ref>. Full simulation parameters can be found in Table # and #.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table S5 | Material parameters used for simulation in SCAPS-1D</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure">S5</ref> | Simulated J-V curves. Curves simulated using (a) 10 nm thick perovskite layer between perovskite and ETL with the band alignment calculated in Table <ref type="table">1</ref> for each n value. The n = ∞ simulation (added to give an idea of the ideal case) corresponds to a version of the cell in which the 2D layer has the same exactly band alignment as the 3D (b) varying thickness of n = 2 perovskite. Clearly both the quasi-2D interlayer species and thickness are important factors. Parameters for simulation were taken from band alignment in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. Other physical properties for 3D perovskite and RDPs used the same value. Full simulation parameters can be found in Table <ref type="table">4</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">a b</formula><p>simulations of RDPs have used the same NC and NV as 3D perovskite; <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">20</ref> we do the same here. The justification for this approximation is that increasing the NC by several orders of magnitude makes little difference to simulation results (Fig. <ref type="figure">S6</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S6 | Simulated J-V curves comparing the conduction band effective density of states in</head><p>the quasi-2D perovskite layer. Curves simulated using 10 nm thick quasi-2D layer using the band alignment from Table <ref type="table">S1</ref>.</p><p>Electron/hole mobilities: Mobilities for NiOx are the same as used for the HTL layers in <ref type="bibr">19</ref> . The electron mobility of SnO2 is taken from <ref type="bibr">14</ref> , the lower hole mobility is used for convenience.</p><p>Mobilities for 3D perovskite are taken from <ref type="bibr">15</ref> . For 2D perovskite this is reduced by an order of magnitude as RDPs are known to have lower mobilities than their bulk counterparts.</p><p>Donor/acceptor densities: Our UPS results suggest that 3D and 2D perovskite are both lightly p-type so have a low acceptor concentration of 1E15 cm -3 . The hole concentration of NiOx was taken from <ref type="bibr">16</ref> .</p><p>The electron concentration of SnO2 was taken from <ref type="bibr">14</ref> .</p><p>Bulk defects: Parameters concerning bulk defects were generated using the SCAPS standard settings which reflect real-world materials. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Table <ref type="table">S3</ref> | Interface parameters used for simulation in SCAPS-1D</p><p>Interface defects: Parameters concerning defects were generated using the SCAPS standard settings which reflect real-world materials. The total defect density (cm -3 ) for the perovskite/ETL interface was increased from the 1E10 generated by SCAPS to 1E+16 based on <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . This was reduced to 1E14 based on results from well passivated surfaces in the same paper. For the perovskite HTL interface 1E13 was used, again using values from <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Parameter Interface</head><note type="other">SnO2</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text 3 | Designing quasi-2D heterostructures</head><p>As mentioned in the main manuscript, several avenues were explored towards producing 2D/3D heterostructures containing wider QWs (n ≥ 3). At first, we attempted to add 3D perovskite components directly into the 2D ligands solution, but this was not possible, due to low solubility of PbI2 in commonly used solvents (IPA, CF, Butanol). Bulk RDP films were prepared from stoichiometric precursors containing 2D perovskite ligands, PbI2 and common 3D perovskite cations (MA, FA or Cs), and found that only bulk RDP films using MA produced large amounts of n ≥ 3 RDPs (Fig. <ref type="figure">S7</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S7 |</head><p>Transient absorption spectra of films of &lt;n&gt; = 2 and &lt;n&gt; = 5 RDP where the additional Asite cation is either MA, Cs or FA. We used peaks from these spectra to extract the absorption wavelengths in Table <ref type="table">S4</ref>. Note that for &lt;n&gt; = 5 FA and Cs based quasi-2D perovskites there is little absorption from the n &gt; 2, this could be due to the phase instability of FAPbI3 and CsPbI3.</p><p>Using MAI as a sole additive with PEAI in our 2D treatment reduced the formation of n = 1 in 2D treated films but did not produce n ≥ 3 (Fig. <ref type="figure">S8d</ref>). Only when DMF was added to this treatment did we produce wider RDPs. When using PEAI and DMF (no MAI in the IPA solution) we found no obvious change in the TA signal compared to using PEAI alone (Fig. <ref type="figure">S8</ref>). However, XRD suggested that more PbI2 was formed using this treatment (Fig. <ref type="figure">S9a</ref>), hence we used a very small amount of DMF (1:200 by vol. to IPA) to ensure that we did not dissolve large amounts of 3D perovskite, as this would not be beneficial to devices. We also used XRD to check the effect of using any combination of MAI/DMF to treat the perovskite surface, with no obvious changes (Fig. <ref type="figure">S9b</ref>).</p><p>We thought to vary the MAI content to induce wider RDPs to grow, but found that this induced disorder into the heterostructure with a broadening of existing peaks rather than the formation of wider RDPs (Fig <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">S10</ref>). Ultimately, we found that using DMF (1:200 by vol. to IPA) and adding MAI (1:2 by wgt.</p><p>to the 2D ligands in solution) produced our most valuable results. However, considering different ligand species this is a large sample space, and one we have not exhausted. Further studies may optimise this for better performance.     GIWAXS results of 2D and quasi-2D treated films, respectively. Films were arranged at a small angle (0.3 °) relative to the incoming x-ray beam so that the surface of the film is probed rather than the bulk.</p><p>High intensity spots at q ~ 0.4 Å -1 and 0.3 Å -1 for the standard 2D treated film, but only one spot at q ~ 0.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Text 4 | UPS and IPES measurements</head><p>As mentioned in the main manuscript, we used ultraviolet photon spectroscopy (UPS) and inverse photoelectron spectroscopy (IPES) to directly measure the valence band and conduction band of our film surfaces. The combined UPS and IPES measurements reported in Figures 3, S18 and Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">S5</ref> were collected with photon and electron energies lower than those of typical UPS and IPES systems (10.2 eV photon for UPS and less than 5 eV electrons for IPES), which has been shown to minimize sample damage. <ref type="bibr">21,</ref><ref type="bibr">22</ref> All ionization energy (IE) and electron affinity (EA) values are assigned based on a Gaussian fit to the UPS and IPES onset region performed on a logarithmic scale.</p><p>Following work by Endres, et al., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> 2.9σ is subtracted from, or added to, the Gaussian peak location to determine the IE of EA, respectively, where σ is the width of the Gaussian (FWHM = 2.35σ).</p><p>The spectra from combined UPS/IPES measurements on control and PEA-based 2D and quasi-2D samples are found in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">S18</ref>, the results are summarised in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">S5</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary text 5 | Density Functional Theory Calculations for RDP width selectivity</head><p>DFT calculations were performed using the FHI-aims <ref type="bibr">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr">[26]</ref> all-electron code. The default numerical settings, referred to as "light" in FHI-aims were used. Local minimum-energy geometries of the Born-Oppenheimer surface were obtained with residual total energy gradients below 1x10 -2 eV Å -1 for atomic positions using the PBE-GGA functional <ref type="bibr">27</ref> within the vdW correction following the Tkatchenko-Scheffler method 28 (PBE+TS). A unified k-point grid 2×2×1 was used to sample the Brillouin zone that corresponds to the slab shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">S19</ref>. The specific arrangements of each ligand were built according to their experimentally defined crystal structure; for BTA, HA, and OTA the BTA structural base was used from; <ref type="bibr">29</ref> The structures of PEA, 2F-PEA, 3F-PEA, 4F-PEA are based on reference. <ref type="bibr">30</ref> The c-direction for all the slabs was set to 100 Å.</p><p>To explore the underlying mechanisms which control RDP formation, the formation process of a 2D/3D heterostructure was divided into three intermediate steps:</p><p>1. Dissolved PbI2 and FAI at the surface will firstly form perovskite flakes, (FA)n-1PbnI3n-1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The products of</head><p>Step 1) will then be selected by different ligands (from the corresponding iodine salt, LI) to form 2D perovskites flakes, L2(FA)n-1PbnI3n+1 3. Those 2D perovskites flakes will stack in the z-direction according to van der Waals interactions to form bulk 2D perovskites. We thus calculated the corresponding formation energies (the definitions are shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">S20</ref>) of each step by density functional theory. Considering that step 3) should be the same regardless of n for a given ligand L, it was ignored. However, we acknowledge that this step may be an important driving force for the lower n 2D perovskites such as n = 1.  Step 1) is independent of ligand and only depends on the amount of dissolved PbI2 and FAI in the surface region. From calculated PBE+TS formation energies, we find that n =1 flakes are not easily to formed compared to wider RDPs (n = 2, 3, 4). As a result, if we have enough PbI2, and FAI dissolved from the surface 3D perovskite (which is the case in our Quasi-2D treatment), the n = 1 perovskites flakes will not form and we will not detect n = 1 2D perovskite, which is consistent within experimental results.</p><p>For step 2), we find that different ligands show different selection behaviour for different RDP widths. With the exception of the 3F-PEA ligands, all the ligands display the same uphill trend: as n increases, the formation energy becomes larger. This agrees with the observation that the n = 2 peak is the major species found for all ligands apart from 3F-PEA (BTA, HA, OTA, PEA, 2F-PEA, 4F-PEA) as the formation energy for n = 2 is consistently lowest (most stable). Considering only chain length (BTA, HA, OTA), we find that as the chain becomes longer, the difference between the formation energy of n = 2, and n = 3 becomes smaller. This explains why we observe stronger absorption from n = 3 as chain length increases for ligands (BTA, HA, OTA). However, as n = 2 still has the lowest formation energy (most stable), the dominant signal remains n = 2 in the quasi-2D treatment. For 3F-PEA, however, we find that n = 3 has the lowest formation energy (most stable) compared to n = 2 or 4. This is consistent with our experimental finding that the n = 3 becomes dominant using the quasi-2D treatment.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary text 6 | One dimensional diffusion/recombination model</head><p>In order to unravel the effect of our surface treatments, we employed a one-dimensional carrier diffusion/recombination model to fit power dependent transient absorption decay curves. This model has been successfully used in both inorganic semiconductors <ref type="bibr">31,</ref><ref type="bibr">32</ref> and perovskites. <ref type="bibr">33,</ref><ref type="bibr">34</ref> It is briefly introduced as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">𝜕𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 𝜕𝑡 = 𝐷 𝜕 2 𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 𝜕𝑥 2 -(𝑘 1 𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) + 𝑘 2 𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 2 +𝑘 3 𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 3 ) (1)</formula><p>Initial carrier distribution: 𝑁(𝑥, 0) = 𝑁(0,0) × exp(-𝛼 𝑥)</p><p>Boundary conditions (front and back interface recombination velocities):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">𝜕𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 𝜕𝑥 | 𝑥=0 = 𝑆 𝑓 𝐷 𝑁(0, 𝑡) (3) 𝜕𝑁(𝑥, 𝑡) 𝜕𝑥 | 𝑥=𝑑 = - 𝑆 𝑏 𝐷 𝑁(𝑑, 𝑡) (4)</formula><p>Herein, N(x, t) denotes the carrier density which is a function of both space (x) and time (t); Sf and Sb denote surface/interface recombination velocities at the front (f) and back (b) surfaces/interfaces, respectively; bulk-specific parameters are the diffusion coefficient (D) and the 1 st (k1), 2 nd (k2), and 3 rd (k3) order recombination coefficients; α is the absorption coefficient; d represents the film thickness. A useful feature of this model is that it not only takes into account of bulk recombination (k1, k2, k3) and diffusion, but also takes into account of what is happening on the surface/interface.</p><p>To unravel the bulk recombination/diffusion and passivating effect of the 2D and quasi-2D treatments, we performed global fitting on control, 2D treated and quasi-2D treated samples (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_18">S26</ref>). These three samples share the same bulk properties and only differ on the surface. Fitting results are presented in S26 as well as Table <ref type="table">S8</ref>. The 1 st , 2 nd , and 3 rd -order recombination coefficients were all evaluated accordingly. And the Sf is a good indication of surface trap state density. It can be clearly observed that both 2D and quasi-2D treatments reduce the surface recombination velocity by half. Table <ref type="table">S8</ref> | Coefficients calculated from the one-dimensional carrier diffusion/recombination model Sf denotes the surface/interface recombination velocity at the front (f) surface/interface; bulkspecific parameters are the diffusion coefficient (D) and the 1 st (k1), 2 nd (k2), and 3 rd (k3) order recombination coefficients. We also calculated the mobility μ and the diffusion length.                     <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Department of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Present address: Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, National University of Singapore, Singapore, Singapore. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> These authors contributed equally: Hao Chen, Sam Teale, Bin Chen, Yi Hou. ✉ e-mail: ningzhj@shanghaitech.edu.cn; ted.sargent@utoronto.ca R educed-dimensional perovskites are perovskite quantum well (QW) layers confined between large organic ligands. The number of stacked lead (Pb) octahedra between the organic spacers determines the width of the RDP layer: n = 1, 2, 3 and so on (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1a</ref>). Changing the RDP layer width (n) within bulk RDP films alters the energy landscape of the resulting material, hence narrow RDP films (n ≤ 5) produce excellent light-emitting diodes (LEDs) and luminescent solar concentrators <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2</ref> . Although films containing wider RDPs (n ≥ 10) have been used to produce highly stable PSCs, these devices suffer from an inferior performance due to poor carrier mobility <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr">4</ref> . More recently, record-performing PSCs have used a 2D/3D heterostructure, fabricated via spin coating RDP (or 2D) ligands onto the surface of a 3D perovskite <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr">[12]</ref> . A comparison of PSC efficiency/stability from recent reports is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1</ref> and demonstrates that all of the most efficient devices reported have used this structure. Studies have revealed that this heterostructure consists of a thin layer of n = 1 and/or n = 2 RDPs atop a bulk 3D perovskite <ref type="bibr">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr">[16]</ref> , which increases performance via passivation and increased electron blocking <ref type="bibr">17,</ref><ref type="bibr">18</ref> . Electron blocking is beneficial for devices built in the negative-intrinsic-positive (NIP) architecture, in which the 2D-treated perovskite surface is coated with a hole transport layer (HTL); however, when used in the generally more stable <ref type="bibr">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr">[22]</ref> inverted (that is, positive-intrinsic-negative, or PIN) structure, this strategy achieves mixed results. Chen et al. found that a 2D treatment applied to inverted cells improved the open-circuit voltage (V OC ) but reduced the fill factor (FF) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23</ref> , and Bai et al. found that introducing a small amount of 2D ligand into the antisolvent improved the device performance, opening the door to further study of the width of RDPs and indeed their presence <ref type="bibr">24</ref> . On the other hand, Park et al., La-Placa et al. and Zhao et al. all found that using a 2D layer in a PIN device reduced the PCE due to a lower current and fill factor <ref type="bibr">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr">[27]</ref> . We speculated that reducing the confinement in the 2D layer could reduce electron blocking and produce inverted PSCs with an exceptional performance.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">Sample Adj. R- square D, cm 2 s -1 Sf, cms -1 , k1, s -1 , k2, cm - 3 s -1 , k3, cm 6 s -1 , μ, cm 2 V - 1 s -</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A quasi-2D surface treatment</head><p>Using ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) and absorption spectroscopy, we estimated the band alignment of RDP films of differing QW widths (n = 1-4; Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1b</ref>) and compared them with the bulk 3D perovskite Cs 0.05 MA 0.1 FA 0.85 PbI 3 (MA, methylammonium; FA, formamidinium). Consistent with earlier reports, we found little dependence between the valence band maximum (VBM) and n (RDP width) <ref type="bibr">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">28,</ref><ref type="bibr">29</ref> . Instead, quantum confinement upshifts the conduction band minimum (CBM), which induces electron blocking in the devices. We confirmed this detrimental effect by comparing NIP and PIN PSCs treated using standard 2D treatments (Supplementary Text 1). Encouragingly, simulations using the solar cell simulation tool SCAPS-1D <ref type="bibr">30</ref> suggested that, due to their deeper CBM, a capping layer of n ≥ 3 RDPs would be beneficial for PIN solar cell performance via surface passivation with reduced resistance to carrier transport (Supplementary Text 2).</p><p>In bulk RDP films, the average layer thickness is modulated by changing the ratio of the 2D ligands to the 3D perovskite precursors in solution <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">4</ref> . We explored several options to reproduce this</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</head><p>Hao Chen 1,2,7 , Sam Teale 1,7 , Bin Chen 1,7 , Yi Hou 1,6,7 , Luke Grater 1 , Tong Zhu The energy landscape of reduced-dimensional perovskites (RDPs) can be tailored by adjusting their layer width (n). Recently, two/three-dimensional (2D/3D) heterostructures containing n = 1 and 2 RDPs have produced perovskite solar cells (PSCs) with &gt;25% power conversion efficiency (PCE). Unfortunately, this method does not translate to inverted PSCs due to electron blocking at the 2D/3D interface. Here we report a method to increase the layer width of RDPs in 2D/3D heterostructures to address this problem. We discover that bulkier organics form 2D heterostructures more slowly, resulting in wider RDPs; and that small modifications to ligand design induce preferential growth of n ≥ 3 RDPs. Leveraging these insights, we developed efficient inverted PSCs (with a certified quasi-steady-state PCE of 23.91%). Unencapsulated devices operate at room temperature and around 50% relative humidity for over 1,000 h without loss of PCE; and, when subjected to ISOS-L3 accelerated ageing, encapsulated devices retain 92% of initial PCE after 500 h. for a 2D post-treatment (Supplementary Text 3). Our most distinctive results came from introducing a small amount of dimethylformamide (DMF) (at 1:200 by volume in isopropanol (IPA)) and methylammonium iodide (MAI) (1:2 by weight) to the 2D ligands in solution. We posit that MAI is needed to reduce the ratio of the 2D ligand to the A-site cation and that DMF introduces Pb directly from the 3D perovskite surface (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">9</ref>). Using this strategy, we were able to produce 2D perovskite capping layers containing n ≥ 3 RDP layers (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1e</ref>). For convenience, we henceforth refer to our altered 2D ligand treatment as a quasi-2D treatment.</p><p>Notably, Zhou et al. demonstrated that adding MAI and DMF to a phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) surface treatment improves the performance of PIN solar cells <ref type="bibr">31</ref> . This earlier study is limited in scope, however, discussing only the effect of DMF on the penetration depth of the 2D treatment. Using time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectrometry, we estimated the penetration depth of phenethylammonium (PEA) from solutions using different DMF concentrations (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">11</ref>) and found no correlation in our sample size (from 1:200 to 1:50 DMF:IPA by volume). We instead expect that the origin of improved performance is the production of wider RDPs at the interface between the 3D perovskite and the electron transporting layer (ETL). Considering this new observation, we sought a treatment that would optimize this effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characterizing the quantum well width in 2D/3D heterojunctions</head><p>A strong dependence between QW width and bandgap exists in 2D perovskites <ref type="bibr">32,</ref><ref type="bibr">33</ref> . Hence, ultrafast transient absorption (TA) spectroscopy is able to accurately identify the distribution of different 2D species in perovskite films <ref type="bibr">[34]</ref><ref type="bibr">[35]</ref><ref type="bibr">[36]</ref> . We first acquired the TA spectra of 2D-and quasi-2D-treated films using the most common 2D perovskite ligands: butylammonium (BTA) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">2a,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>) and PEA (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">2b,</ref><ref type="figure">e</ref>). Although the majority absorption from each film is from the 3D perovskite (780 nm, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">12</ref>), each film displays bleach peaks in the 500-700 nm range, characteristic of RDPs. Similar to spectra acquired by Niu et al., the standard 2D-treated films display bleach signals from n = 1 and/or 2 RDPs 36 .</p><p>Quasi-2D-treated films, however, contain n ≥ 3 RDPs, with the PEA treatment producing more n ≥ 3 RDPs than BTA. Grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering (GIWAXS) confirmed that these 2D layers lie horizontal to the substrate (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">13</ref>), as in other reports <ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">13,</ref><ref type="bibr">15</ref> . Recently, it was documented that bulk quasi-2D perovskite films made using fluorinated PEA ligands form different QW structures compared to unfluorinated PEA <ref type="bibr">35</ref> . To this end, we tested PEA-based ligands with a fluorine at each node (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1c</ref>) and found that this has a dramatic effect on the QW distribution (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">16</ref>). Mostly notably, we found that using our quasi-2D surface strategy, 3-fluoro-phenethylammonium (3F-PEA) produces a 2D/3D heterojunction containing majority n = 3 RDP (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">2f</ref>). The structures of all 2D ligands mentioned are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1c</ref>.</p><p>To better understand why different ligands produce different RDP distributions, we the measured TA spectra in situ while spin coating quasi-2D treatments (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">2g-i</ref>). With a pump-probe delay of 1 ps and a time resolution of 0.3 s, we spun films at 1,500 revolutions per minute (r.p.m.) and deposited the 2D treatment dynamically. A reduction in the 3D perovskite absorption is apparent ~2.4 s after solution deposition for all samples. For the BTA treatment, this reduction in 3D bleach is concurrent with the arrival of a strong n = 2 bleach. For the PEA-based treatments, the 2D signal does not appear until ~1.2 s after the 3D bleach reduction. It has been suggested that bulkier organics intercalate more slowly, which induces them to form wider RDPs <ref type="bibr">34</ref> . Our results agree, indicating that π-π stacking ligands form wider RDPs due to slower crystallization, which suppresses narrower RDP formation. This is corroborated by films treated using hexylammonium (HA) and octylammonium (OTA) ligands, which demonstrate an increased presence of n ≥ 3 RDP with increasing ligand length (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">14</ref>). To investigate the effect of increased π-π stacking, we treated samples with 1-naphthylmethylammonium (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1c</ref>) but found that the quasi-2D treatment substantially reduced the RDP absorption in the TA spectra (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">15</ref>). We also gained insight into why 3F-PEA forms wider RDPs. Standard PEA produces n = 2 and 3 simultaneously, whereas 3F-PEA forms n = 3 one frame (0.3 s) before the appearance of n = 2, suggesting that n = 3 is preferentially formed from the precursor complex.</p><p>Density functional theory (DFT) calculations were used to compute the formation energy of n = 1, 2, 3 and 4 RDPs for each ligand (details in Supplementary Text 5). As previously reported <ref type="bibr">4</ref> , the formation energy of the n = 1 RDP was found to be the lowest for all ligands; however, this was not supported by our experimental findings or results from other studies <ref type="bibr">36,</ref><ref type="bibr">37</ref> . Nonetheless, considering that forming single layers of lead iodide (PbI 2 ) is considerably more energy intensive than larger slabs (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">3a</ref>) it seems reasonable that n = 1 layers are less likely to form, especially when excess cations are available as within the quasi-2D treatment. Hence, we compared the formation energy of n ≥ 2 RDPs. Generally, we found that formation energy increases with increasing width, however, we also found that bonding different ligands onto 2D perovskite flakes (FA n-1 Pb n I 3n-1 ) introduces different types of strain into the system which is released through different distortions of the perovskite (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">22</ref>). The specific orientation and arrangement of the ligands caused by the fluorine atom in 3F-PEA (structure taken from <ref type="bibr">35</ref> ) introduces larger strain compared to PEA or BTA, manifesting as larger distortions, and therefore larger perovskite flakes are need to fully release the additional strain. As a result, a sweet spot for n = 3 is found in the formation energy of 3F-PEA (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">3b</ref>), which results in the preferential formation of n = 3 revealed in the TA data. We calculated the formation energies for each of the ligands 1-7 in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1c</ref> (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">21</ref>, Supplementary Text 5), but only 3F-PEA possessed a preference for n ≥ 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Band alignment of 2D/3D heterostructures</head><p>We proposed to modulate the n distribution of 2D/3D heterojunctions with the aim of reducing the electron barrier at the perovskite/ ETL interface. To verify this, we used surface-sensitive inverse photoelectron spectroscopy (IPES), which directly measures the conduction band of the first few nanometres of film <ref type="bibr">29,</ref><ref type="bibr">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr">[40]</ref><ref type="bibr">[41]</ref> . Following work from Endres et al. <ref type="bibr">42</ref> we used gaussian fittings to extract the CBM and found that, as expected, the CBM values of 2D-treated surfaces are upshifted compared with the controls (Fig. <ref type="figure">4a-c</ref>). Using the quasi-2D treatment the 2D/3D CBM offset is reduced substantially for PEA-and 3F-PEA-treated films relative to their n = 1 (and/or 2) analogues (0.42-0.14 eV and 0.49-0.08 eV, respectively)  <ref type="figure">d-f</ref>, TA spectra of films treated with BTA (d), PEA (e) and 3F-PEA (f) using the quasi-2D treatment. The majority absorption in each case is from the 3D perovskite (780 nm) but this has been excluded for clarity. Absorption peaks are assigned in order, and a comparison with single-cation quasi-2D films is shown in Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>. The inset bar in a-f represents the relative absorption from each RDP species. g-h, Absorption maps from in situ TA spectroscopy obtained during spin coating. Cs 0.05 MA 0.1 FA 0.85 PbI 3 3D perovskite films were spun at 1,500 r.p.m. and a constant 1 ps pump-probe delay time was used. The quasi-2D treatments for BTA (g), PEA (h) and 3F-PEA (i) were all dropped at 7. but less so for BTA (0.41-0.31 eV). We measured the potential of our film surfaces using Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) and found a similar trend (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">17</ref>). This complements the results in the previous section which suggest that the quasi-2D treatment using BTA produces fewer n ≥ 3 RDPs than PEA or 3F-PEA. We also performed surface-sensitive UPS on control, 2Dand quasi-2D-treated films (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">18</ref>) to produce the schematics in Fig. <ref type="figure">4e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref>. Similar to the plot in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">1b</ref> and several previous reports <ref type="bibr">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">28,</ref><ref type="bibr">29</ref> , altering the RDP width has little effect on the VBM, and reducing confinement simply shifts the conduction band deeper, closer to the 3D perovskite. More details on these UPS and IPES measurements can be found in Supplementary Text 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Carrier extraction and photovoltaic performance</head><p>To explore the device implications, we investigated the charge transport in BTA-, PEA-and 3F-PEA-treated films using the 2D and quasi-2D treatments. The photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY) increases after the standard 2D treatment for each ligand (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">6</ref>), suggesting a reduced density of non-radiative recombination centres <ref type="bibr">8</ref> . This effect is enhanced slightly by the quasi-2D treatment, indicating improved passivation. A similar trend is visible in transient photoluminescence (TRPL) spectroscopy results (Fig. <ref type="figure">5a</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">24)</ref>, where longer lifetimes are recorded for 2D-and quasi-2D-treated films (a summary of lifetimes is found in Supplementary Table <ref type="table">3</ref>). The modestly improved passivation of the quasi-2D treatment may be due to the addition of MAI, which has also been reported to passivate perovskite surfaces <ref type="bibr">43</ref> .</p><p>Following the work of Kirchartz et al., we deposited [6,6]-phenyl-C 61 -butyric acid methyl ester (PCBM) atop the perovskite as an ETL and used the quenched τ 1 lifetimes to compare charge extraction (Fig. <ref type="figure">5b</ref>) <ref type="bibr">44</ref> . The quenched τ 1 lifetime of the control film was 4.6 ns. After deposition of 3F-PEA this doubled to 9.2 ns, suggesting that the standard 2D treatment impedes the flow of electrons from the perovskite to the ETL. Using the quasi-2D treatment this was reduced to 4.9 ns, implying a considerably improved extraction compared with the standard 2D treatment. A similar trend is seen using BTA and PEA (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">24</ref>). For quantitative values we repeated these observations using power-dependent TA (Supplementary Text 6 and Supplementary Table <ref type="table">8</ref>) and space-charge-limited current (SCLC) measurements. From the TA data we found that both 2D and quasi-2D treatments reduced the surface recombination velocity (from ~600 cm s -1 to ~300 cm s -1 ). The SCLC measurements show a similar trend (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">27</ref>) but the overall effect is less obvious as we are examining the entire film and not simply the interfaces.</p><p>In PSCs using bulk RDPs, films that contain mixed-dimensional phases have reduced mobility due to charge trapping in the higher n species 3 . To understand why this is not necessarily the case in 2D/3D heterostructure films, we used TA spectroscopy to measure the charge dynamics. Using a 450 nm pump at a low power (5 µJ cm -2 ) to avoid Auger recombination <ref type="bibr">45</ref> , we excited the 2D and 3D layers of 2D-and quasi-2D-treated films. Measuring the n = 2 bleach decay (~570 nm) using monoexponential fits, we calculated the carrier funnelling rates for both treatments; a summary of the results is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">28</ref>. For a standard 2D-treated film, there are no peaks present for n &gt; 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">2a</ref>), thus we expect the charges to funnel directly from n = 2 to the 3D perovskite <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">46</ref> , for which we observed a 28.6 ps decay time. When we generate a favourable pathway for electrons by adding a layer of PCBM, we observed a faster decay (7.5 ps). Repeating these measurements with a quasi-2D-treated film, we observed a decay without PCBM of 5.8 ps, suggesting that the charges are funnelled to the now present n &gt; 2 species <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">46</ref> . However, adding a layer of PCBM resulted in an even faster decay (1.2 ps), indicating that charge trapping does not play a limiting role in charge extraction.</p><p>To gauge the effect of the 2D and quasi-2D treatments in full device stacks, we conducted transient photovoltage (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">25</ref>) and transient photocurrent measurements (Fig. <ref type="figure">5c</ref>). Following ref. <ref type="bibr">47</ref> , devices were biased with the same white-light intensity to reach near-V OC conditions and were photoexcited with low-power laser pulses to generate small photovoltage perturbations (ΔV, kept to lower than 20 mV). Monoexponential fits were used to estimate the carrier lifetime under V OC and short-circuit current density (J SC ) conditions. We observed a slower decay in photovoltage for the quasi-2D-treated films compared with the standard 2D treatment (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">25</ref>), which is consistent with the TRPL results and indicates a reduction in trap states in the absorber. More importantly, we observed a faster decay in the photocurrent for the quasi-2D-treated films (τ quasi-2D = 0.82 µs compared with τ 2D = 1.28 µs for 3F-PEA-treated films), which suggests a substantial improvement in carrier extraction <ref type="bibr">48</ref> . In addition, we performed conductive atomic force microscopy (c-AFM) on these films, revealing increased conductivity in quasi-2D-treated films (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">31</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">32</ref>).</p><p>We fabricated devices with an ITO/NiO x nanoparticles/ perovskite/PCBM/BCP/Ag structure using different surface treatments (BTA, PEA, 2F-PEA, 4F-PEA and 3F-PEA; standard 2D and quasi-2D treatments) for statistical analysis (Supplementary Figs. 33-36). In agreement with our finding that increased n ≥ 3 RDPs result in more efficient charge extraction, 3F-PEA outperformed the PEA-and BTA-treated devices. Improved performance of the quasi-2D-treated over the standard 2D-treated devices is derived mainly from FF and J SC improvements; a typical set of To confirm that improved passivation alone was not the cause of the increased FF, we simulated the effect of reducing only the surface trap density using the SCAPS-1D simulation tool (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">40</ref>) and found that a 20 mV difference in V OC would correspond to an increase in FF of approximately 0.5% rather than the 2.2% increase manifested.</p><p>A quasi-2D-treated device was certified at the National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). The C 60 /BCP-based device produced a quasi-steady-state certified PCE for inverted PSCs of 23.91% (with FF = 83.46, J SC = 24.90 mA cm -2 and V OC = 1.15 V; Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_39">43</ref>). A voltage loss of 0.38 V is the lowest documented for a NiO x -based PSC (bandgap from the external quantum efficiency, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_37">42</ref>) <ref type="bibr">49</ref> .</p><p>We focused on improving the performance of the NiO x -HTL inverted PSCs because they have shown high stability at elevated temperatures <ref type="bibr">19,</ref><ref type="bibr">49,</ref><ref type="bibr">50</ref> . However, 2D treatments have been shown to be unstable above 50 °C, degrading in a matter of hours <ref type="bibr">51</ref> ; thus it was crucial to ascertain whether or not any new 2D treatment could withstand high temperatures. We prepared 2D-and quasi-2D-treated films and heated them at 65 °C for 20 h, periodically measuring their characteristics via TA spectroscopy (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_36">41</ref>). We found that the n distribution of both treatments was robust under heating, suggesting that the quasi-2D treatment could be used to produce extremely stable devices.</p><p>We evaluated the stability of the devices under accelerated-ageing conditions according to International Summit on Organic Photovoltaic Stability (ISOS) protocols <ref type="bibr">52</ref> . We tracked the maximum power point (MPP) of two quasi-2D-treated devices under illumination at ~50% relative humidity. An unencapsulated device was monitored at room temperature for 1,000 h (ISOS-L-1I) and an encapsulated device on a temperature-controllable stage was monitored at 65 °C for 500 h (ISOS-L-3), and the results are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">5e</ref>,f, respectively. The unencapsulated room-temperature devices showed no degradation after 1,000 h of MPP tracking (4.9% increase in PCE), whereas the device baked at 65 °C lost around 8% of its maximum PCE after 500 h. On the basis of a linear extrapolation from these data, we estimate the T 80 lifetime of this device (that is, the time required to drop to 80% of the initial efficiency) to be 1,190 h (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_40">45</ref>) <ref type="bibr">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">52</ref> . After 500 h the MPP tracking for the heated device was paused but the cell remained under illumination at 65 °C, and after 12 h the MPP tracking was resumed. The PCE of the device recovered to 99% of the initial PCE, which is an encouraging indicator of its real-world long-term stability <ref type="bibr">53</ref> . We note that the device structure was not altered for stability testing and the initial efficiency of both devices was &gt;23% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">44</ref>). Therefore, we report an ISOS-L-3 accelerated-ageing test that corresponds directly to high-efficiency PSCs (&gt;20% PCE).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>We presented a simple technique that alters the QW widths in 2D/3D perovskite heterostructures. This was tailored to improve inverted PSCs, and was accomplished by reducing the confinement within the 2D capping layer to reduce the electron barrier between the 3D and 2D perovskite species. This resulted in highly stable NiO x -based PSCs with certified efficiency values, and could be useful in other metal halide-based optoelectronics devices in which well-passivated, negative-intrinsic contacts are desirable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>online content</head><p>Any methods, additional references, Nature Research reporting summaries, source data, extended data, supplementary information, acknowledgements, peer review information; details of author contributions and competing interests; and statements of data and code availability are available at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-022-00985-1">https://doi.org/10.1038/ s41566-022-00985-1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Materials. All the materials were used as received without purification. Commercial indium tin oxide (ITO) substrates (20 Ω per square) with dimensions of 25 × 25 mm were purchased from TFD. PbI 2 and bathocuproine (BCP) were purchased from TCI. Caesium iodide (CsI) (99.999%) and fullerene (C 60 ) (99.5%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. PEAI, FAI (formamidinium iodide) and MAI were purchased from GreatCell Solar. 2F-PEAI (2-fluoro-phenethylammonium iodide), 3F-PEAI, 4F-PEAI (4-fluoro-phenethylammonium iodide) and 1-naphthylmethylammonium iodide were purchased from Xi'an Polymer Light Technology. PCBM was purchased from Nano-C. All the solvents used in the process were anhydrous and purchased from Sigma-Aldrich.</p><p>Nickel oxide nanoparticle synthesis. The NiO x nanoparticles were prepared via the hydrolysis of nickel nitrate following previous work <ref type="bibr">54,</ref><ref type="bibr">55</ref> . Briefly, Ni(NO 3 ) 2 •6H 2 O (20 mmol) was dissolved in deionized water (20 ml) to obtain a dark-green solution. Then, NaOH aqueous solution (4 ml, 10 mol l -1 ) was slowly added to the dark-green solution with stirring. After being stirred for 20 min, the colloidal precipitate was washed thoroughly using deionized water three times and dried at 80 °C for 6 h. The obtained green powder was then calcined at 270 °C for 2 h to obtain a black powder. The NiO x nanoparticle ink was prepared by dispersing the obtained NiO x nanoparticles in a mixed solution of deionized water and IPA (3:1, v/v) for a concentration of 10 mg ml -1 .</p><p>Solar cell fabrication. ITO glass was cleaned through sequential washing with detergent, deionized water, acetone and IPA. Before use, the ITO was cleaned with ultraviolet ozone for 20 min.</p><p>For the inverted solar cells, the substrate was spin-coated with a thin layer of NiO x nanoparticle film using the NiO x nanoparticle ink at 2,000 r.p.m. for 30 s. The perovskite absorber layers were deposited inside a nitrogen-filled glovebox with a controlled water and oxygen level of less than 1 ppm. The temperature inside was monitored to be 25-30 °C. The precursors for the Cs 0.05 FA 0.85 MA 0.1 PbI 3 perovskites were prepared by dissolving the PbI 2 , MAI, CsI and FAI in a mixed solvent (4:1 in volume) of DMF and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), respectively. This was done by adding the powders to a vial (20 ml size) and then adding the mixed solvent (1 ml) before leaving the vial on a stirring hotplate set to 60 °C for 30 min; all steps were undertaken in a glovebox. For fabrication of the perovskite film, the substrate was spun at 2,000 r.p.m. for 30 s with an initial acceleration of 1,000 r.p.m., and then at 6000 r.p.m. for 10 s with an acceleration of 6000 r.p.m. per second. In the second step, anisole (150 μl) was added dropwise onto the substrate during the last 5 s of spinning. The substrate was immediately placed on a hotplate and annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. For the surface treatment, the 2D solutions were prepared by dissolving the 2D ligand salts (that is, PEAI, BTAI, 3F-PEAI, HAI and OTAI) with or without MAI and DMF in IPA. The ligand salt (1 mg ml -1 ), MAI (0.5 mg ml -1 ) and an IPA:DMF v/v ratio of 1:200 was used, unless stated otherwise. The 2D layer was fabricated by depositing the 2D ligand solution (150 µl) onto the perovskite film surface, and immediately after deposition the film was spun at a rate of 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s with a 4,000 r.p.m. per second acceleration. The film was then annealed at 100 °C for 5 min.</p><p>For the ETL, either C 60 /ALD-SnO 2 or PCBM/BCP were used. C 60 was formed via evaporation, and deposition of the ALD-SnO 2 (atomic-layer-deposited tin(IV) oxide) was carried out using a PICOSUN R-200 Advanced ALD system. Water and tetrakis(dimethylamino)tin(IV) (TDMASn) were used as the oxygen and tin precursors, respectively. The precursor and substrate temperature was set to 75 °C and 85 °C, respectively. Nitrogen gas (90 sccm) was used as carrier gas. Pulse and purge times for water were 1 s and 5 s, respectively, and 1.6 s and 5 s, respectively, for TDMASn. The total deposition cycle is 134 s, corresponding to 20 nm of SnO 2 .</p><p>PCBM was formed by spin coating the PCBM solution (20 mg ml -1 in chlorobenzene) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and then annealing at 100 °C for 5 min. Then a thin and uniform BCP layer was deposited via drop-casting 2-3 drops of BCP dissolved in IPA while spinning the substrate at 5,000 r.p.m. Finally, a 120-nm-thick silver contact was deposited on top of the BCP using thermal evaporation under high vacuum (&lt;5 × 10 -7 torr) using an Angstrom Engineering deposition system to produce a cell with an active area of 0.053 cm 2 .</p><p>For non-inverted solar cells, the substrate was spin-coated with a thin layer of SnO 2 nanoparticle solution (1:3:3, SnO 2 (15% in water):IPA:water) at 3,000 r.p.m. for 20 s and annealed in ambient air at 150 °C for 1 h. The perovskite solution was prepared by dissolving FAPbI 3 (889 mg ml -1 ), MAPbBr 3 (33 mg ml -1 ) and MACl (33 mg ml -1 ) in DMF/DMSO (8:1 v/v) mixed solvent. Then, the solution was coated onto the ITO/SnO 2 substrate through two consecutive spin-coating steps, at 1,000 r.p.m. for 5 s and 2,500 r.p.m. for 20 s. During the second spin-coating (2,500 r.p.m.) step, diethyl ether (1 ml) was poured onto the substrate after 15 s. The intermediate phase substrate was then put on a hotplate at 150 °C for 10 min. After the fabrication of the 3D perovskite film, the 2D layer was fabricated by depositing a solution (5 mg ml -1 ) of PEAI in IPA onto the perovskite film and then spinning the substrate at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s. Then, the substrate was heat-treated at 100 °C for 5 min. For deposition of the hole transport material, a spiro-OMeTAD solution in chlorobenzene (90.9 mg mL -1 ) was prepared, and lithium-bis(trifluo romethanesulfonyl) imide solution in acetonitrile (23 μl, 540 mg mL -1 ) and pure 4-tert-butylpyridine (39 μl) were added to an aliquot of the solution (1.1 ml). The spiro-OMeTAD solution including additives was spin-coated onto the perovskite surface at 1,750 r.p.m. for 30 s. Finally, a gold electrode was deposited via thermal evaporation to produce a cell with an active area of 0.053 cm 2 .</p><p>Reduced-dimensional film fabrication. Reduced-dimensional (PEA) 2 (MA/FA/ Cs) n-1 Pb n I 3n+1 perovskite solutions were prepared by dissolving the appropriate stoichiometric quantities of PbI 2 , MAI (or FAI or CsI) with PEAI in DMF/DMSO (4:1 v/v). The resulting solution was filtered using a polytetrafluoroethylene syringe filter (0.2 μm) before deposition. Then, the solution was coated onto the glass substrate through two consecutive spin-coating steps, at 1,000 r.p.m. for 5 s and 2,500 r.p.m. for 20 s. During the second spin-coating (2,500 r.p.m.) step, diethyl ether (1 ml) was poured onto the substrate after 15 s. The intermediate phase substrate was then put on a hotplate at 150 °C for 10 min.</p><p>Device testing. The current density-voltage (J-V) characteristics were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under illumination from a solar simulator (Class A, Newport) with a light intensity of 100 mW cm -2 (checked using a calibrated reference solar cell from Newport). The J-V curves were measured in a nitrogen atmosphere with a scanning rate of 100 mV s -1 (a voltage step of 10 mV and a delay time of 200 ms). The active area was determined by the aperture shade mask (0.049 cm 2 for small-area devices) placed in front of the solar cell. A spectral mismatch factor of unity was used for all J-V measurements. For stabilized output measurements at the MPP, the device testing chamber was left under ambient conditions. Solar cells were fixed at the MPP voltage, (determined from J-V sweeps in both scanning directions) and the current output was tracked over time.</p><p>Stability testing. Devices were placed in a homemade stability-tracking station. The illumination source is a white-light LED with its intensity calibrated to match 1-Sun conditions. For room-temperature tests (ISOS-L-1I), the device chamber was sealed and supplied with continuous nitrogen purging. For the ISOS-L-3 ageing test, the device chamber was left open in a room with 50 ± 10% relative humidity, and the solar cell was mounted on a metal plate kept at 65 °C using a heating element. A thermal couple attached to the metal plate was used to monitor and provide feedback control to the heating element to ensure temperature consistency. The MPP was tracked using a perturb-and-observe algorithm that updates the MPP value every 10 s. Encapsulation was done by capping the device with a glass slide, using UV-adhesive (LT-U001, Lumtec) as the sealant.</p><p>X-ray diffraction. X-ray diffraction patterns were collected using a Rigaku D/ Max-2500 diffractometer equipped with Cu Kα1 radiation (λ = 1.54056 Å).</p><p>Grazing incidence wide-angle X-ray scattering. GIWAXS measurements were conducted at the BL14B1 beamline of the Shanghai Synchrotron Radiation Facility using X-rays with a wavelength of λ = 1.24 Å at a grazing incidence angle of 0.3° and an exposure time of 80 s. The GIXRD patterns were collected using a MarCCD 225 detector with a sample-detector distance of 280 mm and were presented in q coordinates using the equation q = 4πsinθ/λ, where θ is half of the diffraction angle. In the present GIXRD data, q has been calibrated by measuring the X-ray diffraction from a lanthanum hexaboride reference sample. Images were calibrated using lanthanum hexaboride and processed using the Nika software package <ref type="bibr">56</ref> and the GIXSGUI MATLAB plug-in <ref type="bibr">57</ref> .</p><p>Simulations. Simulations of PSCs were conducted using the heterojunction solar cell simulator SCAPS-1D, version 3.3.07 <ref type="bibr">30</ref> . Full simulation details can be found in Supplementary Text 2.</p><p>Conductive atomic force microscopy. Scanning probe microscopy experiments were carried out under ambient conditions using an Asylum Research Cypher S AFM instrument with low-force-constant (k = 2.8 N m -1 ), Ti/Ir-coated, silicon cantilevers (ASYELEC.01-R2). Contact-mode AFM was used to simultaneously produce surface and current maps applying a fixed bias voltage of -0.6 V. Measurements were obtained under top illumination from a 3 W white LED.</p><p>Transient absorption spectroscopy. Femtosecond laser pulses of 1,030 nm generated using a Yb:KGW laser at a 5 kHz repetition rate (Pharos, Light Conversion) were passed through an optical parametric amplifier (Orpheus, Light Conversion) to select 450 nm light. This served as the pump pulse, whereas the probe pulse was generated by focusing the initial 1,030 nm pulse into a sapphire crystal, which resulted in a white-light continuum (Helios, Ultrafast). With a temporal resolution of the system of ∼350 fs, each time step meant delaying the probe pulse with respect to the pump, with time steps that increased exponentially. Every other pump pulse was blocked using a chopper to determine the change in optical density. After going through a grating spectrograph, the pulses were measured using a charge-coupled device (CCD) (Helios, Ultrafast).</p><p>Spinning in situ TA spectroscopy was performed using a purpose-built spinner, designed such that the incident probe light could pass through the spinning substrate and be directed into the CCD. The pump-probe delay was set to 1 ps. The time resolution of the system was 0.3 s. The measurements were taken in an ambient atmosphere with 35% relative humidity.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure S2 |</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Figure S2 | UPS spectra for &lt;n&gt; = 1,2,3 and 4 films. Films were fabricated by spin coating precursor ratios of PEA2MAn-1PbnI3n+1</figDesc><graphic coords="4,284.61,72.00,236.24,178.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure S4 |</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Figure S4 | Performance statistics for Control films and films treated with 1, 2 and 5 mg mL -1 PEAI in IPA solutions. 20 Devices of each type were fabricated and tested for statistical analysis.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,72.00,72.00,451.30,247.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S# | Simulated J-V curves. Curves simulated using (a) 10 nm thick 2D layer between perovskite and ETL of different n species, (b) varying thickness of n = 2 perovskite. Clearly both the quasi-2D interlayer species and thickness are important factors. Parameters for simulation were taken from band alignment in Table2. Full simulation parameters can be found in Table # and #.</figDesc><graphic coords="7,72.02,328.45,241.49,189.73" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure S8 |Figure S9 |</head><label>S8S9</label><figDesc>Figure S8 | Transient absorption spectra of 3D Cs0.05MA0.1FA0.85PbI3 perovskite treated with different surface treatments. (a) Control, (b) 1 mg mL -1 MAI in IPA, (c) 1 mg mL -1 PEAI in 200:1 IPA:DMF solution, (d) 1 mg mL -1 PEAI + 0.5 mg mL -1 MAI in IPA solution.</figDesc><graphic coords="13,277.37,512.52,210.93,179.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure S10 |</head><label>S10</label><figDesc>Figure S10 | TA of heterostructures using increased MAI content. 3D perovskite films treated with the quasi-2D treatment using (a) 1:1 and (b) 2:1 MAI to PEAI by wt.</figDesc><graphic coords="14,67.96,447.05,210.33,210.33" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure S11 |</head><label>S11</label><figDesc>Figure S11 | Time of flight second ion mass spectroscopy (ToF-SIMS) of PEA+ ions in perovskite films treated with PEAI in solution with different DMF:IPA concentrations. Across this range (5 µL DMF in 1 mL IPA to 20 µL in 1 mL IPA) there is no obvious change in penetration depth for the PEA ligand.</figDesc><graphic coords="15,72.00,279.29,451.15,172.15" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure S12 |</head><label>S12</label><figDesc>Figure S12| Full TA spectrum taken of a PEA treated quasi-2D film. Note that the 3D bleach is considerably more absorptive than the 2D, such that we have neglected to include these in Fig.2.</figDesc><graphic coords="16,72.00,72.00,451.30,302.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure S13 |</head><label>S13</label><figDesc>Figure S13 | GIWAXS and XRD results for 2D and quasi-2D treated films using PEA. (a,b)GIWAXS results of 2D and quasi-2D treated films, respectively. Films were arranged at a small angle (0.3 °) relative to the incoming x-ray beam so that the surface of the film is probed rather than the bulk. High intensity spots at q ~ 0.4 Å -1 and 0.3 Å -1 for the standard 2D treated film, but only one spot at q ~ 0.3 Å -1 for the quasi-2D treated film indicate the loss of n = 1 RDPs in the quasi-2D treated film. These spots are arranged along the qz axis, indicating that the RDPs are oriented horizontally with respect to the substrate. (c) XRD results from the same films indicate that only a small proportion of the film has been converted to 2D. To ensure that unreacted PEAI salt was not mistaken for RDPs, we compared the 2D treated sample with the salt n = 1 and &lt;n&gt; = 2 films in (d). Clearly, we can see that the PEAI salt is distinct from the peaks formed from either n = 1 or n = 2 PEA2MAn-1Pb2nI3n+1</figDesc><graphic coords="17,351.80,90.62,190.10,177.43" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>1 Figure S14 |</head><label>1S14</label><figDesc>Figure S13 | GIWAXS and XRD results for 2D and quasi-2D treated films using PEA. (a,b)GIWAXS results of 2D and quasi-2D treated films, respectively. Films were arranged at a small angle (0.3 °) relative to the incoming x-ray beam so that the surface of the film is probed rather than the bulk. High intensity spots at q ~ 0.4 Å -1 and 0.3 Å -1 for the standard 2D treated film, but only one spot at q ~ 0.3 Å -1 for the quasi-2D treated film indicate the loss of n = 1 RDPs in the quasi-2D treated film. These spots are arranged along the qz axis, indicating that the RDPs are oriented horizontally with respect to the substrate. (c) XRD results from the same films indicate that only a small proportion of the film has been converted to 2D. To ensure that unreacted PEAI salt was not mistaken for RDPs, we compared the 2D treated sample with the salt n = 1 and &lt;n&gt; = 2 films in (d). Clearly, we can see that the PEAI salt is distinct from the peaks formed from either n = 1 or n = 2 PEA2MAn-1Pb2nI3n+1</figDesc><graphic coords="17,185.68,91.37,177.15,175.83" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure S15 |</head><label>S15</label><figDesc>Figure S15 | TA spectra of films treated with NPMA ligands. The inset bar charts represent the relative absorption from each RDP species. RDPs struggled to form during the quasi-2D treatment.</figDesc><graphic coords="18,106.85,450.75,380.80,174.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure S16 |</head><label>S16</label><figDesc>Figure S16 | TA spectra of films treated with 2F-PEA and 4F-PEA ligands. The inset bar charts represent the relative absorption from each RDP species.</figDesc><graphic coords="19,109.40,72.95,376.00,319.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure S17 |</head><label>S17</label><figDesc>Figure S17 | Potential profiles from Kelvin probe measurements (a) PEA treated films, (b) 3F-PEA treated films. The overall shift in potential between (a) and (b) is assumed to be due to changing the KPFM tip as measurements were made on separate occasions with different probes.</figDesc><graphic coords="20,116.68,72.00,361.95,320.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure S18 |</head><label>S18</label><figDesc>Figure S18 | UPS spectra showing the secondary electron cut-off region (a) and the valence band onset region (b) with the fittings to a Gaussian function shown in (b) with dashed lines. The x-axis energy scale is with respect to the Fermi energy (EF = 0) for untreated, 2D treated and quasi-2D treated films.</figDesc><graphic coords="21,72.00,387.93,451.30,221.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure S19 |</head><label>S19</label><figDesc>Figure S19 | Idealized crystal structure of n = 3 perovskite flakes (FAn-1PbnI3n-1) and 2D perovskite flakes (L2FAn-1PbnI3n+1, L = BTA, HA, OTA, PEA, 2F-PEA, 3F-PEA, 4F-PEA).The specific arrangements of each ligand were built according to their experimentally defined crystal structure; for BTA, HA, and OTA the BTA structural base was used from;29  The structures of PEA, 2F-PEA, 3F-PEA, 4F-PEA are based on reference.30  The c-direction for all the slabs was set to 100 Å.</figDesc><graphic coords="23,72.00,226.85,468.00,154.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure S20 |</head><label>S20</label><figDesc>Figure S20 | Schematic plots about the formation energy definition of three intermediate steps in the formation of 2D perovskite.</figDesc><graphic coords="24,72.00,72.00,468.00,286.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure S21 |</head><label>S21</label><figDesc>Figure S21 | The PBE+TS calculated formation energy of a) step 1 and b) step 2 for different RDP widths (n = 1, 2, 3, 4) and different ligands (L = BTA, HA, OTA, PEA, 2F-PEA, 3F-PEA, 4F-PEA). In a), the formation energy of bulk FAPbI3 is shown as a black dashed line.</figDesc><graphic coords="24,72.00,424.95,468.00,97.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Figure S22 |</head><label>S22</label><figDesc>Figure S22 | The PBE+TS relaxed slab structures (only the PbI2 octahedral are shown) for different RDP widths (n = 2, 3, 4) and ligands (L = PEA, 2F-PEA, 3F-PEA, 4F-PEA).</figDesc><graphic coords="25,72.00,276.21,468.00,342.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure S23 |Figure S25 |</head><label>S23S25</label><figDesc>Figure S23 | Steady-state PL measurements of Control, 2D treated and quasi-2D treated films for (a) PEA, (b) BTA and (c) 3F-PEALigand Treatment PLQY Control None 0.67 BTA 2D 1.44 Quasi-2D 1.58 PEA 2D 1.73 Quasi-2D 2.33 3F-PEA 2D 3.30 Quasi-2D 3.91 Table S6 | Calculated PLQY values for each treatment</figDesc><graphic coords="26,51.55,398.11,468.85,163.15" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure S26 |</head><label>S26</label><figDesc>Figure S26 | Global fitting of a) control, b) 2D treated and c) quasi-2D treated samples.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>Figure S28 |Figure S29 |</head><label>S28S29</label><figDesc>Figure S28 | Transient absorption traces of the n = 2 bleach (~ 570 nm) for 2D and quasi-2D treated films (using PEAI) with and without a PCBM extraction layer. The films were excited by a 450 nm (5 µJcm -2 ) pump pulse. When a PCBM layer was added, the absorption from the 2D decays more quickly for both the 2D and quasi-2D treated films indicating that charge extraction into the PCBM is favoured over charge funnelling to n &gt; 2 2D species in the quasi-2D treated films. Monoexponential fitting was used to calculate the lifetime (τ). Time traces for (a) a 2D treated film, and (b) a quasi-2D treated film. (c) Illustration of n = 2 bleach decay. (d) Summary of decay times. Note that the rapid decrease in decay time using PCBM for both treatments suggests that carrier extraction into n &gt; 2 RDP is does not limit charge extraction.</figDesc><graphic coords="32,66.60,308.70,213.05,199.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Figure S30 |Figure S31 |</head><label>S30S31</label><figDesc>Figure S30 | SEM images of the surface of (a) Control, (b) 2D treated and (c) quasi-2D treated films</figDesc><graphic coords="34,322.05,263.15,201.35,160.95" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>FigureFigure S33 |</head><label>S33</label><figDesc>Figure S32 | C-AFM of different samples. Perovskite films on NiOx/ITO substrate under illumination. (a) control, (b) 2D treated, (c) quasi-2D treated.</figDesc><graphic coords="35,72.00,327.60,451.30,152.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure S34 |</head><label>S34</label><figDesc>Figure S34 | Performance statistics for 3F-PEA treated devices. Taken from 20 devices of each control, 2D treated and quasi-2D treated.</figDesc><graphic coords="37,51.60,72.00,451.30,366.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Figure S35 |</head><label>S35</label><figDesc>Figure S35 | Performance statistics for BTA treated devices. Taken from 20 devices of each control, 2D treated and quasi-2D treated.</figDesc><graphic coords="38,72.00,509.02,451.30,163.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Figure S36 |</head><label>S36</label><figDesc>Figure S36 | Performance statistics for all ligands, 2D and quasi-2D treated. Taken from 10-20 devices for each condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>Figure S37 |</head><label>S37</label><figDesc>Figure S37 | Season dependant performance statistics for control devices across all four seasons, 14 devices per batch</figDesc><graphic coords="39,72.00,72.00,451.30,302.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_26"><head>Figure S39 |</head><label>S39</label><figDesc>Figure S39 | Season dependant performance statistics for q-2D treated (3F-PEA) devices across all four seasons, 14 devices per batch.</figDesc><graphic coords="40,71.80,72.00,451.30,306.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_27"><head>Figure S40 |</head><label>S40</label><figDesc>Figure S40 | Comparison of experimental results and simulations. (a) Experimental results Taken from Fig 4 d). (b) Simulated J-V curves varying the surface trap density (δ), (c) Comparison demonstrating that the FF increase from the experimental data is unlikely to be a result of reducing δ alone.</figDesc><graphic coords="40,71.80,468.30,451.30,166.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_28"><head>Figure S41 |</head><label>S41</label><figDesc>Figure S41 | Stability test on 2D and quasi-2D treated films.Each film was treated with a 2D or quasi-2D solution and then a layer of PMMA was applied atop to better simulate device conditions. A TA measurement of each film was acquired before putting the film on a hot plate in a N2 environment at 65 °C. Additional TA spectra were recorded at 3 hrs and after 20 hours at 65 °C. Each spectra shown is at a 1 ps delay. The n distribution is unchanged after 20 hours for all devices and only a small change in absorption is visible, which is less obvious in the 3F-PEA treated films.</figDesc><graphic coords="41,72.00,72.00,451.30,461.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head>Figure S42 |</head><label>S42</label><figDesc>Figure S42| Bandgap from EQE of champion device using the method from35  the bandgap was calculated to be 1.53 eV.</figDesc><graphic coords="42,135.65,79.10,323.35,245.22" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>Figure S43 |</head><label>S43</label><figDesc>Figure S43 | Certificate of photovoltaic performance for a 3F-PEA ligand, quasi-2D treated device using an ITO/NiOx/Perovskite/quasi-2D/C60/BCP structure. Quasi-steady state method. Source: NREL.</figDesc><graphic coords="43,72.00,72.00,451.27,512.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S44 | J-V curves and figures of merit for devices used in stability testing. RT = unencapsulated device used for room temperature MPP tracking (using the ITO/ NiOx/Perovskite/quasi-2D/PCBM/BCP structure). 65 = encapsulated device used for 65°C elevated temperature testing (using the ITO/ NiOx/Perovskite/quasi-2D/C60/SnO2 structure).</figDesc><graphic coords="44,164.80,72.00,264.75,264.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_32"><head>Figure S45 |</head><label>S45</label><figDesc>Figure S45 | Linear extrapolation of stability testing. Using linear extrapolation, we estimate the T80 lifetime of our quasi-2D treated device to be ~1190hrs.</figDesc><graphic coords="45,173.15,324.65,249.00,234.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_33"><head>Figure S46 |</head><label>S46</label><figDesc>Figure S46 | Forward and reverse scans of a 3F-PEAI treated device with associated figures of merit. Hysteresis is ~ 1%.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_34"><head>2</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig.S46</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_36"><head>Fig. 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1 | Quasi-2D treatment and its effect on RDP distribution. a, Schematic of n = 1, 2, 3 and 4 RDPs. b, Band alignment of 3D and RDP films with increasing confinement calculated from UPS and the optical bandgap of quasi-2D perovskite films. c, The eight ligands used in the study: 1, phenethylammonium; 2, 4-fluoro-phenethylammonium; 3, 3-fluoro-phenethylammonium; 4, 2-fluoro-phenethylammonium; 5, butylammonium; 6, hexylammonium; 7, octylammonium; and 8, 1-naphthylmethylammonium. d,e, Schematics of the standard 2D treatment (d) and the quasi-2D treatment (e) producing n ≤ 2 RDPs and n ≥ 2 RDPs, respectively.</figDesc><graphic coords="54,197.13,172.85,106.68,88.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_37"><head>Fig. 2 |</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 | Comparison of 2D and quasi-2D treatments using different 2D ligands. a-c, TA spectra of films treated with BTA (a), PEA (b) and 3F-PEA (c) using the standard 2D treatment.d-f, TA spectra of films treated with BTA (d), PEA (e) and 3F-PEA (f) using the quasi-2D treatment. The majority absorption in each case is from the 3D perovskite (780 nm) but this has been excluded for clarity. Absorption peaks are assigned in order, and a comparison with single-cation quasi-2D films is shown in Supplementary Table4. The inset bar in a-f represents the relative absorption from each RDP species. g-h, Absorption maps from in situ TA spectroscopy obtained during spin coating. Cs 0.05 MA 0.1 FA 0.85 PbI 3 3D perovskite films were spun at 1,500 r.p.m. and a constant 1 ps pump-probe delay time was used. The quasi-2D treatments for BTA (g), PEA (h) and 3F-PEA (i) were all dropped at 7.2 s.</figDesc><graphic coords="55,372.70,304.54,161.88,92.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_38"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 2 | Comparison of 2D and quasi-2D treatments using different 2D ligands. a-c, TA spectra of films treated with BTA (a), PEA (b) and 3F-PEA (c) using the standard 2D treatment.d-f, TA spectra of films treated with BTA (d), PEA (e) and 3F-PEA (f) using the quasi-2D treatment. The majority absorption in each case is from the 3D perovskite (780 nm) but this has been excluded for clarity. Absorption peaks are assigned in order, and a comparison with single-cation quasi-2D films is shown in Supplementary Table4. The inset bar in a-f represents the relative absorption from each RDP species. g-h, Absorption maps from in situ TA spectroscopy obtained during spin coating. Cs 0.05 MA 0.1 FA 0.85 PbI 3 3D perovskite films were spun at 1,500 r.p.m. and a constant 1 ps pump-probe delay time was used. The quasi-2D treatments for BTA (g), PEA (h) and 3F-PEA (i) were all dropped at 7.2 s.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_39"><head>Fig. 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig.3| Formation of quasi-2D perovskite capping layers from density functional theory. a, The PBE+TS calculated formation energy of perovskite flakes ((FA) n-1 Pb n I 3n-1 , see inset). The formation energy of FAPbI 3 is shown as a dashed line. Note that the energy required to form a single-layer (PbI 2 ) flake (n = 1 RDP) is much higher than for other layer widths. PBE+TS, Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof functional with the Tkatchenko-Scheffler dispersion correction. b, The formation energy of different RDPs dependent on the layer width n and the ligand (BTA, PEA and 3F-PEA). The same calculations were performed on HA, OTA, 2F-PEA and 4F-PEA and can be found in Supplementary Fig.21.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_40"><head>Fig. 4 |Fig. 5 |</head><label>45</label><figDesc>Fig. 4 | Quantifying the conduction band offset of 2D and quasi-2D surface treatments. a-c, IPES spectra of BTA-(a), PEA-(b) and 3F-PEA-treated (c) films using 2D and quasi-2D treatments. The dashed lines represent the gaussians used to fit the data. The shaded region represents the change in conduction band edge. IPES measurements were taken using a bandpass filter of 254 nm (4.88 eV) for the control and PEA-treated films and 280 nm (4.42 eV) for BTA-and 3F-PEA-treated films. E vac , vacuum level. d, Cross-section of a typical 2D/3D heterostructure in the PIN configuration. e,f, The band alignment of the resulting cell using the 2D treatment (e) or the quasi-2D treatment (f). Values in e,f were calculated for a PEA treatment using combined UPS and IPES.</figDesc><graphic coords="57,251.81,213.36,117.96,78.48" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,117.95,451.30,441.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="5,146.90,333.05,301.07,236.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="10,134.85,155.89,302.60,237.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="27,53.85,75.15,451.30,163.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="31,72.00,93.65,451.30,279.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="33,71.90,79.15,451.30,236.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table S5 | Fitting parameters and calculated band alignment values from</head><label>S5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>WF</cell><cell>VB χo</cell><cell cols="3">VB σ VBM (IE) CB χo</cell><cell cols="3">CB σ CBM (EA) Bandgap (eV)</cell></row><row><cell>Control</cell><cell>4.92</cell><cell>1.47</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>5.49</cell><cell>3.08</cell><cell>0.29</cell><cell>3.93</cell><cell>1.56</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">2D (PEA) treated 4.76</cell><cell>1.84</cell><cell>0.37</cell><cell>5.53</cell><cell>2.50</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>3.51</cell><cell>2.02</cell></row><row><cell>quasi-2D (PEA)</cell><cell>4.88</cell><cell>1.65</cell><cell>0.35</cell><cell>5.51</cell><cell>2.90</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>3.79</cell><cell>1.71</cell></row><row><cell>treated</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Gaussian fitting of</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">combined UPS/IPES measurement from control and treated films.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table S7 | Summary of calculated photoluminescent lifetimes 316</head><label>S7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>τ1 (ns)</cell><cell>τ2 (ns)</cell></row><row><cell>Control</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>681</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>+ PCBM</cell><cell>4.6</cell><cell>581</cell></row><row><cell>PEA</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>958</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2D + PCBM</cell><cell>12.1</cell><cell>196</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D</cell><cell>1117</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D + PCBM</cell><cell>6.2</cell><cell>317</cell></row><row><cell>3F-PEA</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>2309</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2D + PCBM</cell><cell>9.2</cell><cell>17.9</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D</cell><cell>3398</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D + PCBM</cell><cell>4.9</cell><cell>8.2</cell></row><row><cell>BTA</cell><cell>2D</cell><cell>118.3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2D + PCBM</cell><cell>33.3</cell><cell>176</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D</cell><cell>146.5</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quasi-2D + PCBM</cell><cell>16.3</cell></row><row><cell>317</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table S9 | Summary of reported device efficiency and stability corresponding to Figure S1.</head><label>S9</label><figDesc>The 479 reported efficiency is the best certified or best reported in the paper. The stability corresponds to the 480 most rigorous stability test undertaken. It should be noted that names with a * beside them use a different 481 ETL and/or HTL for their stability experiments. The entries in bold font represent stability 482 measurements at elevated temperature under illumination. No other report uses the full ISOS-L3</figDesc><table><row><cell>483</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>484</cell><cell cols="3">protocol (controlled 65°C testing, under illuminations MPP-tracking, ~ 50% RH).</cell></row><row><cell>485</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Name on Figure S1</cell><cell>Efficiency (%)</cell><cell>Stability</cell><cell>Ref.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>M. Degani, Sci. Adv.</cell><cell>23.7</cell><cell>No drop in PCE after 0.5 hrs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>S. Wu, Joule (2020)</cell><cell>22.31</cell><cell>T98 = 10hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>F. Li, JACS (2020)</cell><cell>22.7 (certified)</cell><cell>T90 = 200hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>J. Xue, Science (2021)</cell><cell>23.0</cell><cell>T85 = 2000hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>H. Lu, Science (2020)</cell><cell>23.1</cell><cell>T90 = 500hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>J. Yoo, Nature (2021)</cell><cell>25.2 (certified)</cell><cell>T80 = 500 hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>J. Jeong, Nature (2021)</cell><cell>25.2 (certified)</cell><cell>T85 = 450 hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>H. Min, Nature (2021)</cell><cell>25.5 (certified)</cell><cell>T90 = 500 hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>M. Kim, Science (2022)</cell><cell>25.4 (certified)</cell><cell>T80 = 350 hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Y. Jeong, Science (2020)</cell><cell>24.64</cell><cell>T87 = 500hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>H. Zhu, Adv. Mat. (2020)</cell><cell>23.5</cell><cell>T95 = 1000hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>B. Park, Nature Energy (2021)</cell><cell>23.9</cell><cell>No degradation, 2000hr (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Z. Dai, Science (2021)</cell><cell>21.4</cell><cell>T90 = 1200hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>E.H. Jung, Nature (2019)</cell><cell>22.7 (certified)</cell><cell>T95 = 1370hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>N. Li, Science (2021)</cell><cell>22.3 (certified)</cell><cell>T95 ~ 2000 hrs (RT)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>H. Min, Science (2019)*</cell><cell>23.7 (certified)</cell><cell>T90 = 20hrs (150°C)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Q. Jiang, Nat. Photon. (2019)*</cell><cell>23.32 (certified)</cell><cell>T80 = 500hrs (85°C)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>G. Kim, Science (2020)*</cell><cell>24.37 (certified)</cell><cell>T80 = 1300hrs (85°C)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Y. Jang, Nat. Energy (2021)*</cell><cell>24.35 (certified)</cell><cell>T94 = 1000 hrs (85°C)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>J. Peng, Science (2021)</cell><cell>23.17</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>NATuRE PHoToNiCS | VOL 16 | MAY 2022 | 352-358 | www.nature.com/naturephotonics</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_1"><p>© The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited 2022 NATuRE PHoToNiCS | VOL 16 | MAY 2022 | 352-358 | www.nature.com/naturephotonics</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_2"><p>NATuRE PHoToNiCS | www.nature.com/naturephotonics</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research was made possible by the <rs type="funder">US Department of the Navy, Office of Naval</rs> <rs type="grantName">Research Grant</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">N00014-20-1-2572</rs>). This work was supported in part by the <rs type="funder">Ontario Research Fund</rs>-<rs type="programName">Research Excellence program</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">ORF7</rs><rs type="funder">-Ministry of Research and Innovation</rs>, <rs type="funder">Ontario Research Fund-Research Excellence Round 7)</rs>. We appreciate the <rs type="institution" subtype="infrastructure">Shanghai Synchrotron Radiation Facility</rs> (beamline <rs type="grantNumber">14B</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">16B</rs>) and <rs type="person">X. Gao</rs> and <rs type="person">Z. Su</rs> for their help with GIWAXS characterization. Z.N. is grateful for support by the <rs type="funder">National Key Research Program</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">2021YFA0715502</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">2016YFA0204000</rs>) and the <rs type="funder">National Science Fund of China</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">61935016</rs>). S.M.P., H.R.A. and K.R.G. acknowledge the <rs type="funder">US Department of Energy</rs> under Grant <rs type="grantNumber">DE-SC0018208</rs> for supporting the <rs type="institution">UPS</rs> and IPES measurements. T.F. and T.C. acknowledge the <rs type="funder">Canadian Foundation for Innovation and the Natural Science and Engineering Council of Canada (NSERC)</rs> for KPFM measurements. F.L and Y.G. were funded by the <rs type="funder">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST) Office of Sponsored Research (OSR)</rs> under Award No: <rs type="grantNumber">OSR-CARF/CCF-3079</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">OSR-2018-CRG7-3737</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_8fQexMP">
					<idno type="grant-number">N00014-20-1-2572</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Research Grant</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_HQJvWMH">
					<idno type="grant-number">ORF7</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Research Excellence program</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_v8JMUpZ">
					<idno type="grant-number">14B</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_cHbbeg2">
					<idno type="grant-number">16B</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_3jEkhtJ">
					<idno type="grant-number">2021YFA0715502</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_BaCyPP7">
					<idno type="grant-number">2016YFA0204000</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_FTCT46E">
					<idno type="grant-number">61935016</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_gBYH7zm">
					<idno type="grant-number">DE-SC0018208</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Ezns4Du">
					<idno type="grant-number">OSR-CARF/CCF-3079</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_YjXm6FM">
					<idno type="grant-number">OSR-2018-CRG7-3737</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<listOrg type="infrastructure">
				<org type="infrastructure">					<orgName type="extracted">Shanghai Synchrotron Radiation Facility</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>Source data are provided with this paper. All the data supporting the findings of this study are available within this article and its Supplementary Information. Any additional information can be obtained from corresponding authors upon request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary materials for</head><p>Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells Hao Chen, 1,2, † Sam Teale, 1, † Bin Chen, 1, † Yi Hou, <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">4</ref>, † Luke Grater, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Tong Zhu, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Koen Bertens, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> So Min Park, <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">3</ref> Harindi R. Atapattu, <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Yajun Gao, <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Mingyang Wei, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Andrew K.</p><p>Johnston, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Qilin Zhou, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Kaimin Xu, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Danni Yu, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Congcong Han, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Teng Cui, <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Eui Hyuk Jung, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Chun Zhou, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Wenjia Zhou, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Andrew H. Proppe, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Sjoerd Hoogland, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Frédéric Laquai, <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Tobin Filleter, <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Kenneth R. Graham, <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Zhijun Ning, 2* Edward H. Sargent 1* Publisher's note Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Articles</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nature PhotoNics</head><p>Photoluminescence quantum yield measurements. The excitation source was an unfocused beam from a 442 nm continuous-wave diode laser. Photoluminescence was collected using an integrating sphere with a pre-calibrated fibre coupled to a spectrometer (QE Pro, Ocean Optics) with an intensity of ~100 mW cm -2 . PLQY values were calculated using PLQY = PS Pex×A , where A = 1 -PL/PEx, P S is the integrated photon count of the sample emission on laser excitation, P ex is the integrated photon count of the excitation laser when the sample is removed from the integrating sphere and P L is the integrated photon count of excitation laser when sample is mounted in the integrating sphere and hit by the beam.</p><p>Space-charge-limited current measurements. SCLC measurements were obtained using electron-only (ITO/SnO x /perovskite/PCBM/Ag) devices and hole-only (ITO/NiO x /perovskite/poly(triaryl amine)/Au) devices separately. A Keithly 2400 source meter was used to measure the relevant J-V curves. We calculated the trap density (n t ) by SCLC measurement in the hole-only and electron-only devices. The trap-state density n t can be calculated using the following relation:</p><p>where e is the elementary charge, L is the perovskite film thickness (~650 nm), ε 0 is the vacuum permittivity, ε is the relative dielectric constant and V TFL is the onset voltage of trap-filled limit region.</p><p>Transient photoluminescence spectroscopy. TRPL measurements were carried out using a Horiba Fluorolog time-correlated single photon counting system with photomultiplier tube detectors. A pulsed laser diode (634 nm, 110-140 ps pulse width) was used as the excitation source for steady-state and transient measurements. For transient measurements, a 7,200 ns period for unquenched films and an 800 ns period for quenched films (0.28 nJ per pulse) was used to capture accurate carrier lifetimes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inverse photoelectron spectroscopy and ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy.</head><p>For combined UPS and IPES measurements, an Excitech H Lyman-α photon source (10.2 eV) with an oxygen-filled beam path was used for excitation, coupled with a PHI 5600 ultrahigh vacuum system with a hemispherical electron energy analyser. A sample bias of -5 V and a pass energy of 5.85 eV were used for UPS acquisition. IPES measurements were performed in the Bremsstrahlung isochromat mode with electron kinetic energies below 5 eV and an emission current of 2 μA to minimize sample damage. A Kimball Physics ELG-2 electron gun with a barium oxide cathode was used to generate the electron beam; the emitted photons were collected using a bandpass photon detector that included an optical bandpass filter (280 nm for 3F-PEA-and BTA-treated films, and 254 nm for the control and PEA-treated films) and a photomultiplier tube (R585, Hamamatsu Photonics). Samples were held at a -20 V bias during all IPES measurements and the ultrahigh vacuum chamber was blacked-out to exclude external light. Perovskite films sent for combined UPS/IPES were fabricated on ITO/NiO x substrates.</p><p>UPS measurements of quasi-2D perovskite films were carried out using a Thermo Fisher ESCALAB 250XL instrument; a -10 V bias was applied for UPS measurements.</p><p>Transient photovoltage/photocurrent measurements. These measurements were carried out according to ref. <ref type="bibr">47</ref> .</p><p>Kelvin probe force microscopy. KPFM was conducted using an MFP-3D AFM (Asylum Research, Oxford Instruments) with conductive Ti/Ir-coated tips (ASYELEC.01-R2 probe, f = 71.72 kHz, k = 2.8 N m -1 ). The tips were calibrated using Sader's method <ref type="bibr">58,</ref><ref type="bibr">59</ref> . The KPFM measurement was implemented using a two-path method at a scan rate of 0.5 Hz, where the first pass in every scan line was used to determine the topography and the following second pass was used to measure the contact potential difference between the tip and the sample. The second pass was scanned by raising the tip at a fixed 20 nm height above the sample following the topography. Each set of samples was arranged in proximity on a common substrate and were measured using the same tip and scanning parameters. We also adopted different scanning sequences of the samples in each set to ensure that the obtained potential trend is reliable and the global drift (if any) is not dominating. The two sets of samples (PEA-and 3F-PEA-treated) were measured using different probes, thus a shift in the overall potential is observed.</p><p>Reporting Summary. Further information on research design is available in the Nature Research Reporting Summary linked to this article. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary information</head><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-022-00985-1">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-022-00985-1</ref>.</p><p>Correspondence and requests for materials should be addressed to Zhijun Ning or Edward H. Sargent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Peer review information Nature Photonics thanks Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Ling</head><p>Xu the other, anonymous, reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p><p>Reprints and permissions information is available at www.nature.com/reprints. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Solar Cells Reporting Summary</head><p>Nature Research wishes to improve the reproducibility of the work that we publish. This form is intended for publication with all accepted papers reporting the characterization of photovoltaic devices and provides structure for consistency and transparency in reporting. Some list items might not apply to an individual manuscript, but all fields must be completed for clarity.</p><p>For further information on Nature Research policies, including our data availability policy, see Authors &amp; Referees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental design</head><p>Please check: are the following details reported in the manuscript?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Dimensions Area of the tested solar cells</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Yes No</head><p>The small area of solar cells is 0.053 cm2 (Methods -Solar Cell fabrication)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method used to determine the device area Yes No</head><p>The active area is 0.049 cm2 (Methods -Device testing)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Current-voltage characterization</head><p>Current density-voltage (J-V) plots in both forward and backward direction</p><note type="other">Yes No Figure S46</note><p>Voltage scan conditions </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensional Mixing Increases the Efficiency of 2D/3D Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Teale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1021/acs.jpclett.0c01444</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5115" to="5119" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visualization and suppression of interfacial recombination for highefficiency large-area pin perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stolterfoht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="847" to="854" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modelling polycrystalline semiconductor solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Burgelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nollet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Degrave</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Thin Solid Films</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">361</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<publisher>Elsevier Sequoia SA</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolving spatial and energetic distributions of trap states in metal halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1352" to="1358" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electron affinity and work function of polycrystalline SnO2 thin film</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Hakim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Sci. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nickel oxide for inverted structure perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Energy Chemistry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="411" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chemical management for colorful, efficient, and stable inorganic-organic hybrid nanostructured solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Noh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Im</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Heo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Mandal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Seok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Il</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1764" to="1769" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthesis, characterization and dielectric properties of SnO2 thin films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Yildirim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Yildirim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Sakar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ateş</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Spectrochim. Acta -Part A Mol. Biomol. Spectrosc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relativistic quasiparticle selfconsistent electronic structure of hybrid halide perovskite photovoltaic absorbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Brivio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Schilfgaarde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155204</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dielectric properties of cobalt oxide, nickel oxide, and their mixed crystals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Smakula</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2031" to="2038" />
			<date type="published" when="1965">1965</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PHYSICAL RE V&apos;f EW B VOLUME</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Button</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fonstad~</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gang Dreybrodt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NUM BE R 12 15 DECEMBER 1971 Determination of the Electron Masses in Stannic Oxide by Submillimeter Cyclotron Resonance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determination of the exciton binding energy and effective masses for methylammonium and formamidinium lead tri-halide perovskite semiconductors †</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Galkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">962</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orbital hybridization-induced band offset phenomena in Ni: XCd1-xO thin films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nanoscale</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="669" to="686" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SnO 2 : A Wonderful Electron Transport Layer for Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>You</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Small</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1801154</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Charge-Carrier Mobilities in Metal Halide Perovskites: Fundamental Mechanisms and Limits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1021/acsenergylett.7b00276</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nonstoichiometry and hole doping in NiO</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Osorio-Guillén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zunger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1199</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">128</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Band-gay narrowing and band structure in degenerate tin oxide (Sno2) films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sanon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rup</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mansingh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PHYSICAL REVIEW</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CuSCN as Hole Transport Material with 3D/2D Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Madhavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Appl. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Comment on &quot;Resolving spatial and energetic distributions of trap states in metal halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ravishankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Unold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kirchartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reduced-dimensional perovskite photovoltaics with homogeneous energy landscape</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Near-ultraviolet inverse photoemission spectroscopy using ultra-low energy electrons</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yoshida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">539</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">540</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new photon source for ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy of organic and other damage-prone materials</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Butrouna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Org. Electron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valence and Conduction Band Densities of States of Metal Halide Perovskites: A Combined Experimental-Theoretical Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Endres</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2722" to="2729" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ab initio molecular simulations with numeric atom-centered orbitals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Phys. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">180</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2175" to="2196" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient OðNÞ integration for all-electron electronic structure calculation using numeric basis functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Havu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Havu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Scheffler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Comput. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">228</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8367" to="8379" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolution-of-identity approach to Hartree-Fock, hybrid density functionals, RPA, MP2 and GW with numeric atom-centered orbital basis functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New J. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">53020</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Gradient Approximation Made Simple</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Perdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ernzerhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3865</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate molecular van der Waals interactions from ground-state electron density and free-atom reference data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ruddlesden-Popper Hybrid Lead Iodide Perovskite 2D Homologous Semiconductors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Stoumpos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2852" to="2867" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthetic control over orientational degeneracy of spacer cations enhances solar cell efficiency in two-dimensional perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measurement of surface recombination velocity in semiconductors by diffraction from picosecond transient free-carrier gratings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jarašiūnas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gerritsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Nurmikko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">536</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subpicosecond surface-restricted carrier and thermal dynamics by transient reflectivity measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tanaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sawada</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4033</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Top and bottom surfaces limit carrier lifetime in lead iodide perovskite films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low surface recombination velocity in solution-grown CH3NH3PbBr3 perovskite single crystal</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photovoltaic solar cell technologies: analysing the state of the art</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Nayak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mahesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Snaith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cahen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">23.7% Efficient inverted perovskite solar cells by dual interfacial modification</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Degani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7930</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modulation of Defects and Interfaces through Alkylammonium Interlayer for Efficient Inverted Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1248" to="1262" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regulating Surface Termination for Efficient Inverted Perovskite Solar Cells with Greater Than 23% Efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20134" to="20142" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconfiguring the band-edge states of photovoltaic perovskites by conjugated organic cations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">371</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="636" to="640" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vapor-assisted deposition of highly efficient, stable black-phase FAPbI3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">80</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient perovskite solar cells via improved carrier management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">590</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudo-halide anion engineering for α-FAPbI3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">381</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solar cells with atomically coherent interlayers on SnO2 electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">598</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal quantum dot-SnO2 layers as electron transporters for efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable perovskite solar cells with efficiency exceeding 24.8% and 0.3-V voltage loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1615" to="1620" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tailored Amphiphilic Molecular Mitigators for Stable Perovskite Solar Cells with 23.5% Efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1907757</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilization of formamidinium lead triiodide α-phase with isopropylammonium chloride for perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interfacial toughening with self-assembled monolayers enhances perovskite solar cell reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="618" to="622" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient, stable and scalable perovskite solar cells using poly(3hexylthiophene)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">567</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liquid medium annealing for fabricating durable perovskite solar cells with improved reproducibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">373</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="561" to="567" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient, stable solar cells by using inherent bandgap of a-phase formamidinium lead iodide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">366</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="753" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface passivation of perovskite film for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of strain relaxation on performance of a-formamidinium lead iodide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intact 2D/3D halide junction perovskite solar cells via solid-phase in-plane growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nanoscale localized contacts for high fill factors in polymer-passivated perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">371</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="390" to="395" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing grains and interfaces via ligand anchoring enables 22.3%-efficiency inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving Efficiency and Stability of Perovskite Solar Cells Enabled by A Near-Infrared-Absorbing Moisture Barrier</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1575" to="1593" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metastable Dion-Jacobson 2D structure enables efficient and stable perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lead halide-templated crystallization of methylamine-free perovskite for efficient photovoltaic modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1327" to="1332" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming Redox Reactions at Perovskite-Nickel Oxide Interfaces to Boost Voltages in Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Boyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1759" to="1775" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A piperidinium salt stabilizes efficient metal-halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planar perovskite solar cells with long-term stability using ionic liquid additives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">571</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilizing heterostructures of soft perovskite semiconductors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">365</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="691" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilizing halide perovskite surfaces for solar cell operation with widebandgap lead oxysalts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">365</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="478" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2D metal-organic framework for stable perovskite solar cells with minimized lead leakage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Nanotechnol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="934" to="940" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodine reduction for reproducible and highperformance perovskite solar cells and modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8130</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing heterojunctions by surface sulfidation for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable and low-photovoltage-loss perovskite solar cells by multifunctional passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41566-021-00829-4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021 1-9 (2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite energy funnels for efficient light-emitting diodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Nanotechnol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="872" to="877" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ultrafast narrowband exciton routing within layered perovskite nanoplatelets enables low-loss luminescent solar concentrators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="205" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthetic control over quantum well width distribution and carrier migration in low-dimensional perovskite photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Proppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2890" to="2896" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ligand-stabilized reduced-dimensionality perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Quan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2649" to="2655" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient, stable and scalable perovskite solar cells using poly(3-hexylthiophene)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">567</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient, stable solar cells by using inherent bandgap of α-phase formamidinium lead iodide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">366</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="753" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable perovskite solar cells with efficiency exceeding 24.8% and 0.3-V voltage loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1615" to="1620" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface passivation of perovskite film for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tailored amphiphilic molecular mitigators for stable perovskite solar cells with 23.5% efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1907757</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ultrahydrophobic 3D/2D fluoroarene bilayer-based water-resistant perovskite solar cells with efficiencies exceeding 22%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2543</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of strain relaxation on performance of α-formamidinium lead iodide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudo-halide anion engineering for α-FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensional mixing increases the efficiency of 2D/3D perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Teale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5115" to="5119" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An interface stabilized perovskite solar cell with high stabilized efficiency and low voltage loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2192" to="2199" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hybrid perovskite/perovskite heterojunction solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5999" to="6007" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multication perovskite 2D/3D interfaces form via progressive dimensional reduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Proppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3472</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intact 2D/3D halide junction perovskite solar cells via solid-phase in-plane growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable and efficient 3D-2D perovskite-perovskite planar heterojunction solar cell without organic hole transport layer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2706" to="2721" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planar perovskite solar cells with long-term stability using ionic liquid additives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">571</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A piperidinium salt stabilizes efficient metal-halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing grains and interfaces via ligand anchoring enables 22.3%-efficiency inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodine reduction for reproducible and high-performance perovskite solar cells and modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8130</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Arylammonium-assisted reduction of the open-circuit voltage deficit in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells: the role of suppressed ion migration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2560" to="2568" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensional engineering of a graded 3D-2D halide perovskite interface enables ultrahigh V oc enhanced stability in the p-i-n photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1701038</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface ligands for methylammonium lead iodide films: surface coverage, energetics, and photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abtahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="806" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vacuum-deposited 2D/3D perovskite heterojunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>La-Placa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2893" to="2901" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defect passivation of organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites by diammonium iodide toward high-performance photovoltaic devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-C</forename><surname>Chueh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rajagopal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Jen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">-Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="763" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photochemically cross-linked quantum well ligands for 2D/3D perovskite photovoltaics with improved photovoltage and stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Proppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14180" to="14189" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Double-sided surface passivation of 3D perovskite film for high-efficiency mixed-dimensional perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mahmud</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Funct. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1907962</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modelling polycrystalline semiconductor solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Burgelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Nollet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Degrave</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Thin Solid Films</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">361</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">362</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Highly efficient and stable planar perovskite solar cells with modulated diffusion passivation toward high power conversion efficiency and ultrahigh fill factor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sol. RRL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1900293</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2D homologous perovskites as light-absorbing materials for solar cell applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Stoumpos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Farha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kanatzidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7843" to="7850" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nanoscale charge localization induced by random orientations of organic molecules in hybrid perovskite CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compositional and orientational control in metal halide perovskites of reduced dimensionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Quintero-Bermudez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="900" to="907" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthetic control over orientational degeneracy of spacer cations enhances solar cell efficiency in two-dimensional perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1276</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interfacial engineering at the 2D/3D heterojunction for high-performance perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7181" to="7190" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b104">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Record open-circuit voltage wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells utilizing 2D/3D perovskite heterostructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gharibzadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1803699</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b105">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Practical Surface Analysis. Auger and X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy 2nd edn</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Briggs</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Seah</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b106">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence of surface ligands on energetics at FASnI 3 /C 60 interfaces and their impact on photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abtahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5209" to="5218" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b107">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Near-ultraviolet inverse photoemission spectroscopy using ultra-low energy electrons</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yoshida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">539</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">540</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b108">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new photon source for ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy of organic and other damage-prone materials</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Butrouna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Org. Electron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b109">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valence and conduction band densities of states of metal halide perovskites: a combined experimental-theoretical study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Endres</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2722" to="2729" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b110">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A solvent-based surface cleaning and passivation technique for suppressing ionic defects in high-mobility perovskite field-effect transistors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>She</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Electron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="694" to="703" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b111">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photoluminescencebased characterization of halide perovskites for photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kirchartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Márquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stolterfoht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Unold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1904134</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b112">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Charge transfer and diffusion at the perovskite/PCBM interface probed by transient absorption and reflection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sarmiento</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22095" to="22103" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b113">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spectrally resolved ultrafast exciton transfer in mixed perovskite quantum wells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Proppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="426" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b114">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correlation of energy disorder and open-circuit voltage in hybrid perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15001</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b115">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient and stable large-area perovskite solar cells with inorganic charge extraction layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="944" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b116">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nickel oxide for inverted structure perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Energy Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="411" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b117">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming redox reactions at perovskite-nickel oxide interfaces to boost voltages in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Boyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1759" to="1775" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b118">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamical evolution of the 2D/3D interface: a hidden driver behind perovskite solar cell instability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sutanto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2343" to="2348" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b119">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consensus statement for stability assessment and reporting for perovskite photovoltaics based on ISOS procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Khenkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b120">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vapor-assisted deposition of highly efficient, stable black-phase FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8985</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>References</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b121">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells incorporating secondary amines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1903559</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b122">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Band alignment towards high-efficiency NiO x -based Sn-Pb mixed perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. China Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b123">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nika: software for two-dimensional data reduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ilavsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Crystallogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="324" to="328" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b124">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GIXSGUI: a MATLAB toolbox for grazing-incidence X-ray scattering data visualization and reduction, and indexing of buried three-dimensional periodic nanostructured films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Crystallogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="917" to="926" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b125">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spring constant calibration of atomic force microscope cantilevers of arbitrary shape</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Sader</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Sci. Instrum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103705</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b126">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of cantilever geometry on the optical lever sensitivities and thermal noise method of the atomic force microscope</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Sader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mulvaney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Sci. Instrum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">113702</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
