<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Amine Additive Reactions Induced by the Soft Lewis Acidity of Pb 2+ in Halide Perovskites. Part I: Evidence for Pb-Alkylamide Formation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ross</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kerner</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tracy</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schloemer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Colorado School of Mines</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Institut Photovoltaïque d&apos;Ile de France (IPVF)</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">UMR 9006</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Palaiseau</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berry</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>New Jersey</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Sellinger</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Colorado School of Mines</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Materials Science Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Colorado School of Mines</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>Colorado</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Andlinger Center for Energy and the Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>New Jersey</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>New Jersey</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Amine Additive Reactions Induced by the Soft Lewis Acidity of Pb 2+ in Halide Perovskites. Part I: Evidence for Pb-Alkylamide Formation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">69EC95C267A09F9A8FA2EDA5AAEC90CB</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:56+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The primary precursors used in this study are butylamine (99.5%, Sigma), methylamine (33 wt% in ethanol, Sigma), PbI 2 (98%, TCI), and N,N-dimethylformamide (anhydrous, 99%, Sigma), acetonitrile (anhydrous, 99.8%, Sigma) butylammonium iodide (Dyesol), and tetrabutylammonium iodide (Sigma). All other amines were purchased from Alfa Aesar. Linear PEI (MW = 10,000) was purchased from Sigma. The butylammonium iodide and tetrabutylammonium iodide were not exposed to atmosphere due to their hygroscopic nature. The solution chemistry and sample preparation were mainly performed inside of a N 2 filled glovebox to exclude the effects of moisture and oxygen. However, it was observed to proceed similarly in atmosphere. In addition to the precursors listed above, two different purities of PbI 2 from Alfa Aesar were also examined. The higher purity (99.999% by trace metals) PbI 2 also reacted readily with amines. Solutions where PbI 2 was reacted with methylamine:ethanol in DMF were allowed to react at room temperature for several days to ensure some amide formation.</p><p>The PbI 2 /butylamine reaction product samples for XRD and XPS were prepared in a N 2 glovebox by drop casting 10 μL of solution onto a clean 1 cm x 2.5 cm glass substrate at 110 o C and annealing for 20 min. The PbI 2 /PEI was fabricated in an N 2 glovebox by spin coating PbI 2 (200 mg/mL in DMF, 4000 rpm for 35 s), annealed at 75 o C for 15 min, followed by spin coating linear-PEI (~1 mg/mL in chlorobenzene, 4000 rpm for 60 s). The MAI:PbI 2 (0.8:1 ratio, 345 mg of PbI 2 per mL of DMF) with and without methylamine additive were spin coated onto a 3 cm x 3 cm ITO substrate at 5300 rpm for 35 s also in an N 2 glovebox. A solvent exchange with toluene was performed at 4 s after the start of spinning, and the films were annealed at 75 o C for 15 min. A Bruker D8 Discover X-ray Diffractometer with a Cu X-ray tube, monochromating Göebel mirror, scintillation detector, and 0.6 mm divergence slits was used to obtain Bragg-Brentano geometry XRD patterns. A Thermo-Scientific K-Alpha X-ray Photoemission Spectrometer at a base pressure of 5x10 -8 mbar using an Al anode at a power of 72 W, hemispherical analyzer, pass energy of 50 eV, and 400 μm X-ray beam spot size was used to obtain XPS spectra. A flood gun was used to neutralize the non-conductive, drop cast samples. 1 H-NMR spectra were recorded using a JEOL ECA-500 at room temperature, and chemical shifts were referenced to the chloroform peak at 7.26 ppm and DMF at 8.0 ppm. The PbI 2 •butylamine complex was prepared by reacting PbI 2 with butylamine for 2 hours at 65 o C. The mixture was then diluted in deuterated chloroform and filtered with a 450 nm PTFE syringe filter. The filtered solution continued to react forming more precipitates. After several filtrations, the solution was suitable to collect a 1 H-NMR spectrum. TGA was performed in dynamic rate mode with a nominal rate of 50 o C/min, sensitivity of 1% mass change/min, and resolution of 4. Samples for TGA were prepared by reacting 200 mg of PbI 2 in 1 mL in DMF with 2 molar equivalents of butylamine at 65 o C for at least 2 hours to form a considerable amount of precipitate. The DMF containing excess PbI 2 , BAI, and butylamine was decanted and the solid precipitate was washed 3 more times with 3 mL of ACN. The Electronic Supplementary Material (ESI) for Journal of Materials Chemistry C. This journal is © The Royal Society of Chemistry 2018 solid was dried under vacuum for 8 h before loading into the TGA where it was dried at 150 o C for 10 min prior to starting a scan. Photoluminescence measurements were performed on an Edinburgh Instruments FLS980 photoluminescence spectrometer with an excitation wavelength of 550 nm.</p><p>Acid/Base Chemistry of a variety of Pb salts. A variety of primary and secondary amines reacted with PbX 2 salts (X = Cl, Br, I, and NO 3 ). Tertiary amines and salts of PbX (such as X = SO 4 ) were not observed to react. Salient observations include azobenzene formation between aqueous Pb(NO 3 ) 2 and aniline and gelation when PbBr 2 was reacted with butylamine in DMF under certain conditions.      Fig. <ref type="figure">S7</ref>. XRD versus time of a drop cast film of PbI 2 solvated in a butylamine atmosphere and subsequently encapsulated in PMMA by spin coating (50 mg/mL in chlorobenzene at 4000 rpm giving roughly 300 nm of PMMA). The peak at low angle decreases over time as the solvate loses butylamine at room temperature which is only slowed by the PMMA. The peaks near 2θ ≈ 6.4 o are very near to that of BA 2 PbI 4 which is expected to form from a PbI 2 •butylamine solvate exposed to atmosphere due to a reaction with water.     </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S2. (vials on the right in each image) Days old mixtures of Pb(NO 3 ) 2 and an excess of (a) butylamine, (b) diethylamine, (c) triethylamine, (d) aniline, (e) N, methylaniline, and (f) N,N dimethylaniline alongside (vials on the left in each image) a control of the neat amine liquid reacted at 50 o C. Days old mixtures of PbI 2 with an excess of (g) butylamine, (h) diethylamine, and (i) triethylamine alongside the control of the neat amine liquid reacted at 50 o C.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,72.00,132.69,479.52,346.78" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S3. A reaction of 4 equivalents of butylamine with (a) PbBr 2 in DMF (~183 mg/mL) and (b) PbI 2 (200 mg/mL) completely gelled after 1 day at 55 o C.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,119.74,388.46,438.76,329.07" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure S4 .</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Figure S4. Equimolar tetra-BAI:PbI 2 in DMF after adding 2 equivalents of butylamine and storing at room temperature for 2 months.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S5. (a) Solutions of 200 mg/mL of PbI 2 in DMF with (from left to right) 0, 0.1, 0.2, and 0.5 molar equivalents of butylamine (ba) after reacting for 1 week at 55 o C. Visible precipitates are observed to form even for small additions of butylamine down to 0.2 molar equivalents. (b) Tyndall effect helps to visualize precipitates forming for butylamine ratios down to 0.1 whereas no precipitates are observed in the control solution.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,126.00,72.00,360.00,438.26" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S6. (a) Solutions of PbI 2 in DMF (200 mg/mL) with additives ratios from left to right: methylammonium iodide (MAI):butylamine (ba):PbI 2 (molar ratio 1:1:1), formamidinium iodide (FAI):ba:PbI 2 (molar ratio 1:1:1), and ba:MAI:PbI 2 (molar ratio 0.5:0.5:1) in DMF at a concentration of 200 mg/mL with respect to PbI 2 . The solutions were reacted for one month at room temperature. The FAI and MAI deficient solutions produced an insoluble product which is clearly illustrated by the Tyndall effect (b). The ba:MAI:PbI 2 0.5:0.5:1 solution illustrates that any excess of PbI 2 w.r.t. MAI in solution is available participate in acid-base reactions with free amines.</figDesc><graphic coords="7,149.24,72.00,313.28,442.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. S9. O 1s XPS of PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF versus time showing negligible oxygen content.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure S10. XPS of a thin film of linear-PEI on a glass/Au substrate.</figDesc><graphic coords="10,189.75,72.00,264.79,188.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig.S12. N 1s XPS of the products of the neat reaction of PbI 2 with butylamine (4 equivalents, 24 hours at 60 o C) which were soluble or insoluble in ACN. The butylammonium iodide was selectively extracted due to its solubility in ACN whereas the amide product remained in the precipitate.</figDesc><graphic coords="11,63.62,413.90,581.22,267.97" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Fig. S13 .</head><label>S13</label><figDesc>Fig. S13. TGA under (a) N 2 and (b) ambient air flow of PbI 2 powder.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,98.15,119.61,415.70,215.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Evolution of the N 1s XPS of PbI 2 /butylamine reaction in DMF versus time. The lowest measurable N content is approximately 1-2 atomic % via XPS.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>70000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0hrs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1hr</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2hrs</cell></row><row><cell>Intensity (cps)</cell><cell>40000 50000 60000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>4hrs 6hrs 12hrs 24hrs 48hrs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>30000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>404</cell><cell>402</cell><cell>400</cell><cell>398</cell><cell>396</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Binding Energy (eV)</cell></row><row><cell>Fig. S8.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Information</head><note type="other">Experimental Supplementary Figures</note></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid Perovskite Formation by CH 3 NH 2 Gas-Induced Intercalation and Reaction of PbI 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Raga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yabing</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2494" to="2500" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
