<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">US Department of Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2022-09-01">1 September 2022</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Chemistry and Nanoscience Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy and Wright Center for Photovoltaics Innovation and Commercialization</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toledo</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43606</postCode>
									<settlement>Toledo</settlement>
									<region>OH</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of NanoEngineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Diego</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>92093</postCode>
									<settlement>La Jolla</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Materials Science Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Renewable and Sustainable Energy Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309</postCode>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309</postCode>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Chemistry and Nanoscience Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics and Astronomy and Wright Center for Photovoltaics Innovation and Commercialization</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toledo</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toledo</settlement>
									<region>OH</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="department">Department of NanoEngineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Diego</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>La Jolla</addrLine>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff9">
								<orgName type="department">Materials Science Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Renewable Energy Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Golden</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff10">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Renewable and Sustainable Energy Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff11">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2022-09-01">1 September 2022</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E7A6228F4B8393AA3AFA2F58397DED44</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41586-022-05268-x</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: 15 April 2022 Accepted: 23 August 2022</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We performed 1 H-NMR to support our proposed reaction products for 3-APy. Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows the spectra of 3-APy, MAI + 3-APy, and FAI + 3-APy in DMSO-d6. It is clear from these data that FA + and 3-APy react to form a unique product, whereas MAI and 3-APy simply exchange acidic NH protons. Our results show that a reaction has nearly fully occurred between FA + and 3-APy within 10 minutes at room temperature, which does not rule out a faster reaction time, as this is the minimum amount of time it takes to go from sample preparation to completing the measurement.</p><p>Before concluding these data as direct evidence for our proposed surface mechanism, we need quantitative integration proving a 1:2:3 H-shift ratio of the protons involved in the condensation reaction product (MPyFA, see Scheme above). Unfortunately, clean integration of chemical shifts ascribed to these protons is complicated by the FA "formic" CH peak and broad NH proton peaks overlapping with the MPyFA formic proton. Additionally, the NH3 chemical shifts are un-resolvable at this pH and temperature given how rapidly proton exchange is occurring.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>results quantitatively agree with the expected ratio of CH:CH2:NH4 = 1:2:4 to within expected uncertainty of this measurement (note the ammonia H ratio is not 3 because it is protonated by HI). Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3</ref>. (a) Downfield and (b) upfield 1 H-NMR of the FAI + 3-APy after spiking with 2 µL HI. The "formic" C-H protons in the products are identified slight downfield from the FA CH, and display the similar fine-splittings as the FA CH. The NH4 + is visible as a triplet with ~51 Hz splitting centered near 7.1 ppm. The methylene -CH2-protons corresponding to different isomers for the MPyFA product are located 4.6-4.9 ppm in (b). 400 MHz in DMSO-d6.</p><p>For reference, and to justify our integration of three different -CH2-peaks, the three possible isomers of MPyFA are depicted in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4</ref>, acknowledging both the possibility for resonance and isomers to manifest in the spectra when the proton exchange rate is negligible. Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4</ref>. Different resonance structures and isomers of the 3-MPyFA condensation product that can contribute to three different -CH2-peaks anticipated for the methylene C.</p><p>Finally, we characterized a set of samples to check for the unlikely event of a reaction between FA + and the pyridine (Py) nitrogen, i.e. -investigate the possibility of chemistries occurring besides the ammonia condensation reaction we propose. As shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">5</ref>, the peaks for pyridine in the presence of excess FAI are unchanged from the control, demonstrating the amine nitrogen is the reactive group toward the FA + molecule.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 2. Transient reflectance (TR) analysis</head><p>TR measurements were performed at 400, 600, and 700 nm excitation. By using various wavelengths for excitation, we are able to excite different volumes of the film due to changes in the absorption coefficient of the material. This means that pump wavelengths with higher photon energies (such as 400 nm) will cause a greater initial build-up of photogenerated charge carriers at the surface of the film than pump wavelengths with lower photon energies (such as 700 nm).</p><p>The distribution of photogenerated charge carriers can be well described using a onedimensional diffusion model (Equation S1), which allows for a quantitative analysis of the photogenerated carrier population over time and at different film depths. The one-dimensional diffusion model shown below was used where N(x,t) is the carrier density as a function of film depth (x) over time (t), τB is the lifetime of photogenerated charge carriers in the bulk, and D is the ambipolar diffusion coefficient of charge carriers in the film. By assuming that the initial carrier generation happens instantaneously and within the time resolution of the pump excitation pulse, the initial carrier concentration at the surface of the film can be found using</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">𝑁𝑁 0 = 𝛼𝛼(1 -𝑅𝑅)𝐽𝐽 0 (S2)</formula><p>where N0 is the initial carrier density, α is the absorption coefficient at the chosen pump wavelength, R is the reflectance of the pump, and J0 is the carrier density (calculated by the measured power output and measured spot size of the excitation pulse).</p><p>To solve the diffusion model, boundary conditions were set with the following conditions: where M is the film thickness and SRV is the surface recombination velocity. The assumption was made that the SRV at the front and back sides of the film do not vary significantly, which has been shown to be a valid assumption in previous reports. Additionally, the bulk recombination is considered to be negligible in the time window of the experiment (2.5 ns) since the bulk recombination typically occurs on a much longer time scale (&gt;5 ns). While the film thickness is a known value, this system of equations cannot be solved analytically and must be solved using a backward finite difference method. By using the numerical solution N(0,t), the TR kinetic traces (Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>) at the various pump wavelengths used are modeled with a global fit method which utilizes the above diffusion model and boundary conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 3. External radiative efficiency (ERE) measurement and analysis</head><p>PL emission was measured using 632.8-nm excitation (HeNe laser). To calculate an excitation fluence (in photons cm -2 s -1 )), the excitation beam size was determined with a CCD camera beam profiler (Thorlabs BC106N-VIS/M). We assumed that 1-sun equivalent fluence for our 1.53-eV absorber is 1.73×10 17 photons cm -2 s -1 , and we adjusted the excitation fluence to this level. To measure PL emission spectra, Princeton Instruments HRS300 spectrograph with dual Si CCD (Pixis F100) and InGaAs (PyLoN IR) detectors was used. To correct spectral responses of both detectors, commercial calibration sources (IntelliCal for vis and IR ranges, Princeton Instruments)</p><p>were placed at the sample position. Corrected PL emission spectra measured with two detectors were identical at 1.30-1.38 eV, confirming small band tails for control and target solar cells.</p><p>Spectral integration at 1.30-1.90 eV was used to determine integrated PL intensity, and integrated PL emission intensity is plotted vs. excitation fluence in the inset of Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3d</ref>. To report PL emission spectra in absolute units (photons cm -2 eV -1 s -1 ), we used the same setup to measure excitation laser light scattering from reflectance standards (2%, 5%, and 99%, LabSphere Inc). We normalized PL spectra using the data where reflectance values were known, and in this way obtained absolute PL emission spectra (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3d</ref>).</p><p>Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">17</ref>. Analysis of perovskite bandgap from the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum by taking its derivative spectrum. The bandgap was estimated to be about 1.53 eV.  <ref type="table">Supplementary Table 1</ref> Perovskite solar cells (PSCs) with an inverted structure (often referred to as the p-i-n architecture) are attractive for future commercialization owing to their easily scalable fabrication, reliable operation and compatibility with a wide range of perovskitebased tandem device architectures 1,2 . However, the power conversion efficiency (PCE) of p-i-n PSCs falls behind that of n-i-p (or normal) structure counterparts <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[6]</ref> . This large performance gap could undermine efforts to adopt p-i-n architectures, despite their other advantages. Given the remarkable advances in perovskite bulk materials optimization over the past decade, interface engineering has become the most important strategy to push PSC performance to its limit <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">8</ref> . Here we report a reactive surface engineering approach based on a simple post-growth treatment of 3-(aminomethyl)pyridine (3-APy) on top of a perovskite thin film. First, the 3-APy molecule selectively reacts with surface formamidinium ions, reducing perovskite surface roughness and surface potential fluctuations associated with surface steps and terraces. Second, the reaction product on the perovskite surface decreases the formation energy of charged iodine vacancies, leading to effective n-type doping with a reduced work function in the surface region. With this reactive surface engineering, the resulting p-i-n PSCs obtained a PCE of over 25 per cent, along with retaining 87 per cent of the initial PCE after over 2,400 hours of 1-sun operation at about 55 degrees Celsius in air.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Tables</head><p>During the past decade, perovskite solar cells (PSCs) have been widely studied as a promising alternative photovoltaic technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">6</ref> . Although the perovskite composition is still undergoing fine-tuning and improvement for specific applications, the perovskite field has accumulated various processing strategies for optimizing perovskite bulk materials, including their structure, crystallinity, defects and other optoelectronic properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[11]</ref> . As a result, interface and surface modification has become vitally important to ensure further advances in the areas of charge extraction, interface recombination and device stability <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">13</ref> . At present, the record single-junction PSC efficiencies are all based on n-i-p architectures, which are associated with the optimized electron transport layer (ETL) and perovskite absorber layer <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">14</ref> . However, the standard doped hole transport layer (HTL) in the n-i-p structure presents a challenge for simultaneously achieving both high efficiency and excellent operational reliability. The p-i-n cell structure represents an attractive option for PSC commercialization owing to its low-temperature processing and compatibility with large-scale fabrication <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">16</ref> . Much progress on long-term operation has been reported for p-i-n PSCs 1 . Moreover, the p-i-n-structure-based perovskite tandem solar cells have demonstrated efficiencies surpassing those of single-junction PSCs <ref type="bibr">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">18</ref> . Despite these attractive features, the performance of single-junction p-i-n PSCs has historically fallen behind that of n-i-p PSCs <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">19</ref> . The performance of p-i-n devices has seen clear improvement in recent years, mainly owing to strategies to improve perovskite quality and interfacial properties <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">13</ref> . However, the performance gap is still large, and significant efforts are required to accelerate p-i-n PSC development to its full potential for various applications.</p><p>PSCs have two critical junctions at the perovskite/ETL and perovskite/HTL interfaces, and their quality has been correlated with device performance, including power conversion efficiency (PCE), photocurrent density-voltage (J-V) hysteresis, and stability and reliability <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[22]</ref> . Thus, realizing high-quality junctions is key to achieving high PSC performance. During perovskite-film processing, the top-surface region is prone to defect formation owing to easier escape of volatile species such as organic molecules and iodine; thus, top-surface engineering is particularly important to push p-i-n PSCs to a new level. An ideal surface engineering approach for p-i-n PSCs should: (1) not negatively affect the bulk quality of the perovskite film; (2) not produce materials hindering charge transfer; (3) reduce the density of unwanted defects; and/or (4) have a surface region that creates a built-in electric field, ensuring effective electron extraction and reducing carrier recombination.</p><p>Here we demonstrate that a simple reactive surface engineering approach using the organic amine small-molecule 3-(aminomethyl) pyridine (3-APy, where Py denotes pyridine) can achieve these outcomes and, consequently, improve all photovoltaic parameters for p-i-n cells, amounting to a PCE greater than 25% as well as good operational stability, that is, 87% of the initial PCE for over 2,400 h at about 55 °C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Surface reaction</head><p>We first explain our design strategy of selecting 3-APy for surface treatment. Creating a built-in electric field in the surface region represents a promising approach for minimizing surface recombination and enhancing charge extraction. As good perovskite absorbers typically exhibit weak p-type conductivity or intrinsic nature, generating iodine vacancies, which are shallow donors, in the surface region is a preferred method to create the built-in electric field. The formation of a positively charged iodine vacancy (V I ) can be promoted by introducing a molecule with a negatively charged Py ring owing to their electrostatic attraction. To allow for the incorporation of the molecule without significantly perturbing the lattice in the surface region, it is better for the molecule to contain a formamidinium (FA) unit as its head. This will allow the FA unit to be incorporated into the A site of the lattice, displaying no barrier for charge transfer. In addition, the Py-ring unit will be left outside to promote the formation of a V I nearby. 3-APy is a good candidate for this purpose. It has been shown that organic amine small molecules can react with FA 1+ cations to form bulkier amidinium 1+ cations. For example, methylamine readily reacts with a FA 1+ cation, forming a N-methylformamidinium 1+ cation and releasing an ammonia (NH 3 ) molecule <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">23</ref> . 3-APy contains both a Py ring and an amine group, and is expected to react with FA 1+ to form a 1+ cation composed of an 'FA cation unit' with an attached Py ring. The reaction is depicted in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1a</ref>, where the surface FA + reacts with 3-APy, forming MPyFA + (N-(3-methylpyridine) formamidinium) and releasing NH 3 . Indeed, density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed a reaction energy of 0.72 eV, supporting a spontaneous (thermodynamically favourable) reaction. We also experimentally verified this reaction, as discussed in Supplementary Note 1.</p><p>We now describe the effect of 3-APy treatment of the perovskite surface, the composition of which is Rb 0.05 Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.85 Pb[I 0.95 Br 0.05 ] 3 , where MA is methylammonium. The 3-APy solution was applied to the perovskite surface by spin-coating. We conducted atomic force microscopy (AFM) and Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) to examine the impact of 3-APy treatment on the surface topography and potential distribution. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1b</ref> shows that for the control sample, the perovskite surface consists of clear steps (or terraced edges), which are normally an indication of highly crystalline perovskite <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">24</ref> . However, the corresponding surface potential map shows that the steps cause strong potential fluctuations (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1c</ref>). It is worth noting that various surface defects can modify the potential distribution of the perovskite surface <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">25</ref> . Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1d</ref> compares the line scan of the topography and surface potential variations from a typical perovskite region, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1b,</ref><ref type="figure">c</ref>. These potential fluctuations can be up to about 50-100 mV over a length scale of about 10-20 nm. The steps on the perovskite surface are also probably more active/reactive and effective surface defects able to cause variations in local surface charge. In contrast, the 3-APy treatment drastically smoothed out these steps and suppressed the surface potential variations (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1e-g</ref>; more comparison in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7</ref>).</p><p>The reaction-induced 'polishing' effect is also verified by scanning electron microscopy images (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8</ref>)-the perovskite </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p>surface without 3-APy treatment shows obviously terraced structures, whereas the 3-APy treatment shows a much smoother surface, which is consistent with the topography results observed in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1a,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>. This reactive surface engineering approach showed negligible impact on X-ray diffraction (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">9</ref>) and ultraviolet-visible (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">10</ref>), consistent with the 3-APy treatment being primarily a surface modification. A smoother, less defective surface is expected to be beneficial for improving the perovskite/ETL main junction <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">27</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interfacial properties</head><p>More importantly, we found that the 3-APy treatment can modify the energetics of the perovskite surface, creating a built-in electric field that should favour electron extraction and reduce charge recombination. We utilized ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) to characterize the energetics of the perovskite film with and without 3-APy treatment. The secondary electron cut-off (SECO) and the valence band maximum (VBM) spectra are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">2a</ref>. The 3-APy treatment reduced the work function from about 4.77 eV to 4.21 eV and shifted the VBM from about 0.80 eV to 1.51 eV, creating favourable surface energetics and band bending for extracting electrons and blocking holes (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">11</ref>). X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements were conducted to understand the chemical changes at the surface. Survey spectra, core-level spectra and compositional ratios are shown in Supplementary Figs. that is consistent with the C=CH-N/C-CH=N pyridinic bonds of 3-APy (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">15e</ref>,f) <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">29</ref> . Turning to the N 1s, we see a slight increase in the higher binding-energy peak that is consistent with the proposed reaction, which converts one of the lower-binding-energy C=NH 2 + / C-NH 2 amidine from FA to a pyrrolic C-NH-C bond <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">28</ref> . Moreover, we see no significant change to the peak at a lower binding energy, consistent with the aforementioned reaction being compensated by signals from the pyridinic C-N=C group of 3-APy <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">31</ref> .</p><p>The iodine deficiency is consistent with the observed effective n-type doping and reduced work function associated with 3-APy treatment, because a V I is a shallow donor <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">32</ref> . We also conducted DFT calculations to understand the mechanism leading to the observed n-type Fermi-level shift induced by the 3-APy surface treatment. For simplification, we chose FAPbI 3 for DFT modelling, as it represents the main component used in this study. The DFT results are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">2d-g</ref>. We found that transforming surface FA + via 3-APy treatment into MPyFA + (a reaction product) on the surface can reduce the formation energy of a charged V I by 0.19 eV. This reduced formation energy is consistent with the observed iodine deficiency and effective n-type doping in the surface region upon 3-APy treatment, and it is mainly owing to the electrostatic attraction between the positive charge of the V I and the negative charge on the Py-ring side of MPyFA + , which is consistent with the significant rearrangement of the MPyFA cation (Fig. <ref type="figure">2f,</ref><ref type="figure">g</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optoelectronic properties</head><p>We conducted transient reflection spectroscopy to study the effect of 3-APy treatment on surface charge carrier dynamics (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref> and Supplementary Note 2). With the 3-APy treatment, the effective surface recombination velocity decreased by one order of magnitude, from about 1.9 × 10 3 cm s -1 (control) to 0.2 × 10 3 cm s -1 (target). The ten-times reduction of the surface recombination velocity with 3-APy treatment is consistent with the improved surface potential distribution and the surface field induced by the n-type Fermi-level shift associated with the treatment. Furthermore, time-resolved microwave conductivity measurements showed an improved average weighted carrier lifetime (from about 1.7 µs to 2.1 µs; Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>) with the 3-APy treatment (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3c</ref>).</p><p>Another good way to investigate optoelectronic properties is to measure the absolute photoluminescence of the devices. The photoluminescence intensity is a direct measure of the carrier density in the perovskite absorber and the corresponding quasi-Fermi-level splitting. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3d</ref> compares the absolute intensity photoluminescence of the control and target perovskite films in the p-i-n device configuration. The external radiative efficiency increased from about 0.4 ± 0.1% (control) to 2.0 ± 0.1% (target) at about 1-sun-equivalent photon fluence (about 1.7 × 10 17 cm -2 s -1 ) (Supplementary Note 3). This corresponds to a 42-mV gain in quasi-Fermi-level splitting, which is associated with the reduction of non-radiative recombination enabled by the 3-APy treatment. The inset in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3d</ref> shows that after the 3-APy treatment, the slope of integrated photoluminescence intensity versus excitation fluence decreased from about 1.9 ± 0.1 to 1.6 ± 0.1, indicating reduced interface recombination <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">33</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Device characteristics</head><p>We examined the impact of 3-APy treatment on the device characteristics using a typical p-i-n cell stack: glass/indium tin oxide (ITO)/ MeO-2PACZ/Rb 0.05 Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.85 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 /lithium fluoride (LiF)/C 60 /bathocuproine (BCP)/silver (Ag), where MeO-2PACZ denotes [2-(3,6-Dimethoxy-9H-carbazol-9-yl)ethyl]phosphonic acid and is a self-assembled monolayer for hole-selective contact <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">34</ref> . A typical cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy image of the device </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p>stack is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">16</ref>. The perovskite film thickness is about 860 nm, with grains spanning across the film thickness. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4a</ref> compares the PSCs based on the pristine perovskite (control) and 3-APy-treated perovskite (target). The 3-APy treatment increased the PCE from 23.39% (reverse)/22.18% (forwards) to 25.49% (reverse)/25.27% (forwards), owing to improvements in all parameters (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">2</ref>). The corresponding stabilized power (SPO) was 22.85% and 25.35% for the control and target devices, respectively (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4a</ref>, inset). Moreover, the short-circuit current density J sc reached &gt;26 mA cm -2 for the target cell, which is consistent with the external quantum efficiency (EQE) results (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4b</ref>). Analysis of the EQE spectrum suggests a bandgap of about 1.53 eV (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">17</ref>), which is consistent with the optical absorption measurement (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">9</ref>). It is noted that the device hysteresis is also reduced for the target device. The improvements in these photovoltaic parameters validate the hypothesis that the observed enhancement in structural, interfacial and optoelectronic properties associated with the 3-APy treatment, as discussed in connection with Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">1</ref><ref type="figure">2</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">3</ref>, is directly relevant to photovoltaic performance. The combination of the improved J sc , open-circuit voltage (V oc ) and fill factor (FF) was further verified based on statistical comparison of the photovoltaic parameters from 72 control and 246 target devices, with an average PCE enhancement ranging from 22% to 24.4% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">18</ref>). Among these target devices, a maximum V oc of about 1.19 V (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">19</ref>) and a maximum FF of about 86% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">20</ref>) were achieved, both with PCEs of about 25%. These results further attest to the effectiveness of the reactive surface modification with 3-APy in improving the interface for enhancing charge extraction with reduced recombination loss. One such device was measured by an accredited photovoltaic laboratory, obtaining a certified stabilized PCE of 24.05 ± 0.48% using an 11-point asymptotic P max (maximum power) scan protocol (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">21</ref>), along with J-V scans yielding a reverse-scan PCE of 25.37% and forwards-scan PCE of 25.06% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">22</ref>). We found that our reactive surface treatment also worked effectively for other FA-based perovskites (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">23</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">24</ref>) as well as various 3-APy-related molecules (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">25</ref>), making our approach a general strategy for improving p-i-n device performance. It is worth noting that surface treatment using the 3-APy-based iodide salt (3-APyI 2 )-which can form a two-dimensional surface layer-does not improve p-i-n device performance (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">26</ref>), probably owing to interfacial energy misalignment <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">13</ref> . Furthermore, 3-APy surface treatment in n-i-p devices significantly decreased device performance (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure">27</ref> and<ref type="figure">28</ref>), which confirms that n-type surface doping is ideal for p-i-n device operation, but it is detrimental to n-i-p devices. This result underscores the broader importance of designing surface treatment strategies that are both chemistry and functionality specific to a particular charge extraction interface.</p><p>Finally, we investigated the operational reliability of encapsulated devices aged under continuous light illumination at about 55 °C in ambient air (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">4c</ref>). These devices were biased with fixed resistance loads near the maximum power point during illumination. The target device retained about 87% of its initial maximum PCE after 2,428 h, whereas the control kept only 76% over 1,368 h. We further examined the operation stability of unencapsulated target device at 65 °C under 1.2-sun continuous illumination in nitrogen (ISOS-L-2I). The device retained 90% of its maximum PCE after 1,315 h (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">29a</ref>). Moreover, the damp heat (85 °C and 85% relative humidity; ISOS-D-3) test showed that the device retained 94% of its maximum PCE after 850 h (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">29b</ref>). Taken together, our results suggest that the reactive surface engineering using 3-APy is an effective approach to significantly enhance p-i-n PSC performance to state-of-the-art levels of efficiency and operational reliability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Online content</head><p>Any methods, additional references, Nature Research reporting summaries, source data, extended data, supplementary information, acknowledgements, peer review information; details of author contributions and competing interests; and statements of data and code availability are available at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05268-x">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05268-x</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>XPS and UPS measurements</head><p>XPS and UPS measurements were performed on a Kratos AXIS-Supra in the Surface Science Facility at the UC Irvine Materials Research Institute. X-ray radiation was produced by a monochromatic Al Kα excitation centred at 1,486.6 eV. UPS radiation was produced by ionizing helium i (energy 21.22 eV). XPS survey spectra were collected using a step size of 1 eV and pass energy of 160 eV; core-level spectra were collected using a step size of 0.1 eV and pass energy of 20 eV; and UPS spectra were conducted using a step size of 0.02 eV and pass energy of 10 eV.</p><p>The electron binding-energy scale was calibrated using the Fermi edge and core levels of gold and silver substrates cleaned with argon-ion bombardment. To ensure that important energetic information was preserved, UPS scans and I 3d 5/2 low-power XPS (1.5 W versus 225 W) scans were conducted at the beginning of analysis, each on unanalysed locations. To attempt to account for energetic shifts arising from the beam damage that is unavoidable in the high-power core-level scans, all core levels were shifted back such that their high-power I 3d 5/2 peak (225 W, 0.5 min) overlapped with the low-power peak (1.5 W, 4 min). UPS spectra were numerically corrected for satellite peaks that arose from the polychromic helium radiation <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">35</ref> . XPS peaks were fit using a Gaussian-Lorentzian peak-fitting algorithm with a Shirley background using the XPST package on Igor WaveMetrics. Work functions were determined using the intersection between the baseline and a linear fit to the SECO. VBMs were calculated using linear extrapolation of the valence band feature to the background signal on a semilog plot.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transient reflection measurement</head><p>Transient reflection measurements were performed with a Coherent laser (800-nm fundamental beam, 1-kHz repetition rate, 3-mJ pulse and 100-fs pulse width). The fundamental beam was split into a pump and probe pulse. The probe pulse was used to generate a white light supercontinuum via a sapphire crystal that was then sent through a delay line with a timescale up to 2.5 ns. The pump pulse was tuned using a Palitra Duo optical parametric amplifier to obtain varying excitation wavelengths. The pump and probe pulses were aligned spatially onto the sample at an approximately 45° angle to the sample surface. A Helios ultrafast spectrometer was used for detection, with the spectrometer at a 90° angle to the incident pump and probe beams. The excitation density for all transient reflection measurements was kept so that the initial number of photogenerated charge carriers directly after pump excitation did not exceed about 4 × 10 17 charge carriers per cm <ref type="bibr">3</ref> . A global fit analysis was performed on the measurements in accordance with previously reported protocols <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">36</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time-resolved microwave conductivity measurement</head><p>Perovskite target and control films were prepared in an identical manner to those used in devices, except onto precleaned 25 × 11 × 1-mm quartz plates (Technical Glass Products). Microwave conductivity measurements were conducted using previously described protocols <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">37</ref> . In brief, a 5-ns pulse width, 10-Hz laser at 643 nm was coupled into an X-band resonant cavity to photo-generate carriers in each perovskite film, the power from which was measured before and after each measurement using a photothermal detector placed at the sample position and masked by the optical widow and waveguide sections when the sample was present. Each sample was positioned inside the microwave cavity such that excitation was always incident to the quartz side, and continuous nitrogen purge was applied to the cavity during all measurements. Neutral density filters were used to attenuate the beam power over one order of magnitude to below 10 10 cm -2 absorbed photon flux.</p><p>For analysis, each sample's fraction of absorbed light was measured inside an integrating sphere diffuse reflectance accessory (Cary 7000i), whereas the beam attenuation profiles of the filter combinations were extracted from the measured specular transmission data for each neutral density filter at the excitation wavelength.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Photoluminescence characterization</head><p>Excitation at 632.8 nm (HeNe laser) was used to measure photoluminescence emission spectra. A Princeton Instruments HRS300 spectrograph with silicon charge-coupled-device (Pixis F100) and indium gallium arsenide (PyLoN IR) detectors was used. The spectral response of the detectors and spectrometer system was corrected using calibration sources (IntelliCal for visible and infrared ranges, Princeton Instruments) and placing calibration sources at the sample position. Excitation beam size was determined with a charge-coupled-device camera. Data were measured in absolute photon numbers using Spectralon reflectance standards (LabSphere) and assuming that 1-sun equivalent fluence for 1.53-eV bandgap is about 1.73 × 10 17 photons cm -2 s -1 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DFT calculations</head><p>The structural relaxation and static self-consistent energy calculations are performed by CP2K package at the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof level <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">39</ref> . A six-layer FAPbI 3 perovskite slab model is constructed for the cases before and after 3-APy treatment with typical (001) orientation selected on the surface, which is terminated by FAI. The double-ξ valence polarization basis set trained from optimized molecular geomis used in the calculations with only the gamma point considered, and an energy cut-off of 550 Rydberg is set. The formation energy difference of a charged V I on the surface region with and without 3-APy treatment is calculated by the following equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">E E q E E q E Δ =( (V, ) -) -( (V, ) - ) f w I w w/o I w/o</formula><p>where E w (V I , q) is the total energy of the supercell with the 3-APy cation and a charged V I , E w is the total energy of the supercell with the 3-APy cation but without a charged V I , E w/o (V I , q) is the total energy of the supercell without the 3-APy cation but with a charged V I , q denotes the elementary charge, and E w/o is the total energy of the supercell without the 3-AP cation and without a charged V I .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mass spectrometry measurement</head><p>The sample was diluted 1:1,000 v/v in acetonitrile and analysed with a Thermo Scientific Q-Exactive mass spectrometer equipped with a heated electrospray ionization source. The sample was directly infused via a syringe pump at 10 µl min -1 , with the following source conditions: sheath gas flow, 10 arbitrary units; aux gas flow, 0 arbitrary units; spray voltage, +2.9 kV; capillary temperature, 320 °C; S-lens radio frequency voltage, 50 V; aux gas heater, 0 °C. Spectra were collected with a resolution of 140,000 at m/z 200 and an automatic gain control target of 1 million. Full-scan spectra were collected from m/z 50-700 and mass spectrometry/mass spectrometry data were collected by quadrupole isolation of m/z 136 ± 2 and fragmented with normalized collision energy values of 10 and 60 to yield the full fragmentation profile. Quasi mass spectrometry data were collected by inducing fragmentation in the source region, and isolating m/z 92 ± 2, followed by fragmentation at 60 normalized collision energy. Molecular formula assignments were based on accurate mass and <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">13</ref> C isotopic fine structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Other characterizations</head><p>The optical properties of the perovskite films were measured using ultraviolet-visible spectroscopy (Cary 6000i). The crystal structures of perovskite films were recorded using an X-ray diffractometer (D-Max 2200, Rigaku). The morphologies and microstructures of the perovskite films and cross-sectional structures of the solar cells were investigated using a Hitachi S-4800 scanning electron microscope. The J-V curves were measured in a nitrogen glovebox using a Newport Oriel Sol3A class solar simulator with a xenon lamp that was calibrated before use with a silicon cell under a KG2 filter. The SPOs of the devices were measured by monitoring the photocurrent density output evolution under the biased voltage set near the maximum power point. EQE measurements were performed in ambient air using a Newport Oriel IQE200 with monochromatic light focused on the device pixels and a chopper frequency of 37 Hz.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 22 . 21 .</head><label>2221</label><figDesc>J-V characteristics measured by NREL PV Performance Group on the same device with the certification of the stabilized PV performance as shown in Supplementary Fig. Supplementary Fig. 24. J-V curves (a) and detailed PV parameters (b) of devices without (control) and with 3-APy treatment. The device structure is ITO/PEDOT:PSS/FA0.6MA0.4Sn0.6Pb0.4I3/C60/BCP/Ag. The Sn-Pb-based FA0.6MA0.4Sn0.6Pb0.4I3 perovskite has a bandgap of 1.25 eV.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1 | Surface reaction, topography and potential. a, Condensation reaction scheme of FA + and 3-APy. b-d, AFM topography image (b), KPFM surface potential image (c) and the corresponding line profiles (d) for the perovskite film without surface treatment. e-g, AFM (e), KPFM (f) and line profile comparison (g) for the perovskite film with 3-APy surface treatment. It is noted that the KPFM images were flattened by subtracting a constant baseline potential (-2.4 V for the untreated sample and -1.7 V for the treated sample) for a better comparison of the potential variations.</figDesc><graphic coords="37,233.05,243.34,105.50,105.86" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>12 - 14 . The 3 -Fig. 2 |</head><label>121432</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 | Surface chemistry and energetics. a, UPS measurements for perovskite films without (control, black) and with (target, red) 3-APy treatment. The work function and VBM results are indicted. b,c, Comparison of the XPS spectra of N 1s (b) and C 1s (c) core levels for the control (black) and the 3-APy-treated (red) perovskite films. The expected peak locations of relevant bonding environments are labelled. d-g, DFT modelling of the impact of 3-APy and perovskite interaction on the charged V I formation. Side view (left) and top view (right) of the atomic structures of the pristine perovskite without (d) and with (f) 3-APy modification, and the corresponding atomic structures with one iodine atom removed (e,g). The removed iodine atom is indicated by the orange colour in d and f. The brown, blue, pink, black and purple spheres denote C, N, H, Pb and I atoms, respectively.</figDesc><graphic coords="38,176.89,306.65,122.42,109.34" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3 | Optoelectronic properties. a,b, Comparison of transient reflection spectroscopy measurements of the control perovskite film (a) and the target perovskite film with 3-APy surface reaction (b) to study the carrier diffusion and surface recombination dynamics. R is reflectance. c, Comparison of normalized time-resolved microwave conductivity transients of the control and target perovskite films. The dashed lines are the best fits to a biexponential function that includes the 5-ns-pulse-width generation term. ϕ, free-carrier generation yield; Σ, sum; μ, carrier mobilities of holes and electrons. d, Comparison of absolute intensity photoluminescence (PL) spectra at about 1 sun (about 1.7 × 10 17 photons cm -2 s -1 ), along with the intensity dependence (inset), of representative p-i-n devices based on the control and target perovskite films.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig.4| Device characteristics. a, J-V curves of the champion control and target (with 3-APy surface treatment) p-i-n PSCs under 1-sun (100 mW cm -2 ) illumination. Inset: the corresponding SPO efficiencies. b, Comparison of the EQE spectra with the integrated J sc of 25.17 mA cm -2 and 25.74 mA cm -2 for the control and the target, respectively. c, Stability of encapsulated control and target devices, held under resistive load (560 Ω) near the maximum power point, under 1-sun illumination at 55 ± 2 °C in air with 40-60% relative humidity. The initial device PCE was 22.3% for the control and 24.6% for the target. The devices were encapsulated with cover glass and epoxy (Gorilla 2 Part 4200101-2 Epoxy).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,153.00,382.47,323.96,262.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="5,169.20,72.00,273.59,351.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="6,108.00,134.09,395.98,189.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,108.00,456.86,395.96,195.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="9,108.00,92.70,395.95,144.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="11,108.00,92.70,395.98,196.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="13,108.00,92.70,395.90,130.67" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="14,108.00,92.70,395.98,514.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="16,108.00,92.70,395.97,409.65" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="22,144.00,92.70,323.99,254.15" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="23,198.00,92.70,216.00,273.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="24,198.00,92.70,215.98,276.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="25,144.00,92.70,324.00,475.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="27,108.00,92.70,395.93,179.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="28,108.00,92.70,396.00,180.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="29,108.00,92.70,395.96,177.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="33,180.00,92.70,251.97,236.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>. Fitting results for TRMC transients shown in Fig. 3c</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Sample</cell><cell>A1</cell><cell>𝛕𝛕1 (ns)</cell><cell>A2</cell><cell>𝛕𝛕2 (µs)</cell><cell cols="2">𝛕𝛕avg (µs)</cell></row><row><cell>Control</cell><cell>2.585</cell><cell>8.02</cell><cell>48.449</cell><cell>1.75</cell><cell cols="2">1.66</cell></row><row><cell>Target</cell><cell>16.63</cell><cell>1.95</cell><cell>46.816</cell><cell>2.78</cell><cell cols="2">2.06</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Note: The average weighted lifetime is extracted using the equation 𝜏𝜏 𝑎𝑎𝑎𝑎𝑎𝑎 =</cell><cell>𝐴𝐴 1 𝜏𝜏 1 +𝐴𝐴 2 𝜏𝜏 2 𝐴𝐴 1 +𝐴𝐴 2</cell><cell>.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Supplementary Table 2. PV parameters of champion control and target (with 3-APy surface treatment) p-i-n PSCs. Device Jsc (mA/cm 2 )</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Voc</cell><cell>FF</cell><cell>PCE</cell><cell>SPO</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(V)</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>(%)</cell></row><row><cell>Control</cell><cell>Reverse</cell><cell>25.19</cell><cell>1.12</cell><cell>82.9</cell><cell>23.39</cell><cell>22.85</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Forward</cell><cell>25.35</cell><cell>1.11</cell><cell>78.8</cell><cell>22.18</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Target</cell><cell>Reverse</cell><cell>26.13</cell><cell>1.15</cell><cell>84.6</cell><cell>25.49</cell><cell>25.35</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Forward</cell><cell>26.19</cell><cell>1.15</cell><cell>83.9</cell><cell>25.27</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Article Surface reaction for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells Qi Jiang 1,7 , Jinhui Tong 1,7 , Yeming Xian 2 , Ross A. Kerner 1 , Sean P. Dunfield 3,4 , Chuanxiao Xiao 4 , Rebecca A. Scheidt 1 , Darius Kuciauskas 1 Xiaoming Wang 2 , Matthew P. Hautzinger 1 , Robert Tirawat 1 , Matthew C. Beard 1 , David P. Fenning 3 , Joseph J. Berry 4,5,6 , Bryon W. Larson 1 , Yanfa Yan 2 ✉ &amp; Kai Zhu 1 ✉</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The work was partially supported by the <rs type="funder">US Department of Energy</rs> under</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding authors on reasonable request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Information</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Surface reaction for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</head><p>Qi Jiang, 1 † Jinhui Tong, 1 † Yeming Xian, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Ross A. Kerner, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Sean P. Dunfield, <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">4</ref> Chuanxiao Xiao, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">4</ref> Rebecca A. Scheidt, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Darius Kuciauskas, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Xiaoming Wang, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Matthew P. Hautzinger, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Robert Tirawat, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Matthew C. Beard, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> David P. Fenning, <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Joseph J. Berry, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">6</ref> Bryon W. Larson, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Yanfa Yan, 2* Kai Zhu 1*</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 1. Condensation reaction from perovskite surface treatment</head><p>The general condensation reaction was observed and confirmed for methylamine as shown in ref. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> and 2 . From their 1 H-NMR results, it is unambiguous that a metathesis-like reaction occurs between formamidinium and methylamine, and the reaction products N-methyl formamidinium (MFA + ) and N,N'-dimethyl formamidinium (DMFA + ) are easily identified by proton NMR. This reaction should be general to other "simple" primary amines as well.</p><p>In the scheme in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>, we show 1) the reaction with FA + where the amine molecule is methylamine, as discussed in ref. 6; 2) the generalized reaction between FA + and a primary amine molecule with side group R; and 3) the reaction with FA + where the amine is 3-(Aminomethyl)pyridine (3-APy, where Py denotes pyridine). To facilitate our discussion, we also refer to the main reaction product as MPyFA (N-(3-methylpyridine)formamidinium); the other reaction product is NH3 (ammonia). The key takeaway from the Scheme below is that in all cases To overcome the inability to resolve NH3 shifts under these conditions, as well as sharpen each fingerprint proton shift to allow for clean integration, we employed an HI spiking technique following the protocol published elsewhere <ref type="bibr">3</ref> . NH3/NH4 + would otherwise be invisible to 1 H-NMR due to rapid acidic proton exchange enabled by the addition of amine (3-APy). In doing so, we force HI to protonate all species in solution, including NH3, to form NH4 + , so it can then be detected due to reduced proton exchange rate. Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">15</ref>. XPS core-level spectral fits for N 1s (a-b) and C 1s (c-d), plus an additional fitting attempt utilizing only four peaks (e) with its variance from the best fit line (f). As can be seen, the control sample's C 1s spectra can be easily fit with four peaks, but the 3-APytreated sample requires a fifth peak. For all fits, the full width half maximum (FWHM) was constrained between 0. Publisher's note Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p><p>Springer Nature or its licensor holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</p><p>© The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited 2022</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>Rubidium iodide (RbI, 99.99%), caesium iodide (CsI, 99.99%), lead iodide (PbI 2 , 99.999%) and 3-APy were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Organic salts of formamidinium iodide (FAI) and methylammonium bromide (MABr) were purchased from Greatcell Solar Materials; lead bromide (PbBr 2 ) and MeO-2PACZ were purchased from Tokyo Chemical Industry. Dimethylformamide (DMF, 99.8%, anhydrous), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, 99.9%, anhydrous), chlorobenzene (99.9%, anhydrous) and toluene (99.9%, anhydrous) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. For evaporating materials, LiF was purchased from Alfa Aesar, C 60 was purchased from Lumtec and BCP was purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. All chemicals were used directly as received.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Perovskite precursor solution</head><p>The perovskite composition is Rb 0.05 Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.85 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 . The perovskite precursor was prepared in mixed solvents of DMF:DMSO (volume ratio 4:1). The chemical molar ratio of CsI, RbI, FAI, PbI 2 , PbBr 2 and MABr is 0.05, 0.05, 0.85, 0.95, 0.05 and 0.05, respectively, and the concentration is 1.5 M.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Synthesis of 3-picolyamine iodide salt (3-APyI 2 )</head><p>A mixture of 3-picolyamine (1.50 ml, 14.7 mmol) and ethanol (50 ml) was added to a round-bottom flask and cooled in an ice bath. While rapidly stirring, a slight excess of concentrated hydroiodic acid (4.75 ml, 31.0 mmol) was slowly added. After stirring for 1 h, a precipitate had formed and was removed from the mixture via vacuum filtration and washed with diethyl ether (4 × 50 ml). The product was then dried overnight at 55 °C under vacuum.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Device fabrication</head><p>The patterned transparent conducting oxide glass substrates (ITO or fluorine doped tin oxide [FTO]) were washed with acetone and isopropanol for 15 min each. After ultraviolet ozone treatment for 15 min, a 0.5 mg ml -1 MeO-2PACZ self-assembled monolayer solution dissolved in ethanol was spin-coated on substrates at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s in a nitrogen glovebox, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. The perovskite composition is Rb 0.05 Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.85 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 , and the initial stock perovskite solution is 1.5 M. In detail, CsI (19.5 mg), RbI (15.9 mg), MABr (8.4 mg), FAI (219.5 mg), PbI 2 (656.9 mg) and PbBr 2 (27.5 mg) were dissolved in 1 ml mixed solvent of DMF:DMSO (v:v = 4:1), shaken by a vortex shaker for about 1-2 h to make it fully dissolved. The 1.5 M perovskite precursor solution, without filtering and dilution, was used for preparing perovskite films. Perovskite precursor solutions prepared on the same day or aged within about two weeks (in sealed vials) can be used without noticeable impact on device performance. We used an SCS G3 spin coater (model G3P8) for spin-coating. No intentional acceleration steps were used during spin-coating; the target spin speed can be reached within 1 s. Specifically, the substrate was first spinning at 1,000 r.p.m. (within 1 s from 0 to 1,000; no slow acceleration steps) for 10 s, and then at 3,000 r.p.m. (no slow acceleration steps) for 40 s. After 15 s into the second stage (3,000 r.p.m., 40 s), 150 µl chlorobenzene antisolvent was dropped on top of the spinning substrates (about 1-cm distance). The perovskite sample was subsequently annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. For 3-APy treatment, the diluted toluene solution of 3-APy (0.1 mM) was spin-coated on the perovskite surface at 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 70 °C for 5 min. Afterwards, samples were transferred to an Angstrom evaporator for LiF (1 nm)/C 60 (30 nm)/BCP (6 nm)/Ag (100 nm) deposition. The device area by evaporation was 0.112 cm 2 . Unless otherwise stated, the devices were masked with metal aperture masks (0.059 cm 2 ) during the J-V measurement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>KPFM characterizations</head><p>KPFM measurements were performed on a D5000 atomic force microscope inside an argon-filled glovebox. We used a platinum-iridium-coated silicon probe (PPP-EFM) in tapping mode. The plane-view samples were scanned in at least three random locations to ensure reliable measurements. The mapping contains 1,024 pixels in the fast-scan axis and 256 lines in the slow-scan axis. The scan rate is 0.35 Hz. contract number DE-AC36-08GO28308 with Alliance for Sustainable Energy, Limited Liability Company (LLC), the Manager and Operator of the National Renewable Energy Laboratory. We acknowledge the support on first-principle calculations, surface reaction analysis, synthesis of 3-APyI 2 and optoelectronic characterizations (for example, transient reflection and time-resolved microwave conductivity), from the Center for Hybrid Organic-Inorganic Semiconductors for Energy (CHOISE), an Energy Frontier Research Center funded by the Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Office of Science within the US Department of Energy. A portion of the research was performed using computational resources sponsored by the Department of Energy's Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and located at the National Renewable Energy Laboratory. We acknowledge the support on 3-APy surface treatment and the corresponding device fabrication and characterizations from DE-FOA-0002064 and award number DE-EE0008790, and the support on the general device and thin-film perovskite fabrication and characterizations from the Advanced Perovskite Cells and Modules programme of the National Center for Photovoltaics, funded by the US Department of Energy, Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Solar Energy Technologies Office. This work was also supported in part by the California Energy Commission EPIC programme, EPC-19-004. We acknowledge the use of facilities and instrumentation at the UC Irvine Materials Research Institute (IMRI), which is supported in part by the National Science Foundation through the UC Irvine Materials Research Science and Engineering Center (DMR-2011967). XPS and UPS were performed in part using instrumentation funded in part by the National Science Foundation Major Research Instrumentation Program under grant number CHE-1338173. We thank I. Tran for assistance with collecting the XPS and UPS data; and S. M. Rowland and L. M. Laurens for conducting the mass spectrometry measurements and structure assignments at the NREL Bioenergy Science Technologies directorate. The views expressed in the article do not necessarily represent the views of the DOE or the US Government.</p><p>Author contributions Q.J., J.T. and K.Z. conceived the idea. K.Z. supervised the projects and process. Q.J. fabricated perovskite films and devices and conducted X-ray diffraction, scanning electron microscopy, and ultraviolet-visible and stability measurements. J.T. was involved in material and device design and analysis. Y.X. carried out the DFT calculation, with help from X.W., under the supervision of Y.Y. R.A.K. and B.W.L. were involved in surface reaction study and relevant analysis. S.P.D. performed XPS and UPS measurements and analysis under the guidance of D.P.F. C.X. performed AFM and KPFM characterizations and analysis. R.A.S. conducted the transient reflection measurement and analysis under the guidance of M.C.B. D.K. performed the photoluminescence characterization and analysis. M.P.H. prepared the 3-APy halide salts. R.T. helped to work on device stability test under the supervision of J.J.B. B.W.L. conducted the time-resolved microwave conductivity measurement and analysis. Q.J. and K.Z. wrote the first draft of the manuscript. All authors discussed the results and contributed to the revisions of the manuscript.</p><p>Competing interests An application has been made for a provisional patent (US patent application number 63/344,265) related to the subject matter of this manuscript.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solution aging: what happened and how to inhibit?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1369" to="1378" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methylammonium-formamidinium reactivity in aged organometal halide perovskite inks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Valenzano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell Rep. Phys. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100432</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Degradation of the formamidinium cation and the quantification of the formamidinium-methylammonium ratio in lead iodide hybrid perovskites by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Van Gompel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4117" to="4124" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planar perovskite solar cells with long-term stability using ionic liquid additives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">571</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Monolithic perovskite/silicon tandem solar cell with 29% efficiency by enhanced hole extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Al-Ashouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">370</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1300" to="1309" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing heterojunctions by surface sulfidation for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Damp heat-stable perovskite solar cells with tailored-dimensionality 2D/3D heterojunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Azmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometallic-functionalized interfaces for highly efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Best research-cell efficiency chart</title>
		<ptr target="NRELwww.nrel.gov/pv/cell-efficiency.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface passivation of perovskite film for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solar cells with atomically coherent interlayers on SnO 2 electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">598</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimizing non-radiative recombination losses in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From defects to degradation: a mechanistic understanding of degradation in perovskite solar cell devices and modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dunfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1904054</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solvent engineering for high-performance inorganic-organic hybrid perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jeon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="897" to="903" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal quantum dot-SnO 2 layers as electron transporters for efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inactive (PbI 2 ) 2 RbCl stabilizes perovskite films for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="534" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable fabrication and coating methods for perovskite solar cells and solar modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N.-G</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defect compensation in formamidinium-caesium perovskites for highly efficient solar mini-modules with improved photostability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">All-perovskite tandem solar cells with improved grain surface passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">603</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Carrier control in Sn-Pb perovskites via 2D cation engineering for all-perovskite tandem solar cells with improved efficiency and stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="642" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficiency progress of inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3823" to="3847" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Arylammonium-assisted reduction of the open-circuit voltage deficit in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells: the role of suppressed ion migration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2560" to="2568" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Junction quality of SnO 2 -based perovskite solar cells investigated by nanometer-scale electrical potential profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38373" to="38380" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient tandem solar cells with solution-processed perovskite on textured crystalline silicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">367</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1135" to="1140" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solution aging: what happened and how to inhibit?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1369" to="1378" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intact 2D/3D halide junction perovskite solar cells via solid-phase in-plane growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface defect dynamics in organic-inorganic hybrid perovskites: from mechanism to interfacial properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Stecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12127" to="12136" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">3D/2D passivation as a secret to success for polycrystalline thin-film solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcgott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1057" to="1073" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recombination velocity less than 100 cm/s at polycrystalline Al 2 O 3 /CdSeTe interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kuciauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">263901</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">N-doped carbon quantum dots/TiO 2 composite with improved photocatalytic activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Catal. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">193</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ligand exchange in quaternary alloyed nanocrystals-a spectroscopic study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gabka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23082" to="23088" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting nitrogen species in covalent triazine frameworks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Osadchii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Olivos-Suarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bavykina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gascon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Langmuir</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14278" to="14285" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From graphene oxide towards aminated graphene: facile synthesis, its structure and electronic properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Rabchinskii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6902</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unusual defect physics in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite solar cell absorber</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W.-J</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63903</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optical determination of Shockley-Read-Hall and interface recombination currents in hybrid perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Sarritzu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">44629</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal monolayer contacts with lossless interfaces for perovskite single junction and monolithic tandem solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Al-Ashouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3356" to="3369" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining band-edge energies and morphology-dependent stability of formamidinium lead perovskite films using spectroelectrochemistry and photoelectron spectroscopy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Shallcross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Saavedra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Armstrong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4866" to="4878" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Top and bottom surfaces limit carrier lifetime in lead iodide perovskite films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16207</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative analysis of time-resolved microwave conductivity data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Reid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">493002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">cp2k: atomistic simulations of condensed matter systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Iannuzzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schiffmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vandevondele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wiley Interdiscip. Rev. Comput. Mol. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized gradient approximation made simple</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Perdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ernzerhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3865" to="3868" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
