<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder ref="#_v5XfrM7">
					<orgName type="full">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_Hp9aUZr">
					<orgName type="full">Ministry of Science of the state of NRW</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_b7FghG8">
					<orgName type="full">German Federal Ministry for Education and Research</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_kM8z9Qy">
					<orgName type="full">European Unions 7th Framework Programme</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">71D85D5E7231EB9902994DD5C5061373</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T18:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>scale may be associated with intrinsic changes of the defect structure in the perovskite, which is beyond the scope of the present work. The barrier properties of the AZO and AZO/SnO x EELs have been studied by using Cacorrosion test. Detail of this test have been describe previously. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Specifically, we have used a setup as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5a</ref>. The substrate was a PET/ITO foil, which has an intrinsic water vapor transmission rate of 3×10 -2 gm -2 day -1 . On top of this substrate we have deposited the PCBM layer and the EEL in an identical way as in case of the solar cells. Subsequently, an array of Ca dots has been thermally evaporated (thickness 100 nm). The top-side of this stack has been encapsulated by a 200 nm thick Al 2 O 3 gas diffusion barrier using ALD. The WVTR of the Al 2 O 3 top-encapsulation is expected to be on the order of 10 -6 gm -2 day -1 (ref. 7). Thus only the water ingress from the bottom side through the substrate and the PCBM/EEL will be relevant for the corrosion of the Ca. While the Ca appears metallic in the pristine samples, the corrosion due to moisture will render the Ca transparent Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5b</ref>. Obviously, in the case of AZO the degradation of the Ca pads is substantially faster, as after 36h in air almost all the pads have vanished. Therefore the WVTR of the AZO layer does not provide any significant barrier against the ingress of moisture. On the contrary, in case of the AZO/SnO x EEL the Ca pads appear far less corroded. This corroborates the barrier functionality of the ALD grown SnO x layer on top of the AZO. It has to be noted that some statistical failure may be due to particle defects that may void the effectivity of the top encapsulation layer. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Reviewers' comments:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary</head><p>Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>This manuscript describes a inverted perovskite photovoltaic in which the the electron extraction layer consists of PCBM-only, PCBM + AZO nanoparticles, or PCBM + AZO nanoparticles + SnO2 ALD overcoat. The work convincingly shows an improvement in PV stability with the 3-step overcoat as well as supports a hypothesis for the mechanism by which the devices are stabilized.</p><p>The originality and interest of the report is good but modest. Although the authors do not highlight previous ALD-over-pervoskite work there are other examples including J. Mater. Chem. A, 2015, 3,  20092-20096.   The thickness of the SnO2 layer is suggested to be 20 nm, but this ignores the high likelihood that the ALD SnOx has coated a significant fraction of porous interior of the nanoparticle AZO on which it is grown.</p><p>Overall the paper is modestly well written and its conclusions are sound. However, the impact appears to be below the very high bar of nature communications as the lifetime is good (350 hrs) but never pushed to the real boundaries previous pervoskite systems (1000 hrs of illumination, high relative temperature and humidity, etc) the methods is not totally novel, and efficiency is modest (although unoptimized). While I don't believe all high impact papers need to be 18+ % efficient, the mechanism by which the most efficient devices fail is important.</p><p>Suggested improvements are stability tests that push the device to failure including light soaking under temperature and humidity followed by publication in a journal similar to E&amp;ES.</p><p>Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>This manuscript described the use of a bi-layer oxide AZO/SnOx as electron extraction layer to improve the stability of perovskite solar cell. Stability is a crucial issue for perovskite solar cell before it can be considered as a promising alternative for current existing technologies. The finding and phenomena reported in this communication could be interesting for the community. However, several issues need to be addressed before the acceptance by high-ranking journal.</p><p>1. The results of the most successful device on stability [ Ref 17, Science 350, 944-948 (2015)] shall be briefly described and discussed in the introduction. The device architecture of this communication is conceptually similar to that Science paper, except the use of bilayer oxide. I think the advantages and novelty (vs that Science paper work) shall be clearly expressed in the introduction to show the importance of this work. Otherwise, changing materials can only be considered as a minor progression or follow-up. 2. For the XRD results, the spectra seem to contain only the diffraction pattern of perovskite. As the author said in the manuscript the sample is a full device, I think the author shall see the diffraction of those constituent layers to prove that the sample is the full device and cover with EEL and metal contact. Please clarify this issue. It is quite unusual that under ambient condition, no PbI2 signal were observed. In general the formation of PbI2 prevails extremely fast in air. The explanation of "noncrystalline nature of the degradation product" is not very convincing as no amorphous feature in the XRD spectra. 3. For the XPS results, the baseline of fresh devices made with SnOx and AZO/SnOx shall be included. Since XPS is a surface technique that investigates on the first few 3~5 nm, I wonder if the perovskite can be detected if protected after 10 nm Ag and AZO. The authors shall provide the whole spectrum to show what they have detected on the surface. The signal of Eb close to 622 eV for the blue line on Fig  3 (b) shall be identified and discussed. Is it something other than AgI? 4. Are the SEM images taken on top of Ag or on top of oxides? I think that matters for proposing the mechanism. 5. To demonstrate real stability for solar cells, light soaking is necessary. Especially for perovskite solar cell, light soaking results can really substantiate the claim for long term stability. To be published in such high impact journal like Nature Communications, I think the authors shall show stability under light soaking.</p><p>6. The unit of EQE on Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1b</ref> is wrong.</p><p>7. The first inverted perovskite solar cell using PEDOT:PSS and PCBM shall be cited in the introduction. Adv. Mater. 2013, 25, 3727.</p><p>Overall, I suggest a minor revision for this manuscript.</p><p>Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>The manuscript by Brinkmann et al address the use of AZO/SnOx electron extractor layers in hybrid perovskite solar cells. More specifically, the paper reports improved device stability when such AZO/SnOx layers are used in inverted type solar cells. The paper is interesting but in the current state the paper is not suitable for a journal like Nature Communications. There are a number of significant issues that must be addressed. 1 The more detailed mechanism of how the combined AZO/SnOx layer interlayer improves stability needs to be established. This is not at all clear from the data presented in the paper. 2 Following from above, what is the mechanism by which the SnOx layer improves stability? How does it block water getting in the device? Surely most of the diffusion occurs from the sides of the devices and through the silver? Why can't the metal electrode act as a barrier to water? It is not beyond the realms of possibility that approximately 100 nm thick (or several 10's nm thick) metal electrodes can function good physical blocking layers. Perhaps this should be investigated. 3 The authors suggest that the silver electrode may be involved in the degradation of the device in presence of water. Have the authors tried to replace the silver electrode with lets say gold (which is known to be more stable than silver) in control devices that do now contain the SnOx layer: ITO/PEDOT/active layer/gold. 5 The authors should provide more information about how the device stability experiments were performed. Was this done with maximum power point tracking? Were the experiments performed whilst continuously illuminating the solar cells under load with the solar cells put in ambient environment? Or, are the authors just referring "shelf life" stability. To get a true indication of stability it is important that he authors consider the former (e.g) measurements under continuous illumination under load with MPP tracking. 6 In the temperature stability measurements shown in figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>. It is shown the drop in performance is mainly due to a drop in the fill factor. The authors should discuss the origin of this. The authors should also perhaps repeat temperature stability experiments using a thicker electrode layer -certainly thicker than 10nm !! It is not surprising that with such thin layers of silver (e.g. 10nm) increase the chance that the degradation products escape.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>REVIEWERS' COMMENTS:</head><p>Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author): I am satisfied with the revisions to the manuscript. Although a simultaneous temperature and moisture (damp heat) test, which all commercial PV must pass, would be most interesting there is sufficient data included here for an initial report. The changes raise the quality of this revised work to those required by Nature Comm. I support prompt publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author):</head><p>The revised version has addressed most of the comments and questions raised by the reviewer properly. I would recommend its publication.</p><p>Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>Based on the responses and reading the revised paper the referee believes that the paper may now be suitable for publication in Nature communications.</p><p>Point 1 and 2: The role of metal contact versus SnOx layer in protecting against water vapour ingress has been clarified. The comparison between vapour transmission rates for metal versus ALD grown SnOx is welcome. Point 3: Though a comparison of gold and silver as an electrode and the investigation of the use of SnOx/AZO as a blocking layer (ie reducing migration of metal atoms from electrode) are important issues the referee accepts that this is potentially beyond the scope of the current work. Point 5: The additional solar cell stability experiments (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>) are welcome and serve to clarify the concerns of referee 3. Point 6: comments regarding thickness of Ag layer clarified. Concerning the origin of the drop in the fill factor (FF): the discussion is welcome. However, the referee has an additional question here: Did the authors observe a change in hysteresis in fresh versus aged samples. (referring to a device that is treated in the same way as in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5</ref>; main manuscript). For example, a device that is using an AZO/SnOx extraction layer (with and without heating at 60C)?</p><p>Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>This manuscript describes an inverted perovskite photovoltaic in which the electron extraction layer consists of PCBM-only, PCBM + AZO nanoparticles, or PCBM + AZO nanoparticles + SnO2 ALD overcoat. The work convincingly shows an improvement in PV stability with the 3-step overcoat as well as supports a hypothesis for the mechanism by which the devices are stabilized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We appreciate the referee's assessment of our work. We were pleased to read that he finds our results convincing.</p><p>The originality and interest of the report is good but modest. Although the authors do not highlight previous ALD-over-pervoskite work there are other examples including J. Mater. Chem. A, 2015, 3, 20092-20096.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We are aware of the previous work, in which single ALD layers have been deposited on top of a perovskite to protect it against ambient gases (e.g. moisture) and thereby to improve its resilience in ambient air. The functionality of ALD layers in these earlier papers is that of a permeation barrier. These ALD layers are not a functional part of a device structure and their electrical properties are more or less irrelevant and neglected.</p><p>Opposed to that, our work is essentially different, as the SnOx ALD layer is a functional part of our devices. The SnOx layer is unique in a sense that it provides outstanding gas permeation barrier properties with a water vapor transmission rate orders of magnitude better than that of sputtered ITO or that of solution processed metal-oxides, and at the same time it is optically highly transparent and electrically conductive. Thus it can be positioned right between the sensitive metal cathode and the photo-active perovskite. Thereby, the SnOx layer provides outstanding protection of the perovskite against the ingress of moisture and, even more importantly, at the same time it serves as powerful permeation barrier against the out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite, e.g. CH3NH3I, (CH3)3N, CH3I, HI, etc. We show that the sealing properties of the SnOx layer contain the decomposition products inside the cell, and thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed. We feel that this concept goes significantly beyond the "ALD-on-top-of-perovskite" reports cited by the referee.</p><p>To make things more clear we referenced the above citation and added a sentence to clarify the differences: "Please note, there are reports where ALD layers have been directly deposited on top of a perovskite layer to improve its resilience against ambient atmosphere and heat. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> However, these ALD layers were not a functional part of a device, and therefore most of the experiments were based on electrical insulators like Al2O3."</p><p>The thickness of the SnO2 layer is suggested to be 20 nm, but this ignores the high likelihood that the ALD SnOx has coated a significant fraction of porous interior of the nanoparticle AZO on which it is grown.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>This is an excellent point! Indeed, ALD is known for its conformal, shadow-free type of growth which implies the coating of the interior of porous media. With the specification of a 20 nm thick SnOx layer we referred to a nominal thickness as derived when the layer is coated onto a flat, non-porous substrate. We believe that the ability of the SnOx ALD layer to seal pinholes and/or pores will substantially improve the permeation barrier properties of the AZO/SnOx assembly vs. that of a single AZO layer.</p><p>To analyze this point deeper and to address the point raised by the referee, we performed Rutherford backscattering (RBS) measurements on two samples as shown in the Figure below (which became the new Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S1</ref> in the revised supporting information). Specifically, we have deposited SnOx in one process on top of an AZO layer grown by ALD (ALD-AZO), which is thereby expected to have no pinholes, and on top of an AZO layer derived from a NP dispersion -both AZO layers have an identical thickness. From the RBS spectra attributed to Sn, we are able to determine the number of Sn atoms per area, which is indicative of the amount of SnOx actually deposited. For the SnOx on top of the pin-holefree ALD-AZO we measured (44.5±0.2)×10 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> Sn-atoms/cm 2 , which is in excellent agreement with our earlier RBS measurements of ALD grown SnOx layers (on top of a flat Silicon wafer) with a thickness of 20 nm (determined by stylus profilometry). On the contrary, for the SnOx deposited on top of the AZO (NP) layer we found (72.2±0.9)×10 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> Sn-atoms/cm 2 , which is a factor of 1.62 higher than for the non-porous substrate. This result clearly supports the hypothesis of the ALD growth of the SnOx inside the pores of the nanoparticle derived AZO layer, which increases the total amount of SnOx deposited.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>To clarify the growth of the SnOx on top of the AZO and into the pores, we added in the revised version of the manuscript:</head><p>"The nominal thickness of the SnOx layer is 20 nm. As the AZO layer is derived from a nanoparticle dispersion, it contains pores which are partially coated with SnOx due to the conformal nature of the ALD process. A more detailed discussion of the SnOx growth on top of the AZO layer is provided in the supporting information." We also added to the experimental section: "Rutherford backscattering (RBS) was measured at the RUBION (University of Bochum, Germany), using a dynamitron tandem accelerator with 2 MeV 4 He + beam (beam current of 20-40 nA). A silicon surface barrier detector was placed at an angle of 160 degree with respect to the beam axis. The solid angle of the detector was 1.91 msrad."</p><p>Overall the paper is modestly well written and its conclusions are sound. However, the impact appears to be below the very high bar of nature communications as the lifetime is good (350 hrs) but never pushed to the real boundaries previous pervoskite systems (1000 hrs of illumination, high relative temperature and humidity, etc) the methods is not totally novel, and efficiency is modest (although unoptimized). While I don't believe all high impact papers need to be 18+ % efficient, the mechanism by which the most efficient devices fail is important. Suggested improvements are stability tests that push the device to failure including light soaking under temperature and humidity followed by publication in a journal similar to E&amp;ES.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>As outlined above, we believe that the integration of the SnOx layer inside the device is conceptually significantly different from earlier work. To be able to position a permeation barrier (SnOx) inside the device stack, the SnOx layer must be optically highly transparent and electrically conductive. As a part of the electron extraction layer, the SnOx provides outstanding protection of the perovskite against the ingress of moisture and, even more importantly, at the same time it serves as powerful permeation barrier against the outdiffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite, and thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed.</p><p>As the referee said, the efficiency of our cells is limited by the perovskite precursor used in this study. We agree with him that high impact papers do not necessarily need to report 18+ % efficient devices. The study of failure mechanisms of more efficient perovskite systems is certainly an important field, but it is beyond the scope of the present paper. Our paper focusses on a novel impermeable bi-layered electron extraction layer that serves as a diffusion barrier inside the perovskite solar cell. Thus, we decided to consider the most commonly used perovskite photo-active layer MAPbI3. However, as stated in the manuscript, we believe that the concept of an impermeable electron extraction layer is generally applicable and therefore is expected to provide an avenue to achieve a substantially improved device lifetime of solar cells based on organo-metal halide perovskites even beyond MAPbI3.</p><p>As requested, we have updated the lifetime data for the cells aged at elevated temperature (60°C) which now extends to 1032 h (new Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). We believe that these numbers now more impressively underline the stability enabled by our inverted device structure with impermeable AZO/SnOx EELs. In this set of samples, the thickness of the ALD SnO x layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm. The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction (Figure <ref type="figure">S7</ref>).</p><p>We also agree with the referee that light soaking tests under concomitant heating are an important (and more demanding) stress condition. However, we want to note, that according to a very recent "Research Update" published by the Snaith group in APL Materials [APL Mater. 4, 091503 (2016)], the number of reports on the stability of perovskite solar cells in which the cells are actually stressed by light soaking and heat simultaneously, is very scarce. This may in part be due to the fact that upon "multi-stress" conditions the individual degradation mechanisms are difficult to be separated. Nevertheless, as requested by the referees, we conducted a new set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C. Briefly, the devices were illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation. At the same time, the devices were kept in an oven at 60°C under N2 atmosphere (all experimental details are mentioned in the methods section). We have deliberately chosen the N2 environment for the light-soaking experiment, as we had already clarified the influence of humidity in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>, and we had clearly shown that the encapsulation due to the AZO/SnOx layer is efficiently blocking the ingress of moisture.</p><p>The results of the new light-soaking/heating stress tests are shown in the new Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>.</p><p>In the manuscript we added the following discussion: "Aside from so-called "mono-stress" conditions, like elevated temperature, multi-stressing can be considered. To this end, we conducted set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C under N2, in which the devices were simultaneously illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation (for details see the experimental section). The results of this multi-stress experiment are shown in the supporting information (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>). Briefly, again the AZO/SnOx cells are substantially more stable than the AZO cells under concomitant heat and illumination. This difference is in part due to the suppressed decomposition of the perovskite due to heat in case of the AZO/SnOx (in agreement with the discussion of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). However, there is a clear degradation even of the AZO/SnOx samples where the PCE decays to roughly 60 % of its initial value after 300 hours. This is in contrast to the case where only thermal stress has been used. Earlier  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8f</ref>). This is why we conclude that photo-induced trap-state formation occurs in our cells. However, there have been recent reports confirming that photo-induced degradation is not a general problem of organo-lead halide perovskites, and very recently some optimized mixed cation / mixed halide perovskite active materials were shown to be far less prone to light soaking degradation. <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5</ref> . Heat was found to be a dominating source of degradation in these mixed cation perovskite cells. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Note, our inverted device structure based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer is generally applicable and can also accommodate these next-generation perovskite photo-active systems with enhanced stability and efficiency. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> " V oc,0 , FF 0 , and PCE 0 are the characteristics of the cells before stressing. In this set of samples, the thickness of the ALD SnO x layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm. The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction. Spectrum of the white LED used for the lightsoaking stress test under concomitant heating (e). J/V characteristics of an AZO/SnO x /Ag cell, non-stressed (fresh), stressed for 300 hours (light/heat), and subsequently recovered in in darkness at room temperature for nine days (in the glove box).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>work has unraveled the photo-induced degradation of solar cells based on MAPbI3. While Misra et al. identified a photo-activated decomposition mechanism 2 , more recently Nie et al. reported that continuous illumination of MAPbI3 caused the formation of trap states which spoiled the solar cells performance, especially Jsc. 3 While our sealing approach based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer has been shown to efficiently suppress the decomposition of the perovskite, it cannot suppress the formation of trap states in the perovskite. Similar to the report of Nie et al., the cell characteristics recover after stressing, if the cells are kept in darkness (Figure</head><p>Finally, we agree with the referee that Energy&amp;Environmental Science (E&amp;ES) would also be a potential outlet for our work. While we are convinced that both journals are highly respected, we decided to choose Nature Communications in this case.</p><p>Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>This manuscript described the use of a bi-layer oxide AZO/SnOx as electron extraction layer to improve the stability of perovskite solar cell. Stability is a crucial issue for perovskite solar cell before it can be considered as a promising alternative for current existing technologies. The finding and phenomena reported in this communication could be interesting for the community. However, several issues need to be addressed before the acceptance by high-ranking journal.</p><p>1. The results of the most successful device on stability [ Ref 17, Science 350, 944-948 (2015)] shall be briefly described and discussed in the introduction. The device architecture of this communication is conceptually similar to that Science paper, except the use of bilayer oxide. I think the advantages and novelty (vs that Science paper work) shall be clearly expressed in the introduction to show the importance of this work. Otherwise, changing materials can only be considered as a minor progression or followup. Technology, 205, 5088 (2011)]. The SEM images in their supporting information also show some granularity of the layers. Grain-boundaries are pathways for gas diffusion. Opposed to that, our ALD grown SnOx layers are amorphous and dense. In addition the authors had to limit the thickness of the sol-gel TiNbOx to 10 nm due to its poor electrical conductivity of 10 -5 S cm -1 . For thicker TiNbOx layers some notable deterioration in the J/V characteristics is found. As already discussed in the original version of the paper, our ALD grown SnOx layers show a more than two orders of magnitude higher electrical conductivity of 5x10 -3 S/cm which does not impose such a thickness limitation. Even though the authors did not provide any permeation data for their 10 nm thin Ti(Nb)Ox layers, for the reasons discussed above, it can be expected that the water permeation rate is substantially higher than that of ALD grown SnOx layers with similar thickness. As result, the authors showed device stability only in a dry cabinet or with additional encapsulation of the devices. Opposed to that our devices proved stable in ambient air even without additional encapsulation. Likewise, even though the authors did not provide any experiments at elevated temperatures of 60°C, it must be expected that the 10 nm sol-gel TiNbOx will not form a serious barrier against the egress of perovskite decomposition products. We have clearly shown that in our case the barrier functionality of the AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer not only provides outstanding protection of the perovskite against the ingress of moisture, but at the same time it serves as powerful permeation barrier against the out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite, and thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply: The Science paper mentioned by the referee used an inverted planar device structure. The authors employ NiMgLiO as hole extraction layer and Ti(Nb)Ox as electron extraction layer. Specifically, the Ti(Nb)Ox was prepared by a sol-gel process. It is known that sol-gel layers other than ALD layers do not form conformal pin-hole free coatings and thus they typically afford rather poor permeation barriers [see e.g. Hirvikorpi et al. Surface and Coatings</head><p>As suggested by the referee, we have added the following clear differentiation of our work compared to the report in Science 350, 944-948 (2015) in the introduction of our paper.</p><p>"Chen employed a sol-gel Ti(Nb)Ox electron extraction layer, which was aimed to protect the perovskite against moisture from ambient atmosphere. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Due to its poor electrical conductivity of 10 -5 S cm <ref type="bibr">-1</ref> , in devices the authors had to limit the thickness of the sol-gel Ti(Nb)Ox to 10 nm. Moreover, it is known that sol-gel derived layers state only relatively poor permeation barriers. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> As a result, the device stability tests which afforded a lifetime of 1000 h, were done with additional encapsulation."</p><p>2. For the XRD results, the spectra seem to contain only the diffraction pattern of perovskite. As the author said in the manuscript the sample is a full device, I think the author shall see the diffraction of those constituent layers to prove that the sample is the full device and cover with EEL and metal contact. Please clarify this issue. It is quite unusual that under ambient condition, no PbI2 signal were observed. In general the formation of PbI2 prevails extremely fast in air. The explanation of "non-crystalline nature of the degradation product" is not very convincing as no amorphous feature in the XRD spectra.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We fully understand the comment of the referee. To explain: The XRD spectra shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref> were not measured with the uttermost sensitivity of our equipment, which means that (the weak) signals from Ag or ITO were not clearly visible. Even though, upon closer inspection of the spectrum in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref>, a number of additional weak peaks are present. To clarify the question of the referee, we measured an identical sample again in XRD with a 10 times longer integration time (measurement time for one spectrum: 18 hours) to obtain a better signal to noise ratio and to render these weaker peaks better visible. Moreover we chose a logarithmic representation and included this spectrum as new Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">S3</ref> in the supporting information. Aside from the dominating MAPbI3 reflections, we were able to clearly identify signals attributed to PbI2, Ag and ITO. The AZO layer was not visible. AZO is a nano-crystalline material, however, the size of the AZO particles is only 12 nm, and therefore even in this more sensitive measurement we were not able to detect signs of the AZO layer. We have also prepared single AZO layers (80 nm thickness) on top of a glass substrate but we did also not see any XRD signal from these layers under similar XRD measurement conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure S3</head><p>: Logarithmic representation of the XRD spectrum of a fresh perovskite cell based on AZO as EEL with an assignment of the peaks to layers in the device. The peak positions of MAPbI3, 10 PbI2, <ref type="bibr">11</ref> ITO, <ref type="bibr">12</ref> and Ag, <ref type="bibr">13</ref> were taken from the respective references.</p><p>We also updated Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref> and the inset in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref> with the spectra measured with greater sensitivity. In the manuscript we now note the small PbI2 peak that is present in the fresh samples, already. We also notice that after 7 days of storing the device in ambient air, the PbI2 peak did not show a notable increase.</p><p>In the revised manuscript it now reads: "As this XRD measurement has been made on a full device stack, further signals related to the Ag and ITO electrodes are visible. A detailed assignment of these peaks is shown in the supporting information (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">S3</ref>). Only a very weak signal due to PbI2 was found, which did not significantly increase even after seven days in air (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref>). Thus, no severe decomposition of the perovskite to PbI2 upon storage in air can be inferred from the XRD data." Moreover, we agree with the referee, that there is a general belief that MAPbI3 exposed to air forms PbI2 quite readily. However, a careful review of reports in the literature shows a more ambiguous picture. Especially, a more detailed specification is needed for "ambient conditions" or "exposure to air" (in terms of temperature and relative humidity). For example, Christians et al. have reported XRD studies of MAPbI3 (fresh and after 28 days in air at 23±1°C and 50% relative humidity (similar to our lab)) and did not see any notable change in their XRD spectra [J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2015, 137, 1530-1538]. While at 23±1°C and 90% rH the same authors evidenced the formation of a hydrate phase clearly seen as additional peaks at 10.46° and 16.01°) after 7 days. In our case, at 23°C and 50% relative humidity, we also did not see a notable growth of the PbI2 peak even after 7 days (inset of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref>). However, the detection of iodine at the surface (XPS data Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref>) and the severe degradation of the Ag electrode (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3c,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>) infer that iodine compounds leaked out of the perovskite. The more reasonable explanation is that the amount of PbI2 that is formed upon storage in air is even smaller compared to the small amount of PbI2 already present in the pristine perovskite layer. We note, however, that likely only very small amounts of halide containing decomposition products are required to degrade the interface of the Ag electrode to the device and lead to the deteriorated device characteristics</p><p>We agree with the referee, that we cannot provide unambiguous evidence for amorphous PbI2, and thus we deleted this sentence.</p><p>3. For the XPS results, the baseline of fresh devices made with SnOx and AZO/SnOx shall be included. Since XPS is a surface technique that investigates on the first few 3~5 nm, I wonder if the perovskite can be detected if protected after 10 nm Ag and AZO. The As requested by the referee, we have added the baseline spectra of the fresh samples with SnOx and AZO/SnOx in the revised Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref>.</p><p>We have also added the survey spectra for all samples in the supporting information (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">S4</ref>). As expected, no signal due to the perovskite (e.g. Pb4d) can be detected, because the perovskite in these samples is covered by PCBM/AZO/Ag, or PCBM/SnOx/Ag, or PCBM/AZO/SnOx, respectively. Note, the position where the Pb4f signals would be located is overlaid by Zn3s and Sn4s signals as indicated in the figure, thus we refer to the Pb4d signal. The peak around 622 eV in the XPS spectrum shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref>, does not represent another bonding state of the iodine, it is rather a so called "shake-up" peak. The shake-up process is a two electron process in which a part of the kinetic energy of the photoelectron is used to lift-up an additional electron into an excited state, resulting in an excited ion. Due to the loss in kinetic energy, the apparent binding energy of the emitted and analyzed photoelectron is hereby increased by the energy necessary for the excitation (typically a few eV). Such shake-up peaks are commonly observed in any strong XPS signal. To show that the feature in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref> is not due to an interaction of Iodine with e.g. silver, we analyzed the iodine XPS spectra of pure MAPbI3, as well as of the precursors MAI and PbI2 (see figure below). All of these spectra show this shake up feature at around 622 eV (red curve).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>To clarify, we added in the revised version of the paper:</head><p>"The peak around 622 eV in the XPS spectrum of the aged AZO sample does not represent another bonding state of the iodine, it is rather a so called "shake-up" peak. Such shake-up peaks are commonly observed in strong XPS signals."</p><p>4. Are the SEM images taken on top of Ag or on top of oxides? I think that matters for proposing the mechanism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>The measurements were taken on top of Ag. It may have been overseen, but in the original version of the manuscript we had already specified this in the respective figure caption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.</head><p>To demonstrate real stability for solar cells, light soaking is necessary. Especially for perovskite solar cell, light soaking results can really substantiate the claim for long term stability. To be published in such high impact journal like Nature Communications, I think the authors shall show stability under light soaking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We also agree with the referee that light soaking tests (under concomitant heating) are an important (and more demanding) stress condition. However, we want to note, that according to a very recent "Research Update" published by the Snaith group in APL Materials [APL Mater. 4, 091503 (2016)], the number of reports on the stability of perovskite solar cells in which the cells are stressed by light soaking and heat simultaneously, is very scarce. This may in part be due to the fact that upon "multi-stress" conditions the individual degradation mechanisms are difficult to be separated. Nevertheless, as requested by the referees, we conducted a new set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C. Briefly, the devices were illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation. At the same time, the devices were kept in an oven at 60°C under N2 atmosphere (all experimental details are mentioned in the methods section). We have deliberately chosen the N2 environment for the light-soaking experiment, as we had already clarified the influence of humidity in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>, and we had clearly shown that the encapsulation due to the AZO/SnOx layer is efficiently blocking the ingress of moisture.</p><p>The results of the new light-soaking/heating stress tests are shown in the new Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref> (also shown above in this reply).</p><p>In the manuscript we added the following discussion: "Aside from so-called "mono-stress" conditions, like elevated temperature, multi-stressing can be considered. To this end, we conducted set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C under N2, in which the devices were simultaneously illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation (for details see the experimental section). The results of this multi-stress experiment are shown in the supporting information (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>). Briefly, again the AZO/SnOx cells are substantially more stable than the AZO cells under concomitant heat and illumination. This difference is in part due to the suppressed decomposition of the perovskite due to heat in case of the AZO/SnOx (in agreement with the discussion of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). However, there is a clear degradation even of the AZO/SnOx samples where the PCE decays to roughly 60 % of its initial value after 300 hours. This is in contrast to the case where only thermal stress has been used. Earlier work has unraveled the photo-induced degradation of solar cells based on MAPbI3. While Misra et al. identified a photo-activated decomposition mechanism 2 , more recently Nie et al. reported that continuous illumination of MAPbI3 caused the formation of trap states which spoiled the solar cells performance, especially Jsc. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> While our sealing approach based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer has been shown to efficiently suppress the decomposition of the perovskite, it cannot suppress the formation of trap states in the perovskite. Similar to the report of Nie et al., the cell characteristics recover after stressing, if the cells are kept in darkness (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8f</ref>). This is why we conclude that photo-induced trap-state formation occurs in our cells. However, there have been recent reports confirming that photo-induced degradation is not a general problem of organolead halide perovskites, and some optimized mixed cation / mixed halide perovskite active materials were shown to be far less prone to light soaking degradation. <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5</ref> . Heat was found to be a dominating source of degradation in these mixed cation perovskite cells. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Note, our inverted device structure based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer is generally applicable and can also accommodate these next-generation perovskite photoactive systems with enhanced stability and efficiency. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> " 6. The unit of EQE on Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1b</ref> is wrong.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>Thank you for pointing us to this error. We have revised Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref> b accordingly.</p><p>7. The first inverted perovskite solar cell using PEDOT:PSS and PCBM shall be cited in the introduction. Adv. Mater. 2013, 25, 3727.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>As requested, we have added the reference to Adv. Mater. 2013, 25, 3727 in the introduction.</p><p>Overall, I suggest a minor revision for this manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We deeply value your comments that helped us to improve our paper.</p><p>Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>The manuscript by Brinkmann et al address the use of AZO/SnOx electron extractor layers in hybrid perovskite solar cells. More specifically, the paper reports improved device stability when such AZO/SnOx layers are used in inverted type solar cells. The paper is interesting but in the current state the paper is not suitable for a journal like Nature Communications. There are a number of significant issues that must be addressed.</p><p>1 The more detailed mechanism of how the combined AZO/SnOx layer interlayer improves stability needs to be established. This is not at all clear from the data presented in the paper. 2 Following from above, what is the mechanism by which the SnOx layer improves stability? How does it block water getting in the device? Surely most of the diffusion occurs from the sides of the devices and through the silver? Why can't the metal electrode act as a barrier to water? It is not beyond the realms of possibility that approximately 100 nm thick (or several 10's nm thick) metal electrodes can function good physical blocking layers. Perhaps this should be investigated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>Comments 1+2 point into the same direction, thus we are going to reply to them combined:</p><p>As detailed in the manuscript the root cause of the improved stability due to the addition of the SnOx layer is in its functionality as a permeation barrier. The SnOx provides outstanding protection of the perovskite against the ingress of moisture and, even more importantly, at the same time it serves as powerful permeation barrier against the out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite, e.g. CH3NH3I, (CH3)3N, CH3I, HI, etc. We showed that the sealing properties of the SnOx layer contain the decomposition products inside the cell, and thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed. Water ingress via the sides (so-called: "side-leakage") is severely suppressed by thin-film barrier, as no glues are involved. Permeation via the Ag may occur but please note that the barrier is below the Ag (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1a</ref>). The metal electrode can form some barrier against moisture. They are used for food packaging, e.g. for potato-chips bags. But as is known, metal films do not form the kind of barriers that are required to protect sensitive thin-film devices such as OLEDs or, here, perovskite solar cells. To give some numbers: The water vapor transmission rate (WVTR) through 300 nm thick metal layers has been determined, see e.g. Appl. Phys. Lett. 93, 133307 (2008), to be on the order of 0.2 g/(m 2 day), while the ALD grown SnOx layers provide WVTRs on the order of 7x10 -5 g/(m 2 day). Thus, just like in the case of OLEDs and organic solar cells, the top metal electrode will not provide the level of protection required. Special to perovskites: There is the intrinsic decomposition of CH3NH3PbI3 to CH3NH3I and PbI2, which is thermally activated and which occurs even under inert conditions. The corrosion of metal electrodes due to these decomposition products has been identified to be a critical issue. Thus a permeation barrier against the out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite is required. As we show, the sealing properties of the SnOx layer contain the decomposition products inside the cell, and thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed and the deterioration of the electrode is prevented.</p><p>3 The authors suggest that the silver electrode may be involved in the degradation of the device in presence of water. Have the authors tried to replace the silver electrode with lets say gold (which is known to be more stable than silver) in control devices that do now contain the SnOx layer: ITO/PEDOT/active layer/gold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We are aware of some reports claiming improved stability of perovskite solar cells due to the use of Au. On the other hand, this claim is not free of ambiguity, as there are also reports that found long-term stability issues related to the migration of Au. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>While we assume that our impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer could be well suited to also prevent the migration of electrode metal atoms into the active layer, we feel that this is beyond the scope of the present communication. A further reason why we did not consider Au is its high cost, which might render Au electrodes less attractive for future commercialization.</head><p>Note: Point 4 was missing in the original referee report! experiments were performed. Was this done with maximum power point tracking? Were the experiments performed whilst continuously illuminating the solar cells under load with the solar cells put in ambient environment? Or, are the authors just referring "shelf life" stability. To get a true indication of stability it is important that he authors consider the former (e.g.) measurements under continuous illumination under load with MPP tracking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We applied so-called "mono-stress" conditions, i.e. either in air or under N2 at 60°C without light soaking. [APL Mater. 4, 091503 (2016)], the number of reports on the stability of perovskite solar cells in which the cells are stressed by light soaking and heat simultaneously, is very scarce. This may in part be due to the fact that upon "multi-stress" conditions the individual degradation mechanisms are difficult to be separated. Briefly, our devices were illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation. At the same time, the devices were kept in an oven at 60°C under N2 atmosphere (all experimental details are mentioned in the methods section). We have deliberately chosen the N2 environment for the light/heat stress experiment, as we had already clarified the influence of humidity in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>, and we had clearly shown that the encapsulation due to the AZO/SnOx layer is efficiently blocking the ingress of moisture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nevertheless, as requested by the referees, we conducted a new set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C. However, we want to note, that according to a very recent "Research Update" published by the Snaith group in APL Materials</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The results of the new light-soaking/heating stress tests are shown in the new Figure S8 (also shown above in this reply).</head><p>In the manuscript we added the following discussion: "Aside from so-called "mono-stress" conditions, like elevated temperature, multi-stressing can be considered. To this end, we conducted set of long-term light soaking tests at 60°C under N2, in which the devices were simultaneously illuminated with a white LED to achieve the same Jsc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation (for details see the experimental section). The results of this multi-stress experiment are shown in the supporting information (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>). Briefly, again the AZO/SnOx cells are substantially more stable than the AZO cells under concomitant heat and illumination. This difference is in part due to the suppressed decomposition of the perovskite due to heat in case of the AZO/SnOx (in agreement with the discussion of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). However, there is a clear degradation even of the AZO/SnOx samples where the PCE decays to roughly 60% of its initial value after 300 hours. This is in contrast to the case where only thermal stress has been used. Earlier  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8f</ref>). This is why we conclude that photo-induced trap-state formation occurs in our cells. However, there have been recent reports confirming that photo-induced degradation is not a general problem of organo-lead halide perovskites, and some optimized mixed cation / mixed halide perovskite active materials were shown to be far less prone to light soaking degradation. <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5</ref> . Heat was found to be a dominating source of degradation in these mixed cation perovskite cells. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Note, our inverted device structure based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer is generally applicable and can also accommodate these next-generation perovskite photoactive systems with enhanced stability and efficiency. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> " 6 In the temperature stability measurements shown in figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>. It is shown the drop in performance is mainly due to a drop in the fill factor. The authors should discuss the origin of this. The authors should also perhaps repeat temperature stability experiments using a thicker electrode layer -certainly thicker than 10nm !! It is not surprising that with such thin layers of silver (e.g. 10nm) increase the chance that the degradation products escape.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>work has unraveled the photo-induced degradation of solar cells based on MAPbI3. While Misra et al. identified a photo-activated decomposition mechanism 2 , more recently Nie et al. reported that continuous illumination of MAPbI3 caused the formation of trap states which spoiled the solar cells performance, especially Jsc. 3 While our sealing approach based on the impermeable AZO/SnOx electron extraction layer has been shown to efficiently suppress the decomposition of the perovskite, it cannot suppress the formation of trap states in the perovskite. Similar to the report of Nie et al., the cell characteristics recover after stressing, if the cells are kept in darkness (Figure</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>Obviously, there is a misunderstanding. The devices presented in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref> were based on 100 nm thick silver electrodes. The 10 nm Ag layers were only used in the XPS experiments to provide more sensitivity in the degradation effect.</p><p>To avoid further misconceptions we have specified the electrode thickness in the caption of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>: "In this set of samples, the thickness of the ALD SnOx layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm."</p><p>Regarding the origin of the loss in FF in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>:</p><p>We discussed in the manuscript: "Under inert atmosphere, the thermally activated degradation of the perovskite leads to decomposition products that can easily diffuse through the PCBM/AZO/Ag layers on top of the perovskite. The less volatile PbI2 phase remains in the active layer leading to a substantial decay of the FF of the corresponding devices (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">4c</ref>). Moreover, it has been shown earlier that a change in film stoichiometry (Pb-poor to Pb-rich) may substantially alter the electronic properties of the perovskite and especially the position of the conduction and valence band with respect to the vacuum level. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> Towards increasingly Pbrich conditions, the ionization energy of the perovskite has been shown to increase significantly to values in the order of &gt; 6eV, which would render the extraction of holes more and more challenging."</p><p>Again, we would like to thank the referees for their very helpful comments. We hope that in the revised version, our paper has now become acceptable for Nature Communications. Here is our point-by-point reply to the referees (please note our answers are in italic):</p><p>Reviewer #1 (Remarks to the Author): I am satisfied with the revisions to the manuscript. Although a simultaneous temperature and moisture (damp heat) test, which all commercial PV must pass, would be most interesting there is sufficient data included here for an initial report. The changes raise the quality of this revised work to those required by Nature Comm. I support prompt publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>We value the efforts of the referee and appreciate his supportive recommendation</head><p>Reviewer #2 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>The revised version has addressed most of the comments and questions raised by the reviewer properly. I would recommend its publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>We value the efforts of the referee and appreciate his supportive recommendation</head><p>Reviewer #3 (Remarks to the Author):</p><p>Based on the responses and reading the revised paper the referee believes that the paper may now be suitable for publication in Nature communications.</p><p>Point 1 and 2: The role of metal contact versus SnOx layer in protecting against water vapour ingress has been clarified. The comparison between vapour transmission rates for metal versus ALD grown SnOx is welcome. Point 3: Though a comparison of gold and silver as an electrode and the investigation of the use of SnOx/AZO as a blocking layer (ie reducing migration of metal atoms from electrode) are important issues the referee accepts that this is potentially beyond the scope of the current work. Point 5: The additional solar cell stability experiments (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S8</ref>) are welcome and serve to clarify the concerns of referee 3. Point 6: comments regarding thickness of Ag layer clarified. Concerning the origin of the drop in the fill factor (FF): the discussion is welcome. However, the referee has an additional question here: Did the authors observe a change in hysteresis in fresh versus aged samples. (referring to a device that is treated in the same way as in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5</ref>; main manuscript). For example, a device that is using an AZO/SnOx extraction layer (with and without heating at 60C)?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reply:</head><p>We value the efforts of the referee and appreciate his supportive recommendation We added in the manuscript: "Note, the hysteresis did not increase in the course of aging." The area of thin-film photovoltaics has been overwhelmed by organometal halide perovskites. Unfortunately, serious stability concerns arise with perovskite solar cells. For example, methyl-ammonium lead iodide is known to decompose in the presence of water and, more severely, even under inert conditions at elevated temperatures. Here, we demonstrate inverted perovskite solar cells, in which the decomposition of the perovskite is significantly mitigated even at elevated temperatures. Specifically, we introduce a bilayered electronextraction interlayer consisting of aluminium-doped zinc oxide and tin oxide. We evidence tin oxide grown by atomic layer deposition does form an outstandingly dense gas permeation barrier that effectively hinders the ingress of moisture towards the perovskite and-more importantly-it prevents the egress of decomposition products of the perovskite. Thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed, leading to an outstanding device stability. DOI: 10.1038/ncomms13938 OPEN <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Institute of Electronic Devices, University of Wuppertal, Rainer-Gruenter-Str 21, 42119 Wuppertal, Germany. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> College of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanchang University, 999 Xuefu Avenue, Nanchang 330031, China. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> College of Chemistry/Institute of Polymers, Nanchang University, 999 Xuefu Avenue, Nanchang 330031, China. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Department of Chemistry, University of Cologne, Luxemburger Strae 116, 50939 Cologne, Germany. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Nanograde AG, Laubisru ¨tistrasse 50, 8712 Sta ¨fa, Switzerland. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Ruhr-Universita ¨t Bochum, RUBION, Universita ¨tsstr. 150, 44801 Bochum, Germany. Correspondence and requests for materials should be addressed to T.R. (email: t.riedl@uni-wuppertal.de).</p><p>NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | 8:13938 | DOI: 10.1038/ncomms13938 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications S olar cells based on organolead halide perovskites have seen tremendous progress over the past 5 years 1 . Although their power conversion efficiency (PCE) has skyrocketed to reach a level of 420% (ref. <ref type="formula">2</ref>), concerns about their stability are still intimately linked to this technology <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> .</p><p>Generally, there is consensus that perovskites like CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 decompose to their constituents, that is, HI, CH 3 NH 2 and PbI 2 , in the presence of water <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . Moreover, the intrinsic decomposition of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 to CH 3 NH 3 I and PbI 2 , which is thermally activated and which occurs even under inert conditions, states a more fundamental problem <ref type="bibr">7,</ref><ref type="bibr">8</ref> . At the same time, there are secondary effects of perovskite decomposition such as the degradation of functional building blocks in the solar cell because of the corrosive effect of the perovskite decomposition products <ref type="bibr">9</ref> . Specifically, the corrosion of metal electrodes like Ag or Al has been identified to be a critical issue <ref type="bibr">10</ref> . Overall, without proper concepts to overcome these reliability issues, the prospects of wide-spread application and commercialization of organolead halide perovskite technology may be significantly compromised.</p><p>Among the various device architectures for perovskite solar cells, the inverted planar geometry has been shown to yield devices essentially free of hysteresis <ref type="bibr">11,</ref><ref type="bibr">12</ref> . Here, the photogenerated holes are extracted via the bottom electrode using a hole-extraction interlayer (for example, poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) polystyrene sulfonate (PEDOT:PSS)), while the electron extraction proceeds via the top electrode. The energetic alignment of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 and [6,6 0 ]-phenyl-C61-butyric acid methyl ester (PCBM) has been shown to be especially favourable for the extraction of electrons from the conduction band of the perovskite <ref type="bibr">13</ref> . To overcome the stability issues discussed above, several groups have introduced inverted planar perovskite cells based on metal oxides as electronand hole-extraction interfacial layers adjacent to the cathode and anode, respectively <ref type="bibr">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> . Chen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> employed a sol-gel Ti(Nb)O x electron-extraction layer that was aimed to protect the perovskite against moisture from ambient atmosphere. Because of its poor electrical conductivity of 10 À 5 S cm -1 , the authors had to limit the thickness of the sol-gel Ti(Nb)O x to 10 nm. Moreover, it is known that sol-gel-derived layers state only relatively poor permeation barriers <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">16</ref> . As a result, the device stability tests that afforded a lifetime of 1,000 h were done with additional encapsulation. Kaltenbrunner et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">17</ref> have used Cr 2 O 3 /Cr at the cathode side to protect the metal cathode and thereby to improve the stability under ambient conditions, but still the efficiency was found to drop to 80% of its initial value after only 28 h. Very recently, Guerrero et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">18</ref> confirmed the protective effect of the Cr 2 O 3 /Cr interlayer but still found some severe degradation after only a few hours. You et al. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> have shown that devices based on indium tin oxide (ITO)/NiO/perovskite/ZnO/Al were stable for tens of days in ambient conditions, whereas a reference device based on ITO/PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/PCBM/Al showed severe degradation within half a day. Especially, the ZnO layer, which has been spin coated from a nanoparticle dispersion on top of the perovskite, has been claimed to protect the Al electrode against corrosion. Very recently, Bush et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">19</ref> have found that in their devices a similar nanoparticle-based ZnO layer next to the cathode did not provide any sufficient protection at elevated temperatures. As solar cells in outdoor conditions may reach a temperature significantly above 25 °C, the latter result appears to be extremely relevant. Other reports have evidenced rapid decomposition of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 when in direct contact with ZnO <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">20</ref> .</p><p>Here we propose an inverted cell architecture, where a bilayered aluminium-doped ZnO (AZO)/tin oxide (SnO x ) electron-extraction layer (EEL) affords perovskite solar cells with a remarkable resilience against moisture and heat. AZO is excellently suited to extract electrons from the lowest unoccupied molecular orbital of fullerenes <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">21</ref> . However, the nanoparticlebased AZO layer does not provide sufficient protection against the ingress of moisture or the egress of perovskite decomposition products. Thus, we add a thin SnO x layer to form a bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL assembly. The SnO x is grown by low-temperature atomic layer deposition (ALD) at 80 °C that affords extremely dense, conformal and pinhole-free layers. Please note that there are reports where ALD layers have been directly deposited on top of perovskites to improve their resilience against ambient atmosphere and heat <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">22</ref> . However, these ALD layers were not a functional part of a device, and therefore most of the experiments were based on electrical insulators like Al 2 O 3 . SnO x layers grown by ALD are optically highly transparent, electrically conductive and provide outstanding gas permeation barrier properties with a water vapour transmission rate as low as 7 Â 10 À 5 g (m À 2 day À 1 ), even when grown at a low temperature <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">23</ref> . Their water vapour transmission rate is orders of magnitude better than that of sputtered ITO thin films or that of solution processed metal oxide layers. The electrical conductivity of the SnO x layer on the order of 5 Â 10 À 3 S cm À 1 allows us to place it between the sensitive electrode and the photoactive layers without adding any noticeable series resistance. Thereby, the SnO x provides outstanding protection of the perovskite against the ingress of moisture and, more importantly, at the same time it serves as permeation barrier against the out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite. We will show that the sealing property of the SnO x layer contains the decomposition products inside the cell and, thereby, the overall decomposition of the perovskite is significantly suppressed. Although cells based on LiF/Al or AZO degrade within tens of hours in ambient air (23 °C and 50% relative humidity (rH)), devices based on AZO/SnO x show superior stability of their solar cell characteristics even on a timescale of 4350 h. More strikingly, at 60 °C under inert atmosphere, AZO-based devices degrade within 100 h because of thermally induced decomposition of the perovskite. On the contrary, the suppressed out-diffusion of decomposition products because of the diffusion-barrier properties of the AZO/SnO x EEL affords cells that are essentially unchanged even after 41,000 h under the same conditions. Our paper reports a general strategy to achieve a substantially improved device lifetime in the case of photoactive materials that may come with concerns about their intrinsic compositional stability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Planar inverted cells. The devices used in this study are based on a planar inverted cell layout, where the holes are extracted via the bottom electrode (substrate electrode). The layer sequence is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>. As hole-extraction layer, PEDOT:PSS is used, whereas for electron extraction a 100 nm thick PCBM layer is deposited on top of the typically 180 nm thick CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite layer. Directly adjacent to the PCBM we have used a 100 nm thick AZO layer prepared from a nanoparticle dispersion in isopropylalcohol. In some cells, a SnO x layer is deposited on top of the AZO layer by ALD at 80 °C to form the bilayered electron-extraction assembly (AZO/SnO x ). The nominal thickness of the SnO x layer is 20 nm. As the AZO layer is derived from a nanoparticle dispersion, it contains pores that are partially coated with SnO x because of the conformal nature of the ALD process. A more detailed discussion of the SnO x growth on top of the AZO layer is provided in the Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1</ref>. Please note that we have also prepared devices with SnO x deposited directly on top of PCBM, but the stability of the resulting devices was inferior to that of the AZO/SnO x cells (see discussion below). Reference devices based on ITO/PED-OT:PSS/Perovskite/PCBM/LiF/Al have also been included in our study.</p><p>The external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum of a typical AZO/SnO x -based perovskite solar cell is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1b</ref>. The J/V characteristics of the device measured in forward and reverse direction (scan speed: 500 mV s À 1 ) are presented in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1c</ref>. No substantial hysteresis is found in the J/V data. The extracted characteristics V oc ¼ 0.95 V, FF ¼ 74% and a J sc ¼ 18 mA cm À 2 result in a PCE of 12.8%. We want to note that the perovskite precursor used in this study was commercially obtained from Ossila Ltd with a typically specified efficiency in the range of 11-13% (see Methods for details).</p><p>Significantly higher PCEs can be achieved by using, for example, optimized precursor inks or mixed-cation/mixedhalide perovskite absorbers <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">24</ref> . As the EEL is in the core of this report, further optimization of the perovskite system itself was considered to be beyond the scope here.</p><p>Stability in ambient air. A very striking advantage of the bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL in direct comparison with AZO is displayed in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">2</ref>. Here, the stability of the cell characteristics is shown for devices that were continuously exposed to ambient air at 23 °C and 50% relative humidity. The devices that were based on a single layer of AZO as EEL degrade swiftly within B50 h. A severe decay of the FF from B70% to o25% and a concomitant drop of the J sc from B17 to 8.2 mA cm À 2 is found. Opposed to that, the characteristics of the corresponding cells with the bilayered EEL of AZO/SnO x do not show any degradation even after 4300 h in air. Note that the thickness of the SnO x layer is only 20 nm in these devices. There is a slight increase of the V oc in the AZO/SnO x samples that happens on a timescale of several tens of hours. This increase is only observed in the AZO/SnO x samples, as the LiF/Al and the AZO cells already undergo strong degradation on the same timescale. A similar increase of V oc on such a long timescale has been seen by other authors and it has been explained by an ageing effect that reduces the density of trap states in the perovskite <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">25</ref> . As a reference, the cells based on LiF/Al are essentially degraded within B1 day.</p><p>In order to analyse the reasons underlying the strikingly different degradation phenomena shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">2</ref>, we have performed X-ray diffraction (XRD) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) studies of the respective device structures. Note that in case of the XPS measurements, a thinner top Ag electrode was chosen (10 nm) compared with the actual solar cells (100 nm) because of the small probing depth of the technique. Looking first at the AZO-based device, the XRD spectrum shows the (110) and (220) reflections of tetragonal MAPbI 3 at angles of 14.11°and 28.14, respectively. As this XRD measurement has been made on a full device stack, further signals related to the Ag and ITO electrodes are visible. A detailed assignment of these peaks is shown in the Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3</ref>. Only a very weak signal due to PbI 2 was found that did not significantly increase even after 7 days in air (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref>). Thus, no severe decomposition of the perovskite to PbI 2 upon storage in air can be inferred from the XRD data. On the other hand, when XPS was used to look for degradation products on the surface, a notable amount of iodine was evidenced on the AZO sample (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref>) after exposure to air for 2 days, whereas on identical samples kept in nitrogen no such iodine signal is found. Please note that the peak of B622 eV in the XPS spectrum of the aged AZO cell does not represent another bonding state of the iodine, but it is rather a so-called shake-up peak. Such shake-up peaks are commonly observed in strong XPS signals. The survey XPS spectra can be found in the Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>. Plan-view scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images of the AZO samples aged in air show the formation of spot-like degradation motifs (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3c,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>). These spots point to the local ingress of moisture and out-diffusion of decomposition products of the perovskite, supported by the appearance of the iodine signal in XPS. In the degraded spots, needle-like features occur. Similar features have been reported for Ag electrodes corroded by the decomposition products of MAPbI 3 (ref. 26).</p><p>Our findings are also in line with the results of Kato et al. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> who unveiled a moisture promoted corrosion mechanism of Ag which resulted in the formation of products like AgI. The role of water in the electrode corrosion is further clarified below in cells aged under inert conditions.</p><p>To explain the spot-like degradation, we can assume that structural defects, such as pinholes, in the AZO NP layer would give rise to locally enhanced water permeation. Opposed to that, the sample with the bilayered EEL of AZO/SnO x does not show any sign of degradation in SEM (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3e</ref>) under identical conditions. In XPS, only a negligible amount of iodine at the surface of the AZO/SnO x samples can be detected. For comparison, we have also studied layer stacks where only SnO x , that is, without AZO between the PCBM and the SnO x , has been used as EEL. We have recently shown that SnO x with a work function of 4.1 eV forms an excellent EEL layer in inverted organic solar cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">27</ref> . Here, the resulting perovskite solar cells based on SnO x were more stable than the devices based on AZO. However, they showed a statistical failure on a timescale of 100 h (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5</ref>). This finding could be explained by a nonideal ALD growth of the SnO x directly on top of the organic PCBM layer. ALD as a chemical deposition technique relies on self-limiting chemical reactions on the sample surface <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">28</ref> . For the ALD deposition of oxide layers, -OH surface groups form the nucleation sites for layer growth. In this sense, on organic surfaces like PCBM the nucleation of an ALD layer may deviate significantly from the growth on a surface rich of -OH groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">29</ref> . Therefore, we can assume that the SnO x layer grown on PCBM is not free of some pin-hole defects that compromise its functionality as diffusion barrier. Consequently, substantially more iodine is detected on the surface after exposure to air compared with the AZO/SnO x device (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3b</ref>). Thus, we conclude that the AZO serves two purposes in the bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL: (1) its electronic structure has been shown to facilitate electron extraction from the PCBM (ref. 21) and (2)  the AZO layer provides an improved (oxide-) surface for the nucleation of the subsequent SnO x ALD layer that can thus from a dense, pin-hole-free permeation barrier. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3f</ref>,g shows schemes portraying the specific differences between AZO and AZO/SnO x as EEL in devices exposed to air.</p><p>As indicated before, the AZO layer prepared from the NP dispersion does not provide a significant diffusion barrier against the local ingress of moisture from the ambient air. As a result, decomposition of the MAPbI 3 perovskite occurs and yields iodine-based products that migrate to the surface.</p><p>In the case of AZO/SnO x , substantially better moisture barrier properties prevent the penetration of water. The claim of superior moisture barrier properties of the bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL compared with that of the AZO NP layer is also supported by Ca-corrosion tests (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref>). It has to be noted that the detrimental effects of ambient air could in principle be avoided by using a proper encapsulation of the entire solar cell. However, the out-diffusion of decomposition products from the perovskite and the degradation of the metal electrode (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3c,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>) may impose a more fundamental issue. This is even more important, as earlier reports evidenced the thermally activated decomposition of the MAPbI 3 perovskite even under inert atmosphere <ref type="bibr">7</ref> .</p><p>Stability at elevated temperatures. To study the long-term stability of our solar cells under inert conditions, we have stored a set of devices in a glove box under N 2 atmosphere. All the devices were placed on a hot plate at 60 °C and their characteristics were measured repeatedly. Most remarkably, the characteristics of devices based on AZO EELs degraded on a timescale of 100 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). Although the J sc and V oc of these devices remain fairly stable, the decay of the FF results in the severe drop of PCE to B2% after 360 h. The degradation motif in the AZO-based cells is essentially different from that found in ambient air, where all cell characteristics decayed within a day (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">2</ref>). Again in striking contrast, the characteristics of devices based on the bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL remain almost unchanged even after 1,032 h. Note that the hysteresis did not increase in the course of ageing.</p><p>To unravel the mechanisms behind these results, we have again performed XRD and XPS studies of the respective device structures. After heating the device stacks for 6 days under inert atmosphere, the XRD spectrum of the AZO samples reveals a significant signal due to PbI 2 that is absent in pristine stacks (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5a</ref>). The formation of PbI 2 indicates the thermally activated decomposition of the perovskite upon heating, in agreement with earlier reports <ref type="bibr">7</ref> . Opposed to that, the devices based on the bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL do not show any signature of a PbI 2 phase after identical ageing conditions (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5b</ref>).</p><p>The formation of PbI 2 in the AZO samples is in contrast to the degradation experiments in air, where no PbI 2 phase in the AZO samples was found in XRD (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3a</ref>). At the same time, the I3d 5/2 XPS spectra (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5c</ref>) do not reveal any significant increase of the amount of iodine at the surface of any of the samples aged in N 2 . Please note that the noise in the XPS spectra indicates that the concentration of I3d 5/2 at the surface of all the samples is close to the detection limit and variations between the samples are within the measurement error. A plan-view SEM image of the aged AZO samples does not reveal any degradation of the Ag electrode, in contrast to the experiment where the ageing took place in air (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">3c,</ref><ref type="figure">d</ref>). Thus, we conclude that in the case of AZO, volatile decomposition products of the MAPbI 3 perovskite evaporate from the cell stack without degradation of the Ag electrode. In air, other than in N 2 , the presence of water would promote the corrosion of Ag because of CH 3 NH 3 I and other halide compounds <ref type="bibr">10</ref> . However, the loss of CH 3 NH 3 I etc. drives the further decomposition of the perovskite.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Taken together, the device characteristics (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>) and the XRD and XPS spectroscopy point to a scheme of degradation as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">5e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref>. Under inert atmosphere, the thermally activated degradation of the perovskite leads to decomposition products that can easily diffuse through the PCBM/AZO/Ag layers on top of the perovskite. The less volatile PbI 2 phase remains in the active layer leading to a substantial decay of the FF of the corresponding devices (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">4c</ref>). Moreover, it has been shown earlier that a change in film stoichiometry (Pb poor to Pb rich) may substantially alter the electronic properties of the perovskite and especially the position of the conduction and valence band with respect to the vacuum level <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">30</ref> . Towards In this set of samples, the nominal thickness of the ALD SnO x layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm. The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7</ref>).</p><p>increasingly Pb-rich conditions, the ionization energy of the perovskite has been shown to increase significantly to values in excess of 6 eV that would render the extraction of holes more and more challenging. Opposed to the case of the AZO cells, the AZO/SnO x -based cells do not show any formation of PbI 2 under otherwise identical conditions. We therefore conclude that the decomposition products are contained inside the cell stack because of the dense SnO x layer forming a permeation barrier. Thereby, the equilibrium of the decomposition/formation reaction would be shifted to stabilize the perovskite. Thus, the decomposition of the MAPbI 3 obviously is significantly slowed down, and the cells do not show significant degradation even after heating for 41,000 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). It has to be noted that it is favourable to position the permeation barrier between the perovskite and the Ag electrode, as thereby the known long-term corrosive effect of residual halide components on the Ag electrode <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">31</ref> and on the interface EEL/Ag can be efficiently suppressed. In further work, this concept could even be extended to a setup, in which the perovskite layer is sandwiched between diffusion barriers at the cathode and anode side, in case permeable substrates like polymer foils are used. For example, there are reports on using ALD to prepare V 2 O 5 layers 32 . V 2 O 5 is a high work function transition metal oxide that has successfully been used for hole extraction in organic and perovskite solar cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[33]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[34]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[35]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[36]</ref> . ALD prepared V 2 O 5 would presumably provide similar gas permeation barrier properties as those shown for the SnO x . Thereby, the intrinsic decomposition of the perovskite active layers would be substantially delayed or even prevented as volatile decomposition products would be hindered from evaporating.</p><p>Aside from the so-called mono-stress conditions like elevated temperature, multi-stressing can be considered. To this end, we conducted set of long-term light soaking tests at 60 °C under N 2 , in which the devices were simultaneously illuminated with a white light-emitting diode (LED) to achieve the same J sc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation (for details see the Methods section). The results of this multi-stress experiment are shown in the Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8</ref>. Briefly, again the AZO/SnO x cells are substantially more stable than the AZO cells under concomitant heat and illumination. This difference is in part because of the suppressed decomposition of the perovskite owing to heat in case of the AZO/SnO x (in agreement with the discussion of Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). However, there is a clear degradation even of the AZO/SnO x samples where the PCE decays to roughly 60% of its initial value after 300 h. This is in contrast to the case where only thermal stress has been used. Earlier work has unravelled the photo-induced degradation of solar cells based on MAPbI 3 . Whereas Misra et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">37</ref> identified a photoactivated decomposition mechanism, more recently Nie et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">38</ref> reported that continuous illumination of MAPbI 3 caused the formation of trap states that spoiled the solar cell performance, especially J sc . Although our sealing approach based on the impermeable AZO/SnO x electron extraction layer has been shown to efficiently suppress the decomposition of the perovskite, it cannot suppress the formation of trap states in the perovskite. Similar to the report of Nie et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">38</ref> the cell characteristics recover after stressing, if the cells are kept in darkness (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8f</ref>). This is why we conclude that photo-induced trap-state formation occurs in our cells. However, there have been recent reports confirming that photo-induced degradation is not a general problem of organolead halide perovskites, and some optimized mixed cation/ mixed halide perovskite active materials were shown to be far less prone to light soaking degradation <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">39</ref> . Heat was found to be a dominating source of degradation in these mixed cation perovskite cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">40</ref> . Note that our inverted device structure based on the impermeable AZO/SnO x electron extraction layer is generally applicable and can also accommodate these nextgeneration perovskite photoactive systems with enhanced stability and efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">41</ref> .</p><p>In summary, we have shown an ultra-stable inverted cell architecture, where a bilayered AZO/SnO x EEL has been demonstrated to afford perovskite solar cells with a remarkable resilience. The 20 nm thin ALD grown SnO x has been evidenced to form an outstandingly dense gas permeation barrier that effectively hinders the ingress of moisture towards the perovskite and-more importantly-it prevents the egress of decomposition products like CH 3 NH 3 I, HI out of the perovskite.</p><p>Although the efficiency of cells based on LiF/Al or AZO degraded to o50% of the initial value within less than a day in ambient air, devices based on AZO/SnO x showed superior stability of their solar cell characteristics even on a timescale of 4350 h. Under inert atmosphere, AZO-based devices degraded to roughly 50% of its initial efficiency within 100 h because of thermally induced decomposition of the perovskite. On the contrary, the suppressed out-diffusion of decomposition products because of the diffusion-barrier properties of the AZO/SnO x EEL has been shown to significantly slow down the thermally activated decomposition of the perovskite. This afforded cells that did not change even after 41,000 h. The concept of impermeable EELs is generally applicable and therefore is expected to provide an avenue to achieve a substantially improved device lifetime of solar cells based on organometal halide perovskites even beyond MAPbI 3 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Material synthesis and device preparation. The inverted perovskite solar cells studied in this work are based on the following layer sequence: glass/ITO/ PEDOT:PSS/perovskite/PCBM/EEL/Ag (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">1a</ref>). The PEDOT layer (AI4083) has been spin coated in ambient air and dried on a hot plate at 120 °C for 20 min in air and for another 20 min in a glove box under N 2 atmosphere. The perovskite layer has been spin coated under inert atmosphere from a commercially available precursor solution (Ossila) and the resulting layers were thermally annealed at 100 °C for 80 min. The typical layer thickness was 180 nm.</p><p>On top of the perovskite, PCBM (American Dye Sorce Inc., ADS61BFA) was spin coated from a solution in chlorobenzene (concentration: 100 mg ml À 1 ). AZO has been deposited from a commercial nanoparticle dispersion (2.5 wt% in isopropanol, Prod. No. 8045, Nanograde AG, Switzerland). Tin oxide has been prepared by atomic layer deposition in a Beneq TFS 200 system (base pressure 1.5 mbar). As precursors, tetrakis(dimethylamino)tin(IV) (TDMASn), kept at 45 °C and water, kept at room temperature, were used. At a substrate temperature of 80 °C the growth rate per cycle was 1.1 Å. Further details on the materials properties of the SnO x can be found in our earlier work <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">27</ref> . Ag (100 or 10 nm) layers were thermally evaporated in high vacuum (10 À 7 mbar). In some reference devices, LiF (1 nm) and Al (100 nm) have been thermally evaporated as cathode.</p><p>Materials and device characterization. The electrical conductivity was measured with the Van der Pauw method.</p><p>The SEM studies were conducted using Neon 40 (Zeiss). XRD was measured using a monochromatic Cu-Ka 1,2 source (Philips X'Pert Pro MPD). XPS has been performed using a non-monochromatic Mg K a X-ray source (VG) and a Phoibos 100 (Specs) electron analyser.</p><p>Rutherford backscattering was measured at RUBION (University of Bochum, Germany) using a dynamitron tandem accelerator with 2 MeV 4 He þ beam (beam current of 20-40 nA). A silicon surface barrier detector was placed at an angle of 160°with respect to the beam axis. The solid angle of the detector was 1.91 msrad.</p><p>The solar cells were characterized in ambient air without encapsulation using a Keithley 2400-C source meter and a solar simulator (300 W Newport, model 91160, AM1.5G, 100 mW cm À 2 ). We used a commercial Si reference cell (Rera Systems) that is IEC 60904-9 compliant and certified. Short circuit current was obtained from the EQE data. EQE has been measured with a home-built tunable light source, calibrated with a power meter (Thorlabs). The spectral mismatch factor was 1.163. Some of the devices have been kept in a glovebox under N 2 atmosphere on a hot plate at 60 °C. The J/V characteristics were measured in forward and reverse direction at a scanning speed of 500 mV s À 1 . Cells were measured using a mask with round aperture of 1.5 mm diameter. Stabilized current was measured in the same J/V setup using a voltage source.</p><p>Long-term light soaking tests at 60 °C under N 2 were conducted by simultaneously illuminating the cells with a white LED to achieve the same J sc as upon AM1.5G solar irradiation. The LED spectrum is shown in the Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8e</ref>. The cells were mounted in a home-built oven inside a glove box. They were kept in short circuit conditions during the ageing experiment.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 3 : 4 .</head><label>34</label><figDesc>Logarithmic representation of the XRD spectrum of a fresh perovskite cell based on AZO as EEL with an assignment of the peaks to layers in the device. The peak positions of MAPbI 3 (ref. 2), PbI 2 (ref. 3), ITO (ref. 4), and Ag (ref. 5), were taken from the respective references. The survey XPS spectra for cells based on AZO, SnO x and bi-layered AZO/SnO x EELs, are shown in Supplementary Fig. As expected, no signal due to the perovskite (e.g. Pb4d) can be detected, because the perovskite in these samples is covered by PCBM/AZO/Ag, or PCBM/SnO x /Ag, or PCBM/AZO/SnO x , respectively. Note, the position where the Pb4f signals would be located is overlaid by Zn3s and Sn4s signals as indicated in the figure, thus we refer to the Pb4d signal. Supplementary Figure 4: Survey photoemission spectra. Spectra for cells based on AZO (fresh sample (blue), aged sample (green)), SnO x (fresh sample (red), aged sample (orange))and bi-layered AZO/SnO x (fresh sample (black), aged sample (grey)) EELs are shown, respectively. Samples were either fresh or aged for two days in air, respectively. The top Ag layer was only about 10 nm to see the metal-oxide underneath. The spectral region, where the signals due to electrons resulting from the respective atomic orbitals are found or expected are shaded in grey and labelled with the element and atomic orbital. The spectral region where the Pb4d signal would be expected is shaded on orange. Supplementary Figure 5: Stability of devices based on only SnO x as EEL. (a) Characteristics of perovskite cells with 20 nm of ALD SnO x as EEL upon storage in ambient air (at 22°C, 60%rH). V o c vs. time (a) and FF vs. time (b).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure S1 :</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Figure S1: Layer sequence of the samples used to study the ALD growth of the SnO x on top of an AZO layer grown by ALD, which is expected to have no pinholes (a), and on top of an AZO layer derived from a nanoparticle dispersion (b). The resulting RBS spectra attributed to Sn, which allow to determine the area density of Sn atoms (c).</figDesc><graphic coords="16,185.94,112.14,207.00,203.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure. 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure. 4 Characteristics of inverted perovskite cells with varied cathode electron extraction assemblies (AZO/SnO x /Ag, AZO/Ag) vs. time of storage at 60°C in nitrogen atmosphere. J sc (a), V oc (b), FF (c), and PCE (d). In this set of samples,</figDesc><graphic coords="18,92.22,86.58,391.44,343.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure S8</head><label>S8</label><figDesc>Figure S8 Characteristics of inverted perovskite cells with varied cathode electron extraction assemblies (AZO/SnO x /Ag, AZO/Ag) vs. time of storage at 60°C in nitrogen atmosphere and simultaneous illumination with a white LED to achieve the same J sc as under the solar simulator. J sc (a), V oc (b), FF (c), and PCE (d). J sc,0 ,</figDesc><graphic coords="20,108.00,84.30,391.86,496.38" type="vector_box" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>authors shall provide the whole spectrum to show what they have detected on the surface. The signal of Eb close to 622 eV for the blue line on Fig 3 (b) shall be identified and discussed. Is it something other than AgI? Reply:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure S4 :</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Figure S4: Survey photoemission spectra for cells based on AZO, SnO x and bi-layered AZO/SnO x EELs, respectively. Samples were fresh and aged for two days in air, respectively. The top Ag layer was only about 10 nm to see the metal-oxide underneath.</figDesc><graphic coords="25,92.22,82.02,427.56,306.78" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Thank you for your notification regarding our revised submission NCOMMS-16-14487A.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>ARTICLE Received 21</head><label>21</label><figDesc>Jun 2016 | Accepted 15 Nov 2016 | Published 9 Jan 2017 Suppressed decomposition of organometal halide perovskites by impermeable electron-extraction layers in inverted solar cells K.O. Brinkmann 1 , J. Zhao 1,2 , N. Pourdavoud 1 , T. Becker 1 , T. Hu 1,3 , S. Olthof 4 , K. Meerholz 4 , L. Hoffmann 1 , T. Gahlmann 1 , R. Heiderhoff 1 , M.F. Oszajca 5 , N.A. Luechinger 5 , D. Rogalla 6 , Y. Chen 3 , B. Cheng 2 &amp; T. Riedl 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure1| Basic device characteristics. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) image of the device cross-section along with the assignment of the respective layers (a). In some devices, the SnO x or the AZO layer has been omitted. Note that the contrast between the AZO and the SnO x layers in SEM is relatively poor. External quantum efficiency (EQE) of a representative device based on AZO/SnO x (b). J/V characteristics measured in forward and reverse direction (c), and current density versus time under 0 V (black) and 0.75 V (red) bias (d).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 2 |</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2 | Stability upon storage in ambient air. Characteristics of inverted perovskite collar cells with varied cathode/electron extraction assemblies (AZO/SnO x /Ag, AZO/Ag and LiF/Al) versus time of storage in ambient air (at 23 °C and 50% rH). J sc (a), V oc (b), FF (c) and PCE (d). The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction (examples in Supplementary Fig. 2).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 | Unravelling the ageing mechanism in air. XRD spectrum of a perovskite cell based on AZO as EEL after storage in air for 7 days (inset: magnified view of the (100) PbI 2 reflection for a fresh sample and one that has been stored in air for 7 days; spectra were vertically offset for clarity) (a). Photoemission spectra of the iodine I3d 5/2 peak for fresh and aged cells based on AZO, SnO x and bilayered AZO/SnO x EELs, respectively (b). The aged samples were stored in air for 2 days. Corresponding plan-view SEM images of the 10 nm Ag layer in case of the AZO sample (c,d), and for the AZO/SnO x sample (e). Schemes of ageing for the AZO and the AZO/SnO x samples (f,g).</figDesc><graphic coords="40,124.25,346.57,333.42,188.18" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4 | Stability upon storage at 60 °C in nitrogen atmosphere. Characteristics of inverted perovskite cells with varied cathode electron-extraction assemblies (AZO/SnO x /Ag, AZO/Ag) versus time. J sc (a), V oc (b), FF (c) and PCE (d).In this set of samples, the nominal thickness of the ALD SnO x layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm. The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction (Supplementary Fig.7).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 5 |</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5 | Why impermeable AZO/SnO x EELs afford stable devices. XRD spectra of a perovskite cell based on AZO and AZO/SnO x as EEL before and after heating in nitrogen for 6 days. (a,b) Photoemission spectra of the iodine I3d 5/2 peak for cells based on AZO and bilayered AZO/SnO x EELs, respectively. (c) As a reference, an AZO sample stored in N 2 ambient has been used. The other measurements are for samples aged at 60 °C in nitrogen for 6 days. The open symbols represent the raw measurement data, whereas the solid lines are a result of a peak fit. The colours are defined in the figure legend. Note that the top Ag electrode was chosen to be 10 nm. Corresponding plan-view SEM image of the 10 nm Ag layer in case of the aged AZO sample. (d) Schemes of ageing and decomposition of the perovskite in case of the AZO (e) and the AZO/SnO x samples (f). The yellow spot in the scheme of the AZO sample symbolizes the formation of PbI 2 .</figDesc><graphic coords="42,131.81,207.73,95.66,99.14" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,139.62,85.80,307.14,290.16" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="5,92.22,146.40,427.56,306.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="6,92.22,82.02,427.56,200.22" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,109.86,80.52,380.16,188.22" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,96.00,421.14,427.56,198.36" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="8,119.70,65.86,390.30,494.54" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="23,147.12,216.78,297.42,228.06" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="26,92.64,89.58,430.92,130.26" type="bitmap" /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | 8:13938 | DOI: 10.1038/ncomms13938 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Again, we would like to thank everyone involved in handling and reviewing our paper. We are looking forward to seeing our paper published in Nature Communications.</p></div>
<div><head>Sincerely, Thomas Riedl</head></div>
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We acknowledge the <rs type="funder">German Federal Ministry for Education and Research</rs> (Grant No. <rs type="grantNumber">03EK3529E</rs>) and the <rs type="funder">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG)</rs> (Grants: <rs type="grantNumber">RI1551/4-2</rs>) for financial support. We acknowledge the <rs type="funder">Ministry of Science of the state of NRW</rs> for funding within the <rs type="programName">PeroBOOST (EFRE)</rs> project. The research leading to these results has received partial funding from the <rs type="funder">European Unions 7th Framework Programme</rs> under Grant Agreement no. <rs type="grantNumber">604148</rs> (MUJULIMA).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_b7FghG8">
					<idno type="grant-number">03EK3529E</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_v5XfrM7">
					<idno type="grant-number">RI1551/4-2</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Hp9aUZr">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">PeroBOOST (EFRE)</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_kM8z9Qy">
					<idno type="grant-number">604148</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Data availability. The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author on request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Information</head><p>Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref> studies the ALD growth of the SnO x layer on top of AZO, which has either been derived from an ALD process, and can therefore be considered as free of pinholes, or on top of an AZO layer prepared from a nanoparticle dispersion, where some porosity cannot be avoided. Details of the growth of AZO by ALD have been reported earlier. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The conformal nature of the ALD process is expected to yield some growth of SnO x inside the pores of the AZO layer. To analyze and quantify this effect, we performed Rutherford backscattering (RBS) measurements on the two samples shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>. To this end, we have deposited nominally 20 nm (166 ALD cycles) of SnO x in one ALD process on top of both AZO layers. From the RBS spectra attributed to Sn, we are able to determine the number of Sn atoms per area, which is indicative of the amount of SnO x actually deposited. Interestingly, for the SnO x on top of the pin-hole-free ALD-AZO we measured (44.5±0.2)×10 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> Sn-atoms per cm 2 , which is in excellent agreement to earlier RBS measurements of layers with a thickness of 20 nm (determined by stylus profilometry). On the contrary, for the SnO x on top of the NP-AZO layer we found (72.2±0.9)×10 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">15</ref> Sn-atoms per cm 2 , which is a factor of 1.62 higher than for the non-porous substrate. This result clearly supports the hypothesis of the ALD growth of the SnO x partially inside the pores of the nanoparticle derived AZO layer, which increases the total amount of SnO x deposited.</p><p>Moreover, the shoulder in the RBS spectrum of the Sn in case the SnO x layer has been grown on top of the AZO (NP) layer, is a direct result of a greater spatial variation of the Sn atoms in growth direction compared to the case where the SnO x layer has been grown on top of the AZO (ALD). This spatial variation originates from the infiltration of the SnO x into the porous AZO (NP) layer. J sc (a), V oc (b), FF (c), and PCE (d). J sc,0 , V oc,0 , FF 0 , and PCE 0 are the characteristics of the cells before stressing. In this set of samples, the thickness of the ALD SnO x layer was 20 nm and that of the Ag electrode was 100 nm. The characteristics have been determined from the J/V measurements in reverse direction. Spectrum of the white LED used for the light-soaking stress test under concomitant heating (e). J/V characteristics of an AZO/SnO x /Ag cell, non-stressed (fresh), stressed for 300 hours (light/heat), and subsequently recovered in in darkness at room temperature for nine days (in the glove box).  Publisher's note: Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations. This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article's Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in the credit line; if the material is not included under the Creative Commons license, users will need to obtain permission from the license holder to reproduce the material. To view a copy of this license, visit <ref type="url" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ref> r The Author(s) 2017</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary References</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Highly Robust Transparent and Conductive Gas Diffusion Barriers Based on Tin Oxide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Behrendt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5961" to="5967" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure and function relationships in alkylammonium lead(II) iodide solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Safdari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kloo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Materials Chemistry A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9201" to="9207" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growth control of compact CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 thin films via enhanced solid-state precursor reaction for efficient planar perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Materials Chemistry A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9249" to="9256" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transparent and conducting ITO thin films by spin coating of an aqueous precursor solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tol</forename><surname>Sunde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mater Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15740" to="15749" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Silver Iodide Formation in Methyl Ammonium Lead Iodide Perovskite Solar Cells with Silver Top Electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Raga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advanced Materials Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gas permeation barriers deposited by atmospheric pressure plasma enhanced atomic layer deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hoffmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Theirich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hasselmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Räupke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Schlamm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Vac Sci Technol A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="01A" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Al 2 O 3 /ZrO 2 Nanolaminates as Ultrahigh Gas-Diffusion Barriers-A Strategy for Reliable Encapsulation of Organic Electronics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1845" to="1849" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress Management in Thin-Film Gas-Permeation Barriers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Behrendt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Van De Weijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gahlmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heiderhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acs Appl Mater Inter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4056" to="4057" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilizing hybrid perovskites against moisture and temperature via non-hydrolytic atomic layer deposited overlayers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abf</forename><surname>Martinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Materials Chemistry A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20092" to="20096" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temperature-and Component-Dependent Degradation of Perovskite Photovoltaic Materials under Concentrated Sunlight</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="326" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Light-activated photocurrent degradation and self-healing in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11574</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporation of rubidium cations into perovskite solar cells improves photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saliba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mixed-cation lead mixed-halide perovskite absorber for tandem solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mcmeekin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not All That Glitters Is Gold: Metal-Migration-Induced Degradation in Perovskite Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Domanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acs Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6306" to="6314" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-Quality Mixed-Organic-Cation Perovskites from a Phase-Pure Nonstoichiometric Intermediate (FAI)1-x-PbI2 for Solar Cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4918" to="4923" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient and stable large-area perovskite solar cells with inorganic charge extraction layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="944" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thin Al2O3 barrier coatings onto temperature-sensitive packaging materials by atomic layer deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hirvikorpi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vähä-Nissi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nikkola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harlin</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Karppinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surface and Coatings Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">205</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5088" to="5092" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure and function relationships in alkylammonium lead(ii) iodide solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Safdari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kloo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Materials Chemistry A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9201" to="9207" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growth control of compact CH3NH3PbI3 thin films via enhanced solid-state precursor reaction for efficient planar perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Materials Chemistry A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9249" to="9256" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transparent and conducting ITO thin films by spin coating of an aqueous precursor solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tol</forename><surname>Sunde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Mater Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15740" to="15749" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Silver Iodide Formation in Methyl Ammonium Lead Iodide Perovskite Solar Cells with Silver Top Electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Raga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advanced Materials Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of Film Stoichiometry on the Ionization Energy and Electronic Structure of CH3NH3PbI3 Perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Emara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pourdavoud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Meerholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olthof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The light and shade of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Graetzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="838" to="842" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">348</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1234" to="1237" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recent advances in improving the stability of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Tiep</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ku</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1501420</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability of metal halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Leijtens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500963</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometal halide perovskite solar cells: degradation and stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Berhe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energ. Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Study on the stability of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 films and the effect of postmodification by aluminum oxide in all-solid-state hybrid solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="705" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrinsic thermal instability of methylammonium lead trihalide perovskite</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Conings</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500477</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In situ observation of heat-induced degradation of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Divitini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15012</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fully solution-processed transparent electrodes based on silver nanowire composites for perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nanoscale</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6308" to="6316" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Silver iodide formation in methyl ammonium lead iodide perovskite solar cells with silver top electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mat. Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-efficiency solution-processed perovskite solar cells with millimeter-scale grains</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">347</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="525" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hysteresis-less inverted CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 planar perovskite hybrid solar cells with 18.1% power conversion efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Heo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Im</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energ. Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1602" to="1608" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite/fullerene planar-heterojunction hybrid solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-Y</forename><surname>Jeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3727" to="3732" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved air stability of perovskite solar cells via solutionprocessed metal oxide transport layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>You</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient and stable large-area perovskite solar cells with inorganic charge extraction layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="944" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thin Al2O3 barrier coatings onto temperature-sensitive packaging materials by atomic layer deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hirvikorpi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Va ¨ha ¨-Nissi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nikkola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Karppinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surf. Coat. Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">205</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5088" to="5092" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flexible high power-per-weight perovskite solar cells with chromium oxide-metal contacts for improved stability in air</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kaltenbrunner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1032" to="1039" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interfacial degradation of planar lead halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Guerrero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="224" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal and environmental stability of semi-transparent perovskite solar cells for tandems enabled by a solution-processed nanoparticle buffer layer and sputtered ITO electrode</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bush</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3937" to="3943" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Origin of the thermal instability in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 thin films deposited on ZnO</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Siempelkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mosconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Angelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4229" to="4236" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming the &apos;light-soaking&apos; issue in inverted organic solar cells by the use of Al:ZnO electron extraction layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Trost</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1437" to="1444" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilizing hybrid perovskites against moisture and temperature via non-hydrolytic atomic layer deposited overlayers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abf</forename><surname>Martinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20092" to="20096" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Highly robust transparent and conductive gas diffusion barriers based on tin oxide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Behrendt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5961" to="5967" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mixed-cation lead mixed-halide perovskite absorber for tandem solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mcmeekin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Air-stable, efficient mixed-cation perovskite solar cells with Cu electrode by scalable fabrication of active layer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1600372</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Degradation observations of encapsulated planar CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite solar cells at high temperatures and humidity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8139" to="8147" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tin oxide (SnOx) as universal &apos;light-soaking&apos; free electron extraction material for organic solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Trost</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1500277</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthesis and surface engineering of complex nanostructures by atomic layer deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Knez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Niesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Niinisto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3425" to="3438" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nucleation and growth during Al2O3 atomic layer deposition on polymers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Grubbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5625" to="5634" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of film stoichiometry on the ionization energy and electronic structure of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Emara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A transparent conductive adhesive laminate electrode for highefficiency organic-inorganic lead halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bryant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7499" to="7504" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Atomic layer deposition and characterization of vanadium oxide thin films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Blanquart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">RSC Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1179" to="1185" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic structure of vanadium pentoxide: an efficient hole injector for organic electronic materials</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zilberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">33710</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solution processed vanadium pentoxide as charge extraction layer for organic solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zilberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Trost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transition metal oxides for organic electronics: energetics, device physics and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5408" to="5427" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Achieving long-term stable perovskite solar cells via ion neutralization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Back</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energ. Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1258" to="1263" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temperature-and component-dependent degradation of perovskite photovoltaic materials under concentrated sunlight</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="326" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Light-activated photocurrent degradation and self-healing in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11574</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporation of rubidium cations into perovskite solar cells improves photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saliba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">354</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not all that glitters is gold: metal-migrationinduced degradation in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Domanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6306" to="6314" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-quality mixed-organic-cation perovskites from a phase-pure non-stoichiometric intermediate (FAI) 1 À x -PbI 2 for solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4918" to="4923" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
