<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder ref="#_Yt4cxZx">
					<orgName type="full">Ministry of Science and Technology of China</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_qdZkkVU">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_f8pAS43">
					<orgName type="full">Innovation Project of Optics Valley Laboratory</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Energy Materials</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_g4DQRtm">
					<orgName type="full">Natural Science Foundation of Hubei Province</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_deB3Yne">
					<orgName type="full">CAST</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_XwBssqV">
					<orgName type="full">Self-determined and Innovative Research Funds of HUST</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_xqJ2YKW">
					<orgName type="full">Russian Science Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_9TYZSCH #_dNrsuCH #_S83fv7k">
					<orgName type="full">National Natural Science Foundation of China</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">National Key Research and Development Project</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">CAB398E591F57384C1D49EFA857AE886</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:55+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The film stress can be calculated according to the relationship between 2θ and sin 2 φ as the following equation <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref> ：</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">σ = - E 2(1+υ) π 180 cot θ 0 ∂ (2θ ) ∂ sin 2 φ (1)</formula><p>where E and υ are Young's modulus and Poisson's ratio of the perovskite film, respectively. θ0 is the diffraction peak for strain-free perovskite crystal plane and θ is the diffraction peak for the measured perovskite films. φ is the angle of diffraction vector with respect to the sample normal direction. Here, the values of E and υ are 10200 MPa and 0.3, respectively. By fitting the 2θ as a function of sin 2 φ, we can calculate perovskite film strain from formula (1), and the slope of the fitted line stands for the scale of the residual strain, the negative slope indicates the films bear tension strain.</p><p>It is found that the δ-phase formed in the 0% DBSO sample was completely transformed into α-phase perovskite within approximately 30 s, but after annealing, the formed α-phase perovskite possesses lower diffraction peak intensity and larger halfpeak width (Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">11</ref>). By contrast, the intermediate phase in the 10% DBSO sample disappeared within approximately 10 s, while the fully annealed film shows much stronger α-phase diffraction peaks with smaller half-peak widths. This comparison highlights the important role of DBSO additive in promoting perovskite αphase crystal growth.</p><p>For XRD measurement, we prepared perovskite precursor film samples in N2</p><p>glove box and put it into a sealed chamber. Then, the samples were quickly transferred for XRD testing (The XRD instrument is in the lab on the next floor of the device fabrication lab). When annealing, the perovskite film was kept in a N2 filled small chamber and placed on a temperature controlled hotplate for different time. The annealing hotplate was placed nearby the XRD instrument. When testing, the annealed sample was quickly taken out for XRD measurement.</p><p>nature energy <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p>Reduction of bulk and surface defects in inverted methylammonium-and bromide-free formamidinium perovskite solar cells Rui Chen 1 , Jianan Wang      Power conversion efficiencies of inverted perovskite solar cells (PSCs) based on methylammonium-and bromide-free formamidinium lead triiodide (FAPbI 3 ) perovskites still lag behind PSCs with a regular configuration.</p><p>Here we improve the quality of both the bulk and surface of FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 perovskite films to reduce the efficiency gap. First, we use dibutyl sulfoxide, a Lewis base additive, to improve the crystallinity and reduce the defect density and internal residual stress of the perovskite bulk. Then, we treat the surface of the perovskite film with trifluorocarbon-modified phenethylammonium iodide to optimize the energy levels, passivate defects and protect the film against moisture. The inverted PSCs simultaneously achieve 25.1% efficiency (24.5% from the reverse current-voltage scan measured by a third-party institution) and improved stability. The devices maintained 97.4% and 98.2% of their initial power conversion efficiencies after operating under continuous 1-sun air mass 1.5 G illumination for 1,800 h and under damp heat conditions (85 °C and 85% relative humidity) for 1,000 h, respectively. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modulation of perovskite films crystal growth</head><p>First, we optimized the preparation process of FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 -based perovskite films; a small amount of caesium is introduced to stabilize the black phase of FAPbI 3 -based perovskite <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">11</ref> . We found that it is easier to prepare pin-hole free FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 -based films with DMF/NMP solvent mixture rather not the commonly used DMF/dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) in a N 2 -filled glove box (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1</ref>), which is similar to the results reported in ref. 22. Starting from the DMF/NMP solvent, we further modified it by adding DBSO (longer-chain analogue of DMSO) as a coordination agent to modulate the perovskite growth (Supplementary Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> and<ref type="table">3</ref>). The longer alkyl chains incorporated in DBSO result in its higher boiling point (250 °C versus 189 °C) and stronger electron donating power (Gutmann donor number, 31.0 versus 29.8) as compared with DMSO, which enables more stable coordination with PbI 2 than the DMSO case and also NMP case (donor number of 27.3) as demonstrated below. Such properties play an important role in control of perovskite crystal growth and defects concentration in the resultant FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 films. The effects of different DBSO additive contents (0%, 5%, 10% and 20%, molar ratio to PbI 2 ) on the morphology and crystal size of perovskite films were investigated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM). As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1a</ref>, the average grain size in the perovskite films gradually increases from 260 to 378 and 466 nm following the increase in the DBSO content from 0% to 5% and then to 10%. When the DBSO content further increases to 20%, the average crystal size slightly decreases to 432 nm (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">2</ref>). When the amount of DBSO further increases to 40%, many micron-level cracks are observed in the resultant perovskite films (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3</ref>), which may be due to DBSO residue caused by excessive addition (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4</ref>). Therefore, using an appropriate amount of DBSO is the key factor to improving the film quality.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1b</ref>,c shows the X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of the perovskite films before and after annealing with different DBSO content. As can be seen, the non-annealed precursor film with 0% DBSO exhibits a δ-phase diffraction peak at 11.8°, while the addition of DBSO inhibits the formation of δ-phase in the non-annealed films thus leading to the increased amount of α-phase perovskite with the main peak at 14.0° and a new phase with the main peak at 6.3°. Furthermore, increase in the content of DBSO from 5% to 10% and then to 20% is accompanied by the gradual increase in the XRD peak intensity of the new phase, while the peaks of α-phase perovskite gradually decay. These findings indicate that DBSO induces the formation of a new crystalline intermediate phase facilitating the formation of α-phase perovskite. The diffraction peak at 6.3° is attributed to the formation of DBSO•PbI 2 intermediate phase similar to other Lewis base-PbI 2 intermediate phases <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">23</ref> (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">5</ref>). The interactions between DBSO, PbI 2 and formamidinium iodide (FAI) are confirmed by comparing the Fourier transform infra-red (FTIR) spectra of the DBSO, DBSO•PbI 2 , FAI and FAI•PbI 2 •DBSO samples (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1d</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref> and Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>). The sulfoxide S=O bond stretching vibration peak of DBSO located at 1,028 cm -1 shifted to 968 cm -1 in the DBSO•PbI 2 sample, which is owing to the formation of dative bond by sharing the lone pair electrons in oxygen with Pb 2+ . And the C=N double bond stretching vibration peak of FAI at 1,697 cm -1 shifted to 1,712 cm -1 in the FAI•PbI 2 •DBSO sample. This phenomenon is similar to the peak shift induced by coordination between other Lewis bases to PbI 2 and FAI <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">24</ref> . Although it has been widely reported that many Lewis bases can lead to the formation of intermediate phases (for example, DMSO•PbI 2 and NMP•PbI 2 ) in the perovskite precursor films, it is noteworthy that the specific DBSO•PbI 2 intermediate phase is much more stable than NMP•PbI 2 , so it could resist the instantaneous anti-solvent extraction process (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure">7</ref><ref type="figure">8</ref><ref type="figure">9</ref>). Note that the amount of NMP in our solvent system is large, but the amount of the NMP•PbI 2 intermediate phase in the obtained non-annealed films is negligibly low after the anti-solvent washing process. Based Therefore, it is particularly urgent to improve the efficiency of inverted PSCs at the current stage.</p><p>Screening the performance optimization strategies reported for high-efficiency (&gt;25%) regular PSCs 2-6 reveals that methylammonium (MA + )-and bromide (Br -)-free formamidinium lead triiodide (FAPbI 3 )-based perovskites are commonly employed because of their ideal bandgap close to the Shockley-Queisser optimum. The resultant devices typically simultaneously demonstrate high short-circuit current density (J SC ) of ~26 mA cm <ref type="bibr">-2</ref> , and high open-circuit voltage (V OC ) of 1.17-1.19 V (Supplementary Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). The high-efficiency (&gt;24%) inverted PSCs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[14]</ref> usually incorporated FAPbI 3 as the main component with small amounts of MA + and Br -as additives, which may be beneficial for achieving higher V OC , but also lead to a slight sacrifice of J SC (Supplementary Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) due to the optical loss caused by blue-shifted absorbance. Li  with a lower V OC of 1.095 V. In addition, the introduction of MA + and Br -to FAPbI 3 could raise risk to induce problems such as low thermal stability caused by the existence of MA, phase separation caused by the presence of mixed halides, and reduced photon absorption and current density cause by Br -incorporation <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[17]</ref> . Although some recent literature reported controversal results that the incorporation of small portions of MA + , Br -in hybrid perovskites is benefit for stability improvement <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">19</ref> . FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 has been widely recognized as the most attractive material for PSCs exhibiting both high efficiencies and good thermal stability <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">20</ref> . Until now, the highest certified efficiency of inverted PSCs based on MA + -and Br --free formamidinium cesium perovskite is only 23.5% with V OC of 1.14 V (ref. 11). Thus, it is desirable to further optimize inverted PSCs based on the MA + -and Br --free formamidinium cesium perovskites. So far, key strategies implemented in those high-efficiency inverted PSCs mainly focused on optimizing interfacial materials and surface passivation of perovskite absorber films <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">21</ref> . Beyond these strategies, the management of the bulk and surface defects in perovskite films is of equal importance to achieve an efficient and stable inverted PSCs.</p><p>In this Article, we report an optimization strategy to simultaneously manage the bulk and surface defects in FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 perovskite films to enable high-performance inverted PSCs. Firstly, a low-volatile dibutyl sulfoxide (DBSO) Lewis base additive with a strong coordination ability was introduced into the N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF)/N-methyl pyrrolidone (NMP) solvent system, thus leading to the formation of a stable intermediate phase of DBSO•PbI 2 in the precursor film even after anti-solvent extraction. Such intermediate phase can suppress the formation of undesirable δ-phase FA-perovskite and modulate perovskite crystal growth. The proposed improved film fabrication strategy leads to perovskite films with larger grain size and reduced internal film stress and bulk defects. In addition, 3,5-bis(trifluoromethyl) phenethylammonium iodide (denoted as 2CF 3 -PEAI) was introduced as an interface passivator designed to simultaneously adjust interfacial energy levels, passivate surface defects of the perovskite films and stabilize the films against moisture with help from the presence of hydrophobic CF 3 groups. As a result, the devices demonstrated impressive PCEs of up to 25.1% (24.5% from reverse scan was measured by a third-party institution) owing to the use of the high-quality FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 films. Moreover, the encapsulated devices showed stable operation in air under continuous 1-sun air mass (AM) 1.5 G illumination for up to 1,800 h without notable efficiency decay and also pass the damp heat test (85 °C and 85% relative humidity (RH)) according to the international standards for mature photovoltaics (IEC61215). on the molecular structures of NMP, DBSO and PbI 2 octahedral, we used density functional theory (DFT) to calculate the interaction energy between PbI 2 and the two coordination molecules (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref>). The interaction energy between PbI 2 and DBSO (-1.42 eV) is much higher than that between PbI 2 and NMP (-1.03 eV), and also higher than the interaction energy between PbI 2 and DMSO (-1.01 eV; Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">10</ref>) due to the stronger electron donating of DBSO than the other two Lewis bases. This difference could explain why the  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characterization of the perovskite film's quality</head><p>XRD patterns of the annealed perovskite films made from different precursor solutions show that all the films transform into α-phase FA 1-x Cs x PbI 3 perovskite after annealing at 150 °C for 20 min (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1c</ref>).</p><p>With the increasing content of DBSO loading from 0% to 5% and then to 10%, the XRD peak intensity gradually increases, thus indicating the enhancement of the perovskite crystallinity. This is consistent with the increased grain size upon DBSO addition as observed by SEM. The perovskite crystal growth mechanisms can be explained by two different pathways as described in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1g</ref>. In the case of 0% DBSO sample, the δ-phase transition to α-phase occurs directly during annealing; while in the 10% DBSO sample a molecular exchange between DBSO•PbI 2 intermediate phase and FAI is controlling the α-phase crystal growth upon annealing. It has been widely reported that the intermediate phase or molecular exchange dominated crystal growth could reduce the activation energy of the perovskite crystal formation, which normally leads to larger crystalline grain size in the as-fabricated perovskite films <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">25</ref> . We also conducted XRD characterization to monitor the crystal structure evolution from the as-coated films to fully crystallized perovskite films during annealing (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">11</ref>). The obtained results further confirm the important role of the DBSO•PbI 2 intermediate phase in promoting the crystallinity of the obtained α-phase FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 films. When the DBSO content further increases to 20%, the XRD diffraction peak intensity becomes slightly lower, which is also consistent with the SEM data discussed above.</p><p>It is well known that the internal residual stress in perovskite films can promote the formation of atomic vacancies, increase non-radiative recombination, reduce carrier mobility and structural stability, and thus deteriorate the photovoltaic performance of devices <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[29]</ref> . We employed grazing incident XRD to test the residual stress at the 50 nm and 200 nm depth regions of the perovskite films obtained using different DBSO content (Supplementary Tables <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">5</ref> and<ref type="table" target="#tab_3">6</ref>). The results show that the tensile stress at 200 nm (Fig. <ref type="figure">2a</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">12</ref>) and 50 nm (Fig. <ref type="figure">2b</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">13</ref>) gradually release with the increasing DBSO content from 0% to 5% and then to 10%. In addition, Williamson-Hall analysis also confirmed that the introduction of DBSO can relax the lattice strain (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">14</ref>). This phenomenon may be related to the following two reasons <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">30</ref> : first, when DBSO•PbI 2 reacts with FAI to form perovskite, the formation energy of α-phase perovskite can be significantly reduced, thereby avoiding the formation of δ-phase nuclei in the precursor film. Thus, the tensile stress caused by cell volume shrinkage during the transformation of δ-phase to α-phase in the case of the 0% DBSO samples could be avoided (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">15a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>). Second, the tensile stress remaining at the grain boundaries due to the lattice expansion during high-temperature annealing of perovskite could be further released by reducing the number of grain boundaries when using optimal concentrations of DBSO additive (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">15c</ref>).</p><p>Steady-state photoluminescence (PL) (Fig. <ref type="figure">2c</ref>) and transient PL spectroscopy (Fig. <ref type="figure">2d</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">16</ref>) were used to evaluate the non-radiative carrier recombination behaviour of the perovskite films made from different DBSO additive content. The results show that the addition of DBSO, especially for 10% content, could effectively suppress the fast non-radiative decay component. As can be seen, benefitted from strain relaxation, the fitted carrier lifetime increases from 423 ns (0% DBSO) to 613 ns (5% DBSO) and finally to 708 ns (10% DBSO). The 20% DBSO sample has a shorter PL lifetime (525 ns), which is consistent with its reduced crystallinity (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">1c</ref>). Femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy was further used to analyse the carrier dynamics in the perovskite films with and without DBSO addition (Fig. <ref type="figure">2e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref>). It can be seen that the attenuation rate of ground-state bleaching of perovskite film decreases significantly when DBSO is added, and the single exponential kinetic model delivered the lifetimes of 9.89 ns (0% DBSO) and 32.56 ns (10% DBSO) (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">17</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">32</ref> , which again verified the decrease in defect density within the DBSO-based films. The above results consistently show that using appropriate DBSO loading can effectively release residual stress within the film and reduce defect density due to the ability of this additive to modulate the perovskite crystal growth. These effects inhibit the non-radiative recombination of charge carriers and improve the carrier lifetime.</p><p>To optimize the content of DBSO, we prepared inverted PSCs with the ITO/p-PY/FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 /PCBM/bathocuproine (BCP)/Ag configuration; the typical cross-sectional SEM image of the device is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">18</ref>. p-PY is an efficient and stable hole transport material incorporating pyridine core functionalized with poly(triarylamine) units as we reported recently <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">34</ref> . Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">19</ref> shows the current density-voltage (J-V) curves of the devices based on the perovskite films with different DBSO content. It can be seen that PCE reaches the highest values when DBSO content is close to 10% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">20</ref>). As compared with the reference 0% DBSO samples, J SC of the 10% DBSO device increases from 24.88 mA cm -2 to 25.68 mA cm -2 , V OC increases from 1.024 V to 1.091 V, fill factor (FF) increases from 0.792 to 0.805, and PCE increases from 20.2% to 22.6% (Supplementary Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">7</ref>). The improved device performance is assigned to the reduced defect density and improved carrier lifetimes caused by the use of DBSO additive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of the surface passivation</head><p>In addition to the reduction of bulk defects within the perovskite films by using DBSO additive engineering, we designed phenylethylammonium iodide (PEAI) derivatives containing different fluorocarbon (CF 3 ) functional groups as surface modification reagents to further passivate the defects in the perovskite films. Molecular structures of the PEAI derivatives CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3a</ref>. Top-view SEM images revealed that the surface morphology of the perovskite films after modifications with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI did not change significantly (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">21</ref>), which is consistent with the recent report <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">35</ref> . To further identify the states of above passivators on the perovskite, we performed TA spectroscopy of the perovskite films treated with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI to accurately identify whether 2D phase perovskites were formed in the corresponding perovskite films (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">22</ref>). Both perovskite films showed the characteristic peaks at about 580 nm belonging to n = 2 low-dimensional perovskites <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">21</ref> , which could block minority carriers from the interface/surface <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">36</ref> .</p><p>From the viewpoint of molecular engineering, the CF 3 electron-withdrawing groups could adjust the passivators' molecular dipole moment and hydrophobicity, whereas the size difference among the PEA + , CF 3 -PEA + and 2CF 3 -PEA + cations may also influence their diffusion depths into the bulk of perovskite films. To study this point, we conducted time-of-flight secondary-ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) measurements on the films (based on F signals; Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3e</ref>). We also used F-PEA + to substitute PEA + by deliberately introducing F element but not significantly affect the size of organic cation. It is found that 2CF 3 -PEA + cations show the shallowest diffusion depth and F-PEA + cations show the deepest diffusion depth. This observation is due to the 2CF 3 -PEA + cation having the largest steric hindrance effect, impeding its inward diffusion. This was also confirmed by the X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) depth profiles (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">23</ref>). The distribution of passivator is considered to affect the surface electrical properties and chemical stability of the films.</p><p>To study the surface electrical properties of perovskite films with different passivator, the electrostatic potentials (φ max ) of PEA, CF 3 -PEA and 2CF 3 -PEA were characterized, which were determined to be 183.39, 187.19 and 189.42 kcal mol -1 , respectively. 2CF 3 -PEA has the largest electrostatic potential, that is, the highest dipole moment Article <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref> </p><p>among the three molecules due to the presence of two CF 3 groups with strong electron-withdrawing ability. The electric field generated by the interfacial dipole can change the vacuum energy level and work function of the adjacent material <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[37]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[39]</ref> . We further studied this issue by ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">24</ref>) and ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectroscopy (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">25</ref>) measurements. Work functions of the pristine perovskite films and the films treated with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI or 2CF 3 -PEAI are estimated as 4.83, 4.69, 4.61 and 4.58 eV, respectively (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3b</ref>). This is almost consistent with the evolution of the film surface potentials measured by Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) for the above four conditions (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">26</ref>). The energy level of PCBM was obtained according to previous report <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">40</ref> . The introduction of an extra back-surface field is an effective way to improve device's V OC , which is widely applied in crystalline silicon solar cells and has recently been demonstrated in high-efficiency PSCs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">37</ref> . The extra back electric field caused by the stronger dipole moment of the surface modifiers may be an important factor enabling the device's higher V OC in this work. According to previous reports <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">42</ref> , the terminal group of CF 3 has a strong electron-withdrawing ability, making CF 3 capable of forming a hydrogen bond with the amino group in FA + and reducing the generation of A-site vacancies, thus improving the performance of the device. In addition, the surface passivation of the perovskite absorber films with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI can bring additional functions such as compensation of the loss of I -ions during the annealing process and chelation of the exposed undercoordinated Pb 2+ ions <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">44</ref> .</p><p>The effect of passivators on the carrier dynamic of perovskite films was further studied. Transient PL (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3c</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">27</ref>) and steady-state PL (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">28</ref>) spectra show that the non-radiative recombination becomes further inhibited and the fitted PL lifetime is increased from 0.7 (pristine) to 1.1 (PEAI), 1.4 (CF 3 -PEAI) and 1.6 µs (2CF 3 -PEAI), respectively, after the corresponding surface  passivation. This tendency indicates that 2CF 3 -PEAI enables the best surface passivation effect among the three studied passivators. The transient PL lifetime (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3d</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">29</ref>) of the perovskite/PCBM stacks reflects the difference in interfacial charge transfer rate after the surface passivation. In principle, the Shockley-Read-Hall lifetime as extracted from the slower decay (τ 2 ) is related to the important interfacial recombination <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">45</ref> . The 2CF 3 -PEAI-treated perovskite films show longer lifetime at the same excitation condition, which indicates that 2CF 3 -PEAI enables the best surface passivation effect among the three studied passivators. The obtained results show that the PL lifetime is increased from 21.3 (pristine) to 38.9 (PEAI), 34.6 (CF 3 -PEAI) and finally to 23.5 ns (2CF 3 -PEAI). In comparison with their strongly positive effect on carrier lifetimes within the perovskite absorber films, the modification has negligible impact on the resultant devices' J SC 37 . The lowest 2D perovskite signals in 2CF 3 -PEAI sample indicates that the introduction of two CF 3 groups could suppress the formation of 2D perovskite, which may be helpful for defect passivation.</p><p>The above results confirm that 2CF 3 -PEAI possesses the best surface defects passivation capability, which might be related to its shallowest diffusion depth as compared with other studied organic cations <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">46</ref> . The loss of iodine caused by thermal annealing mainly happens at the surface of the perovskite film. Thus, 2CF 3 -PEAI with its low diffusion depth could enrich the perovskite surface with iodide thus leading to efficient defect passivation. The large size of 2CF 3 -PEAI also prevents its deep diffusion into the interior of the film, which could destroy the ideal three-dimensional (3D) perovskite lattice. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref> </p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3f</ref> shows the external quantum efficiencies of electroluminescence (EQE-EL) of PSCs based on the perovskite films with different passivators. It is well known that V OC of a solar cell is directly related to its internal luminescence efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">44</ref> . In this case, when the injection current density is set to the value equal to J SC under solar illumination, EQE-EL of the pristine device is 0.2%. EQE-EL of the PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI surface passivated devices were shown to be 0.8%, 1.5% and 5.2%, respectively. Based on the formula ΔV OC = k B T/qln(EQE passivation / EQE pristine ) <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">44</ref> , it can be estimated that the V OC improvement after surface passivation with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI are 36, 52 and 84 mV, respectively. The tendency is well consistent with the experimentally observed V OC variation in the devices discussed below. To quantify the V OC potential for every individual stack, we calculated the internal electron-hole quasi-Fermi level splitting from PLQY results (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">30</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">31</ref>) according to previous method <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">48</ref> , which indicated effectively suppressing non-radiative recombination by interface passivation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Performance and stability of PSCs</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4a</ref> shows the J-V curves of the p-i-n PSCs without and with different surface passivation. It was observed that J SC does not change significantly and the enhancement of PCE associated with the surface passivation is mainly due to the increase in V OC and FF (Supplementary Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">8</ref>). The champion PCE reached for the 2CF 3 -PEAI passivated device was 25.1%, with a J SC of 25.88 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.176 V and an FF of 0.825, while the hysteresis effect was negligible (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">32</ref>). The steady-state PCE of the device was 25.0% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">33</ref>), which is very close to the PCE obtained from the reverse voltage sweep J-V curve. EQE spectrum of the corresponding device is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">34</ref>. The integral short circuit current density calculated from the EQE spectrum is 25.74 mA cm -2 , which is nearly identical to the J SC value extracted from J-V measurements. We also sent one of the best devices to a credible third-party organization and got a certified efficiency of 24.5%, with J SC of 25.75 mA cm -2 , V OC of 1.167 V and FF of 0.815 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">35</ref>). Furthermore, the device performance was very well reproducible (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4b</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">36</ref>). Although the efficiency of the fabricated devices is still a little bit lower than that of the best regular PSCs, the measured operation lifetime of our inverted PSCs is much longer. This indicates the potential advantage of inverted PSCs in simultaneously achieving high efficiency and long-term operational stability.</p><p>Besides the impact on photovoltaic performance, defects also considerably affect device operational stability because defect sites disrupt the original lattice arrangement and thus change the thermodynamic energy of the perovskite decomposition and phase change <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">49</ref> .</p><p>To study the influence of our defects management strategy on the device stability, we monitored the long-term ageing behaviour of the encapsulated devices based on different passivators using maximum power point tracking (MPPT) under continuous AM 1.5 G 100 mW cm -2 illumination in ambient air (cell temperature 50 ± 5 °C, 50 ± 5% RH) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4c</ref>). The device based on pristine perovskite films (initial PCE 21.4%) degraded to 67.2% of its initial PCE after 780 h. The PEAI and CF 3 -PEAI passivated devices (initial PCEs of 22.3% and 23.6%, respectively) degraded correspondingly to 72.3% and 82.1% of their initial PCEs after 1,800 h. The 2CF 3 -PEAI passivated device (initial PCE 24.5%) still retained 97.4% of the initial PCE after 1,800 h; the screen capture image demonstrating its continuous power output within almost the entire testing time is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">37</ref>. Since the defects at surface and grain boundaries are the active sites where perovskites have loose chemical binding, which facilitate severe ion migration and degradation, the most effective passivation of 2CF 3 -PEAI and the highest surface hydrophobicity (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4c</ref>) are considered as the main reason for operational stability improvement. This is further supported by the highest activation energy of perovskite degradation of 2CF 3 -PEAI passivation versus the other passivator (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">38</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">39</ref>).</p><p>The higher hydrophobicity of the 2CF 3 -PEAI modified samples could minimize the effect of the absorbed water and oxygen on the stability of encapsulated PSCs. The highest stability of the 2CF 3 -PEAI passivated perovskite films can be further proved by the in situ PL measurements combined with laser light ageing (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">40</ref>).</p><p>It should be emphasized that other important factor enabling that improved device operational stability is the elimination of MA + cations and Br -anions from the perovskite absorber composition as discussed above. Indeed, comparing the stability of the PSCs based on conventional MAPbI 3 and Cs 0.15 FA 0.85 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 perovskite films and the introduced here FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 absorber formulations processed using 0% or 5% DBSO additive with 2CF 3 -PEAI passivation features the importance of several complementary parameters required to reach long operational lifetimes (Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">41</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">42</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">43</ref>). Thus, the superior operational stability of the PSCs reported here is the result of multifactorial comprehensive optimization involving the proper selection of univalent cations (FA + and Cs + ), halide anions (I -only systems), solvent and intermediate phase engineering as well as designing efficient passivation coatings.</p><p>In addition to the enhanced operational lifetime, the damp heat stability of the devices has also been tested in accordance with IEC61215 standard. The 2CF 3 -PEAI treated devices (average initial PCE of 24.8%) could retain 98.2% of their initial performance after ageing at 85 °C/85% RH for 1,000 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">4d</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">44</ref>). Meanwhile, the devices based on pristine perovskite films and the films with PEAI and CF 3 -PEAI passivation coatings degraded under the same ageing conditions to 71.3%, 87.2% and 91.1% of their initial PCEs, respectively. These results further confirm the notable impact of a close-to-ideal perovskite film with the lowest defect density, reduced internal residue stress and higher surface hydrophobicity on the device's stability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>In summary, we report the strategy to improve the quality of both bulk and surface of FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 perovskite films to enable high-performance inverted PSCs. First, we use a low-volatile DBSO Lewis base additive with a strong coordination ability to improve the crystallinity, reduce the defect density and internal residual stress of the perovskite bulk. Then, 2CF 3 -PEAI was introduced as an interface passivator designed to optimize the energy levels, passivate defects and protect the film against moisture. The inverted PSCs achieve 25.1% efficiency and improved stability. The devices maintained 97.4% and 98.2% of their initial PCEs after operating under continuous 1-sun AM 1.5 G illumination for 1,800 h and under the damp heat conditions (85 °C and 85% RH) for 1,000 h. This work not only provides a novel avenue to engineer efficient and stable inverted PSCs, but also deepens the understanding of the correlation between the device performance to the MA + -and Br --free perovskite bulk and surface properties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>p-PY was synthesized according to our previous report <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">33</ref> . Lead (II) iodide (PbI 2 , 99.99%), caesium iodide (&gt;99.0%), FAI (99.99%) and BCP (&gt;99%) were purchased from Tokyo Chemical Industry. PCBM was purchased from Lumtec. The organic halide salts (PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI) were synthesized according to the method similar to the reported for PEAI in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">50</ref> . All other chemicals were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich and used as received. Silver and bismuth with high purity (99.99%) were purchased from Sino-Platinum Metals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The preparation of adduct powders</head><p>For the PbI 2 •NMP adduct, 461 mg PbI 2 was dissolved in 654 mg NMP and stirred at 45 °C for 12 h before use. Then 400 µl solution was spin-coated onto glass substrate (5 × 5 cm 2 ) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 150 s. The film was peeled off by a knife and dried at 60 °C in a vacuum oven for 2 h; the obtained material was used for FTIR and XRD measurements. For the FAI•PbI 2 •NMP adduct, 172 mg FAI and 461 mg PbI 2 were dissolved in 654 mg NMP and stirred at 45 °C for 12 h before use. Then 400 µl solution was spin-coated onto glass substrate (5 × 5 cm 2 ) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 150 s. The film was peeled off by a knife and dried at 50 °C in a vacuum oven for 2 h; the material was used for FTIR measurement.</p><p>For the PbI 2 •DBSO adduct, 461 mg PbI 2 and 82.1 mg DBSO were dissolved in 600 mg DMF and stirred at 45 °C for 12 h before using. Then 400 µl solution was spin-coated onto glass substrate (5 × 5 cm 2 ) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 150 s. The film was peeled off by a knife and dried at 80 °C in a vacuum oven for 3 h; the collected material was used for FTIR and XRD measurements.</p><p>For the FAI•PbI 2 •DBSO adduct, 172 mg FAI and 461 mg PbI 2 and 82.1 mg DBSO were dissolved in 600 mg DMF and stirred at 45 °C for 12 h before using. Then 400 µl solution was spin-coated onto glass substrate (5 × 5 cm 2 ) at 1,000 r.p.m. for 150 s. The film was peeled off by a knife and dried at 80 °C in vacuum oven for 3 h; the collected material was used for FTIR measurement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Device fabrication</head><p>Glass/ITO substrates (15 Ω sq -1 ) were consecutively cleaned by sequential ultrasonication for 20 min with detergent solution, de-ionized water, ethyl alcohol and isopropanol. The cleaned substrates were dried with high-pressure N 2 gas flow, and then were cleaned by UV-ozone treatment for 30 min and finally transferred into a N 2 -filled glove box before use. The p-PY solution was prepared with a concentration of 0.5 mg ml -1 in CHCl 3 . The as-prepared p-PY solution was spin-coated onto the ITO substrates at 1,500 r.p.m. for 30 s, and the substrates were subsequently annealed at 100 °C for 10 min. The FA 0.98 Cs 0.02 PbI 3 perovskite precursor solution was prepared by dissolving 252.8 mg FAI, </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref> </p><p>691.5 mg PbI 2 and 7.8 mg caesium iodide in 1 ml DMF:NMP (6:1 by volume ratio). To prepare the precursor solutions with DBSO (5-20 mol% with respect to PbI 2 ), the additive was added to the DMF: NMP precursor solution. Then the perovskite solution was spin-coated on the substrate at 5,000 r.p.m. for 60 s. At the 12th second of spinning, 500 µl of ethyl acetate was dripped onto the substrate centre. The as-coated precursor films were subsequently annealed on a hotplate at 150 °C for 20 min. Then 100 µl of PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI or 2CF 3 -PEAI (1 mg ml -1 in IPA) were spin-coated onto the as-prepared perovskite films at a speed of 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s; the films were subsequently dried at 100 °C for 5 min. Then a chlorobenzene solution of PCBM (20 mg ml -1 ) was spin-coated on top of the perovskite films (passivated or not) at the rotation speed of 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s and heated at 70 °C for 10 min. In the final step, BCP (8 nm) and Ag (80 nm) were deposited in high vacuum (pressure below 5 × 10 -4 Pa) while finely controlling the evaporation rate at 0.1, 0.1 and 0.1-0.5 Å s -1 , respectively. The Bi/Ag (20 nm/80 nm) electrodes in the devices used for stability tests were thermally evaporated with a controlled evaporation rate of 0.1 and 0.1-0.5 Å s -1 , respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational details</head><p>The calculation model is to calculate the adsorption energy of DBSO, NMP and DMSO on the surface of PbI 2 to characterize the interaction strength between different molecules and PbI 2 . Specifically, the adsorption energy can be obtained by using the following formula: The first-principles calculations were carried out by using the projector-augmented wave representations with DFT as implemented in the Vienna ab-initio simulation package <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[51]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[52]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[53]</ref> . The exchange and correlation energy were approximated by the spin-polarized generalize-gradient-approximation with Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof formula <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">54</ref> . Wave functions were expanded in plane waves up to a kinetic energy cut-off of 500 eV. Γ-centred k-meshes grids of 2 × 2 × 1 was used for slab calculations. To treat the van der Waals interactions, DFT-D3 correction method of Grimme was used <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">55</ref> . All structures were fully relaxed until the force on each atom was smaller than 0.01 eV/Å.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">△E = E PbI 2 ⋅DBSO -E PbI 2</formula><p>The electrostatic potentials (φ) of the passivators were calculated using the Gaussian 09 package at the B3LYP/def2TZVP level with DFT-D3 (ref. 56). The maximum φ (φ max ) of the NH 3 + terminal group in these passivators was obtained with the help of Multiwfn code.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characterizations</head><p>KPFM measurements were conducted using a dimension icon scanning probe microscope (Asylum Research, MFP-3D-Stand Alone) in the tapping mode. KPFM measurements were carried out using an atomic force microscopy under ambient conditions, using a gold-coated Si tip. The KPFM measurement was implemented using a two-path method at a scan rate of 0.5 Hz, where the first pass in every scan line was used to determine the topography and the following second pass was used to measure the contact potential difference between the tip and the sample. The second pass was scanned by raising the tip at a fixed 20 nm height above the sample following the topography. Each set of samples was arranged in proximity on a common substrate and was measured using the same tip and scanning parameters. SEM images were obtained using a Nova NanoSEM 450 scanning electron microscope (FEI). An XPS system (Thermo ESCALAB 250XI) was used to acquire the XPS spectra. UPS spectra were acquired using a Thermo ESCALAB 250XI instrument equipped with a 1 He ultraviolet radiation source (21.22 eV). The both UPS and KPFM are surface-sensitive measurements. The crystal structure of the films was characterized using XRD with an Empyrean X-ray diffractometer with Cu Kα radiation (PANalytical B.V.). The UV-vis spectra of perovskite films were obtained using a Lambda 950 UV-vis spectrophotometer (PerkinElmer). The steady-state PL spectra were recorded using an Edinburgh FLS920 fluorescence spectrometer (Edinburgh) with an excitation source wavelength of 532 nm. The transient fluorescence spectroscopy (TRPL) measurements were conducted using a fluorescence spectrometer with an excitation wavelength of 478 nm (DeltaFlex, Horiba), and the excitation pulse has a repetition rate of 100 kHz with a spot size of 100 µm. The applied excitation fluences were varied between 8.9 nJ cm -2 and 56.3 nJ cm -2 by using neutral density filters. the TRPL profiles were fitted by a bi-exponential decay rate model according to the following function: y = A 1 exp(-t/τ 1 ) + A 2 exp(-t/τ 2 ) + y 0, where τ 1 and τ 2 are the lifetimes for the fast and slow decays, respectively. The femtosecond transient absorption measurements were performed on a Helios spectrometer (Ultrafast Systems) pumped by a Ti:sapphire regenerative amplifier (Legend Elite, Coherent) operating at 5 kHz with fundamental wavelength of 800 nm and pulse width of ~40 fs. Briefly, the 800 nm output pulse by a Ti:sapphire regenerative amplifier was split in two parts. One part was used to pump a TOPAS Optical Parametric Amplifier (Light Conversion), which generates a wavelength-tunable laser pulse from 250 nm to 2.5 µm as pump beam. Another part was attenuated with a neutral density filter and focused into sapphire window to generate a white light continuum (420 nm to 840 nm) used for probe beam. The delay between the pump and probe pulses was controlled by a motorized delay stage. The pump pulses were chopped by a synchronized chopper at 500 Hz, and the absorbance change was calculated with two adjacent probe pulses (pump-blocked and pump-unblocked). All experiments were performed at room temperature. The transient absorption test of perovskite films without DBSO and with 10% DBSO is performed with incident wavelength of 520 nm and incident light excitation power of 0.3 µW. The repetition rate of the TA system is 5,000 Hz, and the diameter of the pump beam spot is 100 µm. Considering that the perovskite film has a high absorption coefficient, to detect the transmitted light more clearly, in all the transient absorption tests, we dilute the perovskite solution to 0.75 M to prepare samples. When we are using 0.3 µW excitation power, we did not observe the signal of 2D perovskite phase due to the small excitation power. To demonstrate the formation of 2D perovskite phase on the surface of perovskite. Keeping other test conditions unchanged, we increased the power to 15 µW to observe that the perovskite films were modified with PEAI, CF 3 -PEAI and 2CF 3 -PEAI.</p><p>Photovoltaic measurements were carried out using a black mask with an aperture area of 0.09 cm 2 under standard AM 1.5 G simulated illumination (Oriel, model 9119), and the simulated light intensity was calibrated with a silicon photodiode (KG3, Enlitech). The PLQY was carried out via exciting the corresponding samples by a 405 nm laser inside an integrated sphere. The laser intensity was adjusted to 1 sun equivalent intensity using a PSC to obtain a current density at 0 V equal to its J SC . TOF-SIMS measurements were performed using a TOF-SIMS V instrument (IONTOF GmbH, 170 Cameca IMS 4F). The EQE spectra were obtained with EQE system (Saifan) using monochromatic light of 1 × 10 16 photons cm -2 in direct current mode. The EQE-EL spectra were recorded by a light emitting diode PL quantum-yield measurement system (Shenzhen Puyan Internet Technology) equipped with Keithley 2400 Source Measurement Unit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Encapsulation</head><p>For PSC encapsulation, the devices were firstly encapsulated by atomic-layer-deposited Al 2 O 3 thin films with the thickness of approximately 20 nm according to our previous report <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">9</ref> . Then the tinned copper ribbons were soldered to the electrodes of the devices to extend the connections. And the device was encapsulated by a cover glass with edges sealed by butyl tape with 1 cm in width. The stack was vacuum laminated in an industrial laminator at 120 °C for 20 min.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stability tests</head><p>For the stability tests, a thin film of Bi with a thickness of 20 nm was inserted before the deposition of Ag, which could enhance the</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Supplementary Figure 14 :Supplementary Figure 17 :</head><label>1417</label><figDesc>Williamson-Hall plots obtained from XRD patterns of the perovskite films without and with 10% DBSO in Figure 1c. TA spectra at selected probe times of the perovskite films. (A) without and (B) with 10% DBSO. (C) The bleach recovery kinetics for the corresponding perovskite films following the excitation at probe wavelength (786 nm).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Supplementary Figure 19 :</head><label>19</label><figDesc>Performance of the devices. J-V curves of the champion devices with different DBSO additive content measured in reverse (dashed line) and forward (solid line) voltage sweeping modes. Supplementary Figure 22: TA spectra of perovskite films after passivation. (A) PEAI, (B) CF3-PEAI and (C) 2CF3-PEAI.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Supplementary Figure 31 :</head><label>31</label><figDesc>PLQY and QFLS diagram for perovskite films, perovskite/PCBM half stack with/without passivators.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1 | Modulation of perovskite films crystal growth. a, Top-view SEM images of the perovskite films processed from the precursor solutions with different DBSO additive content. Scale bars, 500 nm. b,c, XRD patterns of the non-annealed perovskite precursor films (b) and the films annealed at 150 °C for 20 min (c). α and δ indicate the black phase and the yellow phase, respectively. d, FTIR spectra of the power samples of DBSO (red), PbI 2 •DBSO (blue), FAI (orange) and FAI•PbI 2 •DBSO (green). e, Interaction energy of NMP, DMSO and DBSO with PbI 2 . f, Schematic diagram of interaction between NMP, DBSO and PbI 2 . g, Schematic diagram showing two different crystal growth pathways of the films processed with or without DBSO additive.</figDesc><graphic coords="74,436.61,506.80,120.96,120.84" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>2 Fig. 2 |</head><label>22</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 | Characterization of the perovskite film's quality. a,b, Residual strain distribution analysis of the film regions with depths of 50 nm (a) and 200 nm (b) from the surface by linear fitting of 2θ - sin 2 φ for the perovskite films processed with different DBSO loading. c, Steady-state PL spectra of the perovskite films with different DBSO additive content (0%, 5%, 10% and 20%) deposited on</figDesc><graphic coords="76,149.54,356.93,139.50,115.79" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3 | The effects of perovskite surface passivation. a, Molecular structures of the three investigated passivators: PEA, CF 3 -PEA and 2CF 3 -PEA. Corresponding Gaussian calculated electrostatic potentials (φ) are shown. The right colour bar from red to blue marks the increase in electropositivity. b, Energy levels of valence band maximum (VBM) and conduction band minimum (CBM) derived from UPS spectra of the pristine and PEAI-, CF 3 -PEAI-and 2CF 3 -PEAI-treated perovskite films. c,d, Transient PL spectra for the glass/perovskite samples (c) and time-resolved PL spectra of the glass/perovskite/PCBM stacks (d). The excitation fluence of TRPL spectra is 15.8 nJ cm -2 . Included are the extracted lifetimes fitted with a bi-exponential decay function for c and d. e, TOF-SIMS characterization to detect the diffusion depths of 2CF 3 -PEAI and CF 3 -PEAI, F-PEAI into 3D perovskite films. f, EQE-EL measurements for the series of PSCs assembled without and with different passivation coatings. The inset shows the device with visible red emission. The area is about 0.3 cm × 0.3 cm.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Articlehttps://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Fig. 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4 | Photovoltaic performance and operational stability of PSCs. a, J-V curves of the best-performing devices with and without surface passivation. b, Histogram showing the PCE distributions of the compared four types of devices. c, Operational stability of the encapsulated PSCs under MPPT, AM 1.5 G, 100 mW cm -2 continuous illumination. P 0 denotes the initial PCE.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,90.00,92.27,415.30,365.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="4,167.15,75.15,260.80,195.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="6,155.15,79.30,284.30,219.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="8,90.00,75.42,415.30,336.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="9,138.05,83.00,276.85,189.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="13,163.85,78.90,267.60,188.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="17,90.15,72.70,414.70,216.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="18,90.00,74.55,415.30,322.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="21,138.30,79.67,318.70,234.23" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="22,102.65,73.62,390.00,308.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="25,90.00,74.25,415.30,151.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="27,90.00,79.52,415.30,125.35" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="31,91.15,76.80,413.00,161.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="38,134.93,76.27,325.45,256.65" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="39,90.00,77.65,402.05,144.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="41,102.57,73.20,390.15,294.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="43,90.00,79.80,414.70,155.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="44,90.00,78.30,415.30,158.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="45,90.00,78.30,415.30,158.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Overview of the best-performing regular and inverted PSCs with high certified efficiencies (regular &gt;25%, inverted &gt;23%). Certified performance parameters, perovskite and solvent compositions, and the operation lifetimes are featured.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Supplementary Ref 1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell></cell><cell>4</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>6</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>This work</cell></row><row><cell>Thermal</cell><cell>stability</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>T80=1000 h</cell><cell>(60℃/20 RH)</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">T94=850 h (85 ℃/85 RH)</cell><cell cols="2">T92=2200 h (N2, 85 ℃)</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>T95=1000 h (85 ℃/85 RH)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>T98=1000 h (85 ℃/85 RH)</cell></row><row><cell>Measured</cell><cell>operation</cell><cell>lifetime</cell><cell>T88=350 h</cell><cell></cell><cell>T85=450 h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>T90=500 h</cell><cell></cell><cell>T87=2400 h</cell><cell></cell><cell>T90=1000 h</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>T98=1500 h</cell><cell>T92=500 h</cell><cell>T97=1800 h</cell></row><row><cell>Certified</cell><cell>PCE</cell><cell>(%)</cell><cell>25.4</cell><cell></cell><cell>25.2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25.5</cell><cell></cell><cell>25.37</cell><cell></cell><cell>23.5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">22.6 (uncertified ) 24.3</cell><cell>23.9</cell><cell>24.5</cell></row><row><cell>FF</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.820</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.818</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.832</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.838</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.786</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.812</cell><cell>0.806</cell><cell>0.835</cell><cell>0.805</cell></row><row><cell>VOC</cell><cell>(V)</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.174</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.174</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.189</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.160</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.140</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.095</cell><cell>1.179</cell><cell>1.150</cell><cell>1.176</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">JSC (mA</cell><cell>cm -2 )</cell><cell>26.38</cell><cell></cell><cell>26.25</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25.74</cell><cell></cell><cell>26.10</cell><cell></cell><cell>26.30</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25.38</cell><cell>25.59</cell><cell>24.90</cell><cell>25.88</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">key improvements</cell><cell></cell><cell>quantum dot-SnO2</cell><cell>layers</cell><cell>pseudo-halide</cell><cell>anion formate</cell><cell>additive</cell><cell>Cl-bonded SnO2</cell><cell>interlayer</cell><cell>reactive surface</cell><cell>engineering</cell><cell>Hexamethyldisil</cell><cell>athiane surface</cell><cell>modification</cell><cell>FcTc2 surface</cell><cell>modification</cell><cell>2D/3D heterostructures</cell><cell>Systematic</cell><cell>defect passivation</cell></row><row><cell>Solvents</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell>DMF/ DMSO</cell><cell>DMF/NMP/</cell><cell>DBSO</cell></row><row><cell>Perovskite</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>FAPbI3</cell><cell></cell><cell>Fo-FAPbI3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>FAPbI3:0.38MDACl2</cell><cell></cell><cell>Rb0.05Cs0.05MA0.05FA0.85</cell><cell>Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3</cell><cell>Cs0.05FA0.95PbI3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>FAPbI3</cell><cell>(FA0.98MA0.02)0.95Pb(I0.98Br0.02)3</cell><cell>Cs0.05FA0.85MA0.1PbI3</cell><cell>Cs0.02FA0.98PbI3</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Device Structure</cell><cell></cell><cell>Regular</cell><cell></cell><cell>Regular</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Regular</cell><cell></cell><cell>Inverted</cell><cell></cell><cell>Inverted</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Inverted</cell><cell></cell><cell>Inverted</cell><cell>Inverted</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparison of molecular structures, physical appearance, boiling points and vapor pressures of NMP, DMSO and DBSO.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Solvent/additive</cell><cell>N-Methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP)</cell><cell>Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO)</cell><cell>Dibutyl Sulfoxide (DBSO)</cell></row><row><cell>Molecular structures</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Character (20 °C)</cell><cell>Liquid (volatile)</cell><cell>Liquid (volatile)</cell><cell>Crystalline powder (non-volatile)</cell></row><row><cell>Boiling point (°C)</cell><cell>202-204</cell><cell>189</cell><cell>250</cell></row><row><cell>Vapor pressure at 20 °C (Pa)</cell><cell>38.7</cell><cell>55.3</cell><cell>4.6</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The slope of the residual strain fitting line and strain values for the perovskite films with 0%, 5% and 10% DBSO additive content at the depth of 50 nm and 200 nm.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Depth (nm)</cell><cell>Films</cell><cell>Slope</cell><cell>Strain (MPa)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.275</cell><cell>66.542</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell>5% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.110</cell><cell>26.617</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>10% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.020</cell><cell>4.839</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.352</cell><cell>85.173</cell></row><row><cell>200</cell><cell>5% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.140</cell><cell>33.876</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>10% DBSO</cell><cell>-0.022</cell><cell>5.323</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Instrument angles (Ψ, ω, Φ) setting parameters of GIXRD residual strain gradient measurement.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Depth (nm)</cell><cell>(hkl)</cell><cell>Ψ (°)</cell><cell>ω (°)</cell><cell>Φ (°)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>15</cell><cell>0.3213</cell><cell>-43.0644</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25</cell><cell>0.3427</cell><cell>-56.8029</cell></row><row><cell>50</cell><cell>(012)</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>0.3796</cell><cell>-64.3174</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>40</cell><cell>0.4063</cell><cell>-66.8129</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>45</cell><cell>0.4406</cell><cell>-68.7708</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>15</cell><cell>1.8932</cell><cell>-46.2691</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25</cell><cell>2.0273</cell><cell>-59.8863</cell></row><row><cell>200</cell><cell>(012)</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>2.2617</cell><cell>-67.2275</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>40</cell><cell>2.4333</cell><cell>-69.7122</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>45</cell><cell>2.6573</cell><cell>-71.7264</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Summary on the key photovoltaic parameters of PSCs with different DBSO additive content.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>JSC</cell><cell>VOC</cell><cell>FF</cell><cell>PCE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(mA cm -2 )</cell><cell>(V)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(%)</cell></row><row><cell>0% Forward Scan</cell><cell>24.67</cell><cell>1.016</cell><cell>0.785</cell><cell>19.7</cell></row><row><cell>0% Reverse Scan</cell><cell>24.88</cell><cell>1.024</cell><cell>0.792</cell><cell>20.2</cell></row><row><cell>5% Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.19</cell><cell>1.039</cell><cell>0.797</cell><cell>20.9</cell></row><row><cell>5% Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.35</cell><cell>1.043</cell><cell>0.805</cell><cell>21.3</cell></row><row><cell>10% Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.57</cell><cell>1.085</cell><cell>0.801</cell><cell>22.2</cell></row><row><cell>10% Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.68</cell><cell>1.091</cell><cell>0.806</cell><cell>22.6</cell></row><row><cell>20% Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.14</cell><cell>1.049</cell><cell>0.786</cell><cell>20.7</cell></row><row><cell>20% Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.24</cell><cell>1.058</cell><cell>0.792</cell><cell>21.1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Summary on the key photovoltaic parameters of PSCs based on the pristine perovskite film and the films treated with PEAI, CF3-PEAI and 2CF3-PEAI.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>JSC</cell><cell>VOC</cell><cell>FF</cell><cell>PCE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(mA cm -2 )</cell><cell>(V)</cell><cell></cell><cell>(%)</cell></row><row><cell>Pristine Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.57</cell><cell>1.085</cell><cell>0.801</cell><cell>22.2</cell></row><row><cell>Pristine Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.68</cell><cell>1.091</cell><cell>0.806</cell><cell>22.6</cell></row><row><cell>PEAI Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.67</cell><cell>1.123</cell><cell>0.809</cell><cell>23.3</cell></row><row><cell>PEAI Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.74</cell><cell>1.128</cell><cell>0.812</cell><cell>23.6</cell></row><row><cell>CF3-PEAI Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.78</cell><cell>1.135</cell><cell>0.813</cell><cell>23.8</cell></row><row><cell>CF3-PEAI Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.83</cell><cell>1.139</cell><cell>0.818</cell><cell>24.1</cell></row><row><cell>2CF3-PEAI Forward Scan</cell><cell>25.84</cell><cell>1.174</cell><cell>0.821</cell><cell>24.9</cell></row><row><cell>2CF3-PEAI Reverse Scan</cell><cell>25.88</cell><cell>1.176</cell><cell>0.825</cell><cell>25.1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1  </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>1,2 , Fumeng Ren 1 , Sanwan Liu 1 , Jing Zhou 1 , Haixin Wang 1 , Xin Meng 1 , Zheng Zhang</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1  </figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>, Xinyu Guan 1 , Wenxi Liang 1 , Pavel A. Troshin 3,4,5 , Yabing Qi 6 , Liyuan Han 7 &amp; Wei Chen</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>1,2</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Federal Research Center for Problems of Chemical Physics and Medicinal Chemistry of Russian Academy of Sciences, Chernogolovka, Russia.</figDesc><table><row><cell>The certified power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells (PSCs) with the regular (n-i-p) structure has reached 25.7% (ref. 1), approaching that of the mature mono-crystalline silicon solar cells. The regular PSCs with high certified efficiencies of &gt;25% are mainly based on organic hole transport material such as doped 2,2′,7,7′-tetrakis[N,N-bis(p-methoxyphenyl)amino]-9,9′-spirobifluorene (spiro-OMeTAD) 2-6 . However, commonly used spiro-OMeTAD with lithium salt dopants Received: 7 October 2022 Accepted: 1 June 2023 Published online: 3 July 2023 Check for updates 1 Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China. 2 Optics Valley Laboratory, Hubei, could raise additional stability issues of PSCs beyond perovskite absorb-ers themselves 7,8 . Meanwhile, inverted (p-i-n) structure PSCs based on dopant-free interfacial materials such as p-type NiO, poly[bis(4-phenyl) (2,4,6-trimethylphenyl)amine], n-type [6,6]-phenyl-C 61 -butyric acid methyl ester (PCBM) and C 60 tend to present better stability than the regular devices under the same conditions 9,10 . However, up to now, inverted PSCs with efficiencies of &gt;24% have rarely been reported 11-14 . China. 3 Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>et al. recently reported a certified efficiency of 24.3% for inverted PSCs based on (FA 0.98 MA 0.02 ) 0.95 Pb(I 0.98 Br 0.02 ) 3 perovskite 12 ; Jiang et al. used a reactive surface engineering approach based on Rb 0.05 Cs 0.05 MA 0.05 FA 0.85 Pb(I 0.95 Br 0.05 ) 3 , with the resulting p-i-n PSCs obtaining a PCE over 25% (ref. 14); a similar device based on pure FAPbI 3 perovskite delivered a PCE of only 22.6%</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>-E DBSO . The adsorption sites are O atom in organic molecule and Pb atom in PbI 2 substrate. The structures of PbI 2 , DBSO, NMP and DMSO are fully optimized during the calculation.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_0"><p>Zhengzhou Research Institute of HIT, Zhengzhou, China.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_1"><p>Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, China.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_2"><p>Energy Materials and Surface Sciences Unit (EMSSU), Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology Graduate University (OIST), Okinawa, Japan.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7" xml:id="foot_3"><p>State Key Laboratory of Metal Matrix Composites, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China. e-mail: wnlochenwei@mail.hust.edu.cn</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was financially supported by the <rs type="funder">National Key Research and Development Project</rs> funding from the <rs type="funder">Ministry of Science and Technology of China</rs> (grant no. <rs type="grantNumber">2021YFB3800104</rs>), the <rs type="funder">National Natural Science Foundation of China</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">52002140</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">U20A20252</rs>), <rs type="programName">Young Elite Scientists Sponsorship Program</rs> by <rs type="funder">CAST</rs>, the <rs type="funder">Self-determined and Innovative Research Funds of HUST</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">2020kfyXJJS008</rs>), the <rs type="funder">Natural Science Foundation of Hubei Province</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">2022CFA093</rs>) and the <rs type="funder">Innovation Project of Optics Valley Laboratory</rs> (grant no. <rs type="grantNumber">OVL2021BG008</rs>). Y.Q. acknowledges the support from the <rs type="funder">Energy Materials</rs> and <rs type="institution">Surface Sciences Unit of the Okinawa Institute of Science and Technology Graduate University</rs>. P.A.T. acknowledges the support from <rs type="funder">Russian Science Foundation</rs> (project no. <rs type="grantNumber">19-73-30020P</rs>). L.H. acknowledges the support from the <rs type="funder">National Natural Science Foundation of China</rs> (grant nos. <rs type="grantNumber">11834011</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">12074245</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">U21A20171</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Yt4cxZx">
					<idno type="grant-number">2021YFB3800104</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_9TYZSCH">
					<idno type="grant-number">52002140</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_deB3Yne">
					<idno type="grant-number">U20A20252</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Young Elite Scientists Sponsorship Program</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_XwBssqV">
					<idno type="grant-number">2020kfyXJJS008</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_g4DQRtm">
					<idno type="grant-number">2022CFA093</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_f8pAS43">
					<idno type="grant-number">OVL2021BG008</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_xqJ2YKW">
					<idno type="grant-number">19-73-30020P</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_dNrsuCH">
					<idno type="grant-number">11834011</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_S83fv7k">
					<idno type="grant-number">12074245</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_qdZkkVU">
					<idno type="grant-number">U21A20171</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>The main data supporting the findings of this study are available within the published article and its supplementary information and source data files. Additional data are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request. Source data are provided with this paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Supplementary Table <ref type="table">3</ref>  <ref type="figure">6</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 1: Supplementary Note 2:</head><p>As shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">8</ref>, we dissolved PbI2 into DMF, DMF/NMP and the mixed solvent of DMF/NMP containing 10 mol% DBSO to obtain a solution with the PbI2 concentration of 1.5M. The volume ratio of DMF to NMP was 6:1. The solutions were heated at 70 °C and stirred for 1 h. As expected, PbI2 was not completely dissolved in the DMF/NMP mixed solvent and the yellow solid compound were present in the solution. After addition of 10 mol% DBSO, PbI2 dissolved uniformly in the mixed solvent, which was caused by the strong interaction between PbI2 and DBSO.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 3:</head><p>As shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">9</ref>, the stability of NMP•PbI2 and DBSO•PbI2 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 4:</head><p>Supplementary Note 5:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Williamson-Hall analysis</head><p>The crystallite size (D) and micro-strain (ε) of perovskite films can be evaluated from the XRD patterns quantitatively by the relationship plot of</p><p>where 𝛽 is the full width half maximum (FWHM) of diffraction peaks, K is the shape factor is 0.9 for a cubic structure, λ the wavelength of the incident X-rays.</p><p>The positive and negative strain correspond to tensile or compressive strains in the out of-plane direction.</p><p>The Williamson-Hall analysis was conducted on Fig. <ref type="figure">1c</ref>. The 0% and 10% DBSO films change from -0.0439 to -0.0064, respectively, which indicates that the lattice shrinks and releases in the out-of-plane direction, that is, perpendicular to the substrate. This is consistent with the description in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">14</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 6:</head><p>In order to ascertain the accuracy of prolonged PL lifetime, we conducted TRPL measurements with different excitation conditions (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">16</ref>). The applied excitation fluences were varied between 8.9 nJ cm -2 and 56.3 nJ cm -2 by using neutral density filters. N0 is the initial carrier density estimated to be 1.1 × 10 16 cm -3 , 2.0 × 10 16 cm -3 and 7.0 × 10 16 cm -3 according to 𝑁 0 = 𝐴 𝜆 * 𝐹/(𝐸 𝑝ℎ * 𝑑), where A is the absorbance at 478 nm, 𝐸 𝑝ℎ is the photon energy, 𝐹 is the excitation fluence and 𝑑 is the film thickness. The pulse fluences of the 478 nm excitation and the excitation pulse has a repetition rate of 100 KHz. TRPL results showed that the fast non-radiative decay component was suppressed with the use of DBSO, especially for 5% content, leading to radiative bimolecular recombination dominated situation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 7:</head><p>To investigate whether the 2CF3-PEA + and CF3-PEA + cations are located exclusively at the surface of the films or also in their bulk, we monitored the amounts of F in the samples via XPS depth profiling (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">23</ref>). It can be seen that after 30 s and 90 s of etching using an argon cluster ion beam, the F 1s signals are diminished for the films treated with 2CF3-PEAI and CF3-PEAI, respectively.</p><p>Considering the etching rate by the argon clusters (10.8 nm min -1 ), the 120 s etching would remove approximately 20 nm thick perovskite layer from the film surface, thus confirming that the 2CF3-PEA + cations are located at the shallower surface of the perovskite film. The CF3-PEA + cations are estimated to penetrate 2.5 times deeper (roughly 50 nm) to the bulk of perovskite film.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 8:</head><p>We use a laser of 478 nm wavelength to illuminate the samples with a 1-sun equivalent intensity by adjusting the produced current close to the JSC under a standard solar simulator (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">31</ref>). The PLQY of the bare perovskite on glass is improved from 1.18% to 8.89% due to the passivation treatment, indicative of surface trap passivation. When capped with PCBM, the PLQY of the control sample was reduced from 1.18% to 0.26%. In contrast, the PCBM was substantially reduced for the passivation treated perovskite/PCBM stacks. The PLQY of perovskite/passivator/PCBM stack indicated that we overcame the critical PCBMinduced non-radiative recombination upon introducing the interlayer for this system, especially for 2CF3-PEAI based sample.</p><p>To quantify the open-circuit voltage potential for every individual stack, we calculated the internal electron-hole quasi-Fermi level splitting (QFLS) from PLQY results by using the equation QFLS = k B T * ln(PLQY × J G /J 0,rad ) , where J G is the generated current density at 1-sun and J 0,rad is the radiative recombination current in the dark. As shown in Figure <ref type="figure">R10</ref>, the neat perovskite exhibits an implied VOC of 1.17</p><p>V. This value increases to 1.23 V after the introduction of 2CF3-PEAI, which is attributed to the passivation effect on the perovskite surface. The perovskite/PCBM half stack exhibits a lower QFLS of 1.13 V, while the 2CF3-PEAI treated perovskite/PCBM sample shows QFLS of 1.21 V, indicating that the PCBM-induced interfacial recombination is effectively overcome.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 9:</head><p>The operational stability is closely related to the ion migration of perovskite films, and we measured the temperature-dependent conductivity to calculated the activation energy (Ea) of the corresponding films with a previously reported procedure (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">39</ref>). We can estimate the ion migration active energy based on the Nernst-Einstein relation:</p><p>where 𝜎 0 is a constant, kB is Boltzmann's constant, 𝜎 is ionic conductivity, T is temperature, and Ea is the ion-migration activation energy. As expected, the 2CF3-PEAI based perovskite film has the highest Ea, which means the lowest degradation rate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 10:</head><p>A green laser with 532 nm wavelength is used as the incident light source (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">40</ref>). Through the microscope, the light is focused on the perovskite sample's surface. The light intensity is estimated to be equivalent to roughly 10 Suns within a given illumination area with the circular spot diameter of ~100 μm. This laser light can be used as the excitation source for the samples, whereas the excited samples PL spectrum could be monitored by the detector (Ocean Optics, QE-Pro). At the same time, the laser light can also induce photochemical aging resulting in the fast degradation of the perovskite film. Our equipment can automatically record the PL spectral evolution of the perovskite film during aging. This measurement can quickly identify the difference in the perovskite films' stability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 11:</head><p>It can be seen that the pristine sample degrades to ~50% of the initial intensity after about 30 min aging, whereas the samples with PEAI and CF3-PEAI coatings retain ~70% and ~80% of their initial PL intensity after 2 hours aging, respectively. The 2CF3-PEAI-modified sample shows almost constant PL intensity within 2 hours aging (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">41</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 12:</head><p>It can be seen that the MAPbI3 sample degrades to ~70% of the initial intensity after about 2 hours aging, while the PL of Cs0.15FA0.85Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 sample decays to ~93% of the initial intensity under the same conditions. The degradation rates are both faster than that of FA0.98Cs0.02PbI3 film passivated by 2CF3-PEAI as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">S29</ref>, thus reflecting that the presence of MA + and Br -could deteriorate the inherent stability of the perovskite films (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">42</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 13:</head><p>It can be seen that the MAPbI3-based PSC degrades to 80.4% of the initial PCE value after 1000 hours aging, while the Cs0.15FA0.85Pb(I0.95Br0.05)3 based PSC retains 81.3% of the initial PCE after 1800 hours aging. The degradation rates in both cases are higher than that of the device based on FA0.98Cs0.02PbI3 film passivated by 2CF3-PEAI as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">4D</ref>, thus reflecting that the presence of MA + and Br -in the perovskite could deteriorate the long-term operational stability of PSCs (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">43</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 14:</head><p>It can be seen that the 0% DBSO sample degrades to 82.6% of the initial PCE after 1800 hours aging, while the 5% DBSO sample retains 91.2% of the initial PCE after 1800 hours aging. The degradation rates are both higher than that of the 10% DBSO sample as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">4E</ref>. Since the compared perovskite films have the same surface hydrophobicity, the different degradation rates of the corresponding devices should be directly correlated to their different defects density (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">44</ref>).</p><p>Article <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref> </p><p>electrodes anti-corrosive stability according to our previous report <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">40</ref> .</p><p>To perform the damp-heat test of the encapsulated devices, we kept the solar cells at 85 °C/85% RH in the environmental test chamber for 1,000 h. The encapsulated devices were measured periodically after 20 min cooling in ambient air. The operational stability of the encapsulated PSCs was measured by a home-made multichannel stability test system operating in the MPPT mode. The operational stability measurements were carried out by putting the encapsulated devices into a xenon lamp ageing test chamber (Zhenghang Instrument). It should be noted that the illumination was generated by a commercial xenon lamp chamber with AM 1.5 G filter with automatic power reinforcement after fading and black body temperature (50 ± 5 °C, equal to cell temperature). The light intensity was calibrated to achieve the same J SC from the PSCs measured under a standard solar simulator (AM 1.5 G, 100 mW cm -2 ). During MPPT, J-V characteristic curves of the devices were periodically measured every 24 h.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reporting summary</head><p>Further information on research design is available in the Nature Portfolio Reporting Summary linked to this article. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary information</head><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</ref>.</p><p>Correspondence and requests for materials should be addressed to Wei Chen.</p><p>Peer review information Nature Energy thanks Christian Wolff and the other, anonymous, reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p><p>Reprints and permissions information is available at www.nature.com/reprints.</p><p>Publisher's note Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p><p>Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</p><p>© The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal quantum dot-SnO2 layers as electron transporters for efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudo-halide anion engineering for α-FAPbI3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solar cells with atomically coherent interlayers on SnO2 electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">598</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface reaction for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing heterojunctions by surface sulfidation for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometallic-functionalized interfaces for highly efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strain engineering in perovskite solar cells and its impacts on carrier dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Best research-cell efficiency chart. National Renewable Energy Laboratory www</title>
		<ptr target="nrel.gov/pv/cell-efficiency.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient perovskite solar cells via improved carrier management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">590</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal quantum dot-SnO 2 layers as electron transporters for efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solar cells with atomically coherent interlayers on SnO 2 electrodes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">598</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="450" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pseudo-halide anion engineering for α-FAPbI 3 perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">592</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inactive (PbI 2 ) 2 RbCl stabilizes perovskite films for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="534" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fluorene-terminated hole-transporting material for highly efficient and stable perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jeon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="682" to="689" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable perovskite solar cells with efficiency exceeding 24.8% and 0.3-V voltage loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1615" to="1620" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stable and low-photovoltage-loss perovskite solar cells by multifunctional passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="681" to="689" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fatigue stability of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 based perovskite solar cells in day/night cycling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="694" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing heterojunctions by surface sulfidation for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="437" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometallic-functionalized interfaces for highly efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Damp heat-stable perovskite solar cells with tailored-dimensionality 2D/3D heterojunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Azmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface reaction for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">611</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="278" to="283" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reversible photo-induced trap formation in mixed-halide hybrid perovskites for photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hoke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="617" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defect-assisted photoinduced halide segregation in mixed-halide perovskite thin films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Barker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1416" to="1424" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photodecomposition and thermal decomposition in methylammonium halide lead perovskites and inferred design principles to increase photovoltaic device stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Juarez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9604" to="9612" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discovery of temperature-induced stability reversal in perovskites using high-throughput robotic learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2191</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bilayer conducting polymer structure for planar perovskite solar cells with over 1,400 hours operational stability at elevated temperatures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entropic stabilization of mixed A-cation ABX 3 metal halide perovskites for high performance perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="656" to="662" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum-size-tuned heterostructures enable efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tuning molecular interactions for highly reproducible and efficient formamidinium perovskite solar cells via adduct approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6317" to="6324" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1327" to="1332" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Slot-die coating large-area formamidinium-cesium perovskite film for efficient and stable parallel solar module</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3749</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lead halide-templated crystallization of methylaminefree perovskite for efficient photovoltaic modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">372</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1327" to="1332" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lattice strain causes non-radiative losses in halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="596" to="606" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suppression of atomic vacancies via incorporation of isovalent small ions to increase the stability of halide perovskite solar cells in ambient air</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Saidaminov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="648" to="654" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strain engineering in perovskite solar cells and its impacts on carrier dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">815</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strained hybrid perovskite thin films and their impact on the intrinsic stability of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5616</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Additive-free, low-temperature crystallization of stable α-FAPbI 3 perovskite</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2107850</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence of charge transport layers on open-circuit voltage and hysteresis in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ravishankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="788" to="798" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diammonium molecular configuration-induced regulation of crystal orientation and carrier dynamics for highly efficient and stable 2D/3D perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">202114588</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust hole transport material with interface anchors enhances efficiency and stability of inverted formamidinium-cesium perovskite solar cells with a certified efficiency of 22</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2567" to="2580" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving contact and passivation of buried interface for high-efficiency and large-area inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Funct. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2109968</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imaging and quantifying non-radiative losses at 23% efficient inverted perovskite solar cells interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cacovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2868</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01288-7" />
		<title level="m">Article</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D/3D perovskite engineering eliminates interfacial recombination losses in hybrid perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sutanto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1903" to="1916" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability-limiting heterointerfaces of perovskite photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">605</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconfiguration of interfacial energy band structure for high-performance inverted structure perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4593</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Titanium-carbide MXenes for work function and interface engineering in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Agresti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1228" to="1234" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A chemically inert bismuth interlayer enhances long-term stability of inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1161</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cation and anion immobilization through chemical bonding enhancement with fluorides for stable halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="408" to="415" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synergetic passivation of metal-halide perovskite with fluorinated phenmethylammonium toward efficient solar cells and modules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2203681</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imperfections and their passivation in halide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rudd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Soc. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3842" to="3867" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface passivation of perovskite film for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photoluminescence-based characterization of halide perovskites for photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kirchartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Márquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stolterfoht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Unold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1904134</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of encapsulation strategies towards the commercialization of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the relation between the open-circuit voltage and quasi-Fermi level splitting in efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Caprioglio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1901631</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to quantify the efficiency potential of neat perovskite films: perovskite semiconductors with an implied efficiency exceeding 28%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stolterfoht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2000080</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shallow iodine defects accelerate the degradation of α-phase formamidinium perovskite</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2426" to="2442" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2D perovskite stabilized phase-pure formamidinium perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3021</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-consistent equations including exchange and correlation effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1133</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1965">1965</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From ultrasoft pseudopotentials to the projector augmented-wave method</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kresse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Joubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1758</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Projector augmented-wave method</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Blöchl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17953</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized gradient approximation made simple</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Perdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ernzerhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3865</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A consistent and accurate ab initio parametrization of density functional dispersion correction (DFT-D) for the 94 elements H-Pu</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Grimme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Antony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ehrlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Krieg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">154104</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiwfn: a multifunctional wavefunction analyzer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Comput. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="580" to="592" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
