<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Solar Energy Technologies</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">U.S. Department of Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_NFnYbwc #_puRRPEX">
					<orgName type="full">US DOE, Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">US Department of Energy (DOE)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_7guAJnt">
					<orgName type="full">Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Office of Science within the US DOE</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2023-09-28">28 September 2023</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Applied Physical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Chapel Hill</addrLine>
									<region>NC</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Chemical Engineering Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of NanoEngineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Diego</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>La Jolla</addrLine>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of NanoEngineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Diego</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>La Jolla</addrLine>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Materials Science and Engineering Program</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>San Diego La Jolla</addrLine>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Chapel Hill</addrLine>
									<region>NC</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2023-09-28">28 September 2023</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">22AD864E9B26420F771811F6BE58BA67</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: 24 March 2023 Accepted: 29 August 2023</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:55+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Supplementary Figure 2. (a) The spectrum of LED light source. (b) The setup for high temperature photostability measurement. (c) The uniformity of hot plate temperature which set at 85 °C. (d) The actual temperature of perovskite solar cells under one sun illumination at different set temperatures of the hot plate. Supplementary Figure 3. PCE of unencapsulated devices as a function of measurement time under (a) ~55 °C, (b) 85 °C and (c) 100 °C 1-sun illumination at VOC conditions in N2. (d) Typical J-V curves that PSCs with 0.25 mol% PEACl and without PEACl after different measurement hours under 85 °C 1-sun illumination at VOC conditions in N2. (e) PCE of unencapsulated devices as a function of measurement time under 85°C 1-sun illumination at VOC conditions in N2. The PSCs encapsulated with epoxy, PIB, and atomic layer deposition (ALD) SnO2. The data come from 4 devices, respectively. Data are presented as mean values +/-standard deviation. (g-h) PCE of unencapsulated devices as a function of measurement time under 85 °C and 1-sun illumination at VOC conditions in N2. PSCs that delete ZnCl2, FAHPO3, and PEACl, respectively. Data are presented as mean values of four devices +/-standard deviation. (i) Average PCE evolution of unencapsulated devices with 0.25 mol% PEAI as additive in precursor (blue line) and devices with 1mg/mL PEAI surface treatment (purple line) as a function of measurement time under 85 °C 1 sun-illumination at VOC in N2. The data come from 6 devices, respectively. Data are presented as mean values of six devices +/-standard deviation. 1 H NMR. (b) 13 C NMR. The peaks in 13 C NMR have been assigned to two groups, which indicate the co-crystals are mixtures of trans-and cis-PEAMAI isomers.</p><p>However, the isomer peaks in 1 H NMR are overlapped and hard to separate, resulting in multiple splitting. The weak peaks of 1 H NMR at 4.04, 1.99 and 1.17 ppm are assigned to EtOAc, which is a solvent used in recrystallization process. The peaks in 13 C NMR can be clearly separated into two groups due to the trans-and cis-isomers. PEAMA + 2 FA + + PEAMA + 2 FA + a b Supplementary Figure 9. Mass spectrum of PEAMAI. The experimental m/z = 149.10722 (100%), 150.11055(9.2%) are well matched with calculated m/z for [C9H13N2] + = 149.1074 (100%), 150.1107 (9.7%), confirming the PEAMA + formula as we expected.</p><p>4 ALERT type 1 CIF construction/syntax error, inconsistent or missing data 10 ALERT type 2 Indicator that the structure model may be wrong or deficient 5 ALERT type 3 Indicator that the structure quality may be low 5 ALERT type 4 Improvement, methodology, query or suggestion 1 ALERT type 5 Informative message, check</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The following ALERTS were generated. Each ALERT has the format test-name_ALERT_alert-type_alert-level. Click on the hyperlinks for more details of the test. It is advisable to attempt to resolve as many as possible of the alerts in all categories. Often the minor alerts point to easily fixed oversights, errors and omissions in your CIF or refinement strategy, so attention to these fine details can be worthwhile. In order to resolve some of the more serious problems it may be necessary to carry out additional measurements or structure refinements. However, the purpose of your study may justify the reported deviations and the more serious of these should normally be commented upon in the discussion or experimental section of a paper or in the "special_details" fields of the CIF. checkCIF was carefully designed to identify outliers and unusual parameters, but every test has its limitations and alerts that are not important in a particular case may appear. Conversely, the absence of alerts does not guarantee there are no aspects of the results needing attention. It is up to the individual to critically assess their own results and, if necessary, seek expert advice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Alert level C</head><note type="other">STRVA01_ALERT_4_C</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Publication of your CIF in IUCr journals</head><p>A basic structural check has been run on your CIF. These basic checks will be run on all CIFs submitted for publication in IUCr journals (Acta Crystallographica, Journal of Applied Crystallography, Journal of Synchrotron Radiation); however, if you intend to submit to Acta Crystallographica Section C or E or IUCrData, you should make sure that full publication checks are run on the final version of your CIF prior to submission.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Publication of your CIF in other journals</head><p>Please refer to the Notes for Authors of the relevant journal for any special instructions relating to CIF submission. Phenethylammonium (PEA + ) and butylammonium (BA + ) are widely used in three-dimensional (3D) perovskites to form two-dimensional perovskites at film surfaces and grain boundaries (GBs) for defect passivation and performance enhancement. Here we show that these cations are unstable with 3D formamidinium (FA + )-containing perovskites under high-temperature light soaking. PEA + and BA + are found to deprotonate to amines, which then react with FA + to produce (phenethylamino) methaniminium (PEAMA + ) and (butylamino)methaniminium (BAMA + ), respectively, severely limiting device high-temperature photostability. Removing these cations greatly improves the photostability but compromises device efficiency by leaving non-fully passivated surfaces and GBs. Ammonium cations with a high acid dissociation constant (pK a ), including PEAMA + (pK a = 12.0) and BAMA + (pK a = 12.0), can replace PEA + or BA + for passivation and are stable with FA-based perovskites due to their resistance to further deprotonation. P-i-n structure solar cells with PEAMA + additive maintained over 90% of their initial efficiency after light soaking at open circuit and 90 °C for 1,500 hours. Two-dimensional (2D) perovskites have many interesting physical properties due to confinement effects that three-dimensional (3D) perovskites do not have, including exciton dynamics, spin dynamics and electron-phonon coupling <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> . Generally, 2D perovskites are considered to be much more stable than their 3D counterparts due to better moisture resistance of the hydrophobic organic cation <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">5</ref> , larger energy barrier to ion migration <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">7</ref> and increased tolerance to structural stress <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">9</ref> . As a result, they have been widely applied in perovskite solar cells (PSCs) to improve device efficiency and stability in various ways <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[12]</ref> . To overcome their poor carrier transport along the out-of-plane direction, a thin layer of 2D perovskite can be stacked on top of 3D perovskites via sequential deposition, which not only protects but also passivates the 3D perovskite surface <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> . They can also be incorporated into the grain boundaries (GBs) of 3D perovskites by adding the large organic cations into the precursor solution <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">14</ref> . The much larger size of these organic cations causes them to be excluded form the 3D lattice to GBs which, in return, stablizes the GBs <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">15</ref> . Additionally, high layer number (n) phase-pure quasi-2D perovskites have been developed to retain both the advantages of 3D perovskites-such as good charge transport and carrier lifetimes-and 2D perovskites, such as good stability, but neither their efficiency nor stability have reached the parity of other multi-dimensional perovskites <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">17</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PLATON version</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref> chloride (PEACl), formamidinium hypophosphite (FAH 2 PO 2 ), formamidinium chloride (FACl), Zinc chloride (ZnCl 2 ) and excess CsI. FAH 2 PO 2 and FACl were added to enlarge the grain size of perovskite films and passivate the non-radiative recombination defects <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">30</ref> . PEACl was added to passivate the surface and grain boundaries by formation of 2D perovskite and suppress the halide ion migration <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">32</ref> . ZnCl 2 was added to increase device efficiency by optimizing the perovskite morphology and decrease trap density <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">33</ref> . Excess CsI was added to compensate iodide vacancies and suppress ion migration and defect generation during long-term illumination <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">29</ref> . We speculated that some additive(s) may induce the quick degradation observed at high temperatures. To verify this, additives were removed one by one from the perovskite precursor solutions, PSCs were fabricated and then the same high-temperature photostability study was conducted (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3g-h</ref>). Results showed that the PSCs became much more stable after the PEACl additive was removed from the perovskite precursor solution. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1b</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3h</ref>, devices without PEACl retained 90% of their initial efficiency over 750 hours at 85 °C under 1 sun light illumination but started with a lower efficiency of ~20%. This suggests that PEA + cations were the main reason for the poor photostability of FACs-perovskites at high temperatures; note that chloride was excluded using control studies where chloride was replaced by iodide (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3i</ref>). Additionally, to evaluate whether the location of phenethylammonium iodide (PEAI) makes a difference, we removed PEAI in the precursor and instead applied PEAI as surface treatment to the perovskite films. A poor stability was again observed for these PSCs with PEAI surface treatment (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3i</ref>). This shows that the PEA + cations cause poor high-temperature photostability, regardless of how PEA + is introduced into the FACs-perovskites.</p><p>The impact of PEA + on FACs-perovskite intrinsic stability was manifested by the perovskite morphology and crystallinity evolution after light soaking at 85 °C for different durations. X-ray diffraction (XRD) results shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4</ref> revealed that the crystallinity of FACs-perovskite films with PEA + quickly decreased after testing for 260 hours, while FACs-perovskite films without PEA + experienced a slower degradation in crystallinity and retained the majority of their initial crystallinity over 860 hours of testing. This is evidenced by a slower decrease in XRD peak intensity and smaller changes in full-width half maximum values of the (001) plane peak. Additionally, cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) showed that voids formed along grain boundaries during the stability measurement for films containing PEA + (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1c</ref>). This can be explained by the PEA + ions that accumulated at the GBs, which damaged the 3D perovskites during the high-temperature light soaking testing. In contrast, devices without PEA + did not develop voids even after testing for 860 hours (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1d</ref>).</p><p>Electron beam induced current (EBIC) measurements were conducted to further research the stability of PSCs with and without PEACl. For this measurement, devices with thinner electrodes (30 nm) were deposited so that an electron beam with an energy of 5-15 keV could penetrate through the electrode and electron transport layer (ETL), depositing its energy into the perovskite layer. Monte Carlo simulations of the electron trajectories indicate that 75% of the beam energy was deposited within the ETL and the first 10 s of nanometers (nms) of the perovskite (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5</ref>). EBIC results in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1e</ref> reveal that PEA + incorporation results in a lower and less uniform current that further decreases over device ageing, in contrast to PSCs without PEA + . As can be seen in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1f</ref>, the pristine PSCs without PEA + show an average EBIC current of ~3.0 nA. PSCs with PEACl show both a more heterogenous and lower average current collection of ~2.2 nA. Because the devices with PEACl have a larger photocurrent under 1 sun light, we interpret the smaller and more heterogenous EBIC by the faster degradation of the device with PEACl under electron beam. After the devices light soaked under 85 °C 1 sun for 250 hours, the mean current extraction from the device with PEACl decreased to ~1.1 nA. In contrast, the device without PEACl showed a modest increase in current to ~3.7 nA</p><p>The ability of 2D perovskites to enhance the efficiency of perovskite solar cells as additive or surface capping layer is very evident <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[20]</ref> . Among the numerous organic cations reported for 2D perovskites, phenethylammonium (PEA + ) and butylammonium (BA + ) are the most frequently used ammonium cations. Additionally, they have yielded many certified record power conversion efficiencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">21</ref> . Encouraging shelf lifetime or even operational stability under light has also been frequently reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">23</ref> . Nevertheless, almost all previous studies were conducted at relatively low temperatures. Because the operational lifetime of perovskite solar cells are reaching several thousand hours, higher temperatures are needed to accelerate the operational stability test, as demonstrated by several recent studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">23</ref> . Some recent studies have shown poor stability of 2D:3D mixed perovskites and 2D/3D stacking structure at a high temperature of 85 °C, despite their promising stability at a lower temperature of 55 °C <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[24]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[27]</ref> , which raises concerns about whether 2D:3D mixture structure or stacking structure is viable for long-term stability. The underlying mechanism of 2D:3D interfacial instability is still unclear.</p><p>In this manuscript, we show that several commonly used ammonium cations, including PEA + and BA + , are not stable with formamidinium (FA)-containing perovskites at 85 °C under illumination. We identify the easy deprotonation of PEA + and BA + cations as the underlying chemistry for the observed instability. New ammonium cations with high pK a , a parameter characterizing the resistance to deprotonation <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">28</ref> , were used to replace PEA + and BA + cations. These devices based on formamidinium caesium (FACs) perovskites not only retain the high efficiencies but also dramatically enhanced the high-temperature photostability of perovskite solar cells.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PEA + induced worse high-temperature photostability</head><p>PSCs with a structure of indium tin oxide (ITO)/poly[bis(4-phenyl) (2,4,6-trimethylphenyl)amine (PTAA)/FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 /C 60 /bathocuproine (BCP)/copper (Cu) (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1a</ref>) were fabricated via blade coating. A methylammonium (MA + )-free perovskite composition with a slight excess of FAI or caesium iodide (CsI) (0.25 mol%) was used to achieve high intrinsic stability <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">29</ref> . Additionally, 0.25 mol% phenethylammonium chloride (PEACl) (relative to Pb 2+ ) and several other additives were added to the perovskite precursor solution to passivate defects at grain boundaries and film surfaces, which has been widely shown to improve the efficiency and stability of PSCs at relatively low testing temperatures <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[30]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[31]</ref> . The optimized PSCs yielded a power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 23.3% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1b</ref>). Additionally, they showed remarkably good operational stability when soaked under open circuit condition beneath a white light emitting diode (LED) lamp at 1 sun intensity with a spectrum as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2a</ref>. The lamp also heated the devices to a temperature of 55 ± 5 °C. These devices maintained 90% of their initial efficiency after 3,200 hours on operational stability test, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1a</ref>. However, when the temperature was raised to 85 °C using the testing setup shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2b</ref> with the actual temperature of perovskites of 90 °C as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2d</ref>, the PSCs showed dramatically faster degradation. The efficiencies of the PSCs reduced to 90% of their initial value within ~150 hours (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1b</ref>). Stability data from additional devices is displayed in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3a-d</ref>. All photovoltaic parameters, including short-circuit current (J SC ), open circuit voltage (V OC ) and fill factor (FF), rapidly declined. Furthermore, when elevating the measurement temperature to 100 °C, the average T 90 lifetime (T 90 : the time it takes for device efficiency to drop to 90% of initial value) of the devices decreased to ~80 hours. The quick degradation of PSCs at high temperature and under light is not sensitive to encapsulation methods. The PSCs encapsulated with epoxy, polyisobutylene and atomic layer deposition SnO 2 all showed quick degradation (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3e</ref>).</p><p>The perovskite precursor solutions in this study had several additives to improve device efficiency, including phenethylammonium </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The mechanism for PEA + induced instability</head><p>To further understand how PEA + cations damage FACs-perovskites, we increased the amount of PEA + cations in the FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 films by directly mixing PEA 2 PbI 4 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 solutions at molar ratios of 2:1 and 1:2 so that the 2D perovskites could be clearly observed in XRD. These mixed films, pure PEA 2 PbI 4 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 were encapsulated by an inert poly(methyl methacrylate) (PMMA) layer with &gt;1 μm thickness and stressed under 1 sun illumination at 120 °C for a further accelerated photostability test. As shown by the XRD patterns in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2</ref>, pure PEA 2 PbI 4 remained unchanged after testing for 260 hours while FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 decomposed slightly to PbI 2 , showing the better intrinsic stability of PEA 2 PbI 4 than FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . For the fresh PEA 2 PbI 4 : FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 mixture films, only 2D phases with n = 1 and/or n = 2 showed up in the XRD patterns. After testing for 130 hours, the mixture films quickly degraded, and a new set of XRD peaks appears at 7.1° and 14.2° that do not belong to any known low-dimensional perovskites of PEA + . This suggests that a chemical reaction occurred between the PEA + and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 during testing.</p><p>It has been established that amines with lone pairs of electrons can easily attack the electrophilic imine bond in FA + cations, even at room temperature <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">35</ref> . We thus hypothesize that PEA + and FA + ions react via deprotonation of PEA + to PEA 0 followed by a quick condensation reaction between PEA 0 and FA + to form (phenethylamino)methaniminium (PEAMA + ), as shown by the scheme in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3a</ref>. To provide further evidence for this, we verified that the same reaction product could be produced from the reactions of (1) PEA 0 with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 and (2) PEAI with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . In this study, both PEAI and PEA 0 were spun onto FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 films, followed by annealing at 120 °C for 0, 130 and 260 hours under 1 sun illumination. The PEAI-treated samples showed the formation of the PEA + -based 2D perovskites with n = 1 and n = 2 in the fresh films. These PEA + -based 2D perovskites transferred from lower n 2D phases to a higher n 2D phase (n = 3) after annealing at 120 °C for 130 hours, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2e</ref>, indicating loss of PEA + in the films. Meanwhile, the XRD peak at 7.1° emerged. This new material </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref> was denoted as PEAMA product hereinafter and could be a lead iodide octahedral-based low-dimensional perovskite. This result resembles that of directly mixing PEAI with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 , indicating that the PEA + -based 2D perovskites reacted with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . The same PEAMA product was observed from the reaction of PEA 0 with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 as shown by the 7.1° peak in the XRD pattern in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2f</ref>. This indicates the reaction of PEAI with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 goes through a deprotonation process to generate PEA 0 .</p><p>To understand why PEA + easily deprotonates at high temperature, we examined its acid dissociation constant (pK a ), which represents a cation's deprotonation capacity:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">pKa (A + ) = -log 10 [A 0 ] [H + ] [A + ]</formula><p>in which [A 0 ], [H + ], [A + ] represent the concentrations of A 0 , H + and A + , respectively. The lower the pK a of a cation, the greater its ability to deprotonate. pK a is also temperature dependent based on Van't Hoff equation <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">36</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">dln (Ka) dT = ΔH RT 2</formula><p>Because the acid dissociation is an endothermic reaction, the reaction enthalpy change ∆H is positive. R and T indicate the ideal gas constant and temperature, respectively. Thus pK a increases with temperature, and deprotonation accelerates at higher temperatures. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3b</ref> shows the pK a values of common A-site cations. pK a of MA + , ethylammonium (EA + ), dimethylammonium (DMA + ) and BA + have similar values between 10.6 and 10.8 (ref. 37), which are much smaller than those of FA + (11.5-13) and guanidinium (GA + ) (13.6) (refs. 38-40). The chemical structures of these cations are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3c</ref>. FA + and GA + differ from other ammonium cations by their conjugated structure with better stabilized electrons, which results in more stable interaction with the proton and thus makes deprotonation more difficult. Among all these cations, PEA + has the smallest pK a of 9.8 (ref. 38), explaining its quick deprotonation to PEA 0 and the resultant device degradation under high-temperature photostability study. It is noted that BA + , the other most widely used cation for 2D perovskites in perovskite solar cells, also has a small pK a of 10.8. We thus followed the same process to evaluate the protonation and chemical reaction of BA + with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . As shown in the XRD patterns in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref>, the reactions of BAI or BA 2 PbI 4 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 were also observed under high-temperature photostability tests, regardless of whether BAI was mixed directly into or deposited onto the surface of FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . Similarly, the reaction generated a new phase with XRD peaks at 7.9° and 15.7°, resembling the reaction of BA 0 with FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . The pK a table also predicts that GA + cations should be more stable with FA + . To verify this, we introduced 0.2 mol% GAI in PSCs and conducted high-temperature photostability measurements. As illustrated in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7</ref>, the addition of GAI did not accelerate the degradation, as evidenced by the retention of 90% of the initial efficiency after a light soaking stability test at 85 °C for 600 hours, in striking contrast to PEA + . These results suggest that pK a is a reliable parameter for evaluating the high-temperature photostability of various ammonium cations with FA + . However, oversized GA + incorporation into FACs-perovskites The rapid degradation of FACsPbI 3 with PEA + can be explained by the generated ammonia (NH 3 ) by the reaction of PEA 0 and FA + . NH 3 has a strong coordination with FACsPbI 3 and can dissolve it <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">34</ref> , which can accelerate the decomposition of FACsPbI 3 into yellow phases. It also explains the observed void formation at the GBs in the devices with PEA + (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">1c</ref>), considering that PEA + cations are generally excluded to GBs during the crystallization process. The reaction of amines (including PEA 0 ) with FA + in solution has been reported to be as fast as seconds at room temperature <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">42</ref> , which was also confirmed in this study. Thus we can reasonably infer that the reaction rate between PEA + and FA + ions is limited by the PEA + deprotonation process. Because light also enhances the mobility of proton, light should also accelerate the deprotonation of PEA + in the photostability test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Passivation additives with high pK a</head><p>Although completely removing PEA + ions from the precursor solution improves the high-temperature photostability of the devices, it also reduces the device efficiency because of the exposed unpassivated film surfaces and GBs. A passivator is still needed to enhance the device efficiency. The passivator needs to meet three criteria: (1) it should have a suitable terminal size to fit into A-site vacancy at the perovskite surfaces and GBs; (2) it should have a high pK a to resist deprotonation;</p><p>(3) it should not react with FA + itself. Fortunately, we found that the reaction product of PEA 0 and FA + , that is, PEAMA + , perfectly meets these criteria. It terminates with an amidinium group with the same size as FA + , it keeps delocalized electron structure of FA + , making it difficult to deprotonate, and its lack of deprotonation prevents further reactions with FA + . We calculated the pK a of PEAMA + to be 12.0, which is higher than the PEA + benchmark. To better understand this cation, we synthesized PEAMAI by the reaction of PEA 0 with FAI, generating white powders. The single crystals of this salt can be formed by the recrystallization process, with a photograph of the crystal shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">3d</ref>. The crystal structure obtained from single-crystal XRD confirmed the crystal is PEAMAI co-crystallized with two FAI (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>). The bond lengths of C1-N1 and C1-N2 in PEAMAI are 1.30 Å, which is same as in FAI, indicating the resonance stabilization as we expected (Supplementary Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>). The 1 H, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> C nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) in Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure">8</ref> and<ref type="figure">9</ref> confirmed the chemical structure of the obtained salt. The BAMAI was synthesized by the reaction of BA 0 and FAI confirmed by the 1 H, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> C NMR in Supplementary Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">10</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">11</ref>. The BAMA + showed a similar pK a value of 12.0 with PEAMA + . In addition, the synthesized co-crystal was mixed with PbI 2 in dimethylformamide (DMF) to fabricate films by spin coating. The XRD pattern in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">12</ref> verified that PEAMAI-FAI reacted with PbI 2 to form a low-dimensional perovskite phase with XRD peaks at 7.1° and 14.2°, and BAMAI-FAI reacted with PbI 2 to form a low-dimensional perovskite phase with XRD peaks at 7.9° and 15.7°.</p><p>To evaluate if PEAMAI is capable of passivating FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 , we used PEAMAI as a surface treatment for FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 . Different from using PEAMAI as additive, using PEAMAI as a surface treatment avoids a perovskite morphology change as shown by the SEM included in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">13</ref>. The optimized surface treatment using PEAMAI resulted in a 57% increase of steady-state photoluminescence (PL) intensity, accompanied by a small blue shift of the PL peak (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4a</ref>). Step I: Cation deprotonation</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P E A + M A + D M A + E A + B A + F A + G A +</formula><p>Step II: Amine/FA  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref> Furthermore, the carrier lifetime increased from 390 ns to 496 ns (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4b</ref>), confirming that PEAMAI passivates traps on the perovskite surface. To passivate perovskite GBs, we added 0.2 mol% PEAMAI as an additive in the perovskite precursor solution. The samples with and without PEAMAI are referred to as PEAMA + device and control device. We blade coated perovskite films with or without PEAMA + on glass substrates and checked material morphology and passivation effect. Adding PEAMAI increased the steady-state PL intensity by 56% (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4c</ref>) and increased the carrier lifetime from 384 ns to 497 ns (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4d</ref>), indicating a reduced density of deep traps. Direct defect density measurement by thermal admittance spectroscopy shows that the trap density of states (tDOS) in PEAMA + devices is much lower within the trap band III (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4f</ref>). A previous study indicates that this trap band is caused by the amorphous phase in the perovskite material <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">43</ref> .</p><p>Therefore, it appears the PEAMAI additive does change the crystallization process and slightly changes the morphology of perovskite film. This is consistent with PEAMA + films showing better crystallinity with stronger and sharper XRD peaks (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4e</ref>). We estimated the mobile ion concentration in these devices by applying a 1.5 V forward bias for about 30 s to perturb the ion distribution and then measuring the current induced by the back diffusion of ions at zero bias. The measurements were performed in the dark. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">4g</ref>, the mobile ions in the control devices required a much longer time (~5 s) to reach the steady state compared to the mobile ions in the PEAMA + -devices (~1 s). Additionally, the mobile ion concentration in the PEAMA + devices is three times smaller than the </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Device efficiency and high-temperature photostability</head><p>The impact of PEAMA + on the performance of FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 PSCs was investigated. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5a</ref> shows typical current density (J)-voltage (V) curves of PSCs with and without PEAMA + under both forward and reverse scans. The control PSCs had a PCE of 21.2% with a J SC of 24.7 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.07 V and a fill factor (FF) of 80.2%. PEAMA + -PSCs had a PCE of 24.1% with a J SC of 25.8 mA cm -2 , a V OC of 1.14 V, and a FF of 82.1%. The statistical distributions of the V OC , J SC , FF and PCE are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5b</ref>. The steady-state PCEs of the devices with and without PEAMA + under AM 1.5 illumination are 20.9% and 23.8%, respectively (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5c</ref>).</p><p>The external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectra of the devices are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5d</ref>. PEAMA + primarily increased the EQE in the long wavelength range, consistent with a longer carrier diffusion length due to reduced non-radiative charge recombination. The calculated J SC from EQE agrees well with the measured J SC . Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">5e</ref> shows the PCE of unencapsulated control devices and PEAMA + devices as a function of measurement duration under 85 °C 1 sun illumination under V OC condition in N 2 . Stability data for each sample are listed in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">14a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>. The devices maintained 90% of the initial efficiency after ~800 hours in the </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref> absence of ammonium cations in the perovskites, while the devices with PEAMA + maintained 90% of the initial efficiency after ~1,500 hours. The J-V curves of the PSCs with PEAMA + after operational measurement for different durations were exhibited in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">14c</ref>. Furthermore, the high-temperature light stability of PEAMA + devices was also evaluated at 100 °C under 1 sun illumination. As illustrated in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">14d,</ref><ref type="figure">e</ref>, the average T 90 of PEAMA + devices was approximately 500 h, notably surpassing that of the control devices. The improved high-temperature stability of PSCs is attributed to the increased crystallinity and passivation induced by PEAMA + in perovskite films. Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">14f</ref>,g displayed the cross-sectional SEM images and XRD patterns of PSCs before and after 1,400 hours of 1 sun illumination at 85 °C and the V OC condition. The cross-sectional SEM images of the stressed PSCs showed no voids, in striking contrast to the PEA + containing FACs-perovskite devices, which showed voids along the GBs. It demonstrates the excellent high-temperature photostability of PEAMA + with FACs-perovskites. The XRD patterns revealed that the PEAMA + devices had a relatively slower crystallinity degradation compared to PSCs with PEA + after the initial crystallization process induced by heat.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>In conclusion, we found the widely used organic cations PEA + and BA + for 2D perovskites are unstable in FA + -containing perovskites when the films or devices were subject to high-temperature light soaking.</p><p>The PEA + and BA + deprotonate to amines, which further react quickly with FA + to produce PEAMA + and BAMA + , respectively. This process also generates ammonia, which causes damage to perovskite interfaces and grain boundaries, severely limiting the high-temperature photostability of perovskite solar cells. Removing PEA + or BA + cations from precursors or using ammonium cations with high pK a , including PEAMA + and BAMA + can improve the high-temperature photostability due to the difficulty of deprotonation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials</head><p>FAI, formamidinium chloride (FACl), zinc chloride (ZnCl 2 ) and phenylethylammonium chloride (PEACl) were purchased from GreatCell Solar and used without further purification. Lead iodide (PbI 2 , 99.99%) was purchased from Tokyo Chemical Industry. 2-Mercaptoethanol (2-ME), dimethylformamide (DMF), dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), toluene (TL), isopropanol (IPA), ethanol (EtOH), ethyl acetate (EtOAc), caesium iodide (CsI; 99.999%), PTAA (average Mn 7,000-10,000), BCP ( &gt; 96%), deuterated dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO-d 6 ) and phenylethylamine (&gt;99.5%) were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. C60 ( &gt; 99.55%) was purchased from Nano-C. Formamidinium hypophosphite (FAH 2 PO 2 ) was synthesized via a method that was based on and modified from a previously published method <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">30</ref> . Copper (Cu) pellets were purchased from Kurt J. Lesker Company.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Synthesis of PEAMAI</head><p>A colourless solution of 7.74 g (45 mmol) FAI in 50 ml absolute ethanol (EtOH) was stirred with an ice bath and added dropwise into a solution of 0.5 ml (4.5 mmol) phenylethylamine in 50 ml absolute ethanol. After the addition finished, the reaction was stirring for another 2 h and then worked up by evaporating the solvent. The crude product was washed out by 30 ml ethyl acetate two times to remove excess FAI. The eluate was concentrated by rotary evaporation resulting in light yellow oil. Recrystallization from 30 ml EtOAc/EtOH/IPA under -18 °C yielded 0.879 g (1.4 mmol, 31.1%) white solid, which is a co-crystal of PEAMAI and 2 FAI. The co-crystals are mixture of trans-and cis-PEAMAI isomers determined by NMR spectra (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Synthesis of BAMAI</head><p>BAMAI can be similarly prepared from BA 0 and excess FAI. The crude product as a mixture of BAMAI and FAI was used without further purification. The ratio of BAMAI: FAI was determined by NMR spectra (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">10</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preparation of PSCs</head><p>The ITO glass was cleaned with acetone and isopropanol using ultrasonic cleaning for 15 minutes, followed by 15 minutes of ultraviolet ozone treatment before blade coating the hole transport layer (HTL) layer using 2.2 mg ml -1 PTAA in toluene with a 200 μm blade gap. To fabricate high-quality FACsPbI 3 films with PEACl, a mixture of 0.9 M FAPbI 3 (in 2-ME solution) and 0.1 M CsPbI3 (in DMSO solution) was prepared with a molar percentage of DMSO to Pb around 56% in precursor solutions. 2.5% FACl, 1.0% FAH 2 PO 2 , 0.25% PEACl, 0.5% ZnCl 2 and 0.25% CsI were added to the perovskite precursor solution. The FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 films were blade coated on PTAA/ITO substrates at room temperature with a gap of 300 μm and N 2 blowing at 20 pound per square inch (psi), followed by annealing at 150 °C for 3 min to obtain the perovskite phase. The humidity and temperature of the air is ~30% and 21 °C, respectively. We removed each of the additives from the perovskite precursor to fabricate perovskite solar cells and evaluated their effect on the high-temperature photostability of PSCs. For instance, in FACsPbI 3 films without PEACl, a mixture of 0.9 M FAPbI 3 (in 2-ME solution) and 0.1 M CsPbI 3 (in DMSO solution) was used with a molar percentage of DMSO to Pb around 56% in precursor solutions.</p><p>To produce high-quality perovskite films, the perovskite precursor solution was supplemented with 2.5% FACl, 1.0% FAH 2 PO 2 , 0.5% ZnCl 2 and 0.25% CsI, too.</p><p>In addition, we replaced PEACl with PEAI in the precursor solution, adding 0.25% PEAI while retaining the other additives, including 2.5% FACl, 1.0% FAH 2 PO 2 , 0.5% ZnCl 2 and 0.25% CsI in the perovskite precursor solution. To check PEAI surface treatment effect on stability of PSCs at high-temperature light soaking condition, 1 mg ml -1 PEAI solution was prepared in IPA. The solution was spin coated onto perovskite films without PEACl at 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. To check the passivation effect of PEAMAI, 1 mg ml -1 PEAMAI solution was prepared in IPA. The solution was spin coated onto perovskite films without PEACl at 5,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min. For FACsPbI 3 films with PEAMAI, 0.2% PEAMAI was added to the FACs-perovskite solution along with 2.5% FACl, 1.0% FAH 2 PO 2 , 0.5% ZnCl 2 and 0.25% CsI in the perovskite precursor solution. To prepare FACsPbI 3 with PEAMAI, we used 0.9 M FA 0.99 PbI 3 (in 2-ME solution) and 0.1 M CsPbI 3 (in DMSO solution), as the synthesized PEAMAI lattice contains FAI. The precursor solution was blade coated with a 300 μm blade gap and N 2 blowing at 20 psi, followed by immediate annealing at 150 °C for 3 minutes.</p><p>To assemble PSCs, we first evaporated 30 nm of C 60 onto the perovskite films at a vacuum pressure of 10 -6 Pa. We then evaporated 6 nm of BCP onto the sample substrates, which had been heated to approximately 80 °C before BCP deposition. Finally, we thermally evaporated Cu electrodes with 150 nm thickness. The area of shadow masks used in this work is 0.08 cm 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article</head><p><ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref> PEA + and FA + mixed perovskite film fabrication: for high-temperature photostability check of PEA + , we prepared a 1 M PEA 2 PbI 4 precursor solution by mixing 2 M PEAI and 1 M PbI 2 in 1 ml DMF solution, while a 1 M FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 solution was prepared by mixing 0.9 M FAI, 0.1 M CsI and 1 M PbI 2 in 1 ml DMF solution. Then we mixed the PEA 2 PbI 4 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 solutions at a ratio of 1:0, 2:1, 1:2 and 0:1. Subsequently, 40 μl perovskite solution was spin coated onto glass substrates at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s in a glovebox, followed by the addition of 130 μl TL after ~12 s and annealing at 120 °C for 15 minutes. The 3D films were prepared by spin coating FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 solution onto glass substrates at 4,000 r.p.m. for 30 s in a glovebox, followed by the addition of 130 μl TL as antisolvent after ~6 s and annealing at 150 °C for 15 minutes. A PMMA solution in TL was dropped onto the prepared films and annealed at 100 °C for 1 minute to form a PMMA layer with a thickness &gt;1 μm to cover on perovskite films. The BA + and FA + mixed perovskite films were fabricated by mixing 1 M BA 2 PbI 4 precursor solution and 1 M FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 using same way to the PEA + and FA + mixed perovskite film fabrication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>XRD</head><p>Powder XRD patterns were measured by a Rigaku Smart Lab diffractometer with CuKα radiation (λ = 1.5406 Å). The scan rate was 10° min -1 at the step-scan size of 0.01°. Single-crystal XRD was performed on a Bruker D8 VENTURE diffractometer with CuKα radiation (λ = 1.54178 Å). The diffraction data were handled by Olex2 software <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">44</ref> , and the crystal structures were solved and refined by the ShelXT <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">45</ref> and ShelXL 46 programmes, respectively. Thermal ellipsoid models were rendered by VESTA 47 or Ortep3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">48</ref> . PEAMAI-FAI-PbI 2 and BAMAI-FAI-PbI 2 films in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">12</ref> were prepared by spin coating 1 M PEAMAI-FAI (or BAMAI-FAI) and PbI 2 with equal molar ratio in DMF solution at 3,000 r.p.m. for 30 s, followed by annealing at 100 °C for 10 min.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SEM</head><p>The morphology of the samples was measured by a Hitachi-4700 microscope with an electron beam accelerated at 10 kV. The surface of the samples was coated with Au to prevent charging during the measurement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Photocurrent measurement</head><p>J-V curves were measured using a Keithley 2400 source meter under the simulated AM 1.5 G 1 sun illumination (100 mW cm -2 ) using a solar simulator (Oriel Sol 3 A class AAA) equipped with 450 W Xenon lamp (Newport 6280NS). The light intensity was calibrated using a Si solar cell with a KG-5 filter. The active area of devices is 0.08 cm 2 , defined by the size of the Cu electrode. The devices were measured at ambient air with humidity of 30-60% without temperature control. The scan rate during measurement was set to 50 mV s -1 . Steady-state PCE was conducted by measuring stabilized photocurrent density under a constant bias voltage at maximum power point derived from J-V curves. An anti-refection coating was used during measurement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EBIC</head><p>EBIC was performed using a Mighty EBIC 2.0 Controller from Ephemeron Labs Inc. (currently Ephemeral Devices) and a FEMTO DLPCA-200 pre-amplifier. EBIC and a SEM image were collected concurrently in an FEI Scios DualBeam FIB/SEM from Thermo Fisher Scientific. In this study, EBIC was measured at a short-circuit condition. To collect an EBIC scan, first the electron beam was focused on the edge of the device area at low magnification, then moved along the edge to a fresh area to focus on a higher magnification. Once the desired magnification was achieved, the beam was moved towards the centre of the device in one direction to take EBIC measurements on unscanned fresh areas. Five EBIC scans in fresh regions were collected on each active device area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Monte Carlo simulation</head><p>Monte Carlo simulations of the electron beam interaction volume were performed using Monte Carlo simulation of electron trajectory in solids (CASINO) open-source software to estimate the beam spot size and penetration depth. In CASINO, each electron trajectory is approximated as a zigzag trajectory as a result of elastic and inelastic collision of the electron with the atoms in the material <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">49</ref> . For this study, 1,600 electron trajectories were simulated for each run. The incident beam radius is set to 10 nm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EQE</head><p>A Newport QE measurement kit was used to measure the EQE of PSCs. A monochromatic light beam from a Xenon Arc lamp coupled with a Bruker Vertex 80 v Fourier Transform Interferometer was incident and focused onto the devices. Then, the photocurrent was obtained through a Stanford Research SR570 current pre-amplifier. EQE of devices was calibrated by a Newport reference silicon solar cell with a known EQE.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TPV</head><p>TPV decays were measured under 1 sun illumination with a 337 nm laser pulse (SRS NL 100 Nitrogen Laser, pulse duration of less than 3.5 ns) to add a small perturbation to the background illumination. The voltage of the device was measured with a digital oscilloscope (DOS-X 3104 A) with an input impedance set to 1 MΩ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PL</head><p>PL spectra were collected with a Horiba iHR320 Spectrometer. A 532 nm green laser (Laserglow Technologies) with an intensity of 100 mW cm -2 was used as the excitation source.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TRPL</head><p>TRPL measurement was conducted on a DeltaFlex modular fluorescence lifetime system from Horiba Scientific with a pulsed laser source at 406 nm (Horiba NanoLED 402-LH; pulse width below 200 ps, 20 pJ per pulse, ~1 mm 2 spot size) with a repetition rate of 0.3125 MHz. The signal was recorded using time-corrected single photon counting (TCSPC). The fluence of excitation light was 200 nJ m -2 . tDOS tDOS measurement was performed by the thermal admittance spectroscopy measurement using an LCR meter (Agilent E4980A). The tDOS was derived from the frequency-dependent capacitance and voltagedependent capacitance based on the equation: N T (E ω ) = -</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">1 qkT ωdC dω V bi W ,</formula><p>where q, k, T, ω and C are elementary charge, Boltzmann's constant, temperature, angular frequency and specific capacitance, respectively. W and V bi are the depletion width and build-in potential, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mobile ion concentration measurement</head><p>The measurement of mobile ion concentration was conducted using Keithley 4200A-SCS system. We estimated the mobile ion concentration in these devices by applying 1.5 V forward bias for about 30 s to perturb the ion distribution and then measuring current induced by the back diffusion of ions that were quickly zero biased to allow ions to diffuse back to steady state. The transient current induced by ion back diffusion was recorded and the measurements were performed with devices in the dark. The mobile ion concentration was obtained from the integrated transient current over time divided by the perovskite volume and the elementary charge. following the standard procedure for 1 H and <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> C. Chemical shifts were referenced to tetramethylsilane as the internal standard. HRMS was measured by a Q Exactive HF-X (ThermoFisher) mass spectrometer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NMR and HRMS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>pK a calculation</head><p>The pK a values of PEAMA + and BAMA + were calculated using Marvin-Sketch software (<ref type="url" target="https://www.chemaxon.com">https://www.chemaxon.com</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stability characterization</head><p>Photostability measurement was conducted at 55 ± 5 °C; before conducting photostability measurements, the PSCs were encapsulated by epoxy and glass. The encapsulated PSCs were then exposed to white LED irradiation at an intensity of 1 sun, which was calibrated using a Si reference solar cell with a KG-5 filter. The spectral distribution of the lamp used was depicted in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2a</ref>. The PSCs were measured under V oc conditions without temperature controlling. Due to the light exposure, the sample temperature rose to 50-60 °C. High-temperature photostability measurement: to prevent the release of toxic gas into the air due to the instability of the epoxy under high temperature and light, the PSCs were not encapsulated during high temperature photostability measurements. Instead, the measurements were conducted in an N 2 glovebox to maintain an inert atmosphere. The arrangement used for the high-temperature photostability measurement is illustrated in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2b</ref>, wherein unencapsulated PSCs were placed on a hot plate set at a temperature of 85 °C or 100 °C. The PSCs were then exposed to white LED irradiation from above. The uniformity of the hot plate, as displayed in Supplementary Fig. was verified using a thermometer. In addition, the actual temperatures of perovskite under different set temperatures and 1 sun LED light were monitored by sticking a temperature sensor directly onto the Cu electrode layer. As shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">2d</ref>, the actual temperature of perovskites was about 90 °C when the set hot plate temperature was 85 °C. After continuous illumination at high temperature for 48 or 72 hours, unencapsulated devices were taken out from the N 2 glovebox for the J-V measurement. The J-V measurement was conducted in air with humidity of 30-60% without temperature control. An anti-refection coating was used during measurement.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Flack test results are ambiguous. From the CIF: _refine_ls_abs_structure_Flack 0.500 From the CIF: _refine_ls_abs_structure_Flack_su 0.030 PLAT042_ALERT_1_C Calc. and Reported MoietyFormula Strings Differ Please Check PLAT053_ALERT_1_C Minimum Crystal Dimension Missing (or Error) ... Please Check PLAT054_ALERT_1_C Medium Crystal Dimension Missing (or Error) ... Please Check PLAT055_ALERT_1_C Maximum Crystal Dimension Missing (or Error) ... Please Check PLAT342_ALERT_3_C Low Bond Precision on C-C Bonds ............... 0.01312 Ang. PLAT911_ALERT_3_C Missing FCF Refl Between Thmin &amp; STh/L= 0.600 8 Report PLAT934_ALERT_3_C Number of (Iobs-Icalc)/Sigma(W) &gt; 10 Outliers .. 1 Check PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.61Ang From C7 1.97 eA-3 PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.57Ang From C8 1.86 eA-3 PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.13Ang From N4 1.64 eA-3 PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.25Ang From N3 1.57 eA-3 PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.22Ang From N5 1.52 eA-3 PLAT971_ALERT_2_C Check Calcd Resid. Dens. 0.46Ang From N5 1.51 eA-3 Alert level G PLAT003_ALERT_2_G Number of Uiso or Uij Restrained non-H Atoms ... 11 Report PLAT007_ALERT_5_G Number of Unrefined Donor-H Atoms .............. 11 Report PLAT033_ALERT_4_G Flack x Value Deviates &gt; 3.0 * sigma from Zero . 0.500 Note PLAT072_ALERT_2_G SHELXL First Parameter in WGHT Unusually Large 0.10 Report PLAT083_ALERT_2_G SHELXL Second Parameter in WGHT Unusually Large 13.59 Why ? PLAT186_ALERT_4_G The CIF-Embedded .res File Contains ISOR Records 2 Report PLAT790_ALERT_4_G Centre of Gravity not Within Unit Cell: Resd. # 3 Note C H5 N2 PLAT790_ALERT_4_G Centre of Gravity not Within Unit Cell: Resd. # 4 Note I PLAT860_ALERT_3_G Number of Least-Squares Restraints ............. 66 Note PLAT913_ALERT_3_G Missing # of Very Strong Reflections in FCF .... 1 Note PLAT978_ALERT_2_G Number C-C Bonds with Positive Residual Density. 2 Info 0 ALERT level A = Most likely a serious problem -resolve or explain 0 ALERT level B = A potentially serious problem, consider carefully 14 ALERT level C = Check. Ensure it is not caused by an omission or oversight 11 ALERT level G = General information/check it is not something unexpected</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of 28/11/2022; check.def file version of 28/11/2022 Datablock cu_23005_0m -ellipsoid plot nature energy https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0 Article Ammonium cations with high pK a in perovskite solar cells for improved high-temperature photostability Mengru Wang 1,6 , Zhifang Shi 1,6 , Chengbin Fei 1 , Zhewen J. D. Deng 2 , Guang Yang 1 , Sean P. Dunfield 3 , David P. Fenning 2,3,4 &amp; Jinsong Huang 1,5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0 after the same ageing. The faster degradation of current collection during ageing indicates that the PEACl probably creates new mechanisms for the perovskite to degrade under operational stressors.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1 | Temperature-dependent photostability of FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 -perovskites with PEA + additives. a, PCE of encapsulate devices with PEACl as a function of measurement time under ~55 °C 1 sun illumination at V OC conditions in N 2 . Data are presented as mean values of 12 devices ± standard deviation. b, PCE of unencapsulated devices with PEACl (five samples) and without PEACl (eight samples) as a function of measurement time under ~85 °C 1 sun illumination at open circuit conditions condition in N 2 . Data are presented as mean values ± standard deviation. c, Cross-sectional SEM images of PSCs prepared with PEACl after stability measurement under 1 sun illumination at 85 °C and open circuit condition for 0, 80, 160 and 250 hours, respectively. Red circles indicate voids</figDesc><graphic coords="31,45.42,293.22,347.28,95.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 2 |</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig.2| Phase changes in FACs-perovskite films with and without PEA + under high-temperature light soaking. a-d, XRD of perovskite films that were prepared by mixing PEA 2 PbI 4 and FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 at different molar rations of 1:0 (pure PEA 2 PbI 4 ) (a), 2:1 (b), 1:2 (c), 0:1 (pure FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 ) (d). e, FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 perovskite films with PEAI surface treatment. f, FA 0.9 Cs 0.1 PbI 3 perovskite films</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Fig. 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3 | Chemical reactions in PEA + /FACsPbI 3 films. a, Reaction scheme of PEA + with FA + . b, Acid dissociation constant (pK a ) of common A-site cations in H 2 O at 25 °C. Orange: low pK a cations; green: high pK a cations. c, Chemical structure of common A-site cations in b. d, Photograph and crystal structure of PEAMA-FAI 3 co-crystal. Scale bar: 10 mm.</figDesc><graphic coords="33,323.97,252.42,238.92,131.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Fig. 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4 | Passivation of PEAMA + cations. a,b, PL (a) and time-resolved photoluminescene (TRPL) (b) of control perovskite films without or with PEAMAI surface treatment. c,d, PL (c) and TRPL (d) spectra of control perovskite films and PEAMA + perovskite films formed using PEAMAI additive. TRPL spectra were fitted by a bi-exponential decay function to obtain the carrier lifetime. e, XRD of the control perovskite films and PEAMA + perovskite films deposited on glass substrates. The inset shows the amplification of the (001) plane peak.f, tDOS curves of the control and PEAMA + devices. Ew is the demarcation energy. g, Transient currents of the devices under a step voltage (1.5 V forward bias for ~30 s and zero bias). Arrows represent the time interval for mobile ions to reach the steady state. f, Transient photovoltage response of the control and PEAMA + devices under continuous AM 1.5 G illumination with laser pulse perpetuation. TPV curves were fitted by bi-exponential decay function.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Fig. 5 |</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5 | Device performance. a, J-V curves of the control and PEAMA + devices under reverse-scan and forward-scan conditions. An anti-refection coating was used during measurement. b, Distribution of PCE, V OC , FF and J SC of the control and PEAMA + devices from 20 and 27 devices, respectively. The box plots display the mean, median line, 25-75% box limits and the whiskers represent the minimum and maximum values. Each dot represents one device. c, Steady-state</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>1 H</head><label>1</label><figDesc>and<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> C NMR spectra were measured on a Bruker Neo 400 MHz spectrometer. Clear and transparent solutions of PEAMAI-FAI 3 crystal or BAMAI-FAI mixture powder that dissolved in DMSO-d 6 were measured Article https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,90.00,72.00,450.00,182.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="4,90.00,102.70,420.38,283.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="5,90.00,72.00,404.00,443.99" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,90.00,72.00,430.70,354.65" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="8,99.63,72.00,395.90,239.99" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="9,90.00,100.70,437.30,302.37" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="12,132.65,129.40,329.62,177.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="14,90.00,131.05,423.15,243.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="15,90.00,72.00,440.20,198.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="17,90.00,72.00,426.05,341.14" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="21,149.07,413.50,297.15,190.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="28,73.94,96.94,465.09,359.39" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Supplementary Table 1. The pKa summary of common cations at 25 o C.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Supplementary</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cations</cell><cell>pKa</cell><cell>Ref.</cell></row><row><cell>PEA +</cell><cell>9.83</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>BA +</cell><cell>10.60</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>EA +</cell><cell>10.65</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>MA +</cell><cell>10.66</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>DMA +</cell><cell>10.73</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>PEAMA +</cell><cell>11.98</cell><cell>Calculated</cell></row><row><cell>BAMA +</cell><cell>12.03</cell><cell>Calculated</cell></row><row><cell>FA +</cell><cell>11.5-13.0</cell><cell>2,3</cell></row><row><cell>GA +</cell><cell>13.6</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 . Crystal data and structural refinement for PEAMA- FAI3 co-crystal.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Formula</cell><cell>C11H23I3N6 (FW = 620.05)</cell></row><row><cell>CCDC number</cell><cell>2247030</cell></row><row><cell>Temperature (K)</cell><cell>150</cell></row><row><cell>Crystal system</cell><cell>Orthorhombic</cell></row><row><cell>Space group</cell><cell>P212121 (No. 19)</cell></row><row><cell>a (Å)</cell><cell>7.4351(2)</cell></row><row><cell>b (Å)</cell><cell>13.8271(4)</cell></row><row><cell>c (Å)</cell><cell>18.8331(5)</cell></row><row><cell>α, β, γ (°)</cell><cell>90</cell></row><row><cell>V (Å 3 )</cell><cell>1936.15(9)</cell></row><row><cell>Z</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>ρcalc (g•cm -3 )</cell><cell>2.127</cell></row><row><cell>μ (mm -1 )</cell><cell>38.043</cell></row><row><cell>F(000)</cell><cell>1160.0</cell></row><row><cell>Radiation</cell><cell>Cu Kα (λ = 1.54178 Å)</cell></row><row><cell>2θ range for data collection (°)</cell><cell>7.932 to 136.508</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-8 ≤ h ≤ 8</cell></row><row><cell>Index ranges</cell><cell>-16 ≤ k ≤ 15</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>-22 ≤ l ≤ 22</cell></row><row><cell>Reflections collected</cell><cell>16395</cell></row><row><cell>Independent reflections</cell><cell>3516 [Rint = 0.0524, Rsigma = 0.0415]</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 . Bond lengths and related ORTEP diagram of PEAMA- FAI3 co-crystal.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Atom Atom Length/Å</cell><cell cols="3">Atom Atom Length/Å</cell></row><row><cell>N4</cell><cell cols="2">C10 1.311(17)</cell><cell>C9</cell><cell>C8</cell><cell>1.3900</cell></row><row><cell>N5</cell><cell cols="2">C11 1.287(18)</cell><cell>C4</cell><cell>C5</cell><cell>1.3900</cell></row><row><cell>N2</cell><cell>C2</cell><cell>1.461(17)</cell><cell>C4</cell><cell>C3</cell><cell>1.507(13)</cell></row><row><cell>N2</cell><cell>C1</cell><cell>1.309(19)</cell><cell>C5</cell><cell>C6</cell><cell>1.3900</cell></row><row><cell>N6</cell><cell cols="2">C11 1.300(18)</cell><cell>C6</cell><cell>C7</cell><cell>1.3900</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">C10 N3</cell><cell>1.280(18)</cell><cell>C7</cell><cell>C8</cell><cell>1.3900</cell></row><row><cell>N1</cell><cell>C1</cell><cell>1.297(18)</cell><cell>C2</cell><cell>C3</cell><cell>1.540(18)</cell></row><row><cell>C9</cell><cell>C4</cell><cell>1.3900</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>2H), 2.82-2.87 (m, 2H).<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">13</ref> C NMR (101 MHz, DMSO-d 6 ) δ: 157.84, 157.65, 154.68, 138.40, 138.26, 129.39, 129.27, 128.99, 128.90, 127.06, 127.02, 47.71, 42.57, 36.12, 33.58. Single-crystal XRD structure of a trans-PEAMAI-2FAI co-crystal (150 K) is shown in Fig.3dand Supplementary Tables2 and 3. The mass-to-charge ratio (m/z) was determined using high-resolution mass spectrum (HRMS) in conjunction with the electrospray ionization (ESI) technique, and this value was compared to the calculated (calcd) m/z value. HRMS (ESI, m/z): calcd. for [C 9 H 13 N 2 ] + 149.1074 found 149.1072.</figDesc><table><row><cell>H NMR (400 MHz,</cell></row><row><cell>DMSO-d 6 ) δ: 8.54-9.64 (m, 11H), 7.82-7.93 (m, 3H), 7.22-7.35 (m, 5H),</cell></row><row><cell>3.47-3.59 (m,</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was mainly supported by the <rs type="funder">Solar Energy Technologies</rs> office within the <rs type="funder">US Department of Energy (DOE)</rs>, <rs type="funder">Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy</rs>, under award number <rs type="grantNumber">DE-EE0009520</rs>. The chemical synthesis and related charaterization were supported as part of the <rs type="institution">Center for Hybrid Organic Inorganic Semiconductors for Energy (CHOISE)</rs>, an <rs type="grantName">Energy Frontier Research Center</rs> funded by the <rs type="funder">Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Office of Science within the US DOE</rs>. The <rs type="institution">University of California San Diego (UCSD)</rs> portion of the work was supported mainly by the Solar Energy Technologies office within the <rs type="funder">US DOE, Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy</rs>, under award number <rs type="grantNumber">DE-EE0009527</rs>. The EBIC work was performed at the <rs type="institution">San Diego Nanotechnology Infrastructure of UCSD</rs>, an National Science Foundation-supported National Nanotechnology Coordinated Infrastructure site (<rs type="grantNumber">ECCS-1542148</rs>). The views expressed herein do not necessarily represent the views of the <rs type="funder">U.S. Department of Energy</rs> or the <rs type="institution">United States Government</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_7guAJnt">
					<idno type="grant-number">DE-EE0009520</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Energy Frontier Research Center</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_NFnYbwc">
					<idno type="grant-number">DE-EE0009527</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_puRRPEX">
					<idno type="grant-number">ECCS-1542148</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>The main data supporting the findings of this study are available within the published article and its Supplementary Information. Source data are provided with this paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Here, the symbol + denotes the new product phase with XRD peaks at 7.8°.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Crystallographic Information File (CIF)</head><p>No A-and B-level alerts were reported.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary References</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reporting summary</head><p>Further information on research design is available in the Nature Portfolio Reporting Summary linked to this article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head><p>M.W. fabricated perovskite films and perovskite solar cells and conducted SEM, powder XRD, tDOS, mobile ion concentration and device stability measurements. Z.S. developed the empirical criterion and carried out organic systhesis, NMR, MS and SC-XRD measurements. Z.J.D.D. conducted the EBIC measurement and Monte Carlo simulation under the supervision of S.P.D. and D.P.F. C.F. conducted the PL and TRPL measurements. G.Y. performed TPV measurements. M.W, Z.S. and J.H. analysed data and wrote the paper, and all authors reviewed the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing interests</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary information</head><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</ref>.</p><p>Correspondence and requests for materials should be addressed to Jinsong Huang.</p><p>Peer review information Nature Energy thanks Shuping Pang and the other, anonymous, reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p><p>Reprints and permissions information is available at www.nature.com/reprints. Publisher's note Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p><p>Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</p><p>© The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CRC handbook of chemistry and physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>CRC press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming zinc oxide interface instability with a methylammoniumfree perovskite for high-performance solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schutt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advanced Functional Materials</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1900466</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pentamidine is not a permeant but a nanomolar inhibitor of the Trypanosoma brucei aquaglyceroporin-2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS pathogens</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1005436</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The basic strengths of methylated guanidines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Angyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Warburton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Chemical Society (Resumed)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">549</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2492" to="2494" />
			<date type="published" when="1951">1951</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electron-phonon couplings inherent in polarons drive exciton dynamics in two-dimensional metal-halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Thouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7085" to="7091" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exciton and carrier dynamics in two-dimensional perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Burgos-Caminal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Socie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E F</forename><surname>Bouduban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-E</forename><surname>Moser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7692" to="7701" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optical control of exciton spin dynamics in layered metal halide perovskites via polaronic state formation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bourelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3320</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stability of 2D and quasi-2D perovskite materials and devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2D perovskite stabilized phase-pure formamidinium perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3021</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suppressed ion migration along the in-plane direction in layered perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="684" to="688" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Charge-carrier transport in quasi-2D Ruddlesden-Popper perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2106822</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-dimensional perovskites as sensitive strain sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3814" to="3820" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2D hybrid halide perovskites: structure, properties, and applications in solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Small</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2103514</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intact 2D/3D halide junction perovskite solar cells via solid-phase in-plane growth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In quest of environmentally stable perovskite solar cells: a perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Spanopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kanatzidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Helv. Chim. Acta</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2000173. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformal quantum dot-SnO 2 layers as electron transporters for efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surface passivation of perovskite film for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="460" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Carrier control in Sn-Pb perovskites via 2D cation engineering for all-perovskite tandem solar cells with improved efficiency and stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="642" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient ambient-air-stable solar cells with 2D-3D heterostructured butylammonium-caesium-formamidinium lead halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quasi-two-dimensional perovskite solar cells with efficiency exceeding 22%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N.-G</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="757" to="765" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Layered 2D halide perovskites beyond the Ruddlesden-Popper phase: tailored interlayer chemistries for high-performance solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">202112022</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Highly efficient pin perovskite solar cells that endure temperature variations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">379</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="403" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One-year stable perovskite solar cells by 2D/3D interface engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Grancini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15684</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dion-Jacobson phase 2D layered perovskites for solar cells with ultrahigh stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Joule</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="794" to="806" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient, stable solar cells by using inherent bandgap of α-phase formamidinium lead iodide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">366</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="749" to="753" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational design of Lewis base molecules for stable and efficient inverted perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">379</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="694" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accelerated aging of all-inorganic, interfacestabilized perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vapor phase infiltration improves thermal stability of organic layers in perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A.-F</forename><surname>Castro-Méndez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="844" to="852" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tailoring capping-layer composition for improved stability of mixed-halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">T P</forename><surname>Hartono</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2957" to="2965" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal-and light-induced evolution of the 2D/3D interface in lead-halide perovskite films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fiorentino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Albaqami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Poli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petrozza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34180" to="34188" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In situ analysis reveals the role of 2D perovskite in preventing thermal-induced degradation in 2D/3D perovskite interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sutanto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3992" to="3998" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Zumdahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chemistry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="677" to="713" />
			<pubPlace>D.C. Heath, Lexington, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defect compensation in formamidinium-caesium perovskites for highly efficient solar mini-modules with improved photostability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unraveling the hidden function of a stabilizer in a precursor in improving hybrid perovskite film morphology for high efficiency solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-023-01362-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="867" to="872" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lead-chelating hole-transport layers for efficient and stable perovskite minimodules</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="823" to="829" />
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blading phase-pure formamidinium-alloyed perovskites for high-efficiency solar cells with low photovoltage deficit and improved stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rudd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2000995</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of Zn 2+ ion doping on hybrid perovskite crystallization and photovoltaic performance of solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Que</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">517</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ammonia for post-healing of formamidinium-based perovskite films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4417</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methylammonium-formamidinium reactivity in aged organometal halide perovskite inks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Valenzano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell Rep. Phys. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100432</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociation constants (pK a ) of tertiary and cyclic amines: structural and temperature dependences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Rayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Sumon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jaffari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Henni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Chem. Eng. Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3805" to="3813" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CRC Handbook of Chemistry and Physics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pentamidine is not a permeant but a nanomolar inhibitor of the Trypanosoma brucei aquaglyceroporin-2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Pathog</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1005436</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The basic strengths of methylated guanidines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Angyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Warburton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">549</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2492" to="2494" />
			<date type="published" when="1951">1951</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming zinc oxide interface instability with a methylammonium-free perovskite for high-performance solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schutt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Funct. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1900466</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synergistic strain engineering of perovskite single crystals for highly stable and sensitive X-ray detectors with low-bias imaging and monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photonics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="581" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite solution aging: what happened and how to inhibit?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1369" to="1378" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence of voids on the thermal and light stability of perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Uddin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5977</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">OLEX2: a complete structure solution, refinement and analysis program</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Dolomanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bourhis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Puschmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Crystallogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SHELXT-integrated space-group and crystalstructure determination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sheldrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Crystallogr. Sect. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crystal structure refinement with SHELXL</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sheldrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Crystallogr. Sect. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">VESTA: a three-dimensional visualization system for electronic and structural analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Momma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Izumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Crystallogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="653" to="658" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WinGX and ORTEP for Windows: an update</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Farrugia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Crystallogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="849" to="854" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CASINO: a new Monte Carlo code in C language for electron beam interaction-part I: description of the program</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hovington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Drouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gauvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scanning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
