<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder ref="#_X65bqjR">
					<orgName type="full">National Natural Science Foundation of China</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_u4mqCQg">
					<orgName type="full">Beijing Natural Science Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_JKYy8Cp">
					<orgName type="full">National Key Research and Development Program of China</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Cheng</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Material Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100081</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Huachao</forename><surname>Zai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Material Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100081</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mingzi</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Applied Biology and Chemical Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hong Kong Polytechnic University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Hung Hom</addrLine>
									<settlement>Kowloon Hong Kong</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Key Laboratory of Flexible Electronics &amp; Institute of Advanced Materials</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Innovation Center for Advanced Materials</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Jiangsu National Synergetic</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Nanjing Tech University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>211816</postCode>
									<settlement>Nanjing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Shuai</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">CAS Center for Excellence in Nanoscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">National Center for Nanoscience and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">CAS Key Laboratory of Standardization and Measurement for Nanotechnology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Guichuan</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Applied Physics and Materials Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Joint Key Laboratory of the Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Macau</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>999078</postCode>
									<settlement>Macau</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Xinfeng</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">CAS Center for Excellence in Nanoscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">National Center for Nanoscience and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">CAS Key Laboratory of Standardization and Measurement for Nanotechnology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jianpu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Key Laboratory of Flexible Electronics &amp; Institute of Advanced Materials</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Innovation Center for Advanced Materials</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Jiangsu National Synergetic</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Nanjing Tech University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>211816</postCode>
									<settlement>Nanjing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Dongdong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Shanghai Advanced Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>201210</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bolong</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Applied Biology and Chemical Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hong Kong Polytechnic University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Hung Hom</addrLine>
									<settlement>Kowloon Hong Kong</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Material Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100081</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Huanping</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Materials Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">College of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Key Laboratory for the Physics and Chemistry of Nanodevices</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Beijing Key Laboratory for Theory and Technology of Advanced Battery Materials</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">07D75802AAE070FE48EB4D5670A9B7CF</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: 11 August 2018 Accepted: 16 February 2019</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-13T17:54+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We further analyze the underlying film growth mechanism in a theoretical point of view. And we assume the same interdiffusion process between the organic and inorganic species for either the α-phase (cubic) and δ-phase (hexagonal) of FAPbI3 reasonably, due to the same preparation method. The conversion process might be influenced by the alkalinity of additives.</p><p>And we calculate the activation energies with existence of OH  ions in the synthesis of the α-phase (cubic) and δ-phase (hexagonal) of FAPbI3. The formation energies of both phase in normal condition and alkaline condition have been considered and the corresponding reactions of FAPbI3 are shown as follows:</p><p>PbI2 + FAI → FAPbI3</p><p>(2)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">PbI2(OH)n + FAI → FAPbI3(OH)n<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where the constant n represents the concentration of OH  ions in the synthesis. The OH  molecule has been inserted into the PbI2 model and FAPbI3 unit cells with different ratio n (n = 0.1 ~ 0.5) to represent the different concentration, which can be referred as "#/unit cell" in this simulation. The formation energies in normal condition of α-and δ-phase of FAPbI3 have been calculated as 0.157 eV and -0.271 eV, respectively. Such results indicate δ-phase of FAPbI3 is thermodynamically favored in normal synthesis conditions, in which the combination of both phase in the corresponding thin film is likely to be observed. After the introduction of OH  during film formation, the activation energy changes for the two phases follow different patterns, as is summarized in Fig. <ref type="figure">3e</ref> (main text). At the low OH  concentration, the δ-phase FAPbI3 has shown much higher activation energy of 5.352 eV, which is 1.834 eV higher than that of α-phase. As the OH  concentration increases, the activation energies of δ-phase FAPbI3 will experience an evident drop around 0.7 eV meanwhile α-phase FAPbI3 will undergo a subtle increase (&lt;0.1 eV) of the activation energies.</p><p>Notably, the variations of activation energy of α-phase FAPbI3 are relatively inert to the OH  concentration at low level. On contrary, the activation energy of δ-phase FAPbI3 is very sensitive, which decrease around 1 eV from n = 0.1 to n = 0.33 that is 10 times to the variation of α-phase FAPbI3. Nevertheless, when the OH  concentration reaches a high level (n = 0.5), the activation energy of these two phases will meet a cross, in which the δ-phase FAPbI3 will keep decreasing to 4.143 eV. The α-phase FAPbI3 will suddenly experience an obvious increase from 3.660 eV to 4.293 eV, which becomes larger than that of δ-phase FAPbI3. All the above-mentioned results suggest that the OH  concentration exhibits substantial influence to the formation of two phases of FAPbI3. As the OH  concentration increases, the formation of α-phase will gradually lose its advantage, and finally will be suppressed by the formation of δ-phase FAPbI3 at high OH  concentration. This preliminary result is in consistent with the observation of experiment above, illustrating the importance of control of OH  in the synthesis of different phase of FAPbI3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 7.</head><p>In this part, we aim to generalize our findings from two perspectives. Firstly, we verify that the above finding could be applied to all iodine-based perovskite films, e.g. MAPbI3 and</p><p>FAPbI3, since the elimination of incident I2 in organic precursor solutions could effectively reduce the defect state density in resultant films. Thus, four most widely studied perovskites with different processing are investigated, like one-step Cs0.05(MA0.85FA0.15)0.95Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3, two-step MAPbI3, two-step FAPbI3, and quasi two-dimensional (2D) BA2MA3PbI13 perovskite films. Secondly, we validate the operational guideline of weak alkalinity for additive selection by using formamidine acetate (FAAc, pKa ~ 7.64), triethanolamine hydrochloride (TEAHCl, pKa ~ 7.8) and sodium hypophosphite (NaH2PO2, pKa ~ 7.4) as examples.</p><p>Subsequently, we conducted the TRPL measurement to characterize the defect state profile of these different kinds of perovskite films with different additives. When TEAHCl, NaH2PO2</p><p>and FAAc were introduced into two-step MAPbI3 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19a</ref>) film, the carrier lifetime was all prolonged than that of the reference film, suggesting the reduced defect state density. The reference film in this comparison is pure MAPbI3 with NO additive. Similarly, when TEAHCl, NaH2PO2 and FAAc were introduced into two-step FAPbI3 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19b</ref>) film, the carrier lifetime was all prolonged than that of the reference film, suggesting the reduced defect state density. The reference film in this comparison is pure FAPbI3 with NO additive. We validated the effectiveness in one-step Cs0.05(MA0.85FA0.15)0.95Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19c</ref>) and quasi 2D BA2MA3PbI13 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19d</ref>) films, respectively. The fitted lifetime values with the bi-exponential rate law also confirm this phenomenon (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">3</ref>).</p><p>We have further investigated the device performance based on the above different perovskite absorbers and additives, to find the relationship between TRPL and solar cell efficiency. As shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19e</ref>, when TEAHCl, NaH2PO2 and FAAc were introduced into two-step MAPbI3 device, the VOC and efficiency show slight improvement than that of reference device, which is consistent with TRPL result (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19a</ref>). The reference device in this comparison is pure MAPbI3 device with NO additive. And similarly, as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19f</ref>, when TEAHCl, NaH2PO2 and FAAc were introduced into two-step FAPbI3 device, the VOC and efficiency also increased, consistent with TRPL result (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19b</ref>). So it does in one-step Cs0.05(MA0.85FA0.15)0.95Pb(I0.85Br0.15)3 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19g</ref>) and quasi two dimensional BA2MA3PbI13 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">19h</ref>) based devices, respectively.</p><p>To wrap up, we have validated the generality of our findings in both perspectives of additives and materials systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 8.</head><p>The PLQE was relatively small for either PVSK or PVSK-FA at low excitation power, but rapidly went up with the increase of excitation power, which is consistent with other studies <ref type="bibr">8,</ref><ref type="bibr">9</ref> .</p><p>At the lower exciton power, the number of photon generated carriers is relatively small, which is trapped by the defect states leading to predominately non-radiative recombination.</p><p>Thus, the PLQE of PVSK and PVSK-FA films are both very small. However, with the increase of exciton power, non-radiative recombination centers are gradually filled up and the bimolecular radiative recombination became dominant. Thus, the PLQE was increased dramatically for both PVSK and PVSK-FA films. If the exciton power further improved, the third recombination pathway, namely density-dependent non-radiative recombination or Auger recombination, become more and more important and finally dominate, leading to a drop of PLQE. In our research, we focus on the significant enhancement of PLQE for PVSK-FA film, when compared to PVSK film. Notably, the PLQE of PVSK-FA achieved 61% when the excitation power was 100 mW cm -2 , which is more than twice as that of PVSK (PLQE = 25%), which confirms the reduction of deep level defect state in PVSK-FA. It correlates to the improvement in VOC in the corresponding device.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 9.</head><p>We consider the discrepancy in iodine management is mostly due to different physiochemical properties in the corresponding absorber layers from the two film growth techniques. More specifically, we consider the major difference in physiochemical properties for two kinds of perovskite films from Yang's work <ref type="bibr">10</ref> and our study is the defect state properties. In Yang's work, the authors employed deep-level transient spectroscopy (DLTS) and confirmed that the main deep level defects in their fabricated perovskite film was located at energy levels of 0.78 and 0.82 eV below the conduction band, which may be associated with interstitial Pb (Pbi) and antisite defects. However, in our work, we employed the thermal admittance spectroscopy (TAS) as the main characterization method to determinate the defect state profile, which have been widely used in the organic and perovskite solar cell <ref type="bibr">11,</ref><ref type="bibr">12</ref> . From the TAS result, we proved that the dominant deep level defect state in our perovskite film has energy level of 0.283 eV above valence band, which might be originated from the interstitial I (Ii). Several published calculation articles have mentioned the amphoteric interstitial I defect can trap both electrons and holes through the +/0 and 0/-ionization levels placed at 0.57 and 0.29 eV below and above the CB and VB edges, respectively <ref type="bibr">13,</ref><ref type="bibr">14</ref> . For different possible deep level defects, various strategies might been need. Thus, Yang et al reduced the concentration of deep level defects, possibly interstitial Pb, by introduction of iodide ions, and we employed alkaline additives to suppress the incident I2 in the halide precursor solution and effectively reduce the density of deep level defects, possibly interstitial I, in the resultant films.</p><p>In addition, the chemical component (the ratio of FA and MA) for our perovskite film is also quite different with the Yang's perovskite film. And the Yang's perovskite film has more FA component. Our perovskite film contains 5% CsI, which was introduced during the deposition process of PbI2 film.</p><p>Thirdly, we think the major difference in physiochemical properties for two kinds of films was originated from the different film growth techniques. For this point, Yang's group have emphasized the difference between the intramolecular exchange process (IEP, their method) and conventional two-step deposition process (our method) in reported literature <ref type="bibr">15</ref> . Thus, we won't go into detail of the literature. And we concluded that there are several differences between the conventional two-step process and the intramolecular exchange process, such as the interdiffusion of FAI in pristine PbI2 film, the insertion of FAI into PbI2 crystal, and the crystal structure transformation from PbI2 film (hexagonal phase) to perovskite film (cubic phase).</p><p>Considering the second and third point we mentioned above simultaneously, we think all these factors might influence the physiochemical properties for perovskite film and how does the impurity or additives in organic cation precursor solution work when FAI or MAI organic cation reacted with PbI2 or PbI2(DMSO) films. Therefore, we think that the approach in our Further minimizing the defect state density in the semiconducting absorber is vital to boost the power conversion efficiency of solar cells approaching Shockley-Queisser limit. However, it lacks a general strategy to control the precursor chemistry for defects density reduction in the family of iodine based perovskite. Here the alkaline environment in precursor solution is carefully investigated as an effective parameter to suppress the incident iodine and affects the crystallization kinetics during film fabrication, via rationale adjustment of the alkalinity of additives. Especially, a 'residual free' weak alkaline is proposed not only to shrink the bandgap of the absorber by modulating the stoichiometry of organic cation, but also to improve the open circuit voltage in the resultant device. Consequently, the certified efficiency of 20.87% (Newport) is achieved with one of the smallest voltage deficits of 413 mV in the planar heterojunction perovskite solar cell. O rganic-inorganic hybrid perovskite materials have attracted broad attention 1 , owing to their low fabrication cost and intriguing optical and electronic properties <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> . Impressively, it witnessed the power conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells boosted from 3.8% 6 to a certified 23.7% rapidly <ref type="bibr">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr">[10]</ref> . To enable a truly competitive PCE of perovskite solar cells as that of the most efficient inorganic counterpart, e.g., GaAs, it is required to further reduce their energy loss. This relies on the improved charge generation and mitigated non-radiative charge recombination within the complete device. With careful investigations on the absorber materials <ref type="bibr">11,</ref><ref type="bibr">12</ref> , device configuration <ref type="bibr">13,</ref><ref type="bibr">14</ref> , and relevant interfaces <ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">16</ref> , it is found that the intrinsic defect properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">18</ref> in perovskite films influence the charge dynamics in the devices significantly. Halide perovskites are generally regarded as relatively soft ionic solids, which are prone to contain point defects <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">19</ref> in polycrystalline films (e.g., vacancies, interstitials, and cation and anti-site substitutions). They often serve as the non-radiative recombination centers to affect the quantum efficiency of photoluminescence and deteriorate the photovoltaic performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">20</ref> . Therefore, to assure the best power output by reducing energy and voltage loss, it is of great importance to gain profound understanding on the defect physics and chemistry, which results in defects elimination in perovskite films for efficient photo-carrier transport.</p><p>During the past few years, efforts have been attempted to probe the defects to unveil their nature. In the methylammonium lead iodide (MAPbI 3 ) perovskite, it reported a variety of shallow native point defects, e.g., Pb vacancies (V Pb ), MA vacancies (V MA ), interstitials MA (MA i ), etc <ref type="bibr">3</ref> ., and deep energy-level defects 2 in forms of complex and derivatives, such as interstitials I (I i ) and its derivatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">22</ref> . In mixed perovskites, it reveals even more complicated defect physics, wherein formamidinium (FA)related defect I FA (the complexes of I i and V FA ) makes a transition at a Fermi level that sits deep within the bandgap <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">19</ref> . Furthermore, defect formation is reported to be correlated to the processing conditions, wherein films grown under iodine-rich conditions exhibit a higher defect density <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">23</ref> . Among all defects, iodine-related defects receive most interest. It is reported that polyiodide complexes in dimethylformamide (DMF) solution could easily induce defects due to a nonstoichiometric Pb/I ratio in the resultant films <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">24</ref> . When dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) was further introduced, either I-rich or I-deficient intermediates were identified, depending on the ratio of the starting materials <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">25</ref> . Recently, it demonstrated iodine redox chemistry to convert hole traps into electron traps possibly by oxidation during film processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">26</ref> . Subsequently, the iodide management was proposed to effectively decrease the concentration of mid-gap defects in the perovskite films, and improve the PCEs of perovskite solar cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[29]</ref> . Yet, it lacks a feasible approach to be universally adopted in various halide perovskites, which suppresses the incidental I 2 in the absorber for enhanced device performance with reduced energy and voltage loss.</p><p>In this work, we demonstrate a universal technique to suppress the incident I 2 in the halide precursor solution by employing alkaline, wherein iodine can be effectively eliminated via a disproportionation reaction under a number of different alkaline environments. The alkalinity is further demonstrated to affect the crystallization kinetics and optoelectronic properties of perovskite films. For instance, formamidine acetate as a 'residual free' weak alkaline, is found to effectively manipulate the stoichiometry of the cations in the mixed perovskite ((FA,MA,Cs)Pb(I,Br) 3 ) precursor, and in particular to reduce the density of deep-level defects in the resultant films substantially. Consequently, the corresponding mixed perovskite solar cells achieve an average PCE of 20.87% (certified). More interestingly, this modified absorber possesses a smaller bandgap, but the resultant device revealed unambiguous improvement in the open-circuit voltage (V OC ), corresponding to a V OC deficit of 413 mV, which is one of the smallest certified value in the planar perovskite solar cells. These findings provide a universal approach for defect reduction in iodide-based perovskite films, which substantially reduce the energy and voltage loss to boost the efficiency of the devices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Suppression of I 2 impurity via alkaline additives. Precise control of precursor solutions is crucial for perovskite film deposition. Generally, the organic precursors are hygroscopic and unstable in air or under illumination. In particular, formamidine iodide (FAI) and methylammonium iodide (MAI) can be easily oxidized to form I 2 and/or other by-products, which induces the nonstoichiometric ratio in the precursor solution. It further leads to defect states in perovskite films that eventually deteriorate device performance. The degradation mechanism involves the formation of I 2 , which is thoroughly studied in previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">30</ref> . Ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) absorption spectroscopy was conducted to semiquantitatively investigate the formation of iodide species in the precursor solution <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">31</ref> . As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1a</ref>, the organic cation solution used to prepare the perovskite films shows a characteristic peak at 360 nm. It is often attributed to the absorption of I 3 -, stemmed from I -reacting reversibly with I 2 . Interestingly, the peak intensity equals to that of 10 -4 M I 2 in isopropanol, indicating the trace amount of I 2 in the organic cation precursor solution.</p><p>To eliminate the incident I 2 in the precursor solution, we propose to create an alkaline environment by introducing additives in the precursor solution. A series of alkaline additives with different alkalinity were employed, such as formamidine acetate (FAAc, pK a ~7.64), sodium acetate (CH 3 COONa, pK a ~9.24), sodium bicarbonate (NaHCO 3 , pK a ~10.33), sodium hydroxide (NaOH, pK a ~14.56), and potassium hydroxide (KOH, pK a ~14.7), to create the full spectrum of alkalinity precursor environment in the context of the alkalinity (see Supplementary Notes 1 and 2 for details). Take the alkaline solution of FAAc/ ethanol for example, we observed that along with an increasing amount of FAAc, the absorbance at 360 nm for precursor solution was dramatically reduced (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1a</ref>). Similarly, reduced absorbance at 360 nm was also observed when FAAc was added to the iodine solution (10 -4 M, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). This indicates that the diminishing absorbance at 360 nm in the precursor solution is due to the reduction of incident I 2 . Furthermore, CH 3 COONa, NaHCO 3 , NaOH, and KOH took the same effects as expected when added to the precursor solution (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1b-e</ref>). Meanwhile, the addition of pure ethanol does not reduce the absorption peak of I 3 -(Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>). The disappearance of I 3 -(mostly related to I 2 ) in the alkaline environment possibly suggests a disproportionation reaction in the precursor solution, wherein I 2 is converted into iodate and iodide <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">32</ref> (see Supplementary Note 3). In addition (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1f</ref>), we found that the alkalinity of additives would largely influence the disproportionation reaction. It requires less amount of NaOH or KOH to eliminate the I 2 peak of precursor solution than that of FAAc, CH 3 COONa, or NaHCO 3 , mostly because the former ones are 'strong' alkaline in the context of conventional inorganic chemistry.</p><p>Morphology, phase, and carrier lifetime analysis. The typical two-step approach was employed to fabricate the perovskite films (see details in the Methods section). We named the two-step processed reference perovskite film ((FA,MA,Cs)Pb(I,Br) 3 ) as the PVSK film. To ascertain the impact of alkaline additives on the morphology and crystallographic structure of the resultant films, we performed scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements accordingly. Compared with the PVSK film, the perovskite films with CH 3 COONa or FAAc additive exhibited enlarged grain size (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2a-c</ref>), while those with NaOH or KOH remain the same grain size (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2d</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">3</ref>). It possibly indicates the different crystallization kinetics during film growth induced by the alkaline additives. Upon the employment of CH 3 COONa or FAAc, volatile acetate ions are reported to facilitate grain growth for better film quality <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">33</ref> , which might account for the relatively enlarged grain size. On the contrary, perovskite films with the introduction of NaOH or KOH showed similar grain size, but a distinct crystalline grain morphology, as compared with the reference. It is often ascribed to the fact that Na + or K + is too small to incorporate into the perovskite lattice according to the Goldschmidt tolerance factor <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">34</ref> . However, we cannot fully rule out the influences for crystal growth in the kinetics perspective, given the different chemical environments introduced by different alkalines, which will be discussed later.</p><p>Furthermore, XRD results showed a dominating α-phase perovskite in all films (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2e</ref>), indicating that all these additives do not impact the thermodynamics of crystal growth substantially. However, PbI 2 conversion process was affected by additives, as inferred from the formation of δ-phase perovskite, as well as the residual PbI 2 . We purposely controlled the stoichiometry in all samples with a bit excessive of PbI 2 for efficient passivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">36</ref> (see also Supplementary Note 4). We observed that perovskite films with mild alkaline additives (CH 3 COONa or NaHCO 3 ) only exhibited a relatively stronger PbI 2 peak, while a distinct δ-phase perovskite peak occurred when strong alkaline additives (NaOH or KOH) were added during film fabrication. It suggests that the alkalinity of the additives would affect the formation of the by-products, where the stronger alkaline would promote the formation of the δ-phase and suppress the formation of the α-phase perovskite as well. To confirm our speculation, MA (pK a = 10.62)/ethanol was introduced into the precursor solution (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2f</ref>). We found a considerable amount of δ-phase perovskite in the resultant perovskite film. As predicted, the formation of the α-phase perovskite was suppressed substantially when the content of MA/ethanol was twice more. Interestingly, compared with the other additives, the weak alkaline FAAc resulted in the desirable phase quality, with significantly improved film crystallinity and less PbI 2 content, as compared with that of the reference and other additives.</p><p>The intrinsic defects in perovskite films affect the photogenerated carrier behavior and device performance, which also would be affected by the alkalinity of the additives. We therefore conducted time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) analysis to study the dynamics of carrier recombination. The perovskite films were deposited on glass by using a precursor solution with different alkaline additives. The TRPL decay curves (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2g</ref>) were fitted with the bi-exponential rate law (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>). We found that the perovskite films with addition of a weak alkaline possessed a longer carrier lifetime than those with the addition of a strong alkaline. The prolonged lifetime of perovskite films with a weak alkaline additive, compared with that of the PVSK film, was attributed to the suppression of incident I 2 in precursor solution and the desired film features, e.g., morphology and phase. Among all samples with alkaline additives, the perovskite film with FAAc exhibited the longest lifetime for both fast and slow recombination (τ 1 = 132.7 ns and τ 2 = 802.2 ns), indicating its lowest non-radiative recombination centers. To be noted, the introduction of Na + or K + also could possibly deform the perovskite crystal structure, which may lead to shallow defect sites or off-bandgap defects in perovskite films <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[37]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[38]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[39]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[40]</ref> (see Supplementary Note 5). Crystallization kinetics control via alkalinity. We further investigate the underlying crystallization kinetics of the formation of the α-phase perovskite by developing an in situ UV-vis absorption measurement. In a typical experiment, the organic cation solution was spin-coated onto the annealed PbI 2 layer, which was further characterized by a UV-vis absorption spectrometer immediately. By varying the alkalinity in precursor solution (Fig. <ref type="figure">3a</ref>), we clearly observed that the formation of the αphase perovskite, whose main absorption peak ranged from 450 to 800 nm, was suppressed substantially when the alkalinity gets stronger. To be noted, the absorption before 450 nm might stem from the PbI 2 or the δ-phase perovskite. Moreover, we judiciously selected two typical alkaline additives, e.g., FAAc (weak alkaline) and NaOH (strong alkaline), and continuously tracked the conversion evolution from PbI 2 to the α-phase perovskite. Compared with the reference (Fig. <ref type="figure">3b</ref>), the weak alkaline does not affect the formation of the α-phase perovskite, as expected. Accordingly, the absorption peak of the α-phase perovskite in the main range (450-800 nm) is increased continuously as time grows. The inset figure in Fig. <ref type="figure">3b</ref> provides a visualization of the improved absorption in the range of 450 and 800 nm, suggesting the continuous formation of the α-phase perovskite. On the contrary (Fig. <ref type="figure">3c</ref>), the formation of the α-phase perovskite with a strong alkaline was suppressed substantially. Even over time, only small changes occurred, as visualized in the inset figure of Fig. <ref type="figure">3c</ref>. Based on the above analysis, we confirmed that the crystallization kinetics of the transformation from PbI 2 to the α-phase perovskite, namely the activation energy, was influenced by the alkalinity of additives. As shown in scheme (Fig. <ref type="figure">3d</ref>), when the alkalinity in the precursor gets stronger, the activation energy becomes larger, leading to an increased barrier for the transformation from the PbI 2 to the α-phase perovskite. The results suggest that while incident I 2 could be effectively eliminated via a disproportionation reaction under various alkaline environments, the alkalinity of the additives is also crucial to fabricate highquality perovskite films with a desired phase. Because of the enrichment of the OH -anion when alkalinity gets stronger, we speculate that the oxygen in the OH -anion could participate in the coordination with lead iodide with stronger bonding. This may facilitate the structural transformation from PbI 2 to the δphase perovskite, leading to an increased energy barrier for the transformation of PbI 2 to the α-phase perovskite.</p><p>To verify the argument, we further performed the DFT simulation to analyze the exact activation energy for the formation of both the α-phase and δ-phase of the FAPbI 3 perovskite in different conditions. The Calculation setup was given in Methods and Supplementary Note 6. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">3e</ref>, two converse trends of the activation energy change are observed upon the introduction of OH -into synthesis. At the low OH -concentration, the δ-phase FAPbI 3 has shown a much higher activation energy of 5.352 eV, which is 1.834 eV higher than that of the α-phase. As the OH -concentration increases, the activation energies of δ-phase FAPbI 3 decline from 5.352 to 4.143 eV. However, the activation energies of α-phase FAPbI 3 increase from 3.518 to 4.293 eV, and finally exceed that of δ-phase FAPbI 3 . It clearly suggests that the formation of the α-phase perovskite is only preferred at a low OH -concentration. With the increase of OH -concentration, δ-phase FAPbI 3 is more preferred kinetically, which is in consistent with the observation of the experiments above.</p><p>Weak alkaline additives to reduce defect state density. To generalize the above findings, we selected three alkalines with a weak alkalinity, such as FAAc, triethanolamine hydrochloride The results demonstrate that the additives with a weak alkalinity could successfully decrease the trap state density of iodine-based perovskite films via effectively inhibiting incident I 2 in the precursor solution. Combining the influence for alkalinity on the crystallization kinetics of perovskite films, the resultant devices show improved photovoltaic efficiency.</p><p>To obtain an in-depth understanding of the influence of a weak alkaline on the defect state of the perovskite, we chose the FAAc as an example and named the corresponding two-step processed perovskite film ((FA,MA,Cs)Pb(I,Br) 3 -FAAc) as the PVSK-FA. At first, steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectra of PVSK and PVSK-FA over a temperature from 78 to 350 K were obtained and investigated (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>). Within the temperature range of interest, the emission peak of PVSK-FA exhibited a distinct red shift as compared with PVSK, which was consistent with the UV-vis absorption results (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>). It indicates a higher ratio of FA + incorporated into the PVSK-FA due to the addition of an additive in the precursor. It was documented that the MAPbI 3 film exhibited a broadening inhomogeneous multi-peak emission feature from a lowtemperature phase, partially attributed to additional charge or exciton trap states only activated in low temperature <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">41</ref> . However, in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4a</ref>, b, we did not observe the above-mentioned multipeak feature at a low temperature in the PVSK and PVSK-FA, indicating the characteristics of less traps. With temperature increasing, we observed a broadening of the emission line due to the electron-phonon coupling near room temperature, which was a consistent recent study in the FAPbI 3 film 42 . Interestingly, the PL spectra of the PVSK-FA exhibited a better symmetry than the PVSK with temperature increasing from 250 to 350 K (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4c</ref>). On the one hand, the absence of an asymmetric feature in this film may suggest significant reduction of defect states near the band edge. It is believed that reduced grain boundaries may lead to reduced defects <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">43</ref> , which is consistent with the morphology analysis of larger grains in the corresponding films (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>). On the other hand, better symmetry in the PL peak indicates the absence of shoulder peaks often attributed to the slight phase segregation in the mixed perovskites <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">37</ref> . It is thus implied that PVSK-FA possibly exhibited a retarded phase segregation and decreased defect states, when compared with the PVSK.</p><p>We further carefully examined the luminescence efficiency of the absorber, which serves as an important measure to identify a high-quality semiconductor <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[44]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[45]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[46]</ref> . Generally, deep-level defects serve as non-radiative recombination centers to capture the photogenerated charge carriers, thereby dramatically cutting down the quantum efficiency of photoluminescence and photovoltaic efficiency in solar cells. To be noted, a good solar cell has to be a good light-emitting diode <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">44</ref> . According to Shockley-Queisser equation, the V OC of the device decreases when the luminescence quantum efficiency of the absorber decreases. Here, the PL quantum efficiency (PLQE) of the perovskite film was examined as a function of excitation power (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4d</ref>). The PLQE was relatively small for either PVSK or PVSK-FA at low excitation power, but rapidly went up with the increase of excitation power. It indicates that the radiative recombination prevails at high optical injection levels, wherein non-radiative recombination centers were filled up, which have been further discussed in Supplementary Note 8. Notably, the PLQE of PVSK-FA achieved 61% when the excitation power was 100 mW cm -2 (close to the device working condition), which is more than twice as that of PVSK (PLQE = 25%). It further revealed obvious enhancement of PLQE compared with PVSK To find the defect energy level in the perovskite films, we conducted thermal admittance spectroscopy (TAS) analysis. It is widely adopted in perovskite solar cells to extract the native defect state-level information through the identification of junction capacitance. Given a p-type perovskite semiconductor, the defect activation energy (E a ) is approximately the depth of defect state energy level relative to the valance band of the perovskite <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">48</ref> . Here, TAS measurement was carried out from 250 to 350 K with a step of 10 K to obtain the temperature-dependent admittance spectra for PVSK and PVSK-FA-based devices (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref>). The characteristic transition angular frequency (ω 0 ) was extracted from the derivative of the capacitance-frequency spectrum. The relationship between E a and ω 0 follows the equation: ω 0 = βT 2 exp(-E a /kT), where β is a temperature-dependent parameter, k is the Boltzmann's constant, and T is the temperature. The Arrhenius plot (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4g</ref>) derived from the temperature-dependent ω 0 and fitted curves revealed that the E a of PVSK and PVSK-FA devices were 0.282 and 0.238 eV, respectively.</p><p>Moreover, attempted to illustrate the energetic profile regarding the trap density of states (tDOS) in the perovskite absorber (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4h</ref>). It could be derived from the equation N T (E ω ) = -ωV bi /qkTW × dC/dω and E ω = kT ln(βT 2 /ω), where q is the elementary charge, ω is the angular frequency, V bi is the built-in potential, and W is the depletion region, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">49</ref> . The V bi and W were obtained from the Mott-Schottky analysis (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5</ref>). As expected, the PVSK device exhibited a relatively large density of defect states, especially around the deep defect level at 0.282 eV. Previous DFT calculation study <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">26</ref> reported that this defect-state level (0.282 eV) could potentially be ascribed to iodine interstitials (I i ), which was the deep-level defect state and dominating non-radiative recombination centers in devices. Interestingly, the PVSK-FA device exhibited a striking reduction of the deep-level defect state at 0.282 eV for two orders of magnitude. In addition, the shallow defect states (0.1-0.2 eV) were also suppressed. Considering the analysis above, we reasonably claim that the introduction of a weak alkaline additive could effectively suppress the incident I 2 in the precursor solution and significantly reduce the I i defect states and achieve a much smaller defect activation energy in the resultant perovskite films. In this case, our iodine suppression approach looks contradictory with the previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">29</ref> ; however, we argue that the discrepancy in these two approaches of iodine management is mostly due to different physiochemical properties in the corresponding absorber layers. It likely stemmed from the two film growth techniques applied and different material compositions, which is further discussed in Supplementary Note 9.</p><p>Beside of defects at the deep energy level, tail defects at the band edge were further investigated. Urbach tail profiles of perovskite films were calculated according to the formula equation: α = α 0 exp(hv/E U ), where α 0 is a constant, E U denotes Urbach energy, and α is an absorption coefficient. The absorption coefficient versus energy plots were presented in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref>. As is reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">50</ref> , low E U is highly desirable for semiconductor devices, indicative of less electronic disorders in the crystal lattice (or less impurities). Accordingly, the E U values were estimated to be 31.22 and 29.64 meV for PVSK and PVSK-FA, respectively. Assuming the same level of thermal disorder, the smaller E U value obtained from PVSK-FA demonstrated a lower level of electronic disorder at the band edge.</p><p>To quantitatively assess the concentration of defects across the entire device, the current density-voltage curves under the dark state for capacitor-like devices with indium tin oxide (ITO)/ perovskite/gold (Au) configuration were measured (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7</ref>). The linear current density-voltage relation at the low bias suggested an ohmic response, and the transition point was considered as the voltage at which all the traps were filled (trapfilled limit voltage: V TFL ). The concentration of defects was determined by the equation N defects = 2εε 0 V TFL /qL 2 , where q is the elementary charge, ε is the relative dielectric constant, ε 0 is the vacuum permittivity, and L is the thickness of the perovskite films obtained from the cross-sectional SEM images of the ITO/ perovskite/Au devices (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8</ref>). It is reasonable to assume that the slight introduction of an additive would not affect the relative dielectric constants of perovskite films significantly <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">51</ref> . The defect density N defects was estimated to be 1.38 × 10 16 and 0.47 × 10 16 cm -3 for PVSK and PVSK-FA devices, respectively. It clearly confirms that the defect density in the perovskite absorber has been significantly reduced to nearly an order of magnitude by the addition of a weak alkaline additive. Moreover, we have conducted femtosecond optical measurements <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">52</ref> and confirmed that PVSK-FA exhibited a lower defect density than the PVSK film, which is the same order of magnitude as the above result (Supplementary Note 10).</p><p>Weak alkaline additive to improve photovoltaic performance. The significant reduction in intrinsic defect density within the perovskite film was expected to suppress the non-radiative recombination channel effectively and improve the device performance. To prove it, we fabricated the planar heterojunction devices using the structure ITO/SnO 2 /perovskite/spiro-OMe-TAD/Au (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">9</ref>) and studied the impacts of weak alkaline additives on photovoltaic performance. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5a</ref> presents the current density-voltage (J-V) curves of the optimized perovskite devices measured under standard AM 1.5 G at ambient condition. The typical PVSK device yielded a PCE of 19.97% with a V OC of 1.102 V, a short-circuit current density (J SC ) of 23.83 mA cm -2 , and a fill factor (FF) of 76.05%. Meanwhile, the best PVSK-FA device exhibited a significantly improved performance with a V OC of 1.145 V, a J SC of 24.05 mA cm -2 , a FF of 76.31%, and the corresponding PCE of 21.01%. One of our best devices was sent to the accredited PV calibration laboratory (Newport, USA) and the certified PCE was 20.87% (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">10</ref>).</p><p>The slightly enhanced J SC value was attributed to improved lightharvesting capacity and a slightly red shift of the absorption onset. The major improvement in device performance was contributed from V OC enhancement, thanks to the high-quality perovskite thin film with significantly reduced intrinsic defect density by the addition of a weak alkaline additive. To be emphasized, in the present study, the addition of FAAc could slightly reduce the bandgap of the resultant film from 1.57 eV to 1.56 eV but increase V OC from 1.102 to 1.147 V in the resulting device. It is interesting that although the bandgap of the perovskite film decreased, the V OC of the relevant solar devices actually improved (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5b</ref>). It thus reveals one vital feature for this high-efficiency device, which is the small V OC deficit (defined as E g /q -V OC , where E g is the optical bandgap and q is the elemental charge). V OC deficit is an essential indicator to measure the potential of the photovoltaic material and the maturity of the relevant technology. Current V OC deficit for c-silicon, GaAs, and organic solar cells are around 400, 300, and 600 mV, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">53</ref> . Surprisingly, the corresponding V OC deficit in our device decreased to 413 mV upon FAAc addition, wherein both the V OC (1.147 V) and the bandgap (1.56 eV) were certified through a third party. The V OC deficit of 413 mV is one of the smallest certified value for planar heterojunction perovskite solar cells to date. It further implies substantially reduced non-radiative recombination losses in the PVSK-FA device, which was consistent with the high PLQE measured previously.</p><p>In addition, we did not observe an appreciable J-V hysteresis in the corresponding device, and the average PCE of 20.91% was achieved (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5c</ref> and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">10</ref>). The integrated photocurrent density gave a calculated value of 23.47 mA cm -2 from the external quantum efficiency (EQE) spectrum (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">11</ref>), which was comparable with the result from J-V   measurement. In addition, a steady-state current density of 21.89 mA cm -2 and a stabilized PCE of 20.80%, were also achieved by holding the voltage at the maximum power point (0.95 V) for the PVSK-FA device (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5d</ref>). To probe the reliability and repeatability, 20 individual devices were fabricated with the identical processing condition and the corresponding statistical distribution of the PCE values was presented (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">12</ref>). The average efficiency for the PVSK and PVSK-FA devices were 19.34% and 20.63%, respectively. Furthermore, we have investigated the long-term stability of the PVSK and PVSK-FA-based devices, as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">13</ref>. The reference without further encapsulation degraded to be around 80% within 1500 h of storage in an N 2 glove box, whereas the PVSK-FA-based devices exhibited less degradation.</p><p>It is possibly because of the higher thin-film quality of PVSK-FA with reduced defect states, which inhibits the penetration of undesirable water or oxygen molecules that further decompose perovskite films. Meanwhile, it may also correlate to the elimination of incident I 2 , which has been demonstrated to induce the chemical chain degradation of the perovskite <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">31</ref> .</p><p>To gain further insights into the carrier dynamics across the device, we measured transient photocurrent (TPC) and photovoltage (TPV) decays of PVSK and PVSK-FA-based devices on the microsecond scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">54</ref> . The PVSK-FA-based device exhibited a faster decay than that of the PVSK-based device, and the charge transport lifetime (τ t ) derived from TPC measurements (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">14</ref>) was decreased from 4.13 to 1.97 μs, indicating a dramatic improvement of charge transport capability for the PVSK-FA-based device. The TPV curves were correlated to the carrier recombination rates under the open-circuit condition in the full cell. We observed that the PVSK-FA-based device demonstrated a much slower decay, when compared with that of the PVSK-based device (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5e</ref>). The charge recombination lifetime (τ r ) derived from the TPV curves was significantly prolonged from 12.40 to 19.37 μs, suggesting that the carrier recombination was predominately prohibited in the device. It indicates that the prolonged lifetime constant τ r contributed from substantially reduced defect density in the perovskite material by the addition of weak alkaline additives.</p><p>Furthermore, we measured the V OC change as a function of illumination intensity to elucidate the carrier recombination mechanism during device operation. For both PVSK and PVSK-FA-based devices, the V OC increased monotonically with incident light intensity (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5f</ref>). According to the equation V OC = nkT/q ln(I SC /I 0 + 1), the values of the ideality factor were calculated to be 1.51 and 1.02, respectively. Generally, the ideality factor derails from unity if Shockley-Read-Hall (SRH) recombination occurs <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">55</ref> . In our study, the ideality factor for the PVSK-FA-based device showed a significant reduction from 1.51 to 1.02, when compared with that of the PVSK-based device. It demonstrates that trap-assisted SRH recombination was suppressed substantially due to the reduced intrinsic defect density, which was in good agreement with previous results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In summary, we demonstrate a universal pathway to effectively suppress the incident I 2 defects and manipulate the stoichiometry via the iodine disproportionation reaction under an alkaline environment. The alkalinity is proven to be a crucial parameter that greatly impacts the crystallization kinetics and optoelectronic properties of the perovskite films. A weak alkaline consisting of the FA + cation was demonstrated to serve as a 'residual' free agent to suppress deep-level defect density in the mixed perovskites ((FA,MA,Cs)Pb(I,Br) 3 ), which provides extra benefits in tuning the A-site stoichiometry and film morphology. Featured with a narrower bandgap of the absorber though, the device exhibited a significant enhancement on V OC . It observed one of the smallest V OC deficits of 413 mV in a certified planar heterojunction perovskite solar cell with an average PCE of 20.87%. These findings would bridge the gap between precursor chemistry and deep-level defect behavior in the perovskite film, particularly the iodide-based perovskite, which guides the design of nextgeneration perovskite solar cells with an efficiency approaching the theoretical limit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Materials. All the reagents and chemicals were used as received, including PbI 2 (99.999%, Sigma Aldrich), CsI (99.90%, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), N,Ndimethylformamide (99.99%, Sigma Aldrich), dimethyl sulfoxide (99.50%, Sigma Aldrich), sodium acetate (AR, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), formamidine acetate (99%, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), sodium bicarbonate (AR, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), sodium hydroxide (AR, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), potassium hydroxide (AR, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), sodium hypophosphite (99%, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), triethanolamine hydrochloride (99.5%, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), spiro-OMeTAD (Xi'an Polymer Light Technology Corp.), chlorobenzene (99.9%, Aladdin Industrial Corporation), 4tertbutylpyridine (99.90%, Sigma Aldrich), lithium bis(trifluoromethylsulfonyl) imide (99.95%, Sigma Aldrich), anhydrous ethyl alcohol (99.5%, Sigma Aldrich, product code: 459836), anhydrous isopropanol (99.5%, Sigma Aldrich, product code: 278475), and tin-doped indium oxide (ITO) substrates. All the formamidinium iodide (FAI), methylammonium iodide (MAI), methylammonium bromine (MABr), and methylammonium chloride (MACl) were synthesized and purified according to the procedure mentioned in the pervious literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">54</ref> .</p><p>Preparation of the SnO 2 films. The tin-doped indium oxide (ITO) substrates were cleaned with acetone, deionized water, and isopropanol ultrasonically. The tin (IV) oxide colloidal dispersion (SnO 2 , 15% in H 2 O colloidal dispersion) was purchased from Alfa Aesar. The precursor solution was diluted by H 2 O to 2.67% and then spin-coated onto glass/ITO substrates at 4000 rpm for 30 s, and finally baked on a hot plate at 150 °C for 30 min in ambient air.</p><p>Preparation of the perovskite precursor and films. To prepare the PbI 2 and organic cation precursors, 600 mg of PbI 2 and 18 mg of CsI were dissolved in 1 mL of mixture solvent of DMF:DMSO (9:1 v:v) and then annealed on a hot plate at 70 °C for 2 h with vigorous stirring. In all, 40 mg of FAI, 19 mg of MAI, 6 mg of MABr, and 5 mg of MACl were dissolved in 1 mL of isopropanol and then continuously stirred for 2 h at room temperature. To prepare the alkaline additive solution, 45 mg of different additives were dissolved in 1 mL of anhydrous ethyl alcohol at 70 °C for 30 min with vigorous stirring. Due to the different solubility of alkaline additives in ethyl alcohol, the possible supernatant was separated (Supplementary Note 11). For the certified perovskite solar cell, 45 mg of FAAc were dissolved in 1 mL of ethyl alcohol at 70 °C for 30 min with vigorous stirring. Then, 30 μL of FAAc ethanol solution was added to 1 mL of organic cation solution before being prepared with the perovskite film. The typical sequent-step method was employed to fabricate the perovskite film. First, the PbI 2 precursor was spincoated on the SnO 2 substrate in an N 2 glove box at 2300 rpm for 30 s (accelerated speed 6000 rpm s -1 ) and then annealed at 70 °C for 1 min in an N 2 glove box. Then, the organic cation precursor was spin-coated on the PbI 2 film at 2000 rpm for 30 s (accelerated speed 6000 rpm s -1 ) in an N 2 glove box. Finally, the film was kept under vacuum for 5 min and annealed at 150 °C for 15 min in ambient air to form the perovskite film.</p><p>Preparation of the Spiro-OMeTAD films and gold electrode. The Spiro-OMeTAD solution was first prepared by dissolving 72.3 mg of Spiro-OMeTAD, 17.5 μL of a stock solution of 520 mg mL -1 LiTFSI/acetonitrile, and 28.8 μL of tBP in 1 mL of chlorobenzene. Then the Spiro-OMeTAD precursor was spin-coated at 3000 rpm for 30 s (accelerated speed 6000 rpm s -1 ) in an N 2 glove box. Finally, 100 -nm-thick gold was thermally evaporated as a counterelectrode under a pressure of 1 × 10 -4 Pa on top of the Spiro-OMeTAD films to form the back contact by using a shadow mask to pattern the electrode.</p><p>Calculation setup. The calculations have been applied through DFT within CASTEP packages <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">56</ref> . For the functional, the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof-based generalized gradient approximation (GGA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">57</ref> has been selected to describe the electronic exchange-correlation interaction. All the geometry optimizations have been operated based on the Broyden-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shannon (BFGS) algorithm, in which the residue of the Hellmann-Feynman forces will be converged to less than 0.001 eV A -1 . The additional convergence criteria for the total energy and the interionic displacement are set to be less than 5 × 10 -5 eV per atom and 0.005 Å per atom, respectively. The ultrafine plane-wave cutoff energy with the ultrasoft pseudopotential scheme has been chosen as the basis set. The OH - molecule has been inserted into the PbI 2 model and FAPbI 3 unit cells with a different ratio n (n = 0.1-0.5) to represent the different concentration, which can be referred to as '#/unit cell' in this simulation. The corresponding effect to the activation energies will be calculated based on the following equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">E act ¼ E FAPbI 3 OH ð Þ n À E PbI 2 OH ð Þ n À E FAI<label>ð1Þ</label></formula><p>The Monkhost-Pack reciprocal space integration was performed using a spacing of 0.07 Å -1 in all models with a different OH -concentration <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">58</ref> , which was also self-consistently suggested by total energy minimization. With this special kpoint sampling, the total energy is converged within the maximum expected selfconsistent cycles.</p><p>Characterization. The absorbance of different precursor solutions and perovskite films was measured by a Hitachi UH4150 spectrophotometer. The integrating sphere was employed when we characterized the perovskite film. A field-emission SEM instrument (Hitachi S-4800) was used to acquire SEM images. The electron beam was accelerated at 5.0 kV. Temperature-dependent steady-state photoluminescence (PL) spectra were obtained by FLS980 (Edinburgh Instruments Ltd.), equipped with a Xe lamp, a liquid nitrogen cryostat (Oxford Instruments, Optis-tatDN-V), and a photomultiplier tube (PMT) detector. The excitation wavelength was 470 nm. The picosecond pulsed diode laser (EPL-470, Edinburgh Instruments Ltd.) was used to measure PL lifetime with a repetition rate of 0.2 MHz, a pulse width of 91.5 ps, a excitation fluence of ∼30 nJ cm -2 , and maximum average power of 5 mW. The PLQE data were obtained from a three-step technique through the combination of a 445-nm continuous-wave laser, a spectrometer, an optical fiber, and an integrating sphere <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">59,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">60</ref> . The powder XRD spectra (θ-2θ scans) were taken on a X'Pert3 powder X-ray diffraction system (PANalytical Inc.) with Cu Kα (λ = 1.5418 Å) as the X-ray source. The thermal admittance spectroscopy were conducted on Zahner Zennium pro Electrochemical Workstation at various temperatures (T = 250-350 K) in the dark from 10 0 to 10 6 Hz. A small AC voltage of 50 mV was used, and the DC bias was kept at zero to avoid the influence of the ferroelectric effect for perovskite materials during measurement. For temperaturedependent characterization, the sample was mounted in the Cryo Industries Liquid Nitrogen Dewars with Lake Shore model 335 cryogenic temperature controller. The current density-voltage (J-V) curves were measured (2400 Series SourceMeter, Keithley Instruments) under a simulated AM 1.5 G illumination at 100 mW cm -2 (Newport Thermal Oriel 91192 1000-W solar simulator). The light intensity was calibrated using a KG-5 Si diode. The J-V measurements were carried out in ambient air. The sweep speed was fixed at 40 mV s -1 (step 0.02 V, delay time 500 ms). The shading mask and one of our best device were sent to an accredited PV calibration laboratory (Newport, USA) for certification. The active area was defined as 0.09408 cm 2 . External quantum efficiencies (EQE) were obtained by an Enli Technology (Taiwan) EQE measurement system. A calibrated silicon diode with the known spectral response was used as a reference. For the transient photovoltage or photocurrent (TPV or TPC) decay measurements, a white light bias was from an array of diodes (Molex 180081-4320) to simulate 1-sun working condition, and the carriers were excited by a 532-nm pulse laser. The dynamics curves were recorded on a digital oscilloscope at a mega Ω (open-circuit condition for TPV) and a 50-Ω (short-circuit condition for TPC) resistor.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1 Suppression of I 2 impurity via alkaline additives. UV-vis absorption spectra of the organic cation solution, which is used to prepare the perovskite films, with different amounts of (a) FAAc, (b) CH 3 COONa, (c) NaHCO 3 , (d) NaOH, and (e) KOH ethanol solution. f Normalized absorbance for organic cation solution with different additives as a function of the volume</figDesc><graphic coords="43,71.56,209.15,138.76,112.24" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 Morphology, phase, and carrier lifetime analysis. SEM images for the perovskite films deposited on SnO 2 -coated ITO glass prepared from the precursor solution with (a) no additive, (b) FAAc, (c) CH 3 COONa, and (d) NaOH ethanol solution, with a scale bar of 1 μm. e X-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern for the perovskite films deposited on SnO 2 -coated ITO glass prepared from the precursor solution with different alkaline additives. f XRD pattern for the perovskite films with NO additive, MA, and FAAc ethanol solution. g Time-resolved photoluminescence (TRPL) spectra for the perovskite films deposited on glass prepared from the precursor solution with different alkaline additives</figDesc><graphic coords="44,68.05,190.70,131.80,115.24" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>5 FAFig. 3</head><label>53</label><figDesc>Fig. 3 Crystallization kinetics control of perovskite films. a Real-time UV-vis absorption spectra for the perovskite films without annealing prepared under different alkalinity environments. In situ absorption measurement for perovskite films with addition of (b) FAAc or (c) NaOH. The inset figures are derived from the change of absorption intensity (ΔI) for each sample at different times and the y-axis is the right one (Time). d Schematic illustration for the impacts of alkalinity on the crystallization kinetics of perovskite films. e Activation energies of the αand δ-phase of FAPbI 3 in the dependence of OH -concentration</figDesc><graphic coords="45,228.10,189.98,119.32,97.33" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4 Weak alkaline additives to reduce defect state density. Color plots of normalized steady-state PL spectra for (a) PVSK and (b) PVSK-FA at different temperatures from 78 to 350 K. c Corresponding steady-state PL spectra for both films at various temperatures from 250 to 350 K. d The PL quantum efficiency of PVSK and PVSK-FA films as a function of excitation power. The admittance spectra of the (e) PVSK and (f) PVSK-FA devices measured at a temperature from 250 to 350 K with a step of 10 K. g The corresponding Arrhenius plots of the characteristic frequencies to extract the defect activation energy (E a ) for both devices. h Trap density of states (tDOS) for both devices obtained by thermal admittance spectroscopy at room temperature</figDesc><graphic coords="46,70.72,180.74,95.80,77.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5 Photovoltaic device performance. a Current density-voltage curves for PVSK and PVSK-FA devices. b Left part: the UV-vis and PL spectra of for the PVSK and PVSK-FA films. Right part: the histogram of V OC for the PVSK and PVSK-FA devices and the curve represents Gaussian function fit to the statistics data. c The champion device performance under reverse scan (1.2 to -0.1 V) and forward scan (-0.1 to 1.2 V), with a scan rate of 40 mV s -1 . d Steady-state current density and power conversion efficiency holding the voltage at the maximum power point (0.95 V) for the PVSK-FA device. All these photovoltage characterizations were carried out under standard AM 1.5 radiation at ambient condition. e The transient photovoltage decay curves and (f) V OC as a function of light intensity for the PVSK and PVSK-FA devices</figDesc><graphic coords="47,410.20,189.38,123.16,99.76" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,125.05,77.05,344.85,145.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="12,157.20,75.85,280.80,647.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="21,90.00,72.25,414.95,170.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="22,90.00,73.70,414.50,308.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="23,90.00,77.05,414.95,177.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>work just seems contradictory with Yang's work; however, they are quite different due to the different perovskite preparation methods and different perovskite films.</figDesc><table><row><cell>ARTICLE</cell></row><row><cell>Impacts of alkaline on the defects property and</cell></row><row><cell>crystallization kinetics in perovskite solar cells</cell></row><row><cell>Yihua Chen 1 , Nengxu Li 1 , Ligang Wang 1 , Liang Li 1 , Ziqi Xu 1 , Haoyang Jiao 1 , Pengfei Liu 2 , Cheng Zhu 2 ,</cell></row><row><cell>Huachao Zai 2 , Mingzi Sun 3 , Wei Zou 4 , Shuai Zhang 5 , Guichuan Xing 6 , Xinfeng Liu 5 , Jianpu Wang 4 ,</cell></row><row><cell>Dongdong Li 7 , Bolong Huang 3 , Qi Chen 2 &amp; Huanping Zhou 1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Key Laboratory for the Physics and Chemistry of Nanodevices, Beijing Key Laboratory for Theory and Technology of Advanced Battery Materials, Department of Materials Science and Engineering, College of Engineering, Peking University, Beijing 100871, P. R. China.2  School of Material Science and Engineering, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing 100081, P. R. China.3  Department of Applied Biology and Chemical Technology, Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong 999077, P. R. China.4  Key Laboratory of Flexible Electronics &amp; Institute of Advanced Materials, Jiangsu National Synergetic Innovation Center for Advanced Materials, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing 211816, P. R. China.5  CAS Key Laboratory of Standardization and Measurement for Nanotechnology, CAS Center for Excellence in Nanoscience, National Center for Nanoscience and Technology, Beijing 100190, P. R. China.6  Joint Key Laboratory of the Ministry of Education, Institute of Applied Physics and Materials Engineering, University of Macau, Macau 999078, P. R. China.</figDesc><table><row><cell>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09093-1</cell><cell>OPEN</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note><p><p>7  </p>Shanghai Advanced Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 201210, P. R. China. Correspondence and requests for materials should be addressed to H.Z. (email: happy_zhou@pku.edu.cn) NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | (2019) 10:1112 | https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09093-1 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications</p></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | (2019) 10:1112 | https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09093-1 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgements This work is supported by the <rs type="funder">National Natural Science Foundation of China</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">51722201</rs>) (51672008) (91733301), <rs type="funder">Beijing Natural Science Foundation</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">4182026</rs>), <rs type="funder">National Key Research and Development Program of China</rs> Grant no. <rs type="grantNumber">2017YFA0206701</rs>, and <rs type="programName">Young Talent Thousand Program</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_X65bqjR">
					<idno type="grant-number">51722201</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_u4mqCQg">
					<idno type="grant-number">4182026</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_JKYy8Cp">
					<idno type="grant-number">2017YFA0206701</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Young Talent Thousand Program</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author upon request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Impacts of Alkaline on the Defects Property and Crystallization</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Kinetics in Perovskite Solar Cells</head><p>Yihua Chen <ref type="bibr">1</ref> , Nengxu Li 1 , Ligang Wang <ref type="bibr">1</ref> , Liang Li 1 , Ziqi Xu <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  To be more readable, we consider the whole experiment and theoretical calculation, and defined the meaning of weak, mild or strong alkalinity for different alkaline additives by pKa and immediately related to the phase state of the resultant perovskite films, as listed in the Supplementary Table <ref type="table">2</ref>. The weak alkalinity would not affect the phase state of perovskite films. The mild alkalinity could influence the transformation from PbI2 to -phase perovskite, appearing as the relatively increased PbI2 content. The strong alkalinity could promote the formation of δ-phase and suppress the formation of α-phase perovskite in resultant film, appearing as the presence of δ-phase perovskite. This definition has both considered the pKa and solubility difference between different alkaline additives. All detailed discussion will be given in the later.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 3.</head><p>Iodine disproportionation reaction have been widely studied in environmental, nuclear and general chemistry <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Currently, most studies about iodine disproportionation reaction were based on the aqueous solution. To further investigate if the underlying equilibrium of iodine disproportionation in non-aqueous solution was same as that in aqueous solution, we employed Fourier transform ion cyclotron resonance mass spectrometry analysis to exam the possible iodate anion in the equilibrium. As shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">15</ref>, the mass spectrometers work in negative ion mode, and we observed the nearly identical characteristic peak around mass-to-charge (m/z) = 174.899 in both aqueous (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">15a</ref>) and non-aqueous solution (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">15b</ref>), which probably represent the existence of IO3 -anion. This result indicated that the underlying equilibrium of iodine disproportionation in non-aqueous solution probably is same as that in aqueous solution and could been described as follows:</p><p>wherein X refers to the base, and the trace amount of water comes from the solvent (ethanol and isopropanol).</p><p>Based on the above-mentioned equilibrium, the number of iodates was not significant in this reaction, even less than that of I2. It is reported that incident I2 have been found to induce the chemical chain degradation of perovskite films 2 , but it does not apply to iodates. Thus, we think the effect of iodate ion in the system could be ignored.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 4.</head><p>When we struggled for the certification of our high efficiency perovskite solar cells, we have studied the influence of the moderate amount of PbI2 in perovskite solar cell. Just like other work that have been published <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr">4</ref> , we agree the moderate amount of PbI2 could effectively passivate the defect state in perovskite film and improve the device performance. Thus, our control sample contained significant fraction of PbI2. To further help the readers exam the relative intensity of PbI2 peak, we have normalized the XRD result in Fig. <ref type="figure">2e</ref> (main text) as</p><p>shown in Supplementary Fig. 16. We observed that perovskite films with CH3COONa or NaHCO3 additives showed obvious relatively stronger PbI2 peak. Moreover, when NaOH or KOH additives were added into the system, the distinct δ-phase perovskite peak occurred. It suggested that the alkalinity of the additives would affect the transformation process from PbI2 to α-phase perovskite.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 5.</head><p>Considering introduction of Na + and K + and the Goldschmidt tolerance factor, it is reasonable to correlate the shallow defects sites due to deformed crystal structure. Meanwhile, many literatures <ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">6</ref> declared that the incorporation of Na + or K + would effectively reduce the defect density of perovskite film. These results indicate the introduction of Na + and K + actually helps to prevent at least deep energy level defects. In addition, our recent results also show that the cation cascade doping will guide the perovskite crystal orientation <ref type="bibr">7</ref> , which serves as one of major reasons for the improvement of device performance.</p><p>However, almost all of these studies above were based on the one-step approach, which was very different from the two-step method that we employed in the current study. In addition, when exploring the influence of NaI or KI on the iodine-based perovskite film, the iodine ion was always negligible, which is reasonable. However, in our experiment, the effect of OH -is non-negligible and significant. Moreover, we don't deny the possible side effects of Na + or K + from NaOH or KOH on perovskite film. Besides these side effects, the major focus in our research is to reveal the significant effect of non-negligible OH -induced by the alkaline additives on the precursor solution and resultant films. To clearly illustrate the different influence from anions, we further studied additives of NaI, KI, NaOH, and KOH. We conducted UV-vis absorption and XRD analysis, and the results are as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">17</ref>  Supplementary Note 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 10.</head><p>We further conducted the PL emission spectra with increasing light intensity by femtosecond laser in PVSK and PVSK-FA films that spin-coated on a quartz substrate, as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">20a</ref> and<ref type="figure">20b</ref>. At the low excitation power, the integrated intensity from PVSK and PVSK-FA increases with increasing pump fluence. The different trap saturation threshold fluence (Pth trap ) have been observed at 1.85 J/cm 2 for PVSK and 1.29 J/cm 2 for PVSK-FA, as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">20c</ref> and<ref type="figure">20d</ref>. The lower Pth trap indicate that fewer photon was needed to fill the trap state, suggesting lower trap state density. According to the analytical mode presented in previous study <ref type="bibr">16</ref> , we have fitted the experimental data well (R 2 = 0.99). As shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">20e</ref> and<ref type="figure">20f</ref>, the fitted result suggested that the total trap concentration (Nt) in PVSK-FA film is 7.8 ( 0.7)  10 16 cm 3 , which is lower than the Nt in PVSK film (8.6 ( 0.9)  10 16 cm -3 ).</p><p>To characterize the femtosecond optical spectroscopy, A 400 nm laser pulse as the excitation source was obtained by a doubling BBO crystal from the Coherent Astrella amplifier (80 fs, 1 kHz, 800 nm). The pump laser spot size was 250 m (Objective: 10 ×, NA = 0.3). The signal was collected by the same objective lens into an optical fiber as backscattered emission, which was coupled to a spectrometer (Princeton Instrument SP2500i) and detected by a liquid nitrogen cooled charge coupled device detector. A 442 nm long pass filter was used before the optical fiber to block the pump laser. The optical characterization was conducted at room temperature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Note 11.</head><p>In fact, the molar equivalence of additives being added is closely related with the solubility of these alkaline additives in anhydrous ethanol. We have measured the solubility of these alkaline additives in ethanol roughly, and calculated the molar equivalence being added in the organic cation/isopropanol, which is shown in Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>. As expected, the solubility of NaOH and KOH is larger than the other additives, leading to possible precipitation in isopropanol.</p><p>To further examine if these precipitations have influence on the morphology of perovskite film rather than possible alkalinity, we have introduced into two other alkaline additives NH4OH and CH3NH3/ethanol solution. These two additives have not caused the precipitation in organic cation/isopropanol. At first, we employed the XRD measurement to confirm that the addition of NH4OH and CH3NH3/ethanol would facilitate the structural transformation from PbI2 to δ-phase perovskite, just like NaOH and KOH, which is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">21a</ref>, Meanwhile, the introduction of NaI and KI also would not cause the precipitation in precursor and the generation of δ-phase perovskite due to the lack of strong alkalinity. Then, we further performed the SEM measurement, and corresponding images were shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">21b-21h</ref>. We found that the resultant perovskite film with addition of NaI and KI additives is quite similar with the reference. And the resultant perovskite film with addition of NaOH, KOH, NH4OH and MA/ethanol solution is different from the reference.</p><p>Especially, the shape of crystalline grain is various, which might originate from the different phase of perovskite.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary References</head><p>Author contributions </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head><p>Supplementary Information accompanies this paper at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09093-1">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09093-1</ref>.</p><p>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</p><p>Reprints and permission information is available online at <ref type="url" target="http://npg.nature.com/reprintsandpermissions/">http://npg.nature.com/ reprintsandpermissions/</ref> Journal peer review information: Nature Communications thanks E.K. Kim and the other anonymous reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p><p>Publisher's note: Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The kinetics of iodine disproportionation: a system of parallel second-order reactions sustained by a multi-species pre-equilibrium</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Truesdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Luther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3428" to="3435" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accelerated degradation of methylammonium lead iodide perovskites induced by exposure to iodine vapour</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emilio</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Juarez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luis</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planar-Structure Perovskite Solar Cells with Efficiency beyond 21%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1703852</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controllable self-induced passivation of hybrid lead iodide perovskites toward high performance solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4158" to="4163" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing and stabilizing luminescence from halide perovskites with potassium passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abdi-Jalebi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">555</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="501" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A novel quadruple-cation absorber for universal hysteresis elimination for high efficiency and stable perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2509" to="2515" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulation of facet orientation in hybrid perovskite polycrystalline films by cation cascade</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2793</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correlated electron-hole plasma in organometal perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5049</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High photoluminescence quantum yield in band gap tunable bromide containing mixed halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sutter-Fella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="800" to="806" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodide management in formamidinium-lead-halide-based perovskite layers for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">356</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1376" to="1379" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A breakthrough efficiency of 19.9% obtained in inverted perovskite solar cells by using an efficient trap state passivator Cu(thiourea)I</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7504" to="7512" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The identification and characterization of defect states in hybrid organic-inorganic perovskite photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the Interaction of Molecular Iodine with MAPbI3: A Probe of Lead-Halide Perovskites Defect Chemistry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Meggiolaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Energy Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodine chemistry determines the defect tolerance of lead-halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Meggiolaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="702" to="713" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-performance photovoltaic perovskite layers fabricated through intramolecular exchange</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">348</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1234" to="1237" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low-temperature solution-processed wavelength-tunable perovskites for lasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="480" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards stable and commercially available perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N.-G</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grätzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Miyasaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Emery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16152</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unique properties of halide perovskites as possible origins of the superior solar cell performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4653" to="4658" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unusual defect physics in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 perovskite solar cell absorber</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">63903</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Halide-dependent electronic structure of organolead perovskite materials</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Comin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Sargent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4405" to="4412" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low trap-state density and long carrier diffusion in organolead trihalide perovskite single crystals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">347</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="519" to="522" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometal halide perovskites as visible-light sensitizers for photovoltaic cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kojima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Teshima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shirai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Miyasaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6050" to="6051" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growth of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 cuboids with controlled size for high-efficiency perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Im</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pellet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grätzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Nanotech</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="932" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporation of rubidium cations into perovskite solar cells improves photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saliba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">354</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite ink with wide processing window for scalable highefficiency solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17038</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Eu 3+ -Eu 2+ ion redox shuttle imparts operational durability to Pb-I perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">363</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Additive engineering for high-performance room temperature processed perovskite absorbers with micron-size grains and microsecond range carrier lifetimes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2365" to="2371" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employing lead thiocyanate additive to reduce the hysteresis and boost the fill factor of planar perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5214" to="5221" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remarkably high conversion efficiency of inverted bulk heterojunction solar cells: from ultrafast laser spectroscopy and electron microscopy to device fabrication and optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Alsulami</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Energy Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1502356" to="1502363" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lead iodide perovskite sensitized all-solid-state submicron thin film mesoscopic solar cell with efficiency exceeding 9%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H.-S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">591</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photon management for efficient hybrid perovskite solar cells via synergetic localized grating and enhanced fluorescence effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="540" to="549" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient and stable solution-processed planar perovskite solar cells via contact passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">355</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="722" to="726" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defects in perovskite-halides and their effects in solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ball</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Petrozza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16149</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Halide perovskite materials for solar cells: a theoretical review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Phys. -Chim. Sin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1730" to="1751" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">First-principles study of intrinsic defects in formamidinium lead triiodide perovskite solar cell absorbers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6800" to="6804" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defect migration in methylammonium lead iodide and its role in perovskite solar cell operation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Azpiroz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mosconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bisquert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Angelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2118" to="2127" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Density functional calculations of native defects in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 : effects of spin-orbit coupling and self-interaction error</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1461" to="1466" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strong covalencyinduced recombination centers in perovskite solar cell material CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Agiorgousis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14570" to="14575" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Materials processing routes to trap-free halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6281" to="6286" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Molecular origins of defects in organohalide perovskites and their influence on charge carrier dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grieco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Doucette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Asbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12392" to="12402" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying the molecular structures of intermediates for optimizing the fabrication of high-quality perovskite films</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9919" to="9926" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodine chemistry determines the defect tolerance of leadhalide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Meggiolaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="702" to="713" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chemical reduction of intrinsic defects in thicker heterojunction planar perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1606774</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced optoelectronic quality of perovskite thin films with hypophosphorous acid for planar heterojunction solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10030</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iodide management in formamidinium-lead-halide-based perovskite layers for efficient solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">356</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1376" to="1379" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Study on the stability of CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 films and the effect of post-modification by aluminum oxide in all-solid-state hybrid solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mater. Chem. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="705" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accelerated degradation of methylammonium lead iodide perovskites induced by exposure to iodine vapour</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emilioj</forename><surname>Juarez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luisk</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The kinetics of iodine disproportionation: a system of parallel second-order reactions sustained by a multi-species pre-equilibrium</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Truesdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Luther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3428" to="3435" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ultrasmooth organic-inorganic perovskite thin-film formation and crystallization for efficient planar heterojunction solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6142</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phase segregation in Cs-, Rb-and K-doped mixed-cation (MA) x (FA) 1-x PbI 3 hybrid perovskites from solid-state NMR</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kubicki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14173" to="14180" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planar-structure perovskite solar cells with efficiency beyond 21%</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1703852</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controllable self-induced passivation of hybrid lead iodide perovskites toward high performance solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4158" to="4163" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing and stabilizing luminescence from halide perovskites with potassium passivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abdi-Jalebi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">555</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="501" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A novel quadruple-cation absorber for universal hysteresis elimination for high efficiency and stable perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Environ. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2509" to="2515" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alkali metal halide salts as interface additives to fabricate hysteresis-free hybrid perovskite-based photovoltaic devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Appl. Mater. Inter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23086" to="23094" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulation of facet orientation in hybrid perovskite polycrystalline films by cation cascade</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2793</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trap states in lead iodide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2089" to="2096" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electron-phonon coupling in hybrid lead halide perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11755</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A. deconvoluted PL approach to probe the charge carrier dynamics of the grain interior and grain boundary of a perovskite film for perovskite solar cell applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mamun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Namkoong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9143" to="9148" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strong internal and external luminescence as solar cells approach the Shockley-Queisser limit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yablonovitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kurtz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE J. Photovolt</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photon recycling in lead iodide perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pazos-Outón</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">351</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1430" to="1433" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hybrid perovskite films approaching the radiative limit with over 90% photoluminescence quantum efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Braly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="361" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A breakthrough efficiency of 19.9% obtained in inverted perovskite solar cells by using an efficient trap state passivator Cu(thiourea)I</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7504" to="7512" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The identification and characterization of defect states in hybrid organic-inorganic perovskite photovoltaics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="116" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Origin and elimination of photocurrent hysteresis by fullerene passivation in CH 3 NH 3 PbI 3 planar heterojunction solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5784</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organometallic halide perovskites: sharp optical absorption edge and its relation to photovoltaic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>De Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1035" to="1039" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electron-hole diffusion lengths&gt;175 μm in solution-grown CH3NH3PbI3 single crystals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">347</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="967" to="970" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low-temperature solution-processed wavelength-tunable perovskites for lasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="480" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solar cell efficiency tables (Version 45)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Prog. Photovolt. Res. Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interface engineering of highly efficient perovskite solar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">345</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="542" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient luminescent solar cells based on tailored mixed-cation perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci. Adv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1501170</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">First principles methods using CASTEP</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Z. Krist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">220</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="567" to="570" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate and simple analytic representation of the electron-gas correlation energy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Perdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13244" to="13249" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the convergence of defect calculations in supercells: an ab initio study of the neutral silicon vacancy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I J</forename><surname>Probert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">75204</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An improved experimental determination of external photoluminescence quantum efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>De Mello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Wittmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Friend</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perovskite light-emitting diodes based on solutionprocessed self-organized multiple quantum wells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Photon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="699" to="704" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
